Turn 22 (Part Three): An Unkindness

Spoiler: Plan

[X] Focus On Military Targets
[X] Theta
-[X] All forces

An Unkindness
+045.M42+ To +050.M42+
+Never Falter, Never Surrender+

"Explosives planted," the scout murmured into the vox, voice inaudible to the patrolling slaughra soldiers who marched past, chittering to each other in their alien language from maws of pincers and fangs dripping with digestive fluids. "Awaiting your order."

The entire squad remained motionless in the snow, despite the chill seeping into their bones even through the armor, and waited. At one point, one of the slaughra outright stepped on one of the scouts, who remained silent even as the pincers of the leg went into his back. The xeno chirruped as it stumbled slightly, causing its fellows to give harsh rasping laughter at its mistake, a moment of levity despite the battles being fought across the planet. For the scout's credit, even though the armor had been pierced, they did not move, other than shifting ever so slightly to cover the wound with snow. The slaughra which walked away did not even note the blood on its leg which was swept away by the snow it marched across. Five minutes passed before the order came through, the vox crackling quietly. Cyrus' answer and order was the same, a single word that was growled out by the Captain who was providing overwatch on another operation miles and miles away.

"Go."

The trigger was squeezed, and the machine spirits did their duty in transmitting the order. The fuel station was, for a moment, a brilliant multi-colored star against the white and blue of the world's environment, flash heating the snow around the facility into steam immediately on heat alone. More importantly, the entire tank division which had been sat there both for protection and refueling went up as well, the fire scorching all. Secondary explosions went off soon after, fuel tanks on the outer edges of the base erupting in turn, until the entire base was an uninhabited inferno. Less than sixty seconds later, the slaughra patrol which had passed by returned, running, to gape and screech about the destruction, only to be cut short as ten specters dressed in red and black beneath their camo-cloaks rose up and slaughtered them in silence. Only then did they turn away, and retreat for their waiting stolen transports, to drive even further into the enemy lines. For the Blood Ravens had learned from the rage of the Imperial Guard who they had aided. Now, instead of hours ahead, they were days, weeks, months deeper into enemy territory than all but the most specialized and hardy of regiments and specialists, and there they did their work.

The swarm's front would collapse in a dozen places before the unrelenting onslaught of the Imperial Guard, bereft of fuel and reinforcements they had been expecting for quite some time. Soon enough, the aliens would begin to starve as they were forced into retreat, finding only blackened husks that had once been their bastions, bunkers, and holdouts. Supply depots scorched or blasted apart heralded the death knell of not just the Swarm's military forces but the various civilians they had on the world as well. Conscripts died just as well as their cooks and doctors, all starving to death in the cold without fuel or energy lines to provide heat. In those days, many a colonel and general would muse - but never say in the presence of the Lord General - on the wondrous victories that had been effectively piled at their feet for the taking. Morale shattered across the world, compounded in on itself again and again with the ripple effects of a continually broken set of supply lines. Ammo, fuel, food, and medicine, all of these most vital of things which formed the lifeblood of almost every military force in the galaxy, had been clawed away from the slaughra by the Angels of Death.

Spoiler: Slaughra Swarm (Z04X)

Libarius Scrying And Planning: 20. Negligible Results.
World Deployment Selection: 1d5=2= Ice World Deployment.
10th Company Efforts: 100! Natural Critical Success. Effects: Superlatively Effective Efforts Against Swarm Military Targets!
Cervantes Obstruction Attempts: 4. Non-Existent Results.
Conquest Progress:
Slaughra Capital World - 30% Imperial, 70% Slaughra
Slaughra Ice World - 38% Imperial, 62% Slaughra
Slaughra Desert World - 35% Imperial, 52% Slaughra
Slaughra 'Civilized' World Primaris - 24% Imperial, 64% Slaughra
Slaughra 'Civilized' World Secundus - 40% Imperial, 60% Slaughra
Z04X Space Control: Contested - Imperials Strongly Dominant, Z04X Swarm Naval Strength Exhausted, Z04Y Swarm Naval Strength Attempting To Return To Home System To Protect Homeworld

Decisions For 10th Company (Choose One):
[] Focus On Civilian Centers - The Imperial Guard, Imperial Navy, Trontiux Knights, and a Titan Legion are all focused largely on breaking the military capabilities of the Swarm. But this is not a simple military crusade, it is a total reclamation of worlds that should be for humanity's purposes, not the alien. Once, ages ago, they were, and now, they will be again. Thus, genocide. The vast majority of the Swarm, like many species, are either not military or being conscripted. As time goes on, this will continue. The more conscripts there are, the harder the fight will be. It would be better to kill them before they are properly armed, and to hopefully also cause significant morale damage.
[] Focus On Military Targets - The Imperial Guard, Imperial Navy, Trontiux Knights, and a Titan Legion are all focused largely on breaking the military capabilities of the Swarm. The Blood Ravens can aid in this, for there are few amongst any of those mighty forces who can manage the same stealth and capabilities of a properly trained and equipped scout. The more military positions, bases, supply dumps, barrier towers, shield towers, and more that are taken down, the faster the military will be destroyed, and thus, the faster the military can properly begin exterminating the civilian populace of the Slaughra.
[] Something Else - (Write-In)

=======================================

Arrival Through Warp: 43! Turbulence In Transit, Small Spread Of Ships On Arrival!
Tzeentchian Defenses: 77! Enemy Prepared For Arrival, Defensive Posture Assumed!

The orders are given, and the Imperial Navy splits from you with their violent passengers across the rest of the system. The Blood Ravens, on the other hand, turn towards the world which bears the mark of the Changer of Ways. The Librarius reports increased pressure as you approach, some of the younger Lexicani bleeding from an ear or eye but with the guiding hand of Justinius, none come truly close to succumbing. That alone is not enough, however, for you are moments into your arrival, the ship sliding from the screaming maw of the warp itself, when you realize that the enemy ships have already somehow shifted to meet you. The reasoning is simple, especially given Justininus' confirmation of feeling the touch of Chaos in this. It, of course, would be the Tzeentch worshipers who would turn their sorceries towards something like this.

Hadrian's Manuevering: 84
Theta Fleet Assault: 50

In the past, and now, the swarm are not so close to human technologies as to possess lances of their own, but with their connection to Chaos they do not need to be. Their corrupted vessels, the battleship-sized daemonship in the lead, let loose with near-lance equivalents of clearly warp-tainted origin. A screen of bio-mechanical torpedoes scream out through the void towards your ships, joined soon after by small lashes of laser arrays. None of them make significant progress in the goal of destroying your fleets. Hadrian does not bother barking out his orders, instead letting them flow through the command throne with his teeth grit. You clearly cannot feel every single significant movement of the battle barge, but you know they are occurring all the same. The tactical screen lights up with dozens of warning symbols that are answered in turn by the varied salvos of the ships of three company fleets combined.

Master of the Fleet: 99
Tzeentchian Swarm: 11
Tzeentchian Summoning Attempt: 42

A great flaring of light erupts from the planet-wide storm which obscures Theta from view, but it comes about for nothing for now, though you receive reports of the Librarius' youngest members struggling to remain cognizant. A summoning attempt, Justinius informs not just you but all on the bridge, his eyes flaring with light as he sees beyond the ship itself and into the warp. You hardly even need give orders, the Master of the Fleet and Chief Librarian capable of following and anticipating your wishes in a fight such as this. What the enemy misses in technological equality, they have bridged the gap with the tainted strength of Chaos in terms of firepower. Yet they do not face mere men, but space marines. Like a raging tempest, bombardment shells fall upon the enemy ships, a salvo from the strike cruisers knocking out its void shields in time for them to hit, shredding the greatest vessel's front and sides. Even as it lists, the cruisers twist about, undulating unnaturally and impossibly through space, firing all the while without hesitation.

Aggression Is Key: 25
The Changed Swarm: 6
Tzeentchian Summoning Attempt: 90

Aggression does not avail them here, as Hadrian forces your ships to match them strike for strike. The immensely powerful shielding and durable hulls of the battle barges prevents any of your own cruisers or escort ships to be destroyed, instead allowing them to maneuver swiftly and furiously. For all that space marine ships are not directly meant for void combat, they do not entirely fail at it either. Breaching swathes of torpedoes splash out across the somewhat less tainted cruisers, sabotaging systems and killing crew before retreating, while thunderhawks fly out and unleash damaging bombing runs on enemy hard points. But while the ships take heavy damage, a strong push by some of the strike cruisers shattering smaller shoals of escort-tonnage vessels entirely with close-range knife strikes of their weapon arrays, a great cascade of purpled lightning rocks over the spires on the planet below. It is matched by a cloud of lightning and calcified flesh growing out in randomized outcroppings from the wounds torn into the daemonship flesh. Then, to the cries of the lower Lexicanum before the codiciers and epistolaries can shield them, beasts slide out of the daemonship's wounds like maggots, massive things of flesh and warp energies personified.

Reorienting Charge: 86
Changed Swarm + Beasts of Tzeentch: 61

Such signs of Tzeentch are not the best of signs on the greatest of days, but they are foes just as well to be slain. Though they spew warpfire in great blasts across the void, poisoned gobs of plasma launching out of their gaping maws, the Blood Ravens maneuver around them. At one point, Hadrian maneuvers the Omnis Arcanum right in the center of their formation. The largest battle barge the Blood Ravens have ever possessed, one of the largest on record as far as you know due to the sheer breadth of is internal Librarium and Apothecarium facilities, with the requisite defensive capabilities to boot. He practically pushes the bombardment cannon into the daemonship's guts, the shields weathering withering amounts of firepower all around it, drawing the attention of the varied warp beasts that have been summoned - only for them to be flanked and assaulted from the rear by the strike cruisers and remaining battle barges.

Driving Them Back: 90
Sorcerous Defense: 46

In a moment, the enemy fleet doubles. Mirror images shimmer into being, moving in their own directions and firing their own weapons. Some even manage to scratch at the void shields, but Hadrian is undeterred. Which ships are which, for all begin moving at the same time in disturbing coordination, is determined as much by the efforts of the Librarius and Hadrian's intuition. And, perhaps, luck. Whether or not these constructs are as powerful as their fellows, it does not matter, for weapons arrays and torpedoes strike their maligned flesh just as well. The original ships are harder to destroy, but at the same time more hindered than helped by it. It's easier to tell which ships are copies and which are not by their continued survival against the salvos unleashed against them. The macrocannons and plasma projectors of the Omnis fire out again and again, breaking shields and allowing bombardment cannon strikes at the hands of the other battle barges to obliterate the enemy ships.

Crush: 4
Desperation: 92

The psychology of the swarm is obviously alien, though there are certain characteristics which are somewhat recognizable. Desperation. Hatred. Loyalty to the government and state - even if in this case it is to the Dark Powers. In this case, as some of their last ships give up all pretense of victory in favor of causing damage, some of your ships die in fire. One of the last Beasts of Tzeentch manages to coil itself around a gladius of the 4th Fleet, and in its death throes damages it enough to leave it shattered. The spine is broken open, and its innards spill into the void. What remains is then destroyed by another of the swarm ships. You know that you do not have enough escorts, barely even a full squadron where other Chapters would have multiple for each of their strike cruisers, and it bites you badly here. Nevertheless, Hadrian does not give up, and shifts the fleets accordingly. While the escorts flit about, firing as they can, more are destroyed, while the enemy's point defenses destroy some of your thunderhawks as they fly out to bomb them.

Attempted Reversal: 69
Thrashing In Death: 31

They fight, and fight viciously, but they die all the same. Eventually there is nothing more than the shattered molten remains of their vessels, while the daemonships are dematerializing entirely. The blobs of metal and circuitry which remained in their bodies does not phase away as the guiding grip on the materium is slain, but that is cleansed as well. The fight is done, in orbit at least, while lightning crackles across the planet-spanning cloud cover. From point to point are the strange crystalline towers, though you know for a fact that they cannot be allowed to exist for very long. Especially considering how they reacted and were likely at least partially responsible for the summoning which occurred here. While the casualties are counted, the wrecks that might be salvaged later towed back into a more stable position, you ponder your options. Obviously, landing troops without knowing what is down there is repulsive and foolish, you are not in such dire straits as to require it.

Confirmed Naval Presences In System said: said:

Imperial Navy Losses In System
1 Mars-class Battlecruiser
1 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
5 Lunar-class Cruisers
5 Escort Squadrons (x2 Firestorm, x1 Cobra, x2 Sword)

Blood Raven Losses In System
x2 Gladius Frigates (4th Company)
x2 Thunderhawk Gunships Great Father's Fist
x2 Thunderhawk Gunships Omnis Arcanum

Swarmworld Kappa
1 Emperor-class Battleship (Flagship of Admiral Graves)
2 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
4 Lunar-class Cruisers
15 Escort Squadrons (x11 Firestorm, x2 Sword, x2 Cobra)
10 Imperial Transports, Ferrying Order of Lost Rosetta

Swarmworld Theta
1st, 4th, 5th Company Fleets (Blood Ravens)

Swarmworld Nu
1 Apocalypse-class Battleship
3 Mars-class Battlecruisers
8 Lunar-class Cruisers
5 Escort Squadrons (x3 Firestorm, x2 Cobra)
20 Imperial Transports, Ferrying Order of Lost Rosetta

Swarmworld Sigma
2 Retribution-class Battleships
1 Mars-class Battlecruisers
8 Lunar-class Cruisers
9 Escort Squadrons (x5 Firestorm, x2 Sword, x2 Cobra)
20 Imperial Transports, Ferrying Order of Lost Rosetta

Daemonworld/Capital
1 Daemonship (Batteship-tonnage/Undivided-leaning)
1 Beast of Tzeentch (Battlecruiser-tonnage)
2 Swarmships (Battlecruiser-tonnage)
12 Swarmships (Cruiser-tonnage)
4 Daemonships (Cruiser-tonnage/Undivided-leaning)
2 Beasts of Tzeentch (Cruiser-tonnage)
15 Daemonship Squadrons (Escort-tonnages/Undivided-leaning)

Click to expand...

Click to shrink...

Set Approach For Stage Two Of Engagement:

[] Close For Bombardment: One thing that is learned after centuries of warfare in this galaxy - no matter the power of the shield, the strength of the daemon, the technological might, or sheer durability of the target, enough firepower can bring down anything. Blessed items, psychic sorcery, these are useful, true, but on the far end of the destructive scale even daemon princes can be slain by enough concentrated blasts, shells of devastating power, and magma bombs. These...Towers of Tzeentch must fall, both for their obvious connection to greater summoning sorceries, continued use over the planet, etc. Bring the battle barges in close, and begin firing. They are literally made for this one purpose - even if they can be turned to other uses - and break the towers down. Thus, the world beneath will be fully revealed.
[] Remain At Distance And Dispel: You cannot know the defenses of the enemy. How many anti-orbital defenses they might possess, other ships in perhaps dimensionally phased docks beneath the clouds, or what the towers themselves might do if you get close enough. They already spark and crackle with warp lightning, and were part of the summoning ritual which brought forth a group of ship-sized daemons. Who knows what might happen to your ships if they get close enough to be affected by them. Better instead to have the Librarius turn their might against them, to dispel the clouds, to at least reveal their purpose, and perhaps allow you to plan out better what is to occur next. At the least, here, failure might only slay some of the weakest of your Librarians, rather than cost you ships and marines at the same time.

Turn 22 (Part Four): An Unkindness

[X] Write-in: Focus on supply depots of all kind, military or civilian. Scourge entire areas of fuel and food and let them wither and descend into chaos for the Guard to mop up.
[X] Remain At Distance And Dispel

An Unkindness
+045.M42+ To +050.M42+
+Never Falter, Never Surrender+

Cervantes was proving to be...an annoyance. Cyrus growled near silently as he watched a series of basilisk strikes blowing their way along the trench lines. The vox crackled quietly in his bionics as he tapped a finger against them, going on a secure company-wide band.

"Scouts, pull back. There is no point in moving through the shadows if they are to be replaced with craters. Relocate back to secure position tertius-five. We will move on to secondary targets."

The ground trembled, and Cyrus narrowed his eye at the sight of what was pouring out of the heavily disturbed earth. From more than that as well, from the xeno buildings which arched about in all directions, crisscrossing where the biomechanical connectors marked one another. The street was enough for a tank division to drive down, and from the smoke and blood thrown up by the artillery strikes came...exactly what he had suspected would be unleashed. Once enough pressure was put upon the Slaughra, it was inevitable that their masters would unleash themselves. Genestealers screeched as they emerged from the sewer systems like blood from a torn open vein. Bioplasma rockets out of a chitinous cannon wheeled forth, slaughtering a bevy of Guardsmen in one strike. From the buildings of the city around them came more of them, the Guardsmen moving through the buildings forced into immediate close-quarters fighting as the aliens emerged from the shadows. The screams of terror filled the air, and Cyrus watched as the Guardsmen were overwhelmed at their first line, then the second. A group of Leman Russ tanks fired, thundering into the fray, but they took casualties almost immediately. A particularly hulking genestealer leapt atop one, ripping open the top, and leapt within to slaughter the crew in fountains of blood.

"Orders, Captain?"

Cyrus turned to one of the scouts who had approached him before turning towards the enemy once again, a hand held out for silence.

"Squads report on targets."

The vox crackle was near inaudible from the sounds of furious battle as the Guard attempted to regroup against the genestealer horde which was likely erupting across the entire planet.

"Supply Depot burned, no casualties," one scout sergeant returned first, the former 1st Company veteran toneless in his words.

"Farmer fields scorched, no fatalities. Some scouts will need time healing, stealth was compromised by Guard assaults on nearby enemy defensive positions," came another's voice.

"Promethium cache has been given over to Guard hands," a third sergeant replied, causing Cyrus' eye to twitch.

"That was not your mission Tyrus," he grunted, "The fuel stores were to be destroyed."

"I saw an opportunity and took it," the veteran's shrug could practically be heard. "Promethium is promethium, harvested by xeno hands or not. The Guard and Mechanicus we gave it over to were certainly grateful enough. The rest of the base is gone as well, detonation packs deployed successfully."

Cyrus closed his eye and racked his brain on Scout Sergeant Tyrus, flicking through the hundreds who had passed beneath the banner of the 10th Company. Former 1st Company. Former 5th Company. Former...ah. Right. Former 4th Company. Part of Aramus' task force. One of those who did not feel the need to disappear on the Penitent Crusade, citing his lack of presence and input on any of the more controversial decisions made on the Force Commander's part. Dangerously uncaring for authority, yet undeniably effective. A tactical marine who carried a chainsword instead of the common knife, for one. Just one more signal of unorthodox behavior. And for all of this...loyal. Subject to multiple exhaustive tests by the few chaplains the Chapter possessed after the purge. Hmph.

"If this brings harm to the chapter in any way...," he finally murmured.

"Then I won't even see you coming," Tyrus acknowledged before flicking his vox connection off.

"Other squads, report," Cyrus ground out. "The rest of you, with me. We're withdrawing from this fight, and deploying elsewhere."

The Blood Ravens slowly withdrew from the front, their missions accomplished. If the sudden desperation and hungry fury the enemy displayed was at least partially that fault, then so it was and would be. One would be hard tasked to ask the Blood Ravens if they cared for this at all. Even more so to find one to ask. Their presence was marked in the aftermath, in broken fields, shattered supply depots, stolen resources, and vaporized food storage.

Spoiler: Slaughra Swarm (Z04X)

Libarius Scrying And Planning: 21. Negligible Results.
World Deployment Selection: 1d5=5= 'Civilized' World Secundus Deployment.
Cervantes Obstruction Attempts: 62. Notable Success. Effects: 10th Company Effort Success Reduced In Potency!
10th Company Efforts: 80! Significant Success. Effects: Effective Efforts Against Swarm Military Targets!
WARNING: Slaughra Genestealer Cult Has Activated Tyranid Bioforms Out Of Desperation!
Conquest Progress:
Slaughra Capital World - 27% Imperial, 73% Slaughra
Slaughra Ice World - 35% Imperial, 65% Slaughra
Slaughra Desert World - 30% Imperial, 70% Slaughra
Slaughra 'Civilized' World Primaris - 45% Imperial, 55% Slaughra
Slaughra 'Civilized' World Secundus - 40% Imperial, 60% Slaughra
Z04X Space Control: Contested - Imperials Strongly Dominant, Z04X Swarm Naval Strength Exterminated, Z04Y Swarm Navy Surrounded And Brought Down In Attempt To Retreat To Home System

Decisions For 10th Company (Choose One):
[] Focus On Civilian Centers - The Imperial Guard, Imperial Navy, Trontiux Knights, and a Titan Legion are all focused largely on breaking the military capabilities of the Swarm. But this is not a simple military crusade, it is a total reclamation of worlds that should be for humanity's purposes, not the alien. Once, ages ago, they were, and now, they will be again. Thus, genocide. The vast majority of the Swarm, like many species, are either not military or being conscripted. As time goes on, this will continue. The more conscripts there are, the harder the fight will be. It would be better to kill them before they are properly armed, and to hopefully also cause significant morale damage.
[] Focus On Military Targets - The Imperial Guard, Imperial Navy, Trontiux Knights, and a Titan Legion are all focused largely on breaking the military capabilities of the Swarm. The Blood Ravens can aid in this, for there are few amongst any of those mighty forces who can manage the same stealth and capabilities of a properly trained and equipped scout. The more military positions, bases, supply dumps, barrier towers, shield towers, and more that are taken down, the faster the military will be destroyed, and thus, the faster the military can properly begin exterminating the civilian populace of the Slaughra.
[] Something Else - (Write-In)

===============================================

It is the greatest gathering of the Librarians of the Blood Ravens since the purge. What a pitiful sight. Where once an entire squad of Epistolaries could have been formed aside from those dedicated to the companies, now there are but Lexicanum and Codiciers. Younger. Weaker. More prone to destruction and devastation. Even with Justinius standing in the center of them, his eyes blazing with power, the whole of his weighty power an anchor for the rest, it is a reduced gathering compared to what you know might once have existed. So many dead from Kyras' manipulations, assassinations, and in the end his blatant assault on their existence in the last days of the Purge. It will take so long to find those with sufficient strength and will to replace the lost, and even though you are no psyker you can tell that you will not even do so from amongst the ranks of those gathered here, not fully. Some, like Nero, stand above. Damion too, wielding the force staff granted to him by the Death Spectres, stands in his darkly colored armor, more ebony than red or blue.

Out in the void, the world of the Slaughra rumbles beneath the attentions of the powers of the warp. The remains of their ships are broken and scattered, leaving your ships free to assume a defensive posture in preparation for this ritual. The Omnis Arcanum practically rumbles with the psychic power collected now, the Litany of Fury nearby. The Sanctorium Arcanum is still poorly understood by all despite all this time that has passed since it was crafted, but in this measure, it may provide some aid.

Ritual Beginnings: 92

Sorcerous Defenses: 74

The black and blue clouds which span the planet-wide storm roil with the attentions of your librarians. Clouds boil as if they were blood, with thick cables of lightning bursting into being across the skeins of the atmosphere below. The towers which stretch out from below literally warp to the sensors, blowing out a half dozen struggling cogitators trying to make sense of the nature of the immaterium itself before being shut down by the techmarines. Silvery and liquid from one instant, mercurially solid and facet-less the next, the towers ripple.

Ritual Progression: 77
Sorcerous Defenses: 95

Backlash comes, as you knew it would. One of the lexicanum dies horrifically, his head caving inwards further and further in a swirling spiral loop of meat and bone along with his feet towards some unknowable center point. Out of necessity the gene-seed in his bodies is ripped out just before the rest of him is sucked into oblivion. It is a horrifying exchange of soul and body, but Justinius pushes on, marshalling the combined strength of the rest of the Librarius.

Pushing Past: 39
Changed Rejection: 16

And there is strength there, spent yet not drained fully. Nero roars with power, light far brighter than his bionic eyes could possibly emit naturally gleaming forth as he assaults the veil over the world fully. From the bridge, it is a silent contest of wills, one you can only see the results of, not the struggle itself. One of the towers below cracks, suddenly, and a small burst of actually comprehensible data flows through in return.

Warp Piercing: 12
Storm Of Tzeentch: 47

Until the cracks refill, the data received becomes garbled once more, and a codicier dies screaming, his entire body burnt to a crisp before the gene-seed could be recovered. The dark flames disappear as soon as they arrived leaving only a small pile of ash behind.

Redirected Psychic Assault: 89
Tzeentch's Veil: 54

Blood seeps out from the sockets of his bionic eyes, but Nero pushes through all the same. A sweeping burst of his psychic powers is joined by the greater rumbling storm of Justinius, and one of the towers cracks once more, nearly snapping in half. The non-euclidean physical state of the tower is unsustainable without a greater connection to the warp, one that the librarians are struggling to sever.

Shatterpoint: 1
Bound In Crystalline Bone: 75

There is a surge of power from the planet, one that even creates minor gravimetric anomalies amongst the fleet. Serfs screech as their minds are briefly tainted by the touch of the warp, and a full five lexicanum and another two codiciers are burnt out by the ritual outright nearly ending from a fracture in the immaterium. The denizens on the planet are now fully aware of what you are doing, there is little doubt. A cruiser-sized daemonship rips itself out of the clouds which bleed unborn starstuff from the wound ripped open in it which heals slowly, not-flesh knitting back together. It barely births itself before being shot down, but that it managed to push itself forth at all is disturbing in the extreme.

Vengeful Blood: 97
Warped Soulstorms: 27

Deep within the Librarium, Justinius rises from where he had fallen to one knee. His hands stretch out, towards the planet, and the blood spilling from all rises up in the air. From ears, from noses, from eyes, the blood rises up, drawn from the Librarians of every rank to form between his fingers into a steadily growing globe. It roils in his fingers, dancing across the armor, until the ash of the burnt out codicier joins it, the few scraps of armor from the Lexicani lost as well.

Knowledge. Is. Power: 98
Barring The Stormgate: 33

A raven forms, of ash and blood, betwixt the fingers of the Chief Librarian. Student of Jonah Orion, who bore the brunt of the Hive Mind's attentions and yet lived. A legacy writ in sacrifice and near-destruction. Knowledge peeled from texts and tomes of terrible power, the collected knowledge of the Blood Ravens for millennia such that even Inquisitors would balk at what was kept preserved rather than destroyed. A darker ritual, one that some Chapters would never consider, enacted in the blink of an eye to the next beat of a raging heart at those lost already. The red center, the compressed blood of so many Librarians alive and dead, pulses with eldritch power. Below, a tower cracks, breaks, shatters, sending crystalline shards the size of baneblades falling to the planet below. Some dissipate entirely back into the warp, the psychically conductive materials unsustainable without their connection to the warp. Cloudflesh is ripped open, a caesarean unfurling of the veil.

The world below has been wracked by the presence of a planet-spanning storm for so long that you personally have doubts about the ability of the Imperium to actually hold it in the longer term. More likely it will be forced to be some sort of penal colony of some sort, given the blasted wasteland that is the surface. As the tower collapses entirely, the greater lattice is abruptly strained, weakening the overall storm itself, while allowing the hole you've torn open to be widened ever so slightly. Roving bands of mutated Slaughra, the most heavily mutated out of all seen thus far, squeal at the sudden touch of light from their sun, where previously the only light was that of the warp, of lightning strikes, and whatever bio-luminescent technologies they could keep working. The base of the tower appeared to be a small temple-city, of all things, likely built and given upkeep by continual worship and sacrifices by the slaughra to maintain it and allow whatever unknowable things that the Dark Gods might wish to happen to occur hidden from the gaze of the rest of the galaxy. No longer. As the tower collapses, broken by psychic strength, shards that do not dematerialize collapse downwards, a meteor shower of their own creation.

Ritual Results:
-6 Lexicanum, -3 Codiciers
+16 Gene-Seed Recovered
Swarmworld Theta Veil Broken! Hole In Sorcerous Lattice Opened!

Confirmed Naval Presences In System said: said:

Imperial Navy Losses In System
1 Mars-class Battlecruiser
1 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
5 Lunar-class Cruisers
5 Escort Squadrons (x2 Firestorm, x1 Cobra, x2 Sword)

Blood Raven Losses In System
x2 Gladius Frigates (4th Company)
x2 Thunderhawk Gunships Great Father's Fist
x2 Thunderhawk Gunships Omnis Arcanum

Swarmworld Kappa
1 Emperor-class Battleship (Flagship of Admiral Graves)
2 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
4 Lunar-class Cruisers
15 Escort Squadrons (x11 Firestorm, x2 Sword, x2 Cobra)
10 Imperial Transports, Ferrying Order of Lost Rosetta

Swarmworld Theta
1st, 4th, 5th Company Fleets (Blood Ravens)

Swarmworld Nu
1 Apocalypse-class Battleship
3 Mars-class Battlecruisers
8 Lunar-class Cruisers
5 Escort Squadrons (x3 Firestorm, x2 Cobra)
20 Imperial Transports, Ferrying Order of Lost Rosetta

Swarmworld Sigma
2 Retribution-class Battleships
1 Mars-class Battlecruisers
8 Lunar-class Cruisers
9 Escort Squadrons (x5 Firestorm, x2 Sword, x2 Cobra)
20 Imperial Transports, Ferrying Order of Lost Rosetta

Daemonworld/Capital
1 Daemonship (Batteship-tonnage/Undivided-leaning)
2 Beast of Tzeentch (Battlecruiser-tonnage)
2 Swarmships (Battlecruiser-tonnage)
12 Swarmships (Cruiser-tonnage)
4 Daemonships (Cruiser-tonnage/Undivided-leaning)
5 Beasts of Tzeentch (Cruiser-tonnage)
15 Daemonship Squadrons (Escort-tonnages/Undivided-leaning)

Click to expand...

Click to shrink...

Set Plans For For Stage Three Of Engagement:

[] Land And Fortify: The world is meant to be secured after all, and while the orbit can be held, now, troops on the ground are needed to fully claim things. By taking this first landing site and fortifying it, you will possess a beachhead from which to do a number of things, from sending out strike parties against the roving mutant bands, fire artillery at the base of towers nearby without risking more Librarians, or simply provide a focal point to exhaust enemy strength upon. Or perhaps to scout major features of the planet, plant orbital beacons to fire upon through the clouds, etc. [Write-In Forces Deployed]
[] Remain At Distance And Dispel: The proof is before you. It can be done. With each tower brought down, the collective power of the storm of Theta is stripped away. Formerly greater than the sum of its parts, now that same nature can be turned against it. The strain will build upon the rest of the lattice with every tower shattered, each weakened further in magnitude for each that falls. It will cost the Librarians, you know this, but that is the calculus of war. Risk a handful of psykers against more than a hundred battle brothers, with a Chapter not even at half strength.

Turn 22 (Part Five): An Unkindness

[X] Land And Fortify - All Companies+Leadership & Associated Vehicles and Specialists

[X] 10th Company deploys to Slaughra Desert World and continues destroying food and fuel en masse

An Unkindness
+045.M42+ To +050.M42+
+Never Falter, Never Surrender+

There is much to be said of the Titans, the god-machines of the Adeptus Mechanicus. Such mighty beasts of technology they were that even Cyrus knew the faintest hints of awe and trepidation upon viewing one in open battle. Grim anger was the more usual emotion that fluttered through his cold heart when he was forced to face the Titans of the enemy. Of which there were many kinds of course. He had seen the most exotic and horrifying of machines that the Dark Eldar could unleash. The crackling green lightning over metal as black as the void from an awakened Necron Tombworld. Gargants as well could be a threat of truly devastating proportion if marshalled by an ork of significant enough will. But none of these made him feel foreboding as an unleashed Bio Titan of the Hive Mind.

“Detonate the explosives, detonate now!” He barked into the vox, and watched without passion as they went up across the swirling desert.

It was not finished, that monstrous creature. A slaughra given ballooned form, tyranid chitin and claws extending from a multitude of undulating tentacles. It was barely birthed, not fully formed, and that is the only reason it died. The greater plates of chitin which could have resisted blasts from volcano cannons had not interlocked fully, and the vulnerable flesh beneath erupted in vortex and plasma explosions that could be seen from a full mile away. It had taken a significant amount of negotiation with the fleet above to allow him to use the warheads of the torpedoes, but they had acquiesced in the end. If only they had gotten more, before Cervantes had shifted his forces closer and closer. There were many things that Cyrus would do in the name of victory, but needlessly destroying the Guard and reducing them to glass along with the desert was not one of them. When it was not absolutely required, at least.

Still, the creature died, screaming, the blasting sands reduced to boiling molten seas of glass that would solidify eventually. Sheets and panes of flash-forged glass whipped about in the endless desert storms that rocked the world, some shattering harmlessly against the ground or against tanks. Others broke upon some of the scouts, who would require healers for the foot-long shards lodged in their armors and bodies. One scout was unlucky enough to have his entire throat torn open, but lived. In time the flesh would heal. At the least, the Librarius had truly come through in locating the creature in its secreted womb deep within the desert before it could be unleashed. That a half dozen other secondary targets were successfully destroyed was simply a bonus.

Spoiler: Slaughra Swarm (Z04X)

Libarius Scrying And Planning: 94. Extremely Successful Results!
Cervantes Obstruction Attempts: 62. Notable Success. Effects: 10th Company Effort Success Reduced In Potency!
10th Company Efforts: 80! Significant Success. Effects: Effective Efforts Against Swarm Military Targets!
WARNING: Slaughra Genestealer Cult Has Activated Tyranid Bioforms Out Of Desperation!
Conquest Progress:
Slaughra Capital World - 27% Imperial, 73% Slaughra
Slaughra Ice World - 35% Imperial, 65% Slaughra
Slaughra Desert World - 30% Imperial, 70% Slaughra
Slaughra 'Civilized' World Primaris - 45% Imperial, 55% Slaughra
Slaughra 'Civilized' World Secundus - 40% Imperial, 60% Slaughra
Z04X Space Control: Contested - Imperials Strongly Dominant, Z04X Swarm Naval Strength Exterminated, Z04Y Swarm Navy Surrounded And Brought Down In Attempt To Retreat To Home System

Decisions For 10th Company (Choose One):
[] Focus On Civilian Centers - The Imperial Guard, Imperial Navy, Trontiux Knights, and a Titan Legion are all focused largely on breaking the military capabilities of the Swarm. But this is not a simple military crusade, it is a total reclamation of worlds that should be for humanity's purposes, not the alien. Once, ages ago, they were, and now, they will be again. Thus, genocide. The vast majority of the Swarm, like many species, are either not military or being conscripted. As time goes on, this will continue. The more conscripts there are, the harder the fight will be. It would be better to kill them before they are properly armed, and to hopefully also cause significant morale damage.
[] Focus On Military Targets - The Imperial Guard, Imperial Navy, Trontiux Knights, and a Titan Legion are all focused largely on breaking the military capabilities of the Swarm. The Blood Ravens can aid in this, for there are few amongst any of those mighty forces who can manage the same stealth and capabilities of a properly trained and equipped scout. The more military positions, bases, supply dumps, barrier towers, shield towers, and more that are taken down, the faster the military will be destroyed, and thus, the faster the military can properly begin exterminating the civilian populace of the Slaughra.
[] Something Else - (Write-In)

===============================================

Ravenfall
54 vs. 55

The shards of the tower fall, this is true, but they do so in the manner of the warp from whence the tower was forged. Some rocket down at speeds so quickly they crater the ground where they land and obliterate more of the forces of Chaos who had resided there amidst the destruction. Others fall so slowly that they appear practically suspended in the air. Others fall up, some fall sideways into the ruin of the tower, and still others fall and disappear. You see none of this with your own eyes, ensconced as you are in the drop pod as it flies forth. Lightning crackles in the clouds, but the presence of the Librarians in their own pods appears to somewhat repel the mysterious storm of Tzeentch which covers so much of the planet. Around them, at least. Others are less fortunate, their pods knocked aside by anti-aircraft fire launched upwards from the weapons of the enemy, one drop pod smashing directly into a shard and nearly slaying all of the battle brothers within. Instead the unfortunate pod merely tumbles far and away from its designated drop point, slamming sideways into the churned earth with enough force to slay lesser beings entirely. They emerge all the same, set upon immediately by both slaughra and more horrible daemon creatures that gallop on nine legs each.

As for you? You land successfully, but the forces of the xeno and the Great Enemy manage to rally with distressing speed and success to face your brothers as they emerge.

"DIE, you fell cretin," you hear Hadrian yell out from his drop pod, liberally making use of the weapon Martellus crafted for him.

With one swipe, he rips open the daemons belly with the bayonet attached to the plasma pistol before shoving the barrel inside and pressing the firing stud. The explosion of warp-borne gore is...spectacularly messy as a result, though he moves on uncaring of the splattering upon his armor. All around you, the Blood Ravens assemble, firing upon the enemy, preparing themselves for the fight to come. And it will come, of that you have no doubt. Already the shock is fading, the xenos tainted so heavily with the insanity of Chaos that they do not mark the measures of shock and awe tactics upon their minds as they should. Small batteries of anti-aircraft 'vehicles' fire warpstuff in the shape of shells high, before swiveling on their mounts towards the pods that have already landed.

Securing The Landing Zone
80 vs. 2

But their defenses, their hordes of daemons and mutants, and their own malformed weaponry avails them not. The Land Raiders erupt from their moorings, nearly tearing the thunderhawks that delivered them apart with the exertion. Lascannons and heavy bolters fire out with impunity. Hadrian personally leaps upon a rhino and rides it forth, firing krak missiles from two launchers at once, two marines behind him on the rhino loading the weapons in turn after each spear of destruction is launched. You fall upon the enemy, squealing and screeching as they do, with all the fury of the Blood Ravens present and past. Godsplitter reaps a healthy toll amongst the enemy, while amongst you the rest of the Captains and leadership present unleash themselves. Just as you are killing the last of the enemy immediately near the landing site of all of your Blood Ravens, the clouds which were forced back begin to rumble and undulate once more.

The World Against You
9 vs. 94

Shields of psychic energy rise amongst the Librarians, but it is not enough for some. While the domes are wide and strong, they cannot cover all of your brothers present. One of the further squads, returning from pursing the last of the mutant bands which had worshipped at the base of the tower unceasingly for generations, is struck by a blast from the clouds. Three brothers are immolated immediately, but the effects are not that of simple flame and fire. Another simply keels over, no outward sign of his death until his helmet is removed and a vast pile of dust simply slides out, his bones and skin transformed instantly. A fifth has to have his arm and leg removed from the mutations which had immediately set upon him, bleeding profusely as the apothecaries arrive only to die as his blood clots into ink-black ice in his veins. Hannibal has to step forth, then, and bring his crozius down on the limbs - or rather the astartes sized creatures that had grown out of them before they could become fully grown.

The Storm Rages
20 vs. 5

Another set of lightning comes rocketing down, but by then everyone has moved within the protective aegis of the Librarians. Justinius stands at the center of them all, arms splayed out to the sides, light curling around his arm in bangles which chime softly with every movement. You take the moment to study the earth, blackened and crusted after so long beneath the ministrations of the formerly planet-wide storm. Yet, small amounts of vegetation exist. Life is somewhat sustainable here though you do not wish to consider the darker implications of how such large populations managed to exist here. Some died here, from the tower collapsing or from your arrival, but many more escaped. In the distance, at random lengths which do not match up with what the ships scans can determine from above, you see other towers. Other...bastions of the malefic civilization which rules this world in the name of the Dark Gods. At the same time, the forces you run off from around this tower are surely rallying out there, in the vast black desert that is much of this world. Visibility is poor, and more traditional attempts at scans fail easily the moment the distance is extended to beneath the clouds of the storm above. The small hole torn open in the sorcerous lattice which kept the world from the sun's rays is likely the first sunlight that the soil has had in quite some time.

The bulbous white spheres which exist at random places upon even the less mutated slaughra lends credence to that thought, at the least.

"Landing zone secured, Chapter Master," Apollo reports as he strides up to you, gore caking his armor. "What are your orders?"

Landing Results:
-3 Marines (5th Company) Immolated Badly, Unavailable For Combat For Rest Of Battle!
-1 Marine (5th Company) Dead, Skin/Bones Turned To Dust. Organs Unaffected. +2 Gene-Seed Recovered.
-1 Marine (5th Company) Dead, Arm+Leg Amputed/Mutated. Blood turned to ink-black ice in veins. +2 Gene-Seed Recovered.

Set Plans For For Stage Four Of Engagement:

[] To Kill What Comes: You have taken one of their holy sites. You have forced them to retreat. Animalistic pride alone would demand recompense and revenge. Prepare for this. Already you have forces here, and outside of the clearly dangerous cloud cover which could unleash itself at any time if you were directly under it. The enemy will come for you, and they will batter and break upon your weapons and fury. Once they are exhausted, you will likely be able to strike out against the towers with greater ease...supposedly at least. Nothing is certain on a world ruled by Tzeentch - even if it has not yet become a true Daemonworld. [Write-In Forces Deployed]
[] The Speartips: Before the enemy can rally, destroy them! Borrow from the tactics of the White Scars, and strike out before the enemy can prepare for you. They are aware, and so surprise is likely not quite the same devastating weapon it might have been before. However, they likely imagine you will remain in the territory you took, and wait for them to come. Well you will not. Three towers are nearby - relatively at least - and could be attacked. They are as bases and settlements in one, but melta bombs, Land Raiders, and krak explosives will take them down from the base all the same once the aliens, mutants, and daemon which cluster at them are destroyed. They will require heavy Librarian support, however, for they shall be venturing out beneath the practically living storm of Tzeentch which rules here. You will also have to dedicate forces to keep the landing zone clear, else the enemy might come and reclaim it. (NOT REQUIRED TO ASSAULT ALL 3 AT ONCE)
-[] Landing Zone: [Write-In Forces Kept Back For Defense]
-[] Tower 1: The vast majority of those who fled before the Blood Ravens headed in the direction of this tower, bringing their daemon creature packs and more heavily armed Slaughra soldiers with them. [Write-In Forces Deployed]
-[] Tower 2: The lesser minority of those who fled before the Blood Ravens - largely mutants without a large amount of firepower to them - headed in the direction of this tower.
-[] Tower 3: This tower received none of the fleeing forces of the enemy. Further details are unreliable due to the storm preventing both intense psychic scrying and more traditional means of scanning.

Confirmed Naval Presences In System said: said:

Imperial Navy Losses In System
1 Mars-class Battlecruiser
1 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
5 Lunar-class Cruisers
5 Escort Squadrons (x2 Firestorm, x1 Cobra, x2 Sword)

Blood Raven Losses In System
x2 Gladius Frigates (4th Company)
x2 Thunderhawk Gunships Great Father's Fist
x2 Thunderhawk Gunships Omnis Arcanum

Swarmworld Kappa
1 Emperor-class Battleship (Flagship of Admiral Graves)
2 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
4 Lunar-class Cruisers
15 Escort Squadrons (x11 Firestorm, x2 Sword, x2 Cobra)
10 Imperial Transports, Ferrying Order of Lost Rosetta

Swarmworld Theta
1st, 4th, 5th Company Fleets (Blood Ravens)

Swarmworld Nu
1 Apocalypse-class Battleship
3 Mars-class Battlecruisers
8 Lunar-class Cruisers
5 Escort Squadrons (x3 Firestorm, x2 Cobra)
20 Imperial Transports, Ferrying Order of Lost Rosetta

Swarmworld Sigma
2 Retribution-class Battleships
1 Mars-class Battlecruisers
8 Lunar-class Cruisers
9 Escort Squadrons (x5 Firestorm, x2 Sword, x2 Cobra)
20 Imperial Transports, Ferrying Order of Lost Rosetta

Daemonworld/Capital
1 Daemonship (Batteship-tonnage/Undivided-leaning)
2 Beast of Tzeentch (Battlecruiser-tonnage)
2 Swarmships (Battlecruiser-tonnage)
12 Swarmships (Cruiser-tonnage)
4 Daemonships (Cruiser-tonnage/Undivided-leaning)
5 Beasts of Tzeentch (Cruiser-tonnage)
15 Daemonship Squadrons (Escort-tonnages/Undivided-leaning)

Click to expand...

Click to shrink...

Turn 22 (Part Six): An Unkindness

Spoiler: Vote Plan: Desert Speartips

[X] Focus On Military Targets on the Desert World
[X] The Speartips
-[X] Landing Zone - 5th Company, 2 Codiciers, 5 Lexicani, Techmarine Calus, Techmarine Daedal, 3 Predators, all Tarantulas and all but 4 Rapiers, 1 Whirlwind, 1 Hunter, 1 Vindicator Laser Destroyer
-[X] Tower 1 - 1st Company, Chapter Master + Honor Guard, 4 Codiciers, 7 Lexicani, Techmarine Hestior+1 unnamed, Land Raider Litany of Purgation, Land Raider Tarantulus Ultima, 1 Predator, 1 Whirlwind, 2 Rhinos, 4 Razorbacks (Standard Twin-Linked Heavy Bolter), 7 Assault Bikes, 2 Land Speeders (Standard), 1 Land Speeder (Tempest), 2 Rapiers
-[X] Tower 2 - 4th Company, Chief Librarian Justinius Probalis, 3 Codiciers, 7 Lexicani, 2 Techmarines, 2 Predators, 1 Predator (Twin-Linked Lascannons), 1 Whirlwind, 2 Rhinos, 2 Razorbacks (Standard Twin-Linked Heavy Bolter), 1 Razorbacks (Twin-Linked Assault Cannons), 1 Vindicator, 7 Assault Bikes, 1 Land Speeders (Standard), 1 Land Speeder (Tempest), 2 Rapiers
-[X] Assume even split of Apothecaries between Landing Zone, Tower 1, and Tower 2, with Chief Apothecary Nero Gracchus remaining at Landing Zone.
-[X] Assume even split of Chaplains between Landing Zone, Tower 1, and Tower 2, with Master of Sanctity Hannibal Palrun joining the Tower 2 detachment.
-[X] Thunderhawks available for air support wherever necessary
-[X] Techmarine undeployed - Martellus, Quarius Zergan, 2 unnamed

An Unkindness
+045.M42+ To +050.M42+
+Never Falter, Never Surrender+

"Please, please, no, I can't...no! No!"

Scouts were to be space marines, some day. It was space marines who held to the creed of knowing no fear. Scouts, one might suppose, could be accepted to be a lesser form in some measure. They were not fully matured. Still, it was a jarring thing to watch one scream and plead out of fear as the rest of his companions were devoured by genestealers. To the scout's credit, they continued to fire with their bolter as they scrabbled backward like some lost child, the psychic pulses emanating from the pulsating bio-form which crackled with psychic power scorching his neural pathways as it sedately floated forward. The entire sector was overrun, the Imperial defenders having retreated and abandoned the entire sector to the alien. Truth be told, it had been a necessary measure, to retreat to more defensible positions where fortifications were not obliterated by swirling sand storms. That did not take away from the fact that the Blood Ravens were not informed, and in fact minor subterfuge amongst the orders being broadcast had contributed to this utter failure of an operation.

All of this, Cyrus watched, before pressing the detonator stub.

The scout, and the rest of his dead squad, were incinerated instantly as the explosives went off. Around the Captain, the other scouts fought ferociously to defend themselves against the coming swarm. Abandoned heavy weaponry was utilized, heavy bolters and lascannons spearing larger creatures instantly while sniper rounds cracked against genestealers attempting to flank. Despite this, Cyrus watched as the newest crater began to be filled in by more and more tyranids pushing forth. Occasionally one would see an original slaughra fighting alongside them, but more often than not the widespread genestealer cult which had pushed itself into becoming the xenos' state religion showed itself more and more as the dominant populace.

"Captain?"

Cyrus looked at Marius dispassionately, the helmeted apothecary still managing to convey a sense of vague disapproval.

"Go, apothecary. Take what can be taken."

The apothecary turned immediately, and the one who had once been an assault terminator of the 1st Company displayed his skills once more. Once, he had battered aside the alien from within a set of terminator armor, shield and hammer in hand. His reduced armor was, as it turned out, a detriment. Twin chainswords gleamed in his hands as he slaughtered a path forward to the lost scouts. In a better situation they would have been saved, but their position had been too far gone, too lost, with no chance for being saved. No other squads had been close enough, and so the cold calculus had been performed without ending in their favor. For their deaths, half a hundred more scouts lived. For their sacrifice, the whole survived. As it ever was, and perhaps in that measure they had died as space marines. It would be what was reflected in the records. Better that, than reduced to gibbering ruin by a zoanthrope.

When Marius returned, ten blackened husks in tow, there was at least some good news. Some of the gene-seed had been retrieved.

Not a total loss, then.

The position held for a half hour more until the last of the explosives and mines were planted, and then the Blood Ravens melted away, in failure and shame. They slew a thousand tyranids in the ensuing series of explosions, but it was barely notable as the Imperial Guard reorganized across the rest of the planet.

Spoiler: Slaughra Swarm (Z04X)

Libarius Scrying And Planning: 28. No Positive Results. Minor Warp Perils! [Sanctioned Imperial Psyker Containment Efforts: 74! Warp Perils Negated!]
Cervantes Obstruction Attempts: 74. Notable Success. Effects: 10th Company Effort Success Well Reduced In Potency!
10th Company Efforts: 12! Significant Failure. Effects: Notable Failures Against Targets!
WARNING: Slaughra Genestealer Cult Has Activated Tyranid Bioforms Out Of Desperation!
Conquest Progress:
Slaughra Capital World - 30% Imperial, 70% Slaughra
Slaughra Ice World - 37% Imperial, 62% Slaughra
Slaughra Desert World - 30% Imperial, 70% Slaughra
Slaughra 'Civilized' World Primaris - 48% Imperial, 52% Slaughra
Slaughra 'Civilized' World Secundus - 36% Imperial, 64% Slaughra
Z04X Space Control: Contested - Imperial Navy Supreme Across System
Blood Raven Losses: 10 Scouts [1st Stage]
Gene-Seed Recovered: +12, Held By Apothecary Marius

Decisions For 10th Company (Choose One):
[] Focus On Civilian Centers - The Imperial Guard, Imperial Navy, Trontiux Knights, and a Titan Legion are all focused largely on breaking the military capabilities of the Swarm. But this is not a simple military crusade, it is a total reclamation of worlds that should be for humanity's purposes, not the alien. Once, ages ago, they were, and now, they will be again. Thus, genocide. The vast majority of the Swarm, like many species, are either not military or being conscripted. As time goes on, this will continue. The more conscripts there are, the harder the fight will be. It would be better to kill them before they are properly armed, and to hopefully also cause significant morale damage.
[] Focus On Military Targets - The Imperial Guard, Imperial Navy, Trontiux Knights, and a Titan Legion are all focused largely on breaking the military capabilities of the Swarm. The Blood Ravens can aid in this, for there are few amongst any of those mighty forces who can manage the same stealth and capabilities of a properly trained and equipped scout. The more military positions, bases, supply dumps, barrier towers, shield towers, and more that are taken down, the faster the military will be destroyed, and thus, the faster the military can properly begin exterminating the civilian populace of the Slaughra.
[] Something Else - (Write-In)

===================================================================

Holding The Landing: 78

"Come on, come and taste the light that falls upon your benighted world, mutant scum!" Daedal yelled over the roaring of the tarantulas and rapiers firing at once.

"Benighted...benighted? Really? That's the best you can come up with?" Calus queried over their private comm channel, checking over the laser array of one of the rapiers that he was stationed near.

"It's a fair use of the word, brother, Omnissiah knows. The whole planet hasn't seen the sun in who knows how long," Daedal grunted, swiveling the rapier to target another approaching swarm of creatures.

Some, they knew, were daemonic - or at least warp-related. Flesh made of shale and smoke still seemed vulnerable once entering the general psychic field of the librarians, however. Perhaps if the tower's aura and presence was still present, they would have been nigh invincible upon a world so deeply in the throes of the Changer of Ways. As it was, however, Calus knew Daedal was at least somewhat correct. The light burned them.

"I know what the word means, and why you used it. I merely posited that something better could be used."

"Oh please," Daedal droned, hopping off of his rapier to fire the plasma cannon he'd carried with him at a larger creature that was more tentacle than mouth, "Enlighten me, oh linguistic master, oh Magos Dialogus."

"Misbegotten, maligned, malefic, damned, blasphemed," the techmarine responded tartly, watching with narrowed eyes at another section of the defenses. "Just for options. Benighted simply sounds odd."

"I'll use what words I want!"

=========================================

Traveling To Target [Tower 1]: 56
A World's Defenders: 4

Your arrival does not go unnoticed by the tower's defenders. In fact, they turned their own forces against you, those who fled seemingly buoyed by the presence of their fellows. Sorcerous lightning arced down from the clouds, dragged forth by the tower and those who lived under its shadow, only to be deflected by your librarians. Creatures were summoned from the earth and air, only to be torn apart by psychic blasts of flame from the Codiciers and Lexicani. But far more common is somewhat more traditional exchanges of fire. Lances of blazing light erupt from the land raiders, the twin vehicles smashing their way into the enemy as the vanguard force. A tremendous amount of firepower is sent in their direction, yet it is what they were built for, to absorb the damage while delivering to the front lines a squad of space marines who in turn would fall upon the enemy. Your arrival is utterly uncontested, in the end, comparatively to what it could have been.

Assaulting Tower 1: 87
Tower 1 Defenders: 12+30(Landing Tower Survivors)=42

Even though you literally just arrived on the planet, their defenses are already present. Even as you arrive within range for proper attacks upon the Tower itself, barricades of silvery white bone erupt from the ground. Spikes of calcified materials and burning sludge-like marrow are launched forth as point defenses, while howling winged slaughra creatures come howling out of darkness to fall upon your forces as you advance. Even with all of this, and the majority of the survivors of the tower you destroyed, they do not stand against you. More often than not, it is the librarians who you rely upon to ensure you are capable of pushing forward at all. It is they who reverse the earth from slurry and sludge back into things that can actually support the weight of your vehicles. Banks of razor winds of bone and silver fragments come speeding down from the clouds, enveloping your bikers as they flank, yet are torn away by the might of the Librarius before they can do more than cause minor injuries and easily reparable damage to the bikes themselves.

Still, all that and more stand against you, for the enemy knows now that you can hurt them, and they will not surrender the tower without a fight.

"Begin bombardment," you call out before slamming your hammer into a heavily armored slaughra mutant, its claws scraping deep gouges into your armor as it dies.

"Affirmative, Chapter Master," the whirlwind's commander returns. Behind his tank, the razorbacks push into a defensive formation, while the land raiders set them up as well.

It is a simple matter of knowing what could and could not damage the towers.

Tower Bombardment: 52
Tower Defenses: 59
On The Ground (Attackers): 86
On The Ground (Defenders): 15

Outright shields of warp energies form over the tower's base where the first strikes hit. Almost all damage is blocked or deflected, but only almost. A single whirlwind missile gets through, creating a heavy crater in the tower surface. For a moment, at least, before the surface begins to outright heal itself. The damage is not enough. But it will be, you know, if not yet at the moment. Unfortunately, the moment the tower took damage, a greater fervor seemed to overtake its defenders, who throw themselves at you with even greater fury. Some begin to outright mutate further, mid-fight, mid-blow on one stunning occasion. With the towers appearing to possess the greater sorcerous leanings of Tzeentch, his slaves have given themselves fully over to his warping ways in manners both horrific and powerful.

=========================================

Traveling To Target [Tower 2]: 58
A World's Defenders: 82

Justinius growled as his staff crackled with power, his personal field of psychic energies rippling visibly in the air. All around him, the column fought and struggled against the living landscape which had risen up against them. From the very ground itself came waves of screaming creatures, birthed so abruptly by sorcery that at least half of their ferocity came from confusion and fear at suddenly having life forced upon them. That did not mean they were granted anything but the mercy of death. Around him, the rest of the 4th Company fought with the same aggressive nature that their Captain possessed, though none went so far as Hadrian himself. The man was evidently opposed to anything approaching his company's vehicles, and showed it in his fury, repeatedly diving off of the rhino he stood atop to fire his weapons at close range into the great mass of creatures which assaulted them. Still, they were stalled, and unacceptably so. The earth had been turned against them, lightning struck repeatedly from the skies, and the actual mutants of the slaughra who had retreated from the tower had turned about without any sign of them receiving orders. It was just as likely that they were told by the powers they served that the Blood Ravens had been stymied.

"Enough!" Justinius boomed, and he clapped both hands to hold his staff in front of him, raised, before he slammed it down into the cursed soil.

A Storm For A Storm: 75

A cloud of black and red exploded out from the Chief Librarian's form, an ethereal construct which ballooned in size further and further until its edges began to burn at the edges of the narrow column's head. Where it poured out, lightning screamed out against piles of earthen monstrosities, vaporizing them instantly. Lightning blasts from the sky and from the sides of the air around the column fizzled on contact, all the while a nimbus of power bloomed around Justinius, before he was joined by the rest of his librarian brethren. With that, the cloud grew further, until the entire column was protected, small gleams of power emanating from the linked psykers as they were placed across the entire formation. Teeth grinding, Justinius tore his staff upwards, the soil it had impaled bleeding a black ooze. He glared at it, eyes become orbs of contained cerulean flame, and clambered atop one of the leading predators.

Hadrian appeared, bleeding from a half dozen wounds, but grinning fiercely at the sight of the Chief Librarian's efforts. He leapt atop the predator as well, and raised his pistol high, firing it once in the sky.

"Forward, my brothers! ONTO THE TOWER!"

The 4th Captain commanded, and the 4th Company obeyed.

Tower 2 Assault: 67
Tower 2 Defenders: 2

Hadrian was not the most patient of marines. It showed, clearly, in his tactics and behavior. That did not mean he was unaware of the value of patience, of course, to suggest otherwise would be foolish. Be in this case, his aggression and frustration at being stymied as they had was given form through the assault which fell upon the tower. For all that they did not have the Land Raiders on their sides, the sheer volume of fire and breakneck pace that Hadrian demanded practically made up for it. Lacking the numbers and sheer power of those who had followed the Chapter Master, Hadrian and Justinius both made up for it in angry tenacity. They tore across the bonewalls with blasts of krak missiles and lascannons, plasma weaponry scorching blackened sand into outright glass and leaving gleaming holes in those that stood still. They were relentless, and though some of the 4th Company were felled, it was but temporary, and they were on their feet once again moments later either out of fury or from the attentions of the apothecary.

Tower Bombardment: 94
Tower Defenders: 64
On The Ground (Attackers): 9
On The Ground (Defenders): 34

The existence of sorcerous defenses, shields of warp energies, and more were clearly present to Justinius' eyes. As such, the Librarians turned their efforts to stripping the tower of its own natural-borne abilities to repair and shield itself while the rest of the Blood Ravens did their best to shatter it. Yet, as Hadrian discovered to his fury, and the death of one of his marines, without their attentions on defense the enemy became resurgent. Not enough to block out grievous damage from being inflicted on the tower, great chunks of it being torn out by blasts of everything from bolter shells to lascannon blasts and krak missle shots. But enough to heavily press the 4th Company marines who fought to defend those who were focused upon the tower. Hadrian took a blow to the face from some screeching thing made of glass feathers, each mutable and showing a kaleidoscope of horrible images, which tore out his left cheek, and much of the flesh around it. The ghoulish wound did not bring him low, but Hadrian was nonetheless missing outright half of his face to reveal the skull beneath as the fight continued on while the tower shuddered.

================================================

Tower Bombardment: 81
Tower Defenses: 25
On The Ground (Attackers): 23
On The Ground (Defenders): 36

Sustained bombardment was one of the most glorious things in life. For despite the shields, the deflections, the outright portions of the tower which warped themselves to safety, thickened, or wriggled out of an incoming missile or lascannon blast, the tower shuddered in very real pain. Large chunks lay strewn across the ground, warplight sheen no longer glimmering from them after the damage the tower had taken. More and more of the tower was being destroyed, and while it was rebuilding itself at an appreciable rate, it was not even close to what was being unleashed upon it. If only the fight on the ground could be said to be nearly as successful, as two assault bike riders were torn from their mounts, attacks falling apart, defensive lines being bent and twisted by the slaughra mutants which appeared endless in number with daemon support. Wounds were high, more and more marines forced to fall back, to be propped up by their fellows so they could continue fighting, to be taken out entirely as they fell into sustaining comas to prevent their wounds from killing them.

But the tower still stood.

"Chapter Master!" Apollo cries out from nearby. "Look! From the third tower!"

In the distance, clouds of dust and dirt rise into the air, a force coming closer and closer...until it disappears entirely.

"What?"

Misdirection and sorcery. Of course.

"Hadrian, Tarkus, prepare yourselves! The enemy has launched an assault from the third tower, we know not when they will strike!"

===============================

Justinius' attention was upon the cracking tower, spiderwebs of damage crackling up its great frame, but he heard nonetheless.

"Nero," he managed to growl through grit teeth.

"I heard," the epistolary growled from nearby, hands clenched together as he stared unblinking at the tower. "I will try."

(Piercing The World-Veil: 83/100)

Sparks of psychic light bloomed around his bionic eyes, which in turn crackled with their own internal circuitry flickering.

The veil twisted and then split apart before his will. A great bar of black iron, splitting seamlessly in the middle, flying as rods from the heavens and earth at screaming ravens, red stones glimmering in their chests. One that feasted upon a fallen three-legged serpent, one that even now battered at another writhing silvered creature. A third raven, whose red heart blazed with a storm all its own, was left on its own for now, for simple fact of lacking enough strength to cast another rod against it.

"I see," Nero whispered before a hand rose to activate his comm. "I see them! They are splitting their strength! One towards you, Chapter Master, and another towards the 5th Company!"

=======================================

Landing Defense: 79+Advance Warning(15)=94

Tarkus stared out at the masses currently attacking their position, firing his bolter without even changing expression as the epistolary concentrated next to him.

"Damion, do you have them yet?"

The veteran's voice was calm, still, even as he traversed the field with his weapon's angry bite.

Damion was silent, for a moment, before his eyes opened. Unlike the searing sapphire lightning of Justinius, it was black flames that dripped from his eye sockets, licking against his chest before hitting the ground with animalistic hisses. The Umbral Barding gleamed with his power as he exercised it, and a thin grin appeared on the librarian's lips.

"I do. Here, they come from here. They do not know that we have discovered them just yet," he spoke lowly, finger tracing over the tactical dataslate that Tarkus held out to him.

When the daemon-engine led column came, approaching from the 'rear' against the greater push of the enemy, it was speared instantly by every rapier in the detachment, vaporized before the killing could even truly begin. The rest were cut down as well, shocked as their stealth faded away to find a foe prepared and eagerly awaiting them. In a desperately short time the matter was dealt with before Tarkus could turn to defending the landing zone properly once more, tarantula turrets dragged back to their original positions.

===========================

Defending While Attacking: 87+15=102
Bombardment Continuation: 28
Tower Defenses: 17

Were Hannibal a psyker, you would not be surprised if he would have been heralded for his ability to scream infernos into being. As it is, he relies on volume and physical deed to emulate the same effect as he falls upon the enemy column which had attempted to assault your left flank from behind. It was certainly daring, his action, whereby he made use of the black sludge-like sand that was the soil about the base of the tower, and his own blackened armor to camouflage himself. It is hard to believe, sometimes, considering his abnormal size, but the man was indeed a scout once. He and the rest of his chaplains act as a terrifying and hidden force of hatred that unfurls itself just as the slaughra mutants and their own sorcerer are attacked from the front. Their strange spells of invisibility and clouding from sight and sensor alike failing them, they are forced into an open conflict they had no chance of winning.

Which gave the land raiders and the others more time to fire, and fire they did, the whirlwind having not stopped firing the entire time.

==================================

Tower 2 Assault Continuation: 96
Tower 2 Defenses: 43

A crack. A shuddering of the core. A blast of psychic lightning, opening and widening a hole for an entire salvo of whirlwind missiles, followed by a tight grouping of krak missiles. And then Justinius reached up, his hands clenching and tearing at the heavens themselves...and the tower split at the base. A howl of pain and fear erupted from the remaining xenos and their mutants. Daemons flickered out of being entirely, back to the immaterium from whence they came. A scream of victory and hate rose up from the Blood Ravens, Hadrian loudest of all as the Librarians continued their own efforts. As the tower began to collapse, vast chunks beginning to split off as the great silver needle ceased to be able to maintain its own structure with the laws of reality once more imposed upon it, the 4th Company pulled back, further and further, heading out and away. The tower's essence was...broken, for lack of a better word, enough that a good third of it dissipated entirely, phasing out of existence, while other shards hurtled to earth at speeds to create great craters upon the impact sites, but by then, the Blood Ravens were gone from there.

===========================

Tower 1 Assault Continuation: 99
Tower 2 Force Arrival: 54
Tower Defenses: 80

"Damned...gah, we're bogged down again! The land itself rises against us once more!" Hadrian's call is not panicked, but rather more furious that he is once more being waylaid by the corrupted powers which choke the planet.

"It is fine, brother," you comm back, watching as the tower begins to shimmer and crackle. "No need. We will come to you."

Finally, it began to break, and topple. Speed was of the essence, though luckily as before the most dangerous portions of the tower faded away entirely. Entire sections of crystalline shapes which floated in orbit about it collapsed or disappeared back into the warp, but yet more of the tower would be coming down, and coming down hard. The geographical damage of the towers breaking and falling onto the earth would be severe, but better that they be destroyed now, these orbital spokes of a planetary wheel, than survive and taint the planet any longer. Upon the total collapse of the two towers, the clouds which harried you either by carrying flying creatures or by being monsters of smoke themselves - along with the stormbanks overhead - disappear entirely. Not easily, no, but disappear they do, peeled back more and more. The world itself shudders not just with the vast collapses you have begun, but with the rending of its sorcerous connectors. The greater lattice itself is, Justinius tells you, weakened beyond the sum of a single lost tower with every one lost - for it is a system built on great asymmetrical symmetry, all parts different yet the same while working together.

By breaking three, you have harmed the system far more than the numbers would suggest...but that does not mean you have not taken casualties.

Operation Results
-7 4th Company Marines Heavily Injured, Unavailable For Combat Operations
-3 Towers Shattered. Storm Lattice Has Sustained Moderate Damage. Overall Lattice Strength Reduced.

Set Plans For For Stage Five Of Engagement:

[] To Kill What Comes: You have taken one of their holy sites. You have forced them to retreat. Animalistic pride alone would demand recompense and revenge. Prepare for this. Already you have forces here, and outside of the clearly dangerous cloud cover which could unleash itself at any time if you were directly under it. The enemy will come for you, and they will batter and break upon your weapons and fury. Once they are exhausted, you will likely be able to strike out against the towers with greater ease...supposedly at least. Nothing is certain on a world ruled by Tzeentch - even if it has not yet become a true Daemonworld. [Write-In Forces Deployed]
[] Ranging Out: There is one tower close by to you, which has - you can hope - exhausted its strength trying to aid its fellows. But yet more towers remain as well. They are as bases and settlements in one, but melta bombs, Land Raiders, and krak explosives will take them down from the base all the same once the aliens, mutants, and daemon which cluster at them are destroyed. They will require heavy Librarian support, however, for they shall be venturing out beneath the practically living storm of Tzeentch which rules here. You will also have to dedicate forces to keep the landing zone clear, else the enemy might come and reclaim it. The greater worry, of course, is that isolated forces might be ambushed by other tower compliments, by daemons, or other mutant bands which wander aimlessly across the surface of the world. (NOT REQUIRED TO ASSAULT ALL AT ONCE)
-[] Landing Zone: [Write-In Forces Kept Back For Defense]
-[] Tower 3: This tower contributed a great many forces to try and halt you from breaking the towers, as well as to try and take back the landing zone. Perhaps now they are weakened indeed?
-[] Tower 4: Further out, and closer to the ruin of the 2nd Tower, this area is even worse in terms of terrain. Vehicles would be near useless here, of the heavier variety at least. Landspeeders might be able to still make it, but the rhinos and land raiders would not. Nor would the predators or razorbacks. It would have to be a largely infantry-based assault...or perhaps entirely based on thunderhawks making runs into a literally hostile airspace.
-[] Tower 5: Closer to the ruins of the 1st Tower - not the Landing Tower - but further out still. It is on a seemingly flat plain that can suddenly become a roiling sea of dunes where each grain of sand is bladed, but such things could be stopped - Justinius believes - with the proper application of the librarians. Enough at least to allow your forces to advance to the tower itself, and make battle upon it.

Spoiler: Confirmed Naval Presences In System

Imperial Navy Losses In System
1 Mars-class Battlecruiser
1 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
5 Lunar-class Cruisers
5 Escort Squadrons (x2 Firestorm, x1 Cobra, x2 Sword)

Blood Raven Losses In System
x2 Gladius Frigates (4th Company)
x2 Thunderhawk Gunships Great Father's Fist
x2 Thunderhawk Gunships Omnis Arcanum

Swarmworld Kappa
1 Emperor-class Battleship (Flagship of Admiral Graves)
2 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
4 Lunar-class Cruisers
15 Escort Squadrons (x11 Firestorm, x2 Sword, x2 Cobra)
10 Imperial Transports, Ferrying Order of Lost Rosetta

Swarmworld Theta
1st, 4th, 5th Company Fleets (Blood Ravens)

Swarmworld Nu
1 Apocalypse-class Battleship
3 Mars-class Battlecruisers
8 Lunar-class Cruisers
5 Escort Squadrons (x3 Firestorm, x2 Cobra)
20 Imperial Transports, Ferrying Order of Lost Rosetta

Swarmworld Sigma
2 Retribution-class Battleships
1 Mars-class Battlecruisers
8 Lunar-class Cruisers
9 Escort Squadrons (x5 Firestorm, x2 Sword, x2 Cobra)
20 Imperial Transports, Ferrying Order of Lost Rosetta

Daemonworld/Capital
1 Daemonship (Batteship-tonnage/Undivided-leaning)
2 Beast of Tzeentch (Battlecruiser-tonnage)
2 Swarmships (Battlecruiser-tonnage)
12 Swarmships (Cruiser-tonnage)
4 Daemonships (Cruiser-tonnage/Undivided-leaning)
5 Beasts of Tzeentch (Cruiser-tonnage)
15 Daemonship Squadrons (Escort-tonnages/Undivided-leaning)

Turn 22 (Part Seven): An Unkindness

Spoiler: Voted Plan

[X] Focus On Military Targets on 'Civilized' World Secundus
[X] Ranging Out
-[X] Landing Zone - 4th Company, 3 Codiciers, 7 Lexicani, Techmarine Calus, Techmarine Daedal, 3 Predators, 1 Predator (Twin-Linked Lascannons), all Tarantulas and all but 4 Rapiers, 1 Whirlwind, 1 Hunter, 1 Vindicator, 1 Vindicator Laser Destroyer
-[X] Tower 3 - 1st Company, 5th Company, Chapter Master + Honor Guard, Chief Librarian Justinius Probalis, 6 Codiciers, 12 Lexicani, Techmarine Hestior+3 unnamed, Land Raider Litany of Purgation, Land Raider Tarantulus Ultima, 3 Predators, 2 Whirlwinds, 4 Rhinos, 6 Razorbacks (Standard Twin-Linked Heavy Bolter), 1 Razorbacks (Twin-Linked Assault Cannons), 14 Assault Bikes, 3 Land Speeders (Standard), 2 Land Speeder (Tempest), 4 Rapiers
-[X] Assume even split of Apothecaries between Landing Zone and Tower 3 with Chief Apothecary Nero Gracchus remaining at Landing Zone.
-[X] Assume even split of Chaplains between Landing Zone, and Tower 3, with Master of Sanctity Hannibal Palrun joining the Tower 3 detachment.
-[X] Thunderhawks available for air support wherever necessary
-[X] Techmarines undeployed - Martellus, Quarius Zergan, 2 unnamed

An Unkindness
+045.M42+ To +050.M42+
+Never Falter, Never Surrender+

The grime of the desert had been replaced with soot and ash from collapsing Slaughra buildings. A welcome change of locale, Cyrus felt, as another defense tower which had been stymying the Guard’s advance collapsed from the charges placed at its base. The checkpoint had been hardened stupendously, remarkably resilient chitin walls having been spat up by Slaughra bio-mechanical creations in staggered formation weeks before. Now though, with the tower and its cannons brought low, a ragged cheer went up from the Guard and they charged forward, led by their scar riddled Commissar, to rush up and over the walls and into the compound.

Once, in the past, it had been a four-way intersection in the city whose name was both unpronounceable by human tongue and would go unremembered after the conquest. Now it was another charnel pit where the struggling Slaughra defenders and their genestealer masters would be cut down to the last. Cyrus paused in his work, barrel of the sniper rifle faintly smoking, as the vox crackled near him. The other scouts around him continued on their grisly work without pause, as he had taught them, the long-broken skyscraper providing the best possible vantage point for miles around the embattled cityscape.

“Report,” he murmured into the communicator.

“Genestealers are making a push into the western blocks, as the scrying rituals foretold, Captain. There are…more than we thought there would be, however.”

“Do you need me to approve your every move, initiate?” Cyrus growled back, though whether he was more irritated than usual was impossible to tell.

“Ah, no, Captain, I merely wished to inform you that we would be detonating soon, in case you desired to redeploy any of our other forces.”

Cyrus grunted, and was silent for a few seconds more.

“Very well. Detonate, and turn them to smoldering bone.”

“Yes, Captain.”

A dull series of whumps echoed out from the western blocks before towers of flame and plasma went scorching into the skies. Pleasantly, they did not even need to exhaust their own supplies of explosives that the ships could provide – rather, instead of demanding the forges continually produce what they needed, scavenging more than sufficed. There were dozens of overrun Guard positions that the Blood Ravens had come across, broken and mauled by the slaves of the Hive Mind. More than enough promethium besides, plus what fuel sources that the Swarm itself had preciously possessed. Cyrus nodded, and then flipped the channel on the vox with the flick of a finger.

“Squads two and three, shift position three sectors east, resume headhunting. Squads five and six, push north, scatter the enemy before the Guard gets there.”

What luck that Cervantes was busy on the desert world, where the greatest concentration of outright tyranid bio-forms could be found.

Spoiler: Slaughra Swarm (Z04X)

Libarius Scrying And Planning: 73. Notable Positive Results! 10th Company Operations Improved In Efficiency!
Cervantes Obstruction Attempts: 34. Failure!
10th Company Efforts: 67! Notable Success. Effects: Notable Victories Against The Enemy.
WARNING: Slaughra Genestealer Cult Has Activated Tyranid Bioforms Out Of Desperation!
Conquest Progress:
Slaughra Capital World - 35% Imperial, 65% Slaughra
Slaughra Ice World - 50% Imperial, 50% Slaughra
Slaughra Desert World - 25% Imperial, 75% Slaughra
Slaughra 'Civilized' World Primaris - 51% Imperial, 49% Slaughra
Slaughra 'Civilized' World Secundus - 50% Imperial, 50% Slaughra
Z04X Space Control: Imperial Navy Supreme Across System/Imperial Navy Has Split Strength To Send More To Aid Secondary Crusade Targets
Blood Raven Losses: 10 Scouts [1st Stage]
Gene-Seed Recovered: +12, Held By Apothecary Marius

Decisions For 10th Company (Choose One):
[] Focus On Civilian Centers - The Imperial Guard, Imperial Navy, Trontiux Knights, and a Titan Legion are all focused largely on breaking the military capabilities of the Swarm. But this is not a simple military crusade, it is a total reclamation of worlds that should be for humanity's purposes, not the alien. Once, ages ago, they were, and now, they will be again. Thus, genocide. The vast majority of the Swarm, like many species, are either not military or being conscripted. As time goes on, this will continue. The more conscripts there are, the harder the fight will be. It would be better to kill them before they are properly armed, and to hopefully also cause significant morale damage.
[] Focus On Military Targets - The Imperial Guard, Imperial Navy, Trontiux Knights, and a Titan Legion are all focused largely on breaking the military capabilities of the Swarm. The Blood Ravens can aid in this, for there are few amongst any of those mighty forces who can manage the same stealth and capabilities of a properly trained and equipped scout. The more military positions, bases, supply dumps, barrier towers, shield towers, and more that are taken down, the faster the military will be destroyed, and thus, the faster the military can properly begin exterminating the civilian populace of the Slaughra.
[] Something Else - (Write-In)

============================================

Holding The Landing: 81

“Omnissiah’s breath!” Daedal cried out as he dodged another blast of warp-infused energies that illuminated the darkened world.

The soil it passed over writhed with life, new creations blasting out of the earth in a mockery of true births. They screamed and unfurled weapons of crystalized glass and glinting chitin-flesh from their multitudes of limbs, but most if not all were cut down by a hail of bolter fire and flamer bursts. There would be more, it seemed there would always be more, but the fighting grew only more intense elsewhere. The predators swerved and bucked on the uncooperative earth, firing relentlessly at the mutant armies which approached the 4th Company’s entrenched position. Loping things which squealed and roared from the bulk of the cannons that had been grown out of their spinal cords traded fire with the tanks. Dozens of leaping humanoids with too many legs and too many eyes which spat burst of light as if from a grouping of lasguns dragged themselves forth.

A bank of rapiers swiveled on their mounts and fired again and again.

“Fight on, my brothers!” Hadrian boomed from atop the vindicator destroyer. “For the Unknown Primarch and the Imperium!”

They were not overwhelmed. Not quite. And that would have to be enough.

===================================

Pushing To Tower 3: 99

The world hated the interlopers, Justinius knew, and it displayed it well enough. The storms above the column intensified with lighting blasts powerful enough to fell space marines fell near constantly, while roving hordes of creatures came howling out of the darkness and acidic rain to attack them on all sides. At points the air grew so thick with noxious sapphire clouds of toxins that anyone not wearing a helm or filtration system was forced to don them, lest their lungs be scorched from within. Shards of black crystal fell sideways into the column at one point, exploding on contact as they drove forth. None of it was allowed to stymie them. The great voluminous cloud of psychic energies which bloomed from the Librarians of the Blood Ravens expanded to cover the whole of the column, and where it extended to, the sorcery of the enemy failed. Lightning faltered and was diverted to strike harmlessly into the ground. The hordes were cut down by the myriad weapons of the space marines before they could even properly marshal themselves. Toxin clouds were forcibly blown away or dispersed entirely.

At the head, a grim-faced Chapter Master strode, daemonhammer crackling with angry power. A bellowed and endless litany of hatred and purification thundered from Hannibal's throat, the Master of Sanctity an umbral giant who lurked as a specter behind Angelos' more muted fury. On the left, Apollo Diomedes' face could not be seen from within his white helm, his own weapon covered in gravel-blood as well as more sanguine-esque fluids. The two land raiders rumbled along behind them, barrels glowing with heat. All of them beheld the tower as it was illuminated by a truly giant blast of lightning from the worldstorm, and the defenders who had assembled around it. Vehicles of stone and flesh melded with the mutating powers of the warp, while filling the gaps between them were multitudes of horrors. Amongst them were the Slaughra, who marshaled hordes of slaves about and around them - of flesh and daemonic varieties. The moment the first elements of the Blood Ravens arrived, the battle began. There was no point in a warning, or spoken words. Only the great savagery of the enemy matching battle brothers who had long had any hesitation bled from them by time and trial.

Initial Exchange
49 vs. 28

The assault marines flew in first, risking the skies under the aegis of the Librarius, and smashed down amongst the enemy with bone-rattling impacts. Chainswords flashed and slashed, while melta bombs were tossed in clusters into the sides of enemy vehicles. But there were far too many for the Slaughra and their servants and aids to crumble from such a strike. Inhuman minds did not shy away from the carnage, long-tainted souls in fact buoyed by the slaughter after so long without new stimulation to test their horrible bodies against.

Slaughra and Slaughter
97 vs. 92

The sheer heights of what was unleashed next would boil the eyes of a mere mortal to observe. Bright lances of light from lascannons, noises that would curdle eyes from their sockets and force craniums to leak came from ululating throats that swelled and mutated as they spoke the words. Black and blue fires were thrown from screaming horrors, by hand and mouth alike, to splash across great bulwark shields of psychic energy. A librarian slammed their force-staff down to create a moving and controlled seismic shockwave that rippled along the ground at his direction, sending mutants flying hard enough to shatter their chitin outsides and pulp their innards. A flamer-wielding tactical marine bullrushed his way through a group of Slaughra, leaving scorched ruin in his wake. At the same time, it was not a truly devastating blow, for the enemy was nearly as dangerous on their own. A stomping slaughra battered a trio of assault marines with nothing more than a single arm with nine great spines sticking out of it as thick as clubs. Another slaughra roared, nine dozen runes carved across its horribly mutated hide glimmering with power. Justinius himself was forced to intervene before it could extinguish a group of huddled lexicanum who were keeping the greater effects of the worldstorm itself from rending the column apart. Their combating powers manifested minor daemons and scoured them from existence in the next. Some younger marines saw their pasts before recruitment, mothers and fathers forgotten by indoctrination, while others saw their future - or a future, of black armor and a raven that wept tears of blood atop shattered columns of stone.

Push
80 vs. 24

Then Gabriel Angelos appeared from within the rain and thunder, Godsplitter swinging. He cast aside sorcerer and slave alike, cracking the flank of a tank whose rotating bio-cannons could not swivel fast enough in their sockets to fire upon him. Apollo Diomedes, one of the greatest heroes the Blood Ravens had ever known, came as well, at his Chapter Master's side. Two hammers that left craters and smoking destruction behind them, all the while the crackling crozius of Hannibal smote where the Master of Sanctity willed. The enemy lines shattered a half-dozen times over, and while it reformed time and again with frustrating efficiency, it was pushed back further with each retreat and reformation. Enough so that the land raiders could grind corpses and blast silver crystal with their cannons. Behind them came the whirlwinds, and with them came the razorbacks in a protective circle. A mailed fist. A plated fist. The slaughra recoiled and fought with even greater ferocity, for they knew what was to come. The world itself thundered with its fury, and cast out daemons of light and rain from its clouds in great swarms that fell beyond terminal velocity to reach the Blood Ravens.

Tower Breaking: 21
Guarding The Breakers: 7

The Blood Ravens knew it was coming, but the strength levied against them was more than some could handle. A lexcicanum fell to the ground, his mind and soul burnt out by the stress of shielding the column...and failing. A razorback was briefly illuminated by eldritch light, and then it was gone, the serfs dead on the ground as they bled black sludge from every orifice. Of the razorback, there was no sign it had ever existed save for the impressions in the sodden dirt. The great clouds of daemon-swarms which had come from the storm above shredded armor and flesh with equal ease, cutting one assault marine's pack and spine in equal measure, sending him collapsing to the earth at an angle to nearly shatter his spine and skull. The apothecaries advanced out, as best as they could, but they could not save everyone or bring all back to fighting measure. A dozen more marines were forced into comas to preserve themselves, the wounds nearly enough to slay them, one perhaps even enough to demand entombment if the facilities had been present to do so. The first bevy of fire put against the tower faltered from the assault, targeting sectors flaring as the auspex became filled with howling screams.

Tower Breaking: 63
Guarding The Breakers: 18

A great trench was burnt into the side of the tower, the Litany of Purgation relentless even as battle brothers fought and were brought low around its great bulk. Its sister land raider fired as well, though its machine spirit responded sluggishly in comparison. The missiles of the whirlwinds were sent off course entirely, some being wrested from the air by the screaming cloud-daemons which dropped them amongst the Blood Ravens themselves. One marine was unfortunate enough to be struck by one of the blasts directly, his life extinguished in that single instant. The roars of his brothers were almost loud enough to deafen, their bolters rending the daemons apart even after their cackling victory. The wounds built up further and further, another marine dying as his head was blasted apart by a slaughra cannon, his helmet torn from his armor beforehand by a grasping thing that gibbered happily as it was killed in turn.

Tower Breaking: 99
Guarding The Breakers: 93

Then there was light.

Not the broken gleam which glimmered out of the sigils carved in Slaughra flesh. Nor the eldritch light which came from black lightning, flames of deathly sapphire. It was none of these malformed things. The light was borne of purity and cleansing fury, Justinius Probalis striding to the forefront. His eyes blazed with power, armor creaking as it struggled to function as the being within was so painfully illuminated. The codiciers surrounded him, lending their own power, with the lexicanum as well. For a brief instant, the protections around the Blood Ravens faded entirely, but they needed it not. Not when the slack was taken up so intensely by the raging chaplains and their eldest. The living shield that was Apollo. By presence alone Angelos stood above them all, smashing and obliterating all who dared to threaten his battle brothers. A wild daemon of Tzeentch manifested and was obliterated so thoroughly by Godsplitter that it would not be able to return to the materium for a generation. A giant thing that seemed to be multiple slaughra mutated together was beaten out from below and then pulverized beneath the Chapter Master's boot. All of that lost energy pumped inwards, until every Librarian became a pulsating beacon of white hot light.

A vast raven, black of wing but with a core of crimson, appeared above them, and let loose an ear-piercing cry before cracks appeared all along its spectral form. From the cracks came cleansing light, from which daemons scattered and squealed to flee from. The non-euclidean geometries of the silver tower shuddered as order was imposed upon its body, that of its body that could not be maintained in a state where the laws of physics had once more claimed its throne as the dominant force shattered and collapsed. A great portion of the tower simply evaporated beneath that light. Then the raven exploded entirely. The daemons were banished. Machine spirits leapt into activation. A dozen and more cannons and turrets fired without relent at a single target, firepower enough to break an army fired upon but one structure. The tower screamed. The world itself screamed. A world plunged in shadow for centuries and more, swallowed beneath slowly erected towers of churned soulstuff that took years to build, shook beneath a lattice that had been struck again and again, hardpoints destroyed repeatedly on an untested hide.

Then there was light.

The worldstorm rippled and shook, sparse holes torn open in its frame not just over where the greater damage had been done, but across the whole of its body. The lattice, a sum of its parts and more, the damage the sum of what was lost and more, a mirror of strength and weakness thrown to the ground and stomped on by the Angels of Death. It held, in great portions, but the denizens of the planet screamed a thousand screams as the light of the sun drenched them for the first time in their existence. Blackened soil rippled at light not burned by sorcerous intent or bio-luminescence. The branches of darkness between each broken tower disappeared, leaving one great gaping hole where the foe had no reach anymore. The tower that the Blood Ravens stood before rapidly decayed, as if time itself had accelerated around its destruction, before the whole of it had utterly been removed from existence leaving not even the foundation of a thousand bones behind. Of those that had defended the tower...they lasted not a minute longer than the tower that had been their home had.

Vox signals carried this news to the ships waiting above, who brought their own messages from the heavens. The enemy had been so soundly beaten in the void by the God-Emperor's faithful against those of the xeno who had fallen sway to the Hive Mind that a great amount of their number had been dispatched to reinforce the mission here and now, led by a Rear Admiral and a freshly-scarred battleship.

The war was not over yet, but by faith and fury, the end had been pushed back just one step further.

Operation Results
-10 5th Company Marines Heavily Injured, Unavailable For Combat Operations
- 2 5th Company Marines Slain, +4 Gene-Seed Recovered.
-1 Lexicanum Slain, +2 Gene-Seed Recovered.
-1 Razorback (Standard Armament)
-1 Tower Shattered/Landing Zone Held. Storm Lattice Has Sustained Notable Damage! Holes In Storm Lattice Present Across Planet! Overall Lattice Strength Reduced. Limited Orbital Strikes Possible!
- New Imperial Navy ships in-system!

Set Plans For For Stage Six Of Engagement:

[] To Kill What Comes: This world is not done. They know you, now. They might attempt to rebuild their towers, but only if they could crush you within the area you have cleansed. The Landing Zone requires a great many defenses, if the large force ferried against it just now was not the only one that might be sense. The foe knows what you do now, they know very well by the graves of their fallen. They shall come, and they shall come in force. You must respond in kind, and hold the position while the rest of your forces range out against the towers and your ships fire down from above! [Write-In Forces Deployed] (Defense Force Recommendation: High)
[] Fury From The Skies: With the storm lattice broken as it is, the might of your planetary bombardment cannons can now be properly unleashed! The space marines are made to bring planets to heel, to break them in the name of the Emperor. And for all that this world is more...alive...than most...it is what you are for. You will bring this planet to heel! [Name Orbital Bombardment Targets, And Which Ships Fire On Which Target]
[] Ranging Out: There is one tower close by to you, which has - you can hope - exhausted its strength trying to aid its fellows. But yet more towers remain as well. They are as bases and settlements in one, but melta bombs, Land Raiders, and krak explosives will take them down from the base all the same once the aliens, mutants, and daemon which cluster at them are destroyed. They will require heavy Librarian support, however, for they shall be venturing out beneath the practically living storm of Tzeentch which rules here. You will also have to dedicate forces to keep the landing zone clear, else the enemy might come and reclaim it. The greater worry, of course, is that isolated forces might be ambushed by other tower compliments, by daemons, or other mutant bands which wander aimlessly across the surface of the world. (NOT REQUIRED TO ASSAULT ALL AT ONCE/MAY FOCUS ON ORBITAL FIRE RATHER THAN SENDING FORCES OUT IF DESIRED)
-[] Tower 4: Further out, and closer to the ruin of the 2nd Tower, this area is even worse in terms of terrain. Vehicles would be near useless here, of the heavier variety at least. Landspeeders might be able to still make it, but the rhinos and land raiders would not. Nor would the predators or razorbacks. It would have to be a largely infantry-based assault...or perhaps entirely based on thunderhawks making runs into a literally hostile airspace.
-[] Tower 5: Closer to the ruins of the 1st Tower - not the Landing Tower - but further out still. It is on a seemingly flat plain that can suddenly become a roiling sea of dunes where each grain of sand is bladed, but such things could be stopped - Justinius believes - with the proper application of the librarians. Enough at least to allow your forces to advance to the tower itself, and make battle upon it.
-[] Tower 6: Beyond the 3rd Tower, lies this tower. It stands higher than the others, upon a mountain, and guarded by significant shielding that prevents ground-based assault. It would up to your assault marines, to landspeeders, to thunderhawks, to even attempt to destroy this place. Either that or a grueling climb for your marines. Or, perhaps, orbital fire.

Spoiler: Confirmed Naval Presences In System

Imperial Navy Losses In System
1 Mars-class Battlecruiser
1 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
5 Lunar-class Cruisers
5 Escort Squadrons (x2 Firestorm, x1 Cobra, x2 Sword)

Blood Raven Losses In System
x2 Gladius Frigates (4th Company)
x2 Thunderhawk Gunships Great Father's Fist
x2 Thunderhawk Gunships Omnis Arcanum

Newly Arrived Imperial Navy In System (From Z04X)
1 Emperor-class Battleship (Flagship of Vice Admiral Kurek)
2 Retribution-class Battleships
1 Overlord-class Battlecruiser
4 Gothic-class Cruisers
10 Lunar-class Cruisers
3 Dicator-class Cruisers
15 Escort Squadrons (x3 Firestorm , x2 Cobra, x10 Sword)

Swarmworld Kappa
1 Emperor-class Battleship (Flagship of Admiral Graves)
2 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
4 Lunar-class Cruisers
15 Escort Squadrons (x11 Firestorm, x2 Sword, x2 Cobra)
10 Imperial Transports, Ferrying Order of Lost Rosetta

Swarmworld Theta
1st, 4th, 5th Company Fleets (Blood Ravens)

Swarmworld Nu
1 Apocalypse-class Battleship
3 Mars-class Battlecruisers
8 Lunar-class Cruisers
5 Escort Squadrons (x3 Firestorm, x2 Cobra)
20 Imperial Transports, Ferrying Order of Lost Rosetta

Swarmworld Sigma
2 Retribution-class Battleships
1 Mars-class Battlecruisers
8 Lunar-class Cruisers
9 Escort Squadrons (x5 Firestorm, x2 Sword, x2 Cobra)
20 Imperial Transports, Ferrying Order of Lost Rosetta

Daemonworld/Capital
1 Daemonship (Batteship-tonnage/Undivided-leaning)
4 Beast of Tzeentch (Battlecruiser-tonnage)
2 Swarmships (Battlecruiser-tonnage)
12 Swarmships (Cruiser-tonnage)
7 Daemonships (Cruiser-tonnage/Undivided-leaning)
5 Beasts of Tzeentch (Cruiser-tonnage)
15 Daemonship Squadrons (Escort-tonnages/Undivided-leaning)

Karak Eight Peaks: A Quiet Interlude

Spoiler: Voting results [*] King Belegar Ironhammer [*] Grand Master Ruprecht Wulfhart [*] Head Ranger Ulthar Alriksson [*] Mathilde's Multidimensional Aethyric Projection You've an urge to return to the East Gates and collect your quickly-growing Familiar to spend some quality time with him, but the people you've decided to check in with are all here in Karag Lhune, so you quash the desire. The Colleges warn against Familiar Obsession, though opinion remains divided as to whether it's a side effect of the familiar bond itself or just the consequence of being treated with suspicion and prejudice by most others a Wizard will interact with. Your puppy is having a grand old time making friends with the Halfling and Dwarf ladies back at the East Gates, who have proven no more resistant to the charms of a puppy than their human counterparts. He'll be just fine without you for another few days or so. So you finish your tankard, rise to your feet, and smile out at the East Valley as the setting sun turns it into a beautiful pattern of jagged shadows. --- Ulthar remains in the Chiselwards, overseeing the ongoing fortification of the three choke points against the spider-controlled portions of the cave. You pause on your way to him in the ruined room that you and he were using as a base of operations, and find yourself smiling - though your spell has faded, someone with a knack for stonecrafting has chiselled the map you projected onto a wall. You summon a shadowchisel, think for a moment, and carve 'courtesy of Mathilde's Multidimensional Aethyric Projection' underneath it. Mathilde's MAP, you think with a grin. Maybe if it becomes popular enough, people might start to think that's where the word 'map' came from. You entertain yourself with that ridiculous daydream as you make your way through the Chiselwards. The former Squig-farming portions are a mess of splattered mushroom fluids and smouldering spot-fires, whereas the mushroom-farming parts are filled with busy Dwarves. This close to the enemy every Dwarf wears leather and chainmail and carries at least a hand-axe, but the clumsiness of their movements and jumpiness suggests these are civilians, or as close as the Karaz Ankor has to civilians these days. With a careful eye, they examine every sprouting spore and either crush it with gloved hands or transplant it into proper rows. This part of the mountain is destined to become living quarters rather than farming caves, but the Dwarves will allow the edible mushrooms to finish growing and provide one final harvest here. Ulthar is at the central watch post, which is roughly equidistant between the two others. Already some crude beds have been set up, and what looks like a rotating watch of two dozen Dwarves has been set up. A series of ropes hang from the roof, dangling from u-pegs driven into the stone, and a bell on the end suggests a purpose. "Dead Man's Switches, or for reinforcements?" you ask, and the Head Ranger looks up from his conversation with a smile. "Reinforcements," he says, waving away the Thunderer he had been talking to. "As long as there aren't any undiscovered tunnel branches, and I've got Rangers scouring every inch of stone for them just in case, they shouldn't be sneaky enough to reach the fortifications unseen." "Any probing?" "Some," he says. "A few have tried charging and been made to regret it. But every one that has tried it has been crippled or undersized. Maybe they're just the most desperate, maybe they're the ones losing fights for territory and being forced out, but..." "But they'd also be the most disposable." You frown. "I might be jumping at shadows, but I'd rather overreact than underreact." He waves at the barricades, where rubble embankments were being replaced with freshly-quarried stone blocks. Four of the Dwarf-portable bolt throwers stand loaded and ready, their javelin-sized bolts staring down the well-lit tunnel, and a central position remains clear. "Durin's alright, considering he's from Karak Norn - halfway to being elves, that lot - and he's got three cannon on their way over. Once there's grapeshot pointing down the tunnels I'll be a lot happier." You stare down the tunnel, biting your lip in thought. The way to deal with an infestation of unthinking creatures is completely different to how you'd deal with a social hive - or, and you cross your fingers and hope fervently isn't the case, an occupying force of intelligent beings. A slowly-advancing shieldwall covering a rank or two of Thunderers or Quarrelers would dislodge an infestation but would be dangerously vulnerable to a number of tactics, should the spiders prove capable of them. On the other hand, dedicating enough forces and leadership here to account for every possibility could leave other fronts undermanned. Too many variables, not enough hard facts. "When in doubt, fortify," you eventually conclude. Ulthar nods. "Same conclusion I reached." He turns and stares down the tunnel, at the darkness that dominates the tunnel beyond the reach of the flickering torchlight. Dwarves have sharp eyes in near-darkness, but in total darkness they're as helpless as men. You are not quite so limited. Ulgu clings where light and darkness meet, and lingers long after the light has gone. At the end of the tunnel, far beyond the light, where it narrows then opens into a larger chamber, your magical senses reveal to you a creature returning your stare fourfold. At least enough intelligence for curiosity must reside within, for Ulgu denies the call of gravity to swirl around it as its mind wrestles with the unknown. Is this merely the natural cunning every ambush predator must possess? The process of adaptation that smarter creatures are capable of? Or is this a thinking scout compiling information to be shared with others of its kind? You turn your back on the creature and take a seat with Ulthar after filling a wooden tankard from a nearby barrel and grimacing at the taste. Your journeys with the Dwarves have started to refine your palate, and this isn't your typical dinner ale, nor a celebratory quaff - this is Ranger ale, made from the hardy and semi-domesticated grasses Rangers spread the seeds of wherever they range regularly, as well as the seeds of a handful of varieties of near-indestructible shrubs. Tastes like warm death going down, but it gives you a kick of energy. "So, Ulthar," you begin. "What's this about a siege weapon in the armoury?" He winces. "That's-" he begins, then considers. "The amount you've already done, I'll not shut you out. Don't go repeating this to your manling friends, mind." "I swear," you say instantly. And truthfully, too. You might report whatever he says to your superiors in the Grey College, but they're not exactly your friends, are they? "Well, before the Time of Woes was the War of Vengeance, and before the War of Vengeance we actually somehow got along with the pointy-eared buggers. If you believe the stories - and maybe you shouldn't, because there's many a Longbeard that considers history to be the ore one smelts and shapes - we were stupid enough to teach the bastards the secrets of torsion and tension so their sailors could defend their trade ships. What Kragg found in that armoury, and somehow prevented himself from smashing to pieces, appears to be a proof of concept. A bolt thrower that fires six lesser bolts between reloads." He shrugs, and drinks. "O'course, that could all be krut. Maybe some cheeky Engineer decided to tweak some noses by proving whatever Elgi could do, Dawi could do better. Maybe the stupid thing doesn't even work, which is why it was sealed up in the Armoury instead of fighting and dying with the rest of the Hold. Whatever it is, it's Durin's problem now." --- You've shared a Council of War with Grand Master Ruprecht Wulfhart for the past three months or so, but you've never approached him outside of them and neither has he approached you. You are told he is in the Hangars that his men recently fought for, and you watch him thoughtfully as you prepare to break this precedent. The Grand Master of a Knightly Order is an unusual title, and his specifically combines the role of Commander with a High Priest of the Cult of Ulric. In theory he would be under the authority of both the Emperor and the Ar-Ulric, but as his presence here demonstrates, in practice he and his Order are entirely independent - at least as long as he doesn't outright work against either. Currently he is fulfilling his religious role, as he speaks a few words over the bodies of the fallen and lights each pyre as he passes. The flame of his torch was lit from a heavily reinforced lantern one of his men would have transported from the baggage train, which itself was lit from the even more reinforced and carefully-designed brazier that the Knights have brought with them, and its flame would have been lit from the Sacred Flame of Ulric in Middenheim. Many Morrites would consider this form of funeral blasphemous, but Ulricans tend to be a practical lot, and when far from the Gardens of Morr they consider the Sacred Flame they carry with them sufficient to carry the souls of the dead to their rest. Magnus the Pious once stood unburned in that flame to rebut claims he was an agent of the Dark Gods, and went on to fight the Great War Against Chaos and be crowned Emperor, and it was by his decree that the Colleges of Magic were founded. Though your soul belongs to Ranald, you cannot deny a stirring in you as you watch the holy flames envelop the fallen. What isn't said too often is that Magnus the Pious had to stand in the flames because the Ar-Ulric of the time was denouncing him as a pawn of Chaos. You know little of the current Ar-Ulric, but you do know the Winter Wolves have severed ties with both him and Middenheim. With his task done, the Grand Master steps back from the pyres and watches them burn as one of his Knights leans in and has a word in his ear. The man turns and scans the Hangars - now much less cluttered, with the greenskin city dismantled and either thrown from the mountain or used as firewood - until his eyes reach you. The man is a warrior first, but his rank means he has had to learn at least something of statecraft, and you can see the wheels turning in his head as he contemplates the choice before him. He could ignore you, which under the circumstances would not be a snub, but instead a tacit acknowledgement that you have as much right to be here as he does. He could come to you, or summon you to him. Either would be an acknowledgement of your rank - he is technically your superior, as the Grey Order would be roughly equivalent to his own, but that technicality is one few are foolish enough to try to wield against a Magister. If he came to you he'd cede the initiative but imply that your presence is a trespass to be reacted to, while calling you to him would retain the initiative but be a tacit acceptance of your presence. He could also choose to highlight your difference in rank by sending an underling to either dismiss or summon you. It is a horribly intricate game, and one that you're not particularly good at, but you at least know the moves. At last he beckons you over, and with only a little reluctance you leave the embrace of the shadows to walk with him to the edge of the cavern that stands open, presumably for the vast Dwarven airships of times past to enter and exit through. Below you the East Valley stretches out, and you can see growing fortifications of the East Gate on one side and the crumbling form of the Citadel on another, flanked by foothills. Beyond those is the vast caldera that stands at the center of Karak Eight Peaks, once filled with hardy Dwarven crops and now home to a significantly less appetizing harvest of greenskins, their ramshackle hovels stretching from one edge to the other, burning fires forming innumerable pinpricks of light as the sun sets. If they're the same tribe that held the East Gate, then the Broken Toof may be a stronger presence in the Karak than you thought. If not, who are they? And how far does their influence reach? Finally, Ruprecht breaks the silence. "We remain loyal to Ulric and His Empire," he says carefully, "and not those that claim to speak in His name." You do your best to keep your face neutral. "I've no doubt," you reply. "Dwarves are..." his face twists as he searches for words. "Sometimes, not all one could wish for," he says finally. "But nor are we. As allies, they do not dishonour us." What? you think. "I agree," you say. "And the enemies of Dwarves are ones we can bloody our weapons against happily." You nod, and for a moment relief shows on his face. "On that topic, you wield yours with unexpected skill," he nods to the hilt showing over your shoulder, his desire for a safer topic clear. "I've heard the sword is the symbol of your Order, but not that it was also your weapon." "It isn't always," you say, partly glad that the topic has switched to something you actually understand but still utterly confused. The reputation of the Grey College requires that a Magister never let on that they've got no idea what is going on, but damn it, you want answers. "I learned during my service to Stirland from Sir Markus von Pfaffbach, Champion of Stirland's Greatswords, who fell during the Sieges of the Drakenhofs." "I've heard tales of that campaign from some Knights Panther," he says. "Not what I'd call glorious, but it never is with the Undead, and it certainly got the job done." You trade tales of past battles and he starts to relax, and then the topic moves to wolves. Though you're not sure whether yours is properly a wolf, you're pretty sure he's not one of the Giant Wolves that the elite of the Winter Wolves ride, but there's enough common ground for it to be a safe and happy topic of conversation. Ulric and his followers might not like or trust magic, but the reputation of the Grey Order is such that they're cautious rather than disdainful of you, and that's a foundation you can work with. By the time you part ways with the Grand Master, you wouldn't quite call him a friend, but there is a growing sense of mutual respect. --- Technically, Belegar has always been King Belegar; or at least he has been for as long as you've known him - you suppose he had to have been Prince Belegar at one point. But to be a king-in-exile, the latest in a line of kings who have not ruled their supposed kingdom in three thousand years, is very different to being a king in one's kingdom. You've had to mentally remind yourself of his title more than once on this Expedition, but you doubt you'll have to again. In place of the horned helmet you'd seen atop his head for the past few months, there stands a silver crown of sturdy construction that seems no less capable of taking a blow. It bears eight points and each of those points has the socket for a jewel, and only one of those sockets is currently filled. The symbolism is obvious, as is the aura of confidence that radiates from him. The sole sapphire twinkles in the torchlight as King Belegar stands in the Hall of Oaths, and one by one Dwarves speak ritual phrases in Khazalid. The atmosphere in the Hall is solemn, not least of which because to one side the names of the fallen are still being added, but just outside the newly-unsealed doors, newly-minted members of Clan Huzkul celebrate their new identity. By the door stand a pair of Hammerers, the Dwarven equivalent of Greatswords, and even from across the room you can feel the power contained in the runes they bear. You wonder if the Hammerers have been founded because of the discovery of the weapons, or whether that was just a convenient timing and King Belegar could only be guarded by Hammerers once he had a Karak to go with his title. Finally the last of Clan Huzkul swears his oath, and King Belegar stands alone before the Altar of Grimnir. If he's tired after the day's work, he doesn't show it, and at his gesture you move to stand beside him as he gazes at the names freshly carved into the wall. "A thousand times I'd dreamed of the day I finally stood inside the mountains of my ancestors," he says at last. "None of the dreams were anything like what happened. The bloodbath with the trolls, that spectacle of animosity and cowardice in the Hall of the Moon - I didn't know whether to curse you or thank you." He grimaces. "Then word reached me of the battle for the Stairway, and there I saw perhaps a hundred Dwarves already dead or dying, a further hundred felled before my eyes by crude Grobi iron, and a hundred more falling down the shaft as we paid in blood for every step. And though a thousand songs will be sung of the Final Battle of Karag Lhune, I've found I much preferred the Hall of the Moon." The silence between you stretches, broken only by the unceasing tapping of hammer against chisel and chisel against rock. "When we first met in the manling fortress of Grenzstadt, you said you were wandering. Strollendreki. When I spoke to the lads from Karak Kadrin, I got a fair idea why. I don't know whether you'll find what you're looking for here, but know you can always find shelter here while Angrund hearts beat under these mountains." --- The next morning brings headaches to those that overindulged and ten leaders to the King's Gates - there still being a great deal of work to do before the insides of Karag Lhune can be considered hospitable. Kragg's habitual scowl is sharper than ever, either from being drawn away from his study in the Armoury or from his discovery in the Temple of Grungni, so King Belegar passes right over him to Ulthar. "Apart from the spider half of the Chiselwards, Karag Lhune is as cleared as we can make it without a week of sweeps," he reports. "If they're like Forest Spiders - and there's no guarantee of that - they'll start to eat each other after about two weeks, and from there their numbers will halve every week. So unless there's an exit we don't know about, they'll start probing our fortifications soon enough." "I'd pay their weight in gold for some Drakeguns," King Belegar grumbles. "We've repaired the gates that open to the Grand Avenue, and we're building up layers of defences behind them. We've sent a few probes out into it and haven't seen anything, but there's a whiff of Skaven in the air. We've also put a net across the bottom of the shaft - even before it fell, the Grand Abyss was never even close to fully mapped, so better not to take chances." "Agreed. Skaroki?" "Most of our losses were among the Warriors with no Hold affiliation and the Thunderers, before the Umgi warriors arrived. We'll be relying on Quarrelers or bows for ranged fighting from now on." "A great many of them are now affiliated with Karak Eight Peaks," King Belegar corrects, but without rancour. "The Hangars were brutal, but this was never going to be an easy war. Durin?" "The East Gates are about as fortified as we can expect them to be without a good century of work," he reports, as all eyes turn to where the innermost defences can be seen. "The Citadel orcs have tried to venture out a few times and got brutalized for it - from their tattoos, they're Broken Toof." "The Crooked Moon Tribe was dealing in Broken Toof Orc slaves and recruiting the Goblins, even before we arrived," you note. "So their power here could already have been in decline." "That might not be the case," Ulthar warns. "We saw Black Orcs at the gate, and if they're in charge of the Broken Toof they'll care nothing for losing regular greenskins." "We've also found at least some of the southern side-entrances to Karag Nar," Durin continues. "We've got a watch on them for now, but they could be our entrance as easily as they'd be an exit." "That or the Avenue," King Belegar muses. "Have you found where the Avenue reaches the Gates?" "Not yet," Durin says with a frown. "If it was collapsed during the fall, three thousand years of erosion would make it invisible." "We may have to re-excavate it from the inside. Damn. Grand Master Kriegerson, Grand Master Wulfhart. Would either of your Orders' mounts deal well with the darkness?" The former shakes his head, but the latter is smiling. "Better than Night Goblins, I can say from experience." "Having some sort of cavalry in the Grand Avenue could be vital. Marksman Petrescu, how do your men fare?" Codrin thinks before he speaks, his soft voice a contrast to the steel you know is underneath. "My countrymen have taken minimal casualties," he says, "but I regret to report that rumours of treasure have taken hold amongst the unaffiliated. Quite a few have slipped away, either to try their luck at the Citadel or to seek their own entrance to the mountains." "Regrettable," King Belegar says. "But I doubt they'll cause any harm, and they may take some greenskins with them. Marshal Muggins?" "Some of Ulthar's Rangers have been teaching mountaineering to my men," he says. "We've also been standing pickets at night to prevent any surprise raids from the Citadel." King Belegar nods. "The first battle is won, but the Expedition's work continues. We need to find the path to Und-Uzgar so we can better project force along Death Pass - the greenskins of Karak Drazh have yet to make themselves known, but we can't count on that remaining the case. Failing that, it would become necessary to take Karagril and place siege weapons above Death's Crossing." Heads swivel to look at the northernmost mountain, and the chain of foothills that separate it from the East Valley. Hopefully that won't prove necessary in the immediate future. "Secondly," King Belegar continues, "the East Valley cannot be held as is. If we take Karag Nar, then our current holdings will all link up. Alternately, we could take and hold the portion of the Grand Avenue between Karag Lhune and the East Gate. Finally, we could take or destroy the Citadel, and secure the East Valley." Though it does not nearly compare to the mountain below you, the Citadel remains intimidatingly tall. "Finally, we need to know more about our new neighbours. If Karagril or Kvinn-Wyr or some part adjoining us via the Avenue prove capable of threatening us, we need to know now, rather than after we've declared victory and sent everyone home." The meeting breaks up with Ulthar and his Rangers having shouldered the brunt of the work, though Titus' Fieldwardens and the Winter Wolves will be assisting. The War for Karak Eight Peaks has entered a lull, and only time will tell where the next battle will be. Your abilities make you quite capable of contributing to the scouting that must be done, but your position within the Expedition means the decision is yours to make. [ ] Search Karag Lhune for the path to Und-Uzgar with Clan Huzkul. [ ] Plan to secure the East Valley by scouting Karag Nar with Ulthar's Rangers. [ ] Plan to secure the East Valley by scouting the Citadel with Ulthar's Rangers. [ ] Plan to secure the East Valley by scouting the Grand Avenue with Skaroki's Miners. [ ] Scout for future trouble in Kvinn-Wyr with Titus' Fieldwardens. [ ] Scout for future trouble in Karagril with Ulthar's Rangers. [ ] Scout for future trouble along the Grand Avenue with the Winter Wolves. [ ] Other (write in) - Belegar has lost the trait: Crossroads. Belegar has acquired the trait: Goraki: Most Dwarves consider Ranger tactics - ambushes, trickery, assassinations and sabotage - to be distasteful. This Dwarf has embraced them. - This round of scouting will be much shorter than previous - just poke around, see who lives there, and get out. - The East Gate is flanked by Kvinn-Wyr to the south and Karag Nar to the north. After Karag Nar is Karag Lhune, which you currently hold, and then Karagril. Kvinn-Wyr, Karag Nar, and Karag Lhune hem the East Valley.

Turn 22 (Part Eight): An Unkindness

Spoiler: Voted Plan

[X] Priority Targets: Primus Leaders: Specially bred war leaders of any extensive Genestealer Cult, the now noted Primuses of this war are effectively generals and overall theater commanders, both of tyranid bioforms and slaughra forces. They must be expunged, and quickly. Doing so will greatly reduce the power and effectiveness of the Cult forces.
[X] Attacking The Heart: These are but dregs, now, barely worth fighting let alone spending an extensive amount of time killing. Besides which...the Imperium is making its move. While the Sisters of Battle are not wholly finished on their own chosen target worlds, the Navy is moving out against the most dangerous of all the targets, the Daemonworld. It is known that a great amount of Lost Rosetta sisters are travelling there as well on-board multiple ships to repulse boarders or teleported daemons or otherwise. The Blood Ravens should join in this great endeavor. Admiral Graves is leading this attack, for he is the highest ranking Navy officer present. But you must decide how you approach this attack.
-[X] Accept Orders: You position is yet tenuous. Admiral Graves would order your ships within his greater battle plan, if you allow him. This might ease tensions...or provide a way for him to order the ships of the Blood Ravens into danger.

An Unkindness
+045.M42+ To +050.M42+
+Never Falter, Never Surrender+

It was wholly disturbing to see these vaguely alien forms, already twisted into the shape of another and far more terrifying race, go as feral as their secret genetic masters. Cyrus handed the smoking sniper rifle to the scout next to him and focused his bionic eye. Several forms of vision flickered past before centering on thermals, and he watched as they began to fall amongst each other. Far fewer than actual tyranids would, for they had not yet fallen so far. If the Primus equivalent had fallen amongst a true tyranide horde, it would have had truly incredible knockback effects. Here, by the very nature of their significantly greater capacity for higher-tier thought, it was lessened. Instead of falling to a few uncomplicated monstrous yet animalistic instincts, the cult had collapsed in terms of morale and guiding knowledge. They did not suddenly begin shooting one another, but their accuracy was notably reduced. Their inhuman fervor literally stripped from them.

Of course, Cyrus noted as one of the feral gaunts leapt upon a cultist’s back and began tearing away, there were still some constants.

“Note this for the Chapter’s records, initiate,” he grunted. “This highly developed genestealer cult, so distant from other major splinter fleets, had already begun to gestate actual tyranid bioforms despite marked reference to the contrary in previous encounters with their kind.”

The splinter fleet which had fallen upon Subsector Aurelia might have been drawn here instead long ago had it not been specifically drawn there by the eldar. Only now did this become obvious, for had that splinter fleet come here instead, whole worlds worth of biomass would have filled its ranks. Then, not even Aramus would have been able to stop it. The entire Chapter at its near full strength would possibly have not been able to stop it. It would have spread throughout the whole of the Eastern Fringe, potentially. Still, Cyrus would not ever attribute mercy or even the faintest hint of altruism to what had happened by xeno design, regardless of however many more facets remained of that fallen plan. They had sought to bring ruin to human worlds, and so had to be stopped regardless. It was that simple.

Still, it was disquieting to consider, this cult. If left alone long enough, subverting and changing more and more with each generation, was it possible others existed outside of the Imperium’s sight? Cults and worlds that grew their own splinter fleets from the ground up, rather than coming from the void?

Something to be passed on to the Deathwatch, most certainly. Potentially the Inquisitor who had so recently become a Chapter acquaintance.

It was around then that the pulse hit.

Screams, terror, and a sudden shocking cessation of movement amongst purestrains and cultists alike appeared in a field, while Cyrus noted a heavy crackling in every vox nearby regardless of channel. Even his eye, the non-flesh one, suddenly warped in its vision. For a half instant he it was filled with screaming static and the faintest psychic aftershocks of something hungry, something that only one who had faced the tyranids for a long enough time might have discerned. Several guardsmen in the street below who had been attacking the compound where the Primus had been located were lying in the street, bleeding from their eyes and ears. The sanctioned psyker who had been amongst them was screaming as well, hands clutched to her bald head, the metal spikes sticking out of her cranium briefly red-hot with something that was not quite heat.

Less than an hour later, the news was spread across every Imperial channel, and many Slaughra besides. After all, the Patriarch had managed to get himself elected as the combined political and religious leader of the entire Slaughra Swarm and their worlds. The propaganda effects were undeniable, as overall Swarm cohesion broke down across every theater. The feral tyranid bioforms lost their guiding minds, with only minor synapse creatures able to maintain order amongst the hordes. Multiple slain Primuses, many attributed however reluctantly to the Blood Ravens, ensured that cultist resistance was heavily eroded even before the Imperial Guard had properly marshalled themselves to take advantage. On every world, the Imperium advanced, rooting out and burning slaughra and tyranids alike, burning down many a spawning pool and entire cities with Titans and Knights obliterating the offensively alien infrastructure.

Of course, then came the speculation. Who had done it? Which of the mysterious assassin clades had been selected, who was successful? What were the details? The latter would go forever unknown, for the unyielding hand of the Inquisition itself had appeared seemingly from nowhere to classify the information completely and utterly. There were dozens of executions that went from simple basic guardsmen, to captains, to an entire stormtrooper platoon. Three valkyrie pilots as well. This only flamed the fires further, until the Inquisition squeezed the throat of the rumor mill further. None would know of what occurred in the depths of the pits where the Patriarch had been found, or what it took to get there. The records were written, redacted, sealed, and then disappeared entirely.

Cyrus would note, only through the most casual of observation – casually, of course – the Inquisitor herself who had done all of this with her cavalcade of Interrogators and their own retinues.

Lord Inquisitor Christina Brutus Alba Tarquindil impossibly glanced up at him, standing on the top of one of the few remaining slaughra skyscrapers, and lightly tapped a finger to her lips, and then entered the thunderhawk which awaited her. Its paint scheme was as the void itself, with the only color coming from the silver emblem of the Inquisition on it. Behind her stalked a slavering creature, a Culexus, accompanied by a Vindicare who totted their rifle with ease. None had known of this reconvening, yet Cyrus had happened upon it regardless. He, of course, would tell no one, and even the records of the Librarium would require his own personal permission to peruse. It would not do to anger the Inquisition by witnessing what they demanded be redacted, after all.

Spoiler: Slaughra Swarm (Z04X)

Libarius Scrying And Planning: 37. No Successes!
Cervantes Obstruction Attempts: 38. No Successes!
10th Company Efforts: 88! Notable Success. Effects: Notable Victories Against The Enemy.
WARNING: Slaughra Genestealer Cult Has Activated Tyranid Bioforms Out Of Desperation!
NOTICE: With loss of the Patriarch, Slaughra Forces have fallen into infighting against one another! Feral Bioforms are targeting Slaughra and each other randomly!
Conquest Progress:
Slaughra Capital World - 45% Imperial, 32% Slaughra, 23% Feral Tyranid/Genestealer Bioforms
Slaughra Ice World - 70% Imperial, 20% Slaughra, 10% Feral Tyranid/Genestealer Bioforms
Slaughra Desert World - 50% Imperial, 15% Slaughra, 35% Feral Tyranid/Genestealer Bioforms
Slaughra 'Civilized' World Primaris - 60% Imperial, 30% Slaughra, 10% Feral Tyranid/Genestealer Bioforms
Slaughra 'Civilized' World Secundus - 74% Imperial, 19% Slaughra, 7% Feral Tyranid/Genestealer Bioforms
Z04X Space Control: Imperial Navy Supreme Across System/Imperial Navy Has Split Strength To Send More To Aid Secondary Crusade Targets
Blood Raven Losses: 10 Scouts [1st Stage]
Gene-Seed Recovered: +12, Held By Apothecary Marius

Decisions For 10th Company (Choose One):
[] To The End: The Slaughra as a civilization has ended, yet the corpse continues to twitch. The 10th Company could assist in putting down the last of the Slaughra. This is barely even war, rather, it is an extermination. See to it that the Blood Ravens continue to contribute, and thus cannot be complained of leaving the 'grunt work' to mere mortals.
[] Depart: The Patriarch is dead. The Swarm is broken. At this point, the rate of Imperial advance is exponential. The central government has been shattered with the Patriarch and his attendants, who were the central government. It is time for the 10th Company to leave this place - lest Cervantes continue his foolish efforts against your forces.
-[] Rejoin the rest of the Chapter against the Chaos-corrupted Slaughra, who are now the majority of their race.
-[] Leave for Subsector Aurelia, at the least if only to ensure its safety. It does seem to come under threat with frustrating regularity.
-[] Something Else - (Write-In)

=========================================

Admiral Graves is a slip of a man, not even going by space marine standards. A regular bolter would potentially collapse him entirely if thrown with even the slightest of strength. The varied medals he wears are heavy enough, you would think. Entirely clean-shaven, to the point of baldness, his dark brown skin is weathered with wrinkles and liver spots – an impressive signifier of age for a man who likely possesses access to even minor rejuvenat treatments. Despite that, his gaze is bright and his eyes clear. What is also clear is the frown he shows to you as you open communications. Around his holographic image swarm a great number of bridge crew and floating servo skulls that trill and float past, yet he stands at the head of this tide of energy with a great deal of ease.

“Chapter Master Angelos, this is a surprise,” he begins without preamble or greetings, “From what I’ve experienced with Blood Ravens, you would have simply driven against the enemy in your own path.”

“That was under a heretic’s rule, not my own,” you counter, head tilting slightly at him from within your terminator armor.

Graves narrows his eyes at you before nodding, his lips a firm line.

“Fair. Will your captains follow my orders?”

“They will, Admiral.”

Graves is silent for a moment before nodding again.

“Very well. I am not many of my fellows in Sector Command, Angelos. The Inquisition settled the matter, and thus I consider it settled. I can only hope that you and your chapter prove me peers wrong.”

A rare mercy, then, but a welcome one.

“The Sisters currently spread out across my fleet disagree with my agreement to speak with you, and will likely disapprove of you being included within the bounds of our plan,” he notes before the transmission ends. “But, God-Emperor willing, you’ll prove them wrong too.”

=====================================

Contrary to some of the more pessimistic expectations you’ve heard amongst your brothers and the serfs, Graves does not plunge the Blood Raven fleets into the enemy like a speartip to die alone. Instead, he places your ships, battle barges and strike cruisers alike, on the flanks of his formation as it thunders out of the warp, displacing celestial dust and wisps of energy before it. The battleships push forward amongst all of the others, the heavy speartip demanding attention that only their powerful void shield arrays can provide. Even the flagship is a part of this, with packs of cruisers and escorts just barely in their wake. Opposite you, the fleet of the enemy writhes in space, many more of them horrific spawnings of warpflesh and melted metal than actual vessels from a shipyard. Others are pure daemons given great form, beasts of the warp itself. They orient themselves against your forces immediately, they oriented themselves before. An eye visible even from here on the side of one of the greater ships, stares bloodshot at the emblems of the Emperor on your approach. They likely saw you coming through the warp on your way to them.

Arriving on a chorus of the damned and insane ringing out as the grasping tendrils of the warp are cut off as the portal closes behind the fleet, engines activate immediately to push out. And yet, even then, there is the waiting. Space is vast, vaster even than the Imperium, than all of the tyranid Hive Fleets combined. Patiently, you await on your ship, grip tightening and loosening on your hammer alternatively as you watch the tactical screens. The ships inch closer and closer, closer still, until the barest of ranges can be matched. Surprisingly, the enemy does not shy away from this fight, finding some modicum of honor and courage in their tainted hearts, and leave the swell of their disgusting daemonworld to launch themselves forward. Some of the astropaths, your own librarians tell you, are certain to die the closer they get, as the psychic emanations are already growing malicious. The vox channels are filled with screams and laughter, the adepts of the Mechanicus forced to focus their attentions simply on keeping the communications clear.

Then, impact.

Opening Moments:
92 vs. 71

Lance fire crept out, striking down minor escort vessels in great conflagrations, even as the greater beasts shifted themselves to guard with their horrific defenses. Either out of regenerating flesh, shields of sorcery, or bands of pure rage given physical form, they blocked what came. One of the Imperial escort vessels suddenly listed to the side, screams on its channel, as daemons spontaneously manifested out of the flesh portal that had once been their astropath. Closer, the fleets approached, the enemy undulating outward into a wider formation that Graves was forced to match lest his forces be enveloped.

Encirclement Attempt Of Chaos:
64 vs. 11

A shoal of Chaos-aligned cruisers found themselves beset by twice their number in purity, a minute gap in the enemy defenses taken advantage of by two separate squadrons. Fires blazed in the void, while a great batter of lance blasts licked at the flanks of the greater daemon beasts, who responded with slower if more terrifying blasts of warpfire that coasted out. Some peeled their way through the void shields, superheating entire chunks of a Retribution-class battleship’s hull as technology faltered before the unreal. While hundreds of crewmen and serfs died, blood boiling them to death inside of their own veins, it was negligible to the overall functionality of the battleship, which demanded recompense for the slight regardless.

Speartip And Flanking Ravens
91 vs. 66

No new Apocalypse-class battleships had been built in millennia, and that was by itself one of the greatest tragedies of the Adeptus Mechanicus. Those that remained were sovereign entities amongst all the various fleets of the Imperium, their firepower incomparable by all but a few, and the Fist of Macharius was no different. It plunged into the fray, armored prow slamming directly into an opposing Beast of Tzeentch, snapping bone and flesh in equal measure as it plunged itself deep, before its weapon batteries opened up at close range. Hundreds of undulating tentacles slammed into the ship, some managing to find gaps in the weakened void shields, others simply phasing through, to deposit hundreds of screaming daemons of the Changer of Ways. All around the ship, other vessels roared forth, weapons firing endlessly, as the ship was surrounded further and further, the slaves of Chaos eager to destroy such a valuable target. They would not find an easy target, for banks upon banks of lance weapons usually meant for range were practically touching their targets, targets who by the nature of their eagerness found themselves unable to easily maneuver away.

On that ship, corrupt flames spewed out of daemonic arms and orifices, only to find themselves challenged, matched, and then overwhelmed by golden light and holy promethium. The Order of the Lost Rosetta howled litanies of faith as they repelled boarders from beyond the skein of reality, their zeal manifesting through war.

Daemonic Invasion
23 vs. 39

So close to each other, it was inevitable. To be sure, there was the occasional bevy of boarding torpedoes, transports, and such, but these and their unfortunate xeno occupants found themselves destroyed more often than not by point defenses or the thousands of fighters flitting about around their ships. Instead, it was the warp which provided. This close to the daemonworld, it was almost impossible for the sanctioned psykers of the Imperium to repel them, and many died attempting to do so. Out of nothingness, out of the walls, out of the corpses of their brethren came the denizens of the warp. Chuckling plaguebearers, roaring bloodletters, moaning daemonettes, and horrors aplenty appeared across the fleet, across any ship unfortunate to have crossed too close in this deathly knife-fighting range.

Void Bombardments
83 vs. 15

But the plan proceeded apace. The Blood Ravens had been ordered above, to go vertical, to stand above both man and daemon alike, where their bombardment cannons could aim with the greatest ease. The transmission spat outwards from Graves’ command ship, and with that, the bombardment began. There were no atmospheric conditions to care for, yet no gravity to ensure that the shells fell. No matter, however, for the Blood Ravens had fought long enough to adjust their tactics and calculations – though the logic engines proved their worth as well. A shell meant to deliver apocalypse to entire worlds came down from the Litany of Fury directly into the remaining Beast of Tzeentch that was of equal tonnage to a battleship, and the daemon screamed. The cyclonic torpedo’s payload eagerly ate up the warpflesh as fuel, the inexorable power of chemistry ensuring it burned far and wide. By the end of it, a vast crater of blackened flesh had been burnt deeply into the daemon’s frame. Even as it began to split in two, to create two smaller vessel-like beasts, the other shells hit as well.

Grandfather’s Love
30 vs. 79

Next to you, on the bridge, Justinius grit his teeth, collapsing to one knee.

Before you, in the battlefield, the broken remains of multiple ships spasmed wildly as great mucus fibers sprouted from the clouds of corpses that floated about them. Regardless of crew, their corpses served as fertile ground for the predations of Chaos to reunite broken ships, to inflame unlife into shuttered reactors, to ignite shattered guns once more with death. There were even some Imperial vessels who were similarly affected, melding together or simply reviving after being cored by a lucky shot of the enemy. All the while, signals and commands fluttered back and forth from Graves’ ship, the man apparently unfettered by what was occurring all around him.

Response
97 vs. 10

The formation collapsed entirely, and them reformed itself, abandoning a few escort squadrons that had gotten left behind, only for lance and torpedo salvos to obliterate the enemy ships that fell upon them. Orders transmitted to your own ships led to the Blood Ravens to finally descend, firing all the way, into the vertical flanks of the enemy, an almost perpendicular charge downwards, with the battle barges leading all the way. A terrible light emerged from below, where a nova cannon had fired and simply tore apart an enemy battleship, the Fist of Macharius emerging from its ramming and battling scarred but unbroken. Another series of bombardment shells slammed into another battleship, while your lesser weapon arrays fired upon the daemon vessels.

49 vs. 91

The corpses of two Slaughra battleships slammed into one another as if clapped together by the hands of their Gods, their engines long dead but motion still granted to them. The sigils daubed across their frames blazed with light, until finally they began to melt into one another. Where there were still gaps, eldritch energies bled out from the warp within until they combined utterly, growing heavy spires of bone that coughed out globs of viscous blood, literal oceans of blood that somehow yet burned hot enough to burn down void shields and hull plating alike. At the head of the unwieldy beast formed a rictus skull-mask in the shape of a screaming slaughra, yet with a spiked brass collar around its throat. From the tip of each spike came lance-equivalent fire, yet the color alone was enough to blind and madden any who witnessed them.

91 vs. 21

Then you fell upon them, with all the fury of the Blood Ravens. Bombardment cannons fired, weapons arrays targeted, and then finally another exterminatus shell slammed down into that gaping maw. It was the combined mass of two battleships, wounds healed by the warp and daemonflesh, and fired with enough lances and cannons either formed for the first time or bent back into shape to match three smaller vessels. Little of this mattered, for the ships of the space marines are built to withstand the bombardments of worlds as they land their troops. Both the Omnis and Litany have sustained far worse in their time, and will likely suffer more still. Before it can do more than destroy a pair of cruisers and cause damage to several battlecruisers, it is brought low once more. Lance fire from the Fist outright destroys many more escort ships, and some cruisers besides, its advanced targeting allowing it to be a harvester amongst fallow wheat.

72 vs. 45

This time, the comparative purity of the Imperium’s psykers contrasted heavily with the tainted sorcery of the enemy. A hundred psykers shrieked amongst the Navy ships, while Justinius tightened his grip around his staff and muttered words that could not be heard by one not touched by the warp. Light gleamed ephemerally around the fleet, blinking in and out of existence, and another effort to draw forth ships from the warp failed utterly. The portal opened, certainly, and while it was in fact a gaping maw directly into the hellish warp itself, it closed soon after before anything significant could escape it. A few daemons managed to manifest upon the ships on the fringe of the formation, but these were put down after only a few massacres of void armsmen.

76 vs. 35

From below, and then outright behind horizontally, came another of the Avenger-class Grand Cruisers. It was trailing from ten wounds, some scored so deep that you could see the void through the other side, yet its reactors burned brighter than ever. You do not know the captains name, but whoever they were, they were determined to make their sacrifice count. The ship damage was incredible, and essentially irreparable due to the age of the ship, and still it came, firing what few weapons remained to it. Some of the enemy turned to fight it, but they could not stop it, even as they warpfire splashed and clung to its body. If anything, it only made it a brighter comet.

Then it struck, ramming deep into one of the enemy battleships, all energy taken from every weapon, every shield, even likely artificial gravity and life support, all to the engines. A final burst of power exploded at the same time as the ship began to collapse utterly, as it slammed the battleship into the one next to it, crushing hundreds of fighters in between the two by weight and force. Only then did it explode, a brief flash of the warp opening involuntarily, and then all three were gone, leaving only scraps behind.

49 vs. 50

Still, the enemy fought on, despite losing so many crucial components of their fight, a deadlock of painful proportions.

15 vs. 4

But they could not fight forever. There was nowhere to retreat, for this was their last bastion, and if they fled now they would lose their world forever. All who fought knew it, those who fought to save and those who had come to destroy.

89 vs. 13

Perhaps if it had just been the Imperial Navy, there would have been a loss. The enemy was tenacious, the Gods granting their blessings with gleeful abandon, ships and beasts spat out from the warp or at the least freakishly healed by it. Throughout it all, the forces of humanity fought on, and on, and on. Boarding pods carried the Sisters of Battle onto ships that could bear their presence, while outright daemons were instead blown apart by lance and torpedo alike. Waves of bombers and fighters peeled back layers of chitin and rotten musculature alike in equal measure, revealing the innards within and exposing them to destruction from a multitude of sources. When each died its death, the lights emanating from the daemonworld grew brighter, for death was death, and even with their followers and fleet brought low, it could be considered a sacrifice of some sort or another.

The last was a more cowardly sort, a daemonic thing that had only managed to feast upon enough souls and flesh to achieve the size of a Sword-class frigate, and found itself violently hunted down by thrice its number in that which it had aped.

==========================================

“The Inquisition has confirmed it,” Graves states, placing the cold sigil of their organization upon the table, “This planet is to be removed as a threat by way of Exterminatus. Chapter Master, I assume you still yet carry the armaments?”

You nod in turn, though your gaze bounces along varied commanders of the Imperial Guard and a veritable bevy of Lost Rosetta. This time, their Canoness Superior has been joined by an honor guard…of other Canonesses, each apparently leaders of their own divisions within her Order. Tenenbaum, for her part, glares at you with a modicum less violent hatred than when you saw her last. Not enough for her sisters, it seems, who have spent the entire time unblinking as a group the moment the Blood Ravens entered the meeting room, hands resting plainly on their weapons.

“Very well. The issue at hand, then, is to allow your ships the ability to do so. The Tarot, our sanctioned psykers, and what little out scans could manage have confirmed it – numerous sites exist along the planet’s primary continent which would prevent orbital bombardment.”

Said locations flicker into being on the display which is blown up to be viewed by all, the techpriests on their hands and knees, mechadendrites whirring as they ensure the machine continues to function post-battle. To their credit, the image only flickers every few seconds instead of constantly.

“Towers and pits, either technological or sorcerous, are the source of these things. A large enough number must be destroyed to open a window for the ships of the Blood Ravens to unleash a bombardment enough to wipe this accursed rock clean,” he speaks calmly, circling a group in particular. “Landing will begin soon, and we must be ready to fight for every inch. This world is beholden to none of the Dark Gods in particular, as near as we can tell, so there is no single precise set of tactics or expectations we may hold within ourselves.”

Margaret stands, her fists slamming onto the table heavily, making it list slightly.

“They will all die in the flames of the Emperor regardless. Let us land first, and the Guard can come in behind us. Together, we shall all tear down the works of the heretic and xeno alike!”

The General, whose name you do not know, stands as well.

“A fair plan, we can only hope that we’ll be able to reach the surface in enough numbers to pull it off.”

Something ugly dances in one of the Canonesses eyes as she turns her head towards him.

“You doubt the God-Emperor’s holy warriors, and your own forces? Are they…impious?” Her tone is at once accusing and threatening, but before anyone can do more than begin to raise their voice, Margaret’s voice clamps own on her lesser’s shoulder.

“Calm yourself, Clarissa,” she chides in a surprisingly motherly tone, “It is a daemonworld, and they have defenses aplenty. You cannot fault him for his concern.”

“But he doubts,” Clarissa replies, her eyes still on the General.

“And he will see that he was wrong to do so when we obliterate this world.”

It is at that point that Admiral Graves coughs.

“All well and good, but there is another voice we have not heard much from,” he turns towards you. “Chapter Master?”

Select Plan For For Stage Eight Of Engagement [Choose One]

[] The Hammer: Join the Blood Ravens with the landings of the Guard and the Order of the Lost Rosetta. While not necessarily performing speartip strikes or the like, the force multiplier of having space marines augmenting these somewhat more mundane forces cannot be underestimated, in morale and effectiveness. If the Blood Ravens should show themselves to be pure once more, what better way than this, when you can amply demonstrate yourselves to those who are certainly watching? It might not be as precisely effective as more traditional space marine tactics, but how long was your Chapter aloof under the hand of Kyras?
[] The Scalpel: Allow the Guard and Sisters to land as they must, to begin advances towards the towers. You should forge ahead of them all, and break the enemy from afar. Shatter power stations, shield emitters, and enemy supply locations ahead of the advance, ensuring it to be that much easier. Will it be more difficult? Of course, your marines will be alone, but they will be alone doing what only they can and could. The potential for danger is always there, and yet more so without any support from the Guard or the Sisters. But, then again, is that not what the Blood Ravens were meant for?
[] The End: This fight has stretched long enough, and the ranks of the Guard of the Sector require time to resupply, rearm, and recruit once more. The same can be said of the Sisters. End this war, here, now, but sending your forces directly through the teleportariums deep into enemy territory, into the planetary shield emitters and ritual sites directly. It would be tremendously dangerous, for in this environment teleporting could easily result in the utter disappearance of your forces into the warp forever. Yet if you could bring down the proper targets, then all could leave this cursed place, an allow for a proper exterminatus to take place. This world is tainted, has been for too long, and must be destroyed. You would be alone, in the fiercest possible fighting, and might end up losing troops simply in attempting to get them there. But if successful it would spare far more lives of the Guard and Lost Rosetta.
[] Write-In: (Write-In)

Spoiler: Confirmed Naval Presences In System

Imperial Navy Losses In System
1 Mars-class Battlecruiser
1 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
5 Lunar-class Cruisers
5 Escort Squadrons (x2 Firestorm, x1 Cobra, x2 Sword)

1 Emperor-class Battleship (Flagship of Vice Admiral Kurek) Hull To Be Reclaimed
2 Retribution-class Battleships 1 Of 2 Hulls Able To Be Reclaimed
1 Mars-class Battlecruisers
1 Overlord-class Battlecruiser
1 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
4 Gothic-class Cruisers
14 Lunar-class Cruisers
3 Dictator-class Cruisers
17 Escort Squadrons (x9 Firestorm, x0 Cobra, x8 Sword)

Blood Raven Losses In System
x2 Gladius Frigates (4th Company)
x2 Thunderhawk Gunships Great Father's Fist
x2 Thunderhawk Gunships Omnis Arcanum

Swarmworld Kappa
4 Lunar-class Cruisers
5 Imperial Transports, Ferrying Order of Lost Rosetta

Swarmworld Theta
3 Lunar-class Cruisers
3 Imperial Transports, Ferrying Order of Lost Rosetta

Swarmworld Nu
5 Lunar-class Cruisers
5 Escort Squadrons (x3 Firestorm, x2 Cobra)
2 Imperial Transports, Ferrying Order of Lost Rosetta

Swarmworld Sigma
4 Lunar-class Cruisers
9 Escort Squadrons (x5 Firestorm, x2 Sword, x2 Cobra)
5 Imperial Transports, Ferrying Order of Lost Rosetta

Daemonworld/Capital
1 Emperor-class Battleship (Flagship of Admiral Graves)
1 Emperor-class Battleship (Flagship of Vice Admiral Kurek) Mission Killed, Hull To-Be-Salvaged
1 Apocalypse-class Battleship
2 Retribution-class Battleships
3 Mars-class Battlecruisers
1 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
10 Lunar-class Cruisers
13 Escort Squadrons (x5 Firestorm, x4 Cobra, x4 Sword)
35 Imperial Transports, Ferrying Order of Lost Rosetta
1st, 4th, 5th Company Fleets (Blood Ravens)

Turn 22 (Part Nine): An Unkindness

Spoiler: Voted Decisons

[X] To The End: The Slaughra as a civilization has ended, yet the corpse continues to twitch. The 10th Company could assist in putting down the last of the Slaughra. This is barely even war, rather, it is an extermination. See to it that the Blood Ravens continue to contribute, and thus cannot be complained of leaving the 'grunt work' to mere mortals.
[X] The Hammer: Join the Blood Ravens with the landings of the Guard and the Order of the Lost Rosetta. While not necessarily performing speartip strikes or the like, the force multiplier of having space marines augmenting these somewhat more mundane forces cannot be underestimated, in morale and effectiveness. If the Blood Ravens should show themselves to be pure once more, what better way than this, when you can amply demonstrate yourselves to those who are certainly watching? It might not be as precisely effective as more traditional space marine tactics, but how long was your Chapter aloof under the hand of Kyras?

An Unkindness
+045.M42+ To +050.M42+
+Never Falter, Never Surrender+

Sorcery and technological defenses both prevented an easy landing, but the forces of mankind were not so spineless as to turn away from such a fight. Heavy transports slammed down through the atmosphere like stones carrying the forces of the Imperial Guard and Order of the Lost Rosetta alike, while vast clouds of fighters and bombers flooded down from the lower atmosphere. There was no time to waste, no uncertainty that could be allowed. In a rolling tide of steel and fury, did the forces of the Imperium assault the combined heresy of Chaos and xeno life at once. The response, of course, was immediate, as cannons all across the surface of the main city woke up. The daemonworld had its own defenses spewing unnaturally moving sludge and acids that melted through void shields and metal alike, spikes of crystallized light and shredding clouds of laughter and scream given physical form. Bombardments slammed down into those shields, forcing the attentions of those who maintained them, just one more component of the oncoming invasion which sought to burn the entire planet down to its cinders.

Invasion Wave 1
93 vs. 36

Sanctioned psykers cried out, Librarians grit their teeth, and for a wonder, the first wave plowed through the defenses without breaking apart entirely. Assaults of daemonic screams and great plumes of flame that erupted from diseased pustules on the planet’s surface were diverted, dissipated, destroyed. A great bevy of drop pods bearing the tested yet unbroken sigil of the Blood Ravens, crashing down at landing sites to release space marines into the horrific landscape that was the daemonworld. It had no name known to human ears, much less one that could be understood without stripping slivers of one’s soul away, but it did not matter. Bolter shells and heavy boots sufficed to crush and stomp out a writhing living world which had sunk halfway into the accursed Warp. They called out their litanies of hatred, and ranks and ranks of brothers of a diminished chapter who fought on regardless. You crushed a dozen mutated slaughra in the first few moments as they charged out of the muck that was their home, great resounding booms of Godsplitter matching the entry of transport ships bearing the sigils of the Ecclesiarchy.

Invasion Wave 2
91 vs. 1

An ailing and ancient transport ship carrying Imperial Guardsmen was struck, only for it to slam instead into one of the very defense towers that had killed it. In a miracle, it would later be told, the vessel’s Machine Spirit managed to save almost all its occupants despite slamming into the earth at fatal speeds. They would emerge to unleash their fury with grenade and flamer and plasma, as screaming sisters of battle secreted amongst their number stood at the forefront against a world for which every inch was steeped in corruption. A trio of basilisks fired earthshaker rounds at distant targets as they were disembarking, one firing so powerfully that the war machine was knocked back almost halfway into its own carrier. One shielding array failed entirely as a swarm of sororitas ignored orders to link up with other troops and charged ahead, alone, faith and flame marking their merciless passage through the streets. They returned carrying a third of their number in dead, but with smiles and songs on their lips as the ash from the destroyed shielding tower coated their bodies.

Invasion Wave 3
44 vs. 35

A beast emerged from the depths of the planet, blasting out of the streets and sewers, the size of a Titan, made of chitin and metal alike, ten thousand twisted slaughra whose flesh and forms had bulged and grown and melted together as heated wax as a sheath of musculature to form the beasts frame. It roared out, nine arms with far too many joints and far too much strength, each swatting at incoming transports. It died, screaming, as it fell to the earth once more, this time dead, from combined armor assaults from a dozen Leman Russ tanks, but the damage had been done. More would begin to emerge, the buildings which had made up the cursed city writhing in their birthing throes as daemons found their holds into the material realm, for blood was spilling and war was being made. But the landing was done, with the favor going in the name of the Emperor, and so the true fighting began. Thousands had died before firing a shot, and thousands more would die in the fight to come.

===========================

Technological Shielding Assaults
65/42/54/79/62/23/95/13
Vs.
25/51/31/45/21/40/82/15

4 Of 8 Shield Sources Destroyed

Ahead, the tower glimmered with eldritch warplight, the environment writhing more and more the closer one got to it. The thunder of the storm about them was phelgmatic laughter and sultry moans, maddened shrieks of rage and fury, and screams of avian and man alike. Lightning was multicolored, appeared from nowhere and lancing out with no discernable specific pattern.

Ten tanks advance in front of everyone else, liberally spraying copious amounts of purifying flame upon every possible surface. This is partially because everything is made of twisting daemonflesh or sprouting stone which either grows spikes and fires them or simply sprouts daemons, and partially because of the daemon hordes which come screaming out of the shadows and even thin air. The Guard huddle close to the tanks and their own marching sororitas guards, priests bearing chainswords bellowing endless litanies of purity and courage. From the speakers of the tanks and rhinos come further Ecclesiarchal hymns that serve to at the least keep the majority of the Guard from collapsing outright from their terror, though even an hour’s march has seen notable casualties to madness and suicide. Of those that run screaming out into the bloodmist, nothing can be done. Interspersed throughout, the Blood Ravens fire their own weapons upon the seemingly endless foes before them, a single marine standing close more than enough to bolster the hearts of the men and women of the Imperial Guard.

Canoness Clarissa hums quietly and quite atonally as she slams her ceramite-clothed fingers onto the war machines heavy keys. They clack heavily, but for all that the music that erupts from the device is hauntingly beautiful. As it advances, the Exorcist continues to fire missiles high into the air from its pipes, each salvo accompanied by the music she plays. At some unseen signal, Tarkus noted that they could only guess as the Lost Rosetta seemed wholly unwilling to share their private channels, the entire formation came to a halt. His company twisted back and forth, firing continually, while others dared to dance close enough with chainsword and power sword against the creatures who got far enough. Finally, a second and clearly heavily modified rhino approached in reverse, before the hatch slammed down and a duo of techpriests emerged, a mottled servitor between them carrying a new rack of missiles in multiple servo-arms.

“Is it ready, then?”

Tarkus turned to look at the Canoness, whose expression was unreadable due to her helmet. Even now, in the depths of a Daemonworld, she was dour and calm.

“Yes, Canoness, and Omnissiah willing, this will bring us one step closer,” one of the techpriests calls back, scratchy vocoder making them sound reedy and skittish.

“Then load it, and we shall see,” she nods firmly.

The difference between what had been fired before and would be now was clear, and unsettlingly slow. What replaced those pure promethium and chemical flames was something else entirely, something that was not-quite something that Tarkus had seen before in his many long years as a Blood Raven. Only a few others would have recognized it, he knew, Cyrus perhaps amongst them, but none of the younger marines in the Chapter would. He was as of yet still unsure whether or not it was a good thing. His face cast into its permanent scowl, he stomped forward until his approach garnered the attention of Canoness and techpriest alike.

“What do you want, space marine,” was her almost droning sneer.

“Where did the Order of the Lost Rosetta gain phosphex from? Or at least this near-imitation of it.”

Unconcealed malice glimmered in the Canoness’s eyes above her breathing mask.

“You are correct, space marine,” she tilted her head robotically at him, “It is not phosphex. Not yet.”

“You’re trying to recreate it?” Tarkus stared at the Canoness.

“It is the Omnissiah’s will,” the techpriest half-screeched. “The heretek Veriliad damned himself the moment he destroyed the holy STC!”

“You risk much using something even somewhat similar on this world, the consequences -,” Tarkus began before the Canoness let loose a rusted laugh.

“This is a world doomed to die, forever, space marine. What does it matter how we poison its surface beforehand?”

=====================================

Sorcerous Shielding Assaults
53/47/65/69/51/70/43/5/82
Vs.
6/3/47/84/55/88/69/54/73

4 Of 9 Shield Sources Destroyed

A blazing golden aura surrounded them as they marched, the writhing earth burning seemingly both from presence and blazing promethium alike. The sororitas prodded the bevy of sanctioned psykers forward, their guards adding to the punishment. Men, women, and a duo of bawling children bled from the eyes and ears as the surgically implanted devices that filled their skulls demanded ever more from them. Before them, walls that resisted krak explosives, tank shells, and worse finally began to shudder and break as the metaphysical bonds that kept them strong were torn apart in multiple planes of reality. At a cried signal, a group of seraphim plunged forward through the air, a squad of Blood Ravens beneath them, smashing through the barriers that had been built on sacrifice and sorcery. Within, daemons screeched in challenge as their sanctum was breeched, while dozens of Guardsmen went mad at the noise alone. Those that survived that much and were ordered inside by Commissar’s more often than not ended up dying as their souls were snuffed out by the environment itself, seeping and bleeding out of their very pores to be absorbed by the world around them.

Elsewhere, the Chief Librarian of the Blood Ravens clapped his hands together, the spells barring the way unraveling entirely to reveal the target within. It was a massive spinal cord, made of blood and brass melded together, from which monstrosities of both substances were unnaturally birthed. In the gaps between the segments creatures crawled forth creatures of sinew and screams woven into physical form, only to be caught alight by blessed promethium and unrelenting bolter fire. Guardsmen howled into the madness with their own screams, many shutting their eyes and blindly loosing las bolts into the oncoming hordes, contributing as best as they could. A penitent engine, carrying a sororitas who had dared to counsel mercy instead of purgation for a horde of cultist children, stomped forth towards the column, laden with explosives in such number as to make its machinery groan with the effort. She hummed a lullaby even as she was filled with razor spines and burnt black, embracing the Chaotic edifice with care before the explosives detonated. In an instant, she was redeemed in the annals of her Order, while the daemons howled from their anchors lost. Two dozen guardsmen were caught in the explosion, regarded as acceptable casualties.

=============================

The daemonworld shudders from the war that has become its surface.

Daemons explode into being from the air, from the ground, and from the very corpses of the fallen. Of the guard, at least, for the sororitas are somewhat more inviolate to the influence of the Great Enemy all about them. Sisters of the Lost Rosetta chant holy hymns and let loose with every bit of fiery fury that they can, with Retributor squads making their way through organic slurry turned flash fried ash. So too do the Blood Ravens, the standards of the chapter raised high upon the backs of sergeants and taken hills alike. But none of this, even the successes made, are without cost. A city block transforms into a giant maw, swallowing three Leman Russ tanks and a squad of sororitas whole. Artillery shells fly up into the air, are possessed by daemons, and fly back to their launching point to erupt into rifts into the Warp itself.

Even as certain vital towers fall, ritual sites torn asunder, and lives lost in sacrifice and heroism, the result remains grim.

“It is not enough, Chapter Master,” Graves tells you through weak and tinny vox cast, a chorus of damning whispers attempting even now to worm their way in your ears, “Initial bombardment attempts are not yet having any noticeable effect!”

“Very well, Admiral,” you mutter, Godsplitter’s head swinging out to crack a daemonette in the chest and tear it apart. “We shall fight on.”

You lift the daemonhammer high, its field sparking furiously as its fulfills its purpose, and march atop the nearest pile of slaughra corpses. Behind you, weary guardsmen, wide-eyed zealots of the Lost Rosetta, and Blood Ravens watch as you ascend. The terminator armor crunches and squelches the corpses beneath, but you make your way regardless. A xeno round smashes against your armor, but fails to do more than scuff the paint. Apollo, you can see, even now is charging against the enemy ahead. The enemy surrounds him and an assault marine squad, daring to probe the enemy lines before the battle you were fighting was even done.

“In the Emperor’s name!”

Godsplitter points out at the enemy, ensconced in their bunkers and buildings, spiked chitin-wire over their trenches. Behind that lies yet another site where sorcerers and slaves labor.

“LET NONE FIND US WANTING!”

First Phase Losses

Fatalities

[4] 4th Company Marines Slain, Gene-Seed Recovered (5)
[1] 1st Company Marine Slain, Gene-Seed Recovered (1)
[3] 5th Company Marines Slain, Gene-Seed Recovered (3)

Casualties

[2] 4th Company Marines Severely Injured, Non-Combat Effective
[5] 1st Company Marines Severely Injured, Non-Combat Effective
[3] 5th Company Marines Severely Injured, Non-Combat Effective

=======================================

Technological Shielding Assaults
61/73/93/5
vs
41/50/2/69

7 of 8 Shielding Sources Destroyed

The sky was a multicolored nightmare, screaming faces of brothers lost and foes slain leering. But for the life of him, he could not figure out why he was stuck staring at it as he was. His body shook from side to side, and that alone engendered anger. One had to keep moving, always, for that was life itself. To be without movement was to die! Yet despite this he could not do it, he could not move! Fury burned in him, his veins ignited, but he couldn’t move! All that was possible was for him to blink and snarl at the sky which snarled back. Daemons, guardsmen, sororitas, even dead Blood Ravens. For an instant, worse than any of them all, he thought he saw the sneering face of Kyras.

“K…,” he spoke through split lips and bleeding guns.

“By the Emperor!”

“The Captain is down! Move up, move up, protect the captain!”

“K-kk,” Hadrian growled.

‘Let the Galaxy Burn!’ Those damn words, spoken for the first time since the Horus Heresy and resounding even now. Daring to use the vox channels of the chapter, laughing, cackling, glorifying in it all! In that moment, Hadrian had been attacked from behind by traitors within his very squad. Forced to fight across the void itself as the chapter turned in on itself. Traitors and heretics. Monsters and cowards, all of them, waiting, waiting! Waiting to betray them all!

“The predator is damaged, get to the Captain!”

“How could he have survived!?”

“KKKKYYYYRRRASSSSSS!”

And Hadrian rose, his broken neck and cracked vertebrae shifting as his twinned hearts pounded. Smoking ruin was all that was left of the front of his power armor, from pauldron to pauldron, from gorget to belt, and yet the Captain of the 4th Rose. A broken arm flexed, hand gripping around the scorched edges from where the warp blast had slammed into the front of the predator he had been atop, while the other grasped the flickering plasma pistol he had carried with him all this time. The predator’s crew had been injured, forced into suspended animation, one likely dead regardless, but he rose from their motionless bodies screaming fury.

One eye, the other obscured by bruised and pain-swollen flesh, glared in the direction of the slaughra mutant beast, its entire mouth replaced with a bastardized and xeno equivalent of a lascannon.

“I’M NOT FINISHED WITH YOU YET!” Hadrian roared, firing at it with remarkable accuracy.

An instant later, the rest of the 4th were there, firing krak missiles and heavy bolters. The beast died in a wild conflagration, its own corrupted fuel fluids igniting. Hadrian did not notice this, firing until the heat of his plasma pistol began to boil at his hand’s flesh. He screamed and raged at the dead even as his marines dragged him back, retreating from the failed assault and bringing the ruined predator with them. It took five marines to hold him down for the apothecary to force him into suspended animation. The other marines injured in the failed attack were taken into the hands of the healers as well, while the rest of the Company fanned out to defend them.

Elsewhere, the battles were more successful, the daemons and beasts assigned to that defense lost to the others. The Guard’s armored fist pounded one arcane tower to oblivion, its heretical xeno mechanisms broken down by relentless basilisk and leman russ fire. The Sisters of Battle simply hacked another apart with penitent engines, whose flanks and rears were guarded by repentia sisters who screamed as they fought the daemons and slaughra which reared up to try and repulse them. In another location, the hammer Godsplitter and legendary Apollo Diomedes shattered the enemy, breaking their defenses and bodies with equal prejudice. The 1st Company bore the brunt of the assault, and did not falter in the slightest.

====================================

Sorcerous Shielding Assaults
50/75/32/96/97
Vs.
25/32/77/14/9

8 of 9 Remaining Shielding Sources Destroyed.

“I…I can’t, my…my mind!”

The lexicani howled, yet even as he collapsed to his knees, clutching at his head, the pain lifted away. No. It remained, yet simply somehow was weathered. The psyker blinked bleeding eyes to stare up at the giant figure which had stepped up next to him. Justinius reached down, lending his hand, to help the younger marine to his feet, before the Chief Librarian of the Blood Ravens let a mirthless yet somehow comforting smile come to his lips. The rest of the Libarians, their blue armor splattered with ichor and dirt, assembled as well.

“Rest, young one. You do not bear this burden alone. Blood Ravens!” Justinius boomed, his voice unnaturally loud, “Bring it down!”

Lighting, clean and jagged, erupted from around them. Barriers of solidified blood brought strength of adamantium through sorcery were melted to bubbling slag. Slaughra sorcerers found their own minds crushed, the daemons they summoned and bound to them turning upon them. Before the assembled might of the Blood Ravens, their powers and arcane might availed them for nothing more than dying tired. Behind them, two dreadnoughts crunched into the earth from drop pods, emerging quickly and firing krak missiles and lascannon fire as well. The immaterial and material alike burned with that which could destroy them, and so with the snapping of a hundred minds and a thousand souls, the barrier in the atmosphere disappeared.

The lexicani stared at this, his own powers meager yet in comparison, before nodding, helped to his feet by his fellows. Around them, detachments of the 1st and 5th Companies stirred, as their psyker brethren took the requisite sixty seconds of rest. Once it was done, Justinius nodded, and jerked his chin towards the next target. Across the vox, they felt reports flitter in. One tower down as Hannibal marshalled an entire regiment of Guardsmen to follow him into battle. Another as the Order of the Lost Rosetta used enough promethium as to allow the flames to be seen dozens of miles away, an entire xeno city-spire set to burn down. Elsewhere, the 5th Company under Tarkus fought in a combined force with the Guard to bring ruin to the works of the xenos.

“I have word from the Chapter Master,” Justinius told them all, through flesh and mind-voice. “It is done. We all have orders to pull out before Exterminatus commences.”

=======================================

Evacuation Procedures (Guard): 84 vs. 5
Evacuation Procedures (Rosetta): 20 vs. 68
Evacuation Procedures (Blood Ravens: 33 vs. 50

The slaughra knew. How could they not? There were a vast number of sources which engendered their final desperate fury. Foresight from the sorcerers. Whispers from the warp in the minds of the mad. Daemons cackling from the skies and in the shadows. Some had known it was coming, yet with Nurgle in their hearts they had persevered. Or for the joy of the experience. Some were so lost to Khorne’s bloodlust that they did not have the actual thought to spare for it. Orbital scans and observer posts knew something was coming as well, even as the orbital fire from the ships of the Imperial Guard had steadily walked their way from battle to battle. Yet in the end, it came down to instinct. The sensation of the final blow on the way, and a final lashing out. In vast numbers the slaughra abandoned their defensive posts, their daemon-machines unleashed in their totality, plague bombs and other weapons unleashed.

They could not actually stop it, but they could make the ones who had come from the stars bleed for every inch. A half dozen aspiring sororitas who wished to become Canonesses instead became martyrs, screaming in hatred and ecstasy as the bombs they had willingly born with them went off. Brother Deimos of the 5th Company let himself be torn asunder, the young assault marine showing mettle centuries older than his scant decades should have provided, his two chainswords preventing an entire tide from overtaking his squad for precious moments. A pair of 4th Company Devastators allowed themselves to be swallowed up as a distraction, only the arrival of Hannibal Palrum himself ensuring their savaged corpses could be retrieved. All this and more, and yet of those superhuman beings of the Blood Ravens, the holy servants of the Ecclesiarchy, it was the Guard which fared best in comparison.

For those but mere mortals, recruited and garbed in flak armor and lasgun, they fought and bled and obliterated the foe as they attempted to advance. Ranks of armor steadily churned their treads, bulwarks each, while an endless hailstorm of valkyries and marauder bombers blew apart the field. It was they who turned, a regiment here, a half-a-regiment there, forging out into the tainted landscape to fight alongside those who had shed blood with them. Certain commissars wished to enact executions for daring to go against the retreat orders. Certain commissars were found dead from enemy fire. It was the priests, wielding their gigantic blades, who cheered the fight, the heroism, and tore apart the xenos with sheer volume of fire. They screamed, and shuddered, those guardsmen, but they grit their teeth and continued to fight regardless.

Many died, many were injured, and many were lost forever to the daemonworld’s embrace. But many more escaped. And thus did the ships of the Blood Ravens flock together over the last world of the Slaughra, tainted or otherwise. Their machine spirits glowered with spite for what lay beneath them, and the munitions loaded would be the display of that fury. There was no pause. There was no offer of surrender. For this was not orbital bombardment. It was genocide. Utter destruction. And all the howling of Chaos below would not avail it, not in this moment, for the spirit of the defenders was too weak, their devices and rituals broken, and there would be no saving them. A warp storm, perhaps, began to shudder and shift throughout the solar system, but it would not be fast enough.

For the first of the cyclonic torpedoes began to fall. Thermonuclear atmospheric obliteration and nuclear fission were unleashed, and the daemonworld screamed. Its shriek flooded the vox, scattered the auspex to paint the picture of a furious snarling face out of target points. Astropaths died outright, mutated and had to be put down, or in one case exploded into a warp portal that released a full dozen bloodletters that required a great number of armsmen to put down. Continental plates cracked open, and released magma that twisted and shifted like a living organism. A civilization died screaming, and it was good. A world died, and it was good. A threat to the Imperium ended.

Praise the Emperor, for his work here was done.

Second Phase Losses

Fatalities

[2] 4th Company Marines Slain, Gene-Seed Recovered (4)
[1] 5th Company Marines Slain, Gene-Seed Recovered (2)

Casualties

[5] 4th Company Marines Severely Injured, Non-Combat Effective
[6] 1st Company Marines Severely Injured, Non-Combat Effective
[4] 5th Company Marines Severely Injured, Non-Combat Effective
Captain Hadrian Priscus Severely Injured, Non-Combat Effective

================================================

There are a great many less sororitas present at the meeting than there were before. Only Tenenbaum is present, in fact, and two seraphim honor guard. Her armor is still dripping with gore, blood steamed into dryness from the heat venting of her fists. The same General as before is here, though he looks to have aged a remarkable number of years since you saw him last. Graves, out of everyone, looks as he did before. Only the slightest amount of bloodshot in his eyes marks the stress he was under. Before you is a display of the planet below, a molten and dead ruin where once there was a blasphemous civilization of xenos. The techpriest present adjusts some knobs and depresses some ruins, and the holo shifts, expanding outwards to mark the entire system.

“It is done,” Graves pronounces, and a faint weight lifts from the shoulders of everyone here, save your own and that of Tenenbaum. “The slaughra threat is ended.”

She knows, as you do, that they next fight is surely just barely in the distance.

“General Filmore, your men did well, well indeed,” Graves nods towards the man, who curtly nods his own head. “Holy sister, Chapter Master Angelos, my thanks to you as well,” he looks at you. “Without the aid of both of your organizations, this fight may have taken far longer.”

“The Emperor’s Will was done here today,” Tenenbaum says, her voice still filled with a quiet simmering hatred. “Many of my sisters died to fulfill it, but they do so joyously, in His name.”

“It is the duty of His Angels of Death, Admiral,” you say, nevertheless granting a bow of your head at his words.

“Nevertheless…rest assured that Segmentum Command will hear of all of your valor, all of you,” he shifts his eyes from each one of those who commanded on the ground. “But I shall not keep you. We all have our dead to tally, the costs to pay, and repairs to make.”

Tenenbaum clamps her power fist over her heart, bowing slightly, before turning to leave with a heated glare at you. Let her keep her suspicion and mistrust. The Blood Ravens have done little but earn it. You can only continue on your own course, and show her the error of her anger’s direction. Hours later you and the rest of the Blood Ravens have gathered together, to honor the dead, process those who must be healed, and see to the vehicles and drop pods back to their stations. The techmarines will certainly have their hands full as you move on. Already, other ships from the Imperial Navy are entering the system, for while the sororitas may be leaving, as are the Blood Ravens, it will be up to the Guard and Navy to fortify and hold these worlds, that colonies may be built upon them and make better use than the slaughra ever could have. All three Company Fleets return to join their remaining brothers in the void. The 10th Company rejoins the rest of the Chapter, their grim work complete, the scouts of the Blood Ravens proving to be of great use in hunting down the last of the slaughra and tyranid organisms. All the while, throughout the fighting, had the forges burned, every moment of downtime - what little there was - dedicated to further training. So does the Reclamation Crusade come to an end.

Polonius Reclamation Crusade Results:

Z04X

Fatalities

[10] Scouts [1st Stage] (12 Geneseed Recovered)

Promotions

14 Scouts [2nd Stage] Advance to Full Battle Brothers
50 Scouts [1st Stage] Advance to Scouts [2nd Stage]

Relations

No Imperial Guard Reputation Loss
No Imperial Navy Reputation Loss
No Ecclesiarchy Reputation Loss

Z04Y

Fatalities

[6] 4th Company Marines Slain, Gene-Seed Recovered (5)
[1] 1st Company Marine Slain, Gene-Seed Recovered (1)
[4] 5th Company Marines Slain, Gene-Seed Recovered (3)
9 Gene-Seed Total Recovered

Casualties

[7] 4th Company Marines Severely Injured, Non-Combat Effective
[11] 1st Company Marines Severely Injured, Non-Combat Effective
[7] 5th Company Marines Severely Injured, Non-Combat Effective
Captain Hadrian Priscus Severely Injured, Non-Combat Effective

Promotions

[5] 4th Company Marines Deemed Veterans
[10] 5th Company Marines Deemed Veterans
3 Lexicani Deemed Codicier-worthy In Control And Strength

Land Vehicle Damages

[1] Predator Badly Damaged! Requires 50BP To Repair.

Fleet Losses

x2 Gladius Frigates (4th Company)
x2 Thunderhawk Gunships (Great Father's Fist)
x2 Thunderhawk Gunships (Omnis Arcanum)

Relations

Battlefleet Korianis [Imperial Navy] Is Now Suspect[+]
Korianis Sector Command [Imperial Guard] Is Now Suspect[+]
Order of the Lost Rosetta [Order Minoris - Descendant of Order of the Bloody Rose] Is Now Suspect [+]

Overall

Tyranid-tainted Slaughra Civilization Destroyed
Chaos-tainted Slaughra Civilization Destroyed
Slaughra Race Extermination Complete
Guard Losses Above Administratum Estimates, Deemed Acceptable After Analysis Of Enemy Post-Campaign.
Lost Rosetta Loses Above Ecclesiarchy Estimates, Convent Sanctorum Messaged For Replenishment.
Imperial Navy Fleet Losses Above Administratum Estimates. Undergoing Replacement, Repairs.
Victory Achieved

Other Matters

Librarium
Justinius Creation Attempt: 90
Relic Force Staff Created

Talonstaff of Jonah- Forged in the same vein as the daemonhammer Godsplitter, this Force Staff possesses a fragment of an Ulthwé Avatar of Khaine's Wailing Doom weapon implanted in it, as well as fragments of the Force Staff used by Jonah Orion. It crackles with a deadly energy that is anathema to warpspawn, and seems to carry with it the same unrelenting will of Jonah himself at times. (+1 Toughness, +Miscast Chance Reduction, +Anti-Daemon Effects) [Special Characteristics: Master Crafted, Shard of Ulthwé Avatar Wailing Doom Weapon Implanted In Force Staff]

Forges

Recovered Ultrafortress Predator Hulls Reconsecration And Repair 57/73/51/85/64 [All Successes, 5 Predators Added To Chapter Ranks. One predator possessed Twin-Linked Lascannons]

25x Scout Armor Constructed

7 Psychic Hoods Constructed

3 Crozius Arcanum Constructed

Relic Armor Construction For Cyrus Octavius [30] Failure. Regular Scout Armor Constructed.

The Howling Hatred [7+5=12/500]

Training

[Training With Apollo – Weapon Skill From 7 to 8: 704+90+Apollo(29)=823/800] Maximum With Apollo Training Possible Achieved! Further improvement will now only come from within, not without.
[Chapter Training – Weapon Skill 4 To 5: 396+59+Apollo(29)=484/500]
[Chapter Training – Strength 4 To 5: 96+30+Hannibal(25)=151/500]
[Chapter Training – Ballistic Skill 5 to 6: 314+40+Hadrian(25)=397/600]

Recruitment
To be posted along with other things at beginning of Turn 23.

As decided by exacting conversation, the gene-seed implanted under Plan: You Are Not Welcome Here, Alien Scum at the beginning of Turn 22, will be harvested at the beginning of Turn 23, for usage within various purposes. This is the method for going forward. Gene-Seed implanted during Turn A is harvested at the beginning of Turn B, and that's just it. If I contradict this going forward, inform me.

Turn 23: Ashen Flight (Part One)

Spoiler: Start Of Turn Matters

Gene-Seed Harvest
116 Implanted Into Test-Slaves
232 Successfully Harvested From Test-Slaves

Recruitment (Advances During Last Turn To Start Of This Turn) [Scout Advances Already Collated Last Turn Post]
Planets Chosen: Meridian+Junius
Aspirants Gained: 145
Psyker Aspirants Gained: 5
Aspirant Advances: 145-> 110 Neophytes [1st Stage]/ 5 -> 5 Psyker Neophytes [1st Stage]
Neophyte Advances: 110 Neophytes [1st Stage] -> 90 Neophytes [2nd Stage] / 5 Psyker Neophytes [1st Stage] -> 3 Psyker Neophytes [2nd Stage]
Specialist Leaning Neophytes Recognized: 2 Apothecary Neophytes / 3 Techmarine Neophytes / 1 Chaplain Neophytes -> 6 Specialist Neophytes
2nd Stage Neophytes Require Immediate Gene-Seed Implantation

Healing Matters
With major combat concluded, the Apothecarium could turn its attention to returning various marines to combat-ready viability.

Fleet Matters
Reconsecration and Rebuild Complete!
Blood Ravens Gain Unnamed Strike Cruiser! [Possesses Powerful Prow Lance Turret, Additional Weapon Arrays, Eager Machine Spirit, Reduced Planetary Assault Capacity] (50BP/Turn)

Ashen Flight
+050.M42+ To +055.M42+
+To The End, Always+

"The techpriests seemed rather unhappy, Martellus."

In fact, they seemed outright upset, but it was considerably difficult to say for certain. None of the adherents of the Machine Cult were those who had faces anymore, so you were stuck analyzing emotionless vocoder-filtered rasps as you had exchanged mutual friendly greetings. For your part, you had no reason to find the strike cruiser unacceptable. They had done their work well, restoring it to full functionality at a remarkable pace. The Machine Spirit of the vessel seemed almost too eager to get back out into the void, or so you had heard them mutter to themselves. Perhaps it was yet affected by the taint of the greenskins...but no, the shipyards of Zerann would not have delivered it back to you if they had not thoroughly cleansed it. No, the Machine Spirit is simply eager to prove itself, and to bring the fight to the foes of the Imperium, surely. As for Martellus himself, he and his own techmarines deemed that the vessel was capable, perhaps even more so, though unfortunately the desecration of the greenskins was such that neither he nor the priests of Zerann could discern its original identity. All that can be known is that some chapter, somewhere, lost this vessel. Which in its own way is something that must be avenged upon the foes of humanity.

"Indeed, Chapter Master. They discovered that, while most of the greenskin 'modifications'," Martellus uses the word as he would 'excrement', "Could be removed, the lance weapon could not without necessitating total disassembly of the vessel - likely irrevocably. While this Strike Cruiser is no longer capable of the same bombardment procedures as other strike cruisers, it nonetheless possesses a powerful weapon for void-combat."

That is indeed somewhat concerning. The techpriests likely found their inability to rectify this change to their holy design frustrating. Worse, the Imperial Navy's concerns of space marine chapters with frigates capable of lance fire worth disputing in their own way. On the other hand, this is a strike cruiser, and you certainly require such a ship. On the mechadendrite, it is a strike cruiser that has been warped by greenskin madness into a ship possessing multiple more weapon arrays, laser cannons, and torpedo launchers. It can still carry a full company, of course, that function was one of the main priorities, but it is most certainly not within the usual bounds of such vessels. It's tactical value, however, should you become involved with more void combat of any kind, is undeniable. A conundrum. One that you will deal with later. For now, the Chapter is largely focused on repairing their wargear and healing up after the many casualties taken in the fight. It was not nearly as bad as it could have been, if your forces had not been amongst the Guard and Lost Rosetta they would have been considerably higher, but you still took many. One of those is Hadrian himself, though your brother-captain is already awake and cognizant. He would likely speak towards keeping the ship as it is, which would not be surprising considering his...nature.

"It functions correctly, though, correct?"

"It does, yes. A welcome addition to the Chapter Fleet. Luckily, the meks aboard did not realize what the forges were. They used it as a...storage room."

He says luckily, but you can feel the fury at the desecration in his voice for a molten moment before it passes.

Then the two of you are silent, simply taking in the sight of the strike cruiser which hangs just outside the Omnis Arcanum. From within the launch bay, it is a stark sight, but as Spiraling Fury drifts past, the differences between the two are obvious. But of course, you would not bring Martellus so far away from his forges just for a simple viewing of the ship that has just been delivered. Especially after the rest of the Chapter Leadership including yourself already saw the thing when it first arrived. Another matter, one of dire importance, has come up as well.

"But you have also received communication on the gene-seed tithe."

"Yes."

Martellus swivels his head to look at you, nodding slightly as he does so.

"They are coming, soon. Possible within the next five years, possibly within ten, warp currents depending."

Would that you could do the reverse, gain back some of the gene-seed you have spent such time dedicating over the years, but you dare not make that request in the here and now. Not with relations being what they are at the moment. Besides which, you gained a considerable amount this year through the test-slaves. Just another matter that must be taken care of. Yet all around you, the galaxy continues to spin. The hunt for Governor Vandis continues through the Inquisitor's agents, farther reaching than yours ever have been, more likely than not. You have received no calls specifically for your Chapter to attend any battle or another, now that Polonius has been reclaimed. But that is not to say that you are not unneeded. Derosa has requested that the brothers seconded to her remains for another year, citing concerns about the nobility of her planet once more as the reason. There are rumors of greenskin pirates and eldar corsairs somewhere in the sector, assaulting outposts and supply routes. There yet remain greenskins within Korianis as well. Potentially, you could even return to the older ways of the Blood Ravens, and send out your fleets into the wider galaxy, to aid where they will. Finally, the missives continue to come from the Deathwatch, ever-asking for more space marines to aid them in their fight.

Lead Your Chapter (All Technically Available):
[] Further Black Crusade Contributions – Send forces to aid in the Black Crusade, even though Aramus’s presence apparently counts enough for some. (Write-In)
[] Train 1st Company Battle Brothers In Terminator Armor Usage (Write-In Amount) [Note: Those selected will be unusable for any other purpose during the turn this option is selected i.e. 5 years.]
[] Assign 14 New Battle Brothers To Companies (Write-In Battle Brother Allotment)
[] Assign Veterans To 1st Company If Desired (Write-In, If Desired, Not Required)
[] Assign x8 Thunderhawks (x8 Gunships) Within Chapter Fleet (Write-In)
[] Name And Assign Unnamed Strike Cruiser To A Fleet (Write-In)
[] Derosa's Request - While originally, Talon Squad was meant to only spend five years working with Governor Derosa, she has requested that this be extended another five, as apparently matters on Meridian yet merit the presence of a squad of Blood Ravens. By her reckoning, at least. Talon Squad would remain on Meridian as a result instead of returning to the Chapter.
[] Korianis Hunting - Greenskins: Greenskin raiders have been sighted across the entire Sector, and their Anchorage point is unknown. The Blood Ravens could work towards hunting them down. While this would not be the same as defending the worlds they raid, the routes they assault, but it would end them as a threat sooner, would it not? They have been noted to rely not on a few powerful ships, but frustrating mobs of smaller vessels, which swarm and board the vessels and outposts they currently raid. Their numbers are enough such that much of the sector is under threat, especially with many forces sent to Polonius for its settling. (Write-In Forces Contributed)
[] Korianis Defending - Greenskins: Greenskin raiders have been sighted across the entire Sector, and their Anchorage point is unknown. While the Blood Ravens have no homeworld, it cannot be denied that this Sector is home to much of value to the Chapter, their recruiting worlds for instance. The Sector must be defended. Send out forces to patrol and work towards the defense of those under attack. The greenskins have been noted to rely not on a few powerful ships, but frustrating mobs of smaller vessels, which swarm and board the vessels and outposts they currently raid. Their numbers are enough such that much of the sector is under threat, especially with many forces sent to Polonius for its settling. (Write-In Forces Contributed)
[] Korianis Hunting - Eldar: Eldar corsairs have been sighted in the Krasus and Aralakh Subsectors. Why are they here? Amusement? Plunder? Or some other secretive plot hatched by a farseer of some sort? Does it matter? They must be hunted down, and soon, for they are led by a Void Stalker battleship. A powerful vessel, those isolated groups it attacks have little defense against it or its smaller escort fleet of two Shadow cruisers and four Hemlock destroyers. They are brazen, these Eldar, which is the only reason their fleet has been recorded as well as they have. They must be hunted down and brought to justice...but extreme caution must be had, for surely they have a greater plan at hand than simple raids, especially with a good amount of the Imperial Navy in Polonius watching over settlement and fortification. (Write-In Forces Contributed)
[] Korianis Defending - Eldar: Eldar corsairs have been sighted in the Krasus and Aralakh Subsectors. Why are they here? Amusement? Plunder? Or some other secretive plot hatched by a farseer of some sort? Does it matter? They must be hunted down, and soon, for they are led by a Void Stalker battleship. A powerful vessel, those isolated groups it attacks have little defense against it or its smaller escort fleet of two Shadow cruisers and four Hemlock destroyers. They are brazen, these Eldar, which is the only reason their fleet has been recorded as well as they have. At the least, they have only been sighted in two subsectors, meaning less difficulty in trying to defend against them. On the other hand, they are powerful void combatants indeed. (Write-In Forces Contributed)
[] Deathwatch Desperation - Rise of the Alien: The Deathwatch is being strained to the breaking point, by their own secretive messages to all Chapters in the galaxy who can hear them. Watch Fortresses and Stations are under assault, alien civilizations are rising in ever higher number, deadly threats are growing in severity and breadth. Normally only the best of the best marines would be given over to the Deathwatch, but out of sheer desperation the Ordos Xenos is loosening their standards in an uncharacteristic display of acceptance. That is, apparently, how bad the problem has gotten across every single Segmentum. Ordo Xenos Inquisitors are calling in favors, the Deathwatch is calling upon nearly every Chapter possible to send someone, anyone, as many space marines as possible. With such threats as the Black Crusade, the War for Armageddon, the Hive Fleets, all of the Deathwatch cannot hope to fight back against the apparent thousands of full-scale alien invasions of the Imperium going on across the galaxy without help. How could you possibly stand by and do nothing, in the face of this? (Write-In Additional Forces Sent To The Deathwatch)
[] Terminator Exchange: Theodosia is willing to produce some Terminator Armor for you, having gotten those forges and designs online. But she will, one, require a full squad of marines with at least one psyker amongst them to safeguard the area - not that she doesn't trust the defenses and holy blessings of the Omnissiah, she just wants to ensure protection for your own equipment. And the hexagramic wards of the Blood Ravens should be especially valuable. Second, for each set of five terminator suits you desire built, she will require aid in other things, allowing her to free up production systems for what you desire. [1 Squad+Librarian Required To Help Oversee Production Whenever Selected. 1 Squad Required For Minor Favor Works In Exchange Per 5 Suits]
[] Something Else (Write-In)

Training With Apollo
Training Automatic Now As Only Skill That Can Be Trained Is Ballistic Skill

Train Your Chapter
The Blood Ravens have lost so many, both fresh blood and veteran. It may aid in the rebuilding of the Chapter for you to work upon them and try to impart the skill and experience that the Blood Ravens of the past once possessed. [Toughness And Agility Characteristic Has Reached Its Cap And Can No Longer Be Selected]

[] Select Main Characteristic (1d100+Trainer)
- [] Specify Teacher

[] Select Two Secondary Characteristics (1d50+Trainer Each)
- [] Specify Teacher(s)

Things To Consider – Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos
- Remember that Chapter Master Angelos, Chief Librarian Probalis, and Apollo are mighty champions and can be deployed on operations. They need not remain in their ships doing nothing. To have them participate in an operation, it must be specified that they do so.
- It would be unwise to split our fleets between hunting and guarding against both the greenskins and Eldar. Better to focus our forces on one of the xenos or the other, or one of the tasks, such as focusing entirely on defense, or entirely on hunting. Otherwise our fleets might find themselves torn asunder piecemeal.
- The Deathwatch seem desperate indeed, willing to take scouts, veterans, or even tomb-brothers, should they be sent to them.

Nero Gracchus – Chief Apothecary (Choose 2):
[] Implant Test-Slaves with Gene-Seed to harvest At Start Of Next Turn. Write-In the amount of Gene-Seed you wish to use. [Possess 259 Total Gene-Seed]
[] Implant Neophytes [2nd Stage] (90 Total)/ Psyker Neophyte [2nd Stage] (3 Total) with Gene-Seed.
[] Write-In

Things To Consider – Nero Gracchus
- The Apothecarium is growing well, the trainees and graduates are a good boon to my efforts. I may even be able to focus all of my efforts on studying our gene-seed soon.
- The Arcanum may have the largest of our Apothecarium, but it is the Potentia that possesses the most advanced, as befitting its name. This should aid in the works of the Apothecarium for its purposes in the future.

Justinius Probalis - Chief Librarian (Choose One):
[] Request to recruit and train potential psyker aspirants from the Adeptus Astra Telepathica. High likelihood of successful training and implantation for recruits made in this manner.
[] The Raven's Talons: Justinius believes that it should be possible to craft weapons that would be highly effective against daemons and the malefic powers of the Warp itself, as Godsplitter is. With five usable shards taken from Wailing Doom of the Unknown Craftworld's Avatar of Khaine from Typhon Primaris, he believes he could make similar weapons. Whether another daemonhammer, a blade, axe, maul, or spear, he thinks it possible. [100 BP Per Raven Talon, Powerful Anti-Daemon Power Weapons, x4 Shards Remaining For Usage In A Weapon. Success is not guaranteed for creation.]
[] The Raven Aegis: The powers of the Warp and the daemons of Chaos are things that you know for a fact the Blood Ravens will face in the future. Creating talismans which would protect against such things would be incredibly valuable indeed. Justinius' successful efforts at using the materials of the fallen Avatars of Khaine from Craftworld Ulthwé has made him believe it possible to create such things. [50 BP Per Raven Aegis, Powerful Anti-Daemon/Warp Protection Talisman. x8 Shards Remaining For Usage In A Talisman. Success is not guaranteed for creation.]
[] Anti-Anti-Psyker Study: The Split Heart Kabal made strange xeno advances in the baffling, diffusing, and blocking of psyker powers and abilities. By making a study of such things, the Librarius of the Blood Ravens would be able to train its forces against such things, improving their ability to defeat such things in the future while providing an additional aid of likely effectiveness against the vile Eldar specifically. [Note: This will mean that all non-Company Epistolary Librarians and Justinius Probalis are unusable for other tasks for 2 turns i.e. 10 years.]

Things To Consider - Justinius Probalis
- The latest combat against the daemons of the Judgement of Carrion has made me think on the daemonhammer that the Chapter Master wields. We could, perhaps, use more of such weapons. It was created using a shard of the weapon of an Avatar. Perhaps we could make some ourselves, if we studied it enough?
- The Chapter's greatest advantage was its Librarians. I know that they were used for...ill purpose in the past by Kyras, but I will not allow such a political character to be assigned to them ever again. We were meant for more than that. For the betterment of the Chapter, for its coming battles, and the maintenance of the Sanctorium Arcanum, we must rebuild our ranks, and soon.

Martellus Ravias – Master of the Forge (Choose 1):
[] Build Order (675 BP Available)
[] Improve the Forges Of
-[] The Omnia Arcanum [0/1000] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
-[] The Litany Of Fury [0/750] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
[] Construct Forge Facilities On Company Ships (Current/Former)
- [] The Ravenous Spirit [0/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
- [] The Spiraling Fury [0/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
- [] The Burning Seeker [0/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
- [] The Rage of Erudition [0/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
- [] The The Great Father's Fist [0/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
- [] The Howling Hatred [12/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
- [] The ??????? [0/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
[] Study The Hrud Fusils For ???? (Warning: May end up losing some Fusils as a result of the study) [0/????]

Things To Consider – Master of the Forge Ravias
- We should probably build more Tarantula turrets.
- The Forges could use improvement, I think. It is not blasphemy against the Omnissiah to improve what facilities we have, increase their capacity and sophistication.
- We have proven, now, our techmarine cadre to have the ability to properly construct the forges on our ships. We should continue this practice, for the Chapter is dangerously under-equipped compared to the strength it once possessed before the Purge.
- We should work to ensure that our ships possess Thunderhawks or some form of strike craft at the least in abundance for defensive and offensive purposes in void and planetary-combat. Especially if we plan on our ships engaging in such in the near future!
- Have we considered building more Tarantula turrets? Deploying them to aid our forces in upcoming fighting would be most valuable indeed, all things considered.
- Thank goodness the Potentia has returned to service. Amongst the rest of the ships within the Chapter Fleet, it possesses the most advanced forge facilities, as befitting its name. This will surely aid me in construction of more advanced technologies in the future, as well as their study!
- Our Chapter will remain low in number for quite some time yet. I believe that one of the best ways to alleviate such issues is the noble Tarantula turret.
- Hrud Fusils are prizes indeed. It is said they are an extremely advanced example of symbiosis between melta and plasma weaponry. I could attempt to study them, and discover if they may inspire further secrets of the Omnissiah in their nature - though surely not as if I would be committing to xeno tech-heresy. Obviously.

Cyrus Octavius – Master of Recruits (Choose 1):
[] Enact Blood Trials Upon The Four Of Your Viable Recruiting Worlds (Calderis/Trontiux III/Meridian/Junius) And Train Those Who Survive
[] Enact Blood Trails Upon The Following Of Your Recruiting Worlds (Write-In) [Note: If desired, as to leave one or more planets to grow their population, recover, out of lack of Gene-Seed for the potential crop, etc.]
[] Something Else (Write-In)

Things To Consider – Master of Recruits
- The only thing that can truly help the 10th Company is time, dedicated time, to train your initiates, neophytes, and scouts.
- With the arrival of many experienced 1st Company Sergeants, more Blood Trials can be enacted without Cyrus' direct observation.
- The Deathwatch would not ask so desperately if it were not needed. We could, conceivably, send scout marines to them. A number of these scouts would die, but they would die doing the Emperor's work. Those that survive would return with a vast amount of experience as well.

Turn 23: Ashen Flight (Part Two)

Spoiler: Plan: Those Who Hunt Eldar

[X] Plan: Those Who Hunt Eldar
-[X] Lead Your Chapter
--[X] Assign 14 New Battle Brothers To Companies
---[X] 7 to 4th Company
---[X] 7 to 5th Company
--[X] Test and attempt to audition Fourth Company Champion from among the 1st Company Veteran Sergeants seconded to it.
--[X] Promote 5 Veteran 4th Company Marines to Sergeants. If no 1st Company Veteran Sergeant was selected as Company Champion, then return one of the 1st Company Sergeants back to the 1st Company.
--[X] Promote 10 Veteran 5th Company Marines to Sergeants.
---[X] Return 6 1st Company Veteran Sergeants from 5th Company to 1st Company
--[X] Name And Assign Unnamed Strike Cruiser
---[X] Legacy of Polonius
---[X] Assign to 4th Company Fleet
--[X] Assign x8 Thunderhawks (x8 Gunships) Within Chapter Fleet
---[X] x4 to new 4th Company Strike Cruiser
---[X] x1 to 1st Company Battle Barge Omnis Arcanum
---[X] x1 to 4st Company Battle Barge Scientia Est Potentia
---[X] x2 to 5th Company Battle Barge Litany of Fury
--[X] Use 1 Minor Favor to gain 8 Thunderhawks (8 gunships) from Governor Derosa
--[X] Derosa's Request - Talon-Squad
--[X] Korianis Hunting - Eldar - Chapter Leadership, 1st Company + 1st Company Fleet, 4th Company + 4th Company Fleet, 10th Company + 10th Company Fleet and unassigned specialists, heavy support from the Librarium to locate the Eldar
--[X] Korianis Defending - Eldar - 5th Company + 5th Company Fleet
--[X] Inquire with Forge World Zerann about work for Turn 24 (055-060.M42) for the accumulation of favors for usage requisitioning Thunderhawks, Frigates, and/or Destroyers
-[X] Training
--[X] Chapter Main: Ballistic Skill with Hadrian
--[X] Chapter Secondary: Weapon Skill with Apollo Diomedes
--[X] Chapter Secondary: Strength with Hannibal Palrun
-[X] Apothecary
--[X] Implant Neophytes [2nd Stage] (90 Total)/ Psyker Neophyte [2nd Stage] (3 Total) with Gene-Seed. - 93 Total
--[X] Implant Test-Slaves with Gene-Seed to harvest in 5 years. - 114 Gene-Seed
--[X] Reserve 52 Gene-Seed (20%) for Tithe
-[X] Chief Librarian
--[X] 2x The Raven's Aegis [100 BP]
-[X] Forge [575 BP Total]
--[X] Scout Armor x63 [504 BP]
--[X] Repairs
---[X] Damaged Predator from Z04Y [50 BP]
--[X] Relic Construction
---[X] Scout Armor for Cyrus Octavius [20 BP]
--[X] Construct Forge Facilities On The Howling Hatred [1 BP]
-[X] Master of Recruits
--[X] Enact Blood Trials Upon Two Of Your Viable Recruiting Worlds (Calderis/Trontiux III) And Train Those Who Survive

Note, much of this will be collected/performed/tallied at end of Turn. Focus is on the Hunt, for now.

Ashen Flight
+050.M42+ To +055.M42+
+To The End, Always+

The hololith flickered, but maintained a substantially clear image of both Phokas and Theodosia. Or rather, a flat square symbol signifying the latter, as to try and fit her dreadnought-sized chassis into the image would have strained it beyond functionality.

“Are you aware of the Argante Station incident, Chapter Master?”

“No,” Gabriel shook his head, “But I assume I am about to be informed of it.”

“During the Gothic War, one of the eldar ship-type known as ‘Shadow-class was captured remarkably intact. It was undergoing study at Argante Station by the Adeptus Mechanicus and Imperium, together, when a fleet of eldar emerged and destroyed not just the captured vessel but the station and all of its defenders,” Phokas recited flatly, yet even then one could hear the emotion that was muted by his mechanical voice.

“A desperate maneuver by their cowardly race,” Thedosia’s square booms, “For they knew that should we unlock the secrets of their ships, we would destroy their misbegotten race all the sooner!”

Gabriel glanced at the angrily vibrating square that represented the Magos Prime of Aerus, before looking back towards the Fabricator of Zerann.

“And now that we are hunting the Eldar, you wish us to try to capture their vessels for study?”

“THE BETTER TO DESTROY THEM!” Theodosia booms.

Phokas may have replaced his face with a metallic plate, throat and mouth wholly replaced, a trio of mechanical sensors and cameras instead of eyes, but the strange noise that comes from him now is nothing less than a sigh. Gabriel raised an eyebrow at him, but said nothing more.

“Yes. In exchange, we would be more than willing to discuss terms of replacing your fleet’s losses.”

The Chapter Master rubbed at his chin for a moment before shaking his head.

“If we can, we will, but I cannot promise anything.”

Phokas bowed deeply, hands folded behind his back.

“I understand, of course. They are fragile ships after all, if deadly. I would not demand that the Blood Ravens needlessly sacrifice their lives for filthy alien technologies.”

==============================================

“I would have thought you would protest this deployment,” Cyrus murmured as they headed out to their separate ships.

The thunderhawks continued to shudder and lift off, rapidly shifting what marines the Blood Ravens possessed to their ships after the Chapter Master’s speech upon the decks of the Omnis Arcanum. The two captains, not quite-friends, but brothers still, walked towards their own separate transports. Cyrus’ cybernetic eye carefully tracked the marshalling of the various neophytes and scouts under his command, while the other looked at Tarkus. Who, for his part, remained silent instead of immediately responding. The larger, yet younger, yet more weathered captain eventually shook his head as his armor thumped against the metal floor.

“I would prefer to go with you on the hunt, but I know the value of dedicating the 5th Company to defending the worlds of the Imperium,” Tarkus glowered, “They may rest assured that the eldar will not find such easy targets any longer. And consider this, Cyrus,” his face twisted into a malicious grin, “If they come to us, I do not have to waste fuel and supplies on a chase.”

Cyrus snorted, but the time had come. Both looked at one another, nodding but once, and then they separated towards their thunderhawks and the fleet of each company. Tarkus raised his bolter high, and that was enough to gain the attention of every marine that served under him. They turned, as one, some standing from the weapon crates they had sat upon, to hear his words. Elsewhere, the long train of the 10th Company paused, only some of them noticing as their Captain slipped in amongst them, those that failed noted down for further training.

“Brothers, we go! We go to become shields against the void, against those that would prey on humanity! But we are the Emperor’s Angels of Death, and it is they who are the prey, now!”

Fists slammed to ceramite, while the 10th Company watched on with awe at what they could become marshaled before them. Cyrus let them have it, the better to motivate them later on when they battled against the alien threat – should they find them at all. Others, he noted with approval, continued to move on regardless. Those of his scouts who had more experience, more knowledge, and were less prone to being struck with awe continued to march into the thunderhawks. Good. Awe was a pointless emotion at best, an active detriment on operations at worst.

“Let None Find Us Wanting!”

=========================================

[Piercing The Veil – Psyker Attempts:37 vs. 64]
[Piercing The Veil – Technological Attempts: 42 vs. 61]
[Defending The Sector – 5th Company: 56 vs. 84]

And so the Blood Ravens set out. They searched the void, breaching the perimeters of solar systems before moving on, the Librarius honed to a fine point by their Chief Libarian. Justinius Probalis saw little of this, consumed as he was with the scrying rituals that he undertook. Within the depths of the Omnis Arcanum, the currents of the warp twisted and aligned before him, before scattering all over again. Lexicanum and Codiciers muttered, joining the strength of their minds and souls, transforming themselves from targets for daemons and instead became arcing beacons, from ship to ship. They blazed in the warp, piercing the veil put up before them. And there was a veil, beyond the skein of daemons looking to catch the unwary, through the natural wall that as space and time and further yet. There was a veil, hanging like a spider’s web yet barbed with infused spikes of codified emotion, spite turned outward and given form yet formless.

It was magnificent. The views of astropaths, the distant golden light of Terra, all of this passed over it without pausing, without the eddies and blockages, the fogging of the sight of those who saw beyond sight. A fine working indeed, the madmen, the sanctioned psykers, and more alike failed to spy its existence simply because it existed alongside rather than in front or behind. None of the Lexicanum could possibly find it, but they added their comparatively meager strength to those above them. Single droplets of blood fell from Justinius’ eyes, multicolored tears that were vaporized before they had even fallen a foot from his face. And yet, despite his strength, despite his power, he could not grasp the veil which hung over his sight, the veil that only could truly be known for what it guarded. This angered him.

Severely.

But in the end, it would not come from the works of the Librarius. Nor would it be the stringent auspex scans of their ships, the technological power of humanity faltering despite Martellus and his students’ best attempts. And attempts there were, attempts to infuriate a techpriest had there been any present. They tweaked and tested, adjusted and worked, coaxing their machines as best they could. But the Machine Spirits, whether cooperating or not, could not seem to produce any better results. Only ghosts found them, ghosts which were silent or laughed at their foolishness, ghosts that had to be ignored. The ships thundered across the Sector, back and forth, providing their own presence in systems for but days or weeks before disappearing again. None could stop this, of course, no matter how discomforted they were by the arrival of the Blood Ravens, while others took some comfort in that at least one of the fleets remained slower moving, preparing for a battle that for all they knew might not even come.

Instead, it would be the eldar who struck first, with speed and alien sorcery.

Over the world Alanara, which had once been held by the eldar known as Exodites, they came. Half of the 5th Company Fleet had begun departure procedures, the apertures into the warp opening, when the eldar ships revealed themselves. First and most damaged was the Nova Frigate, its weaponry disabled by precision pulsar lance fire, while the Shadow-class cruisers flanked the strike cruisers of the 5th Company. With the rest of the Chapter fleets dispersed and searching the rest of the sector, the chapter’s gambit of dividing their strength was thoroughly taken advantage of. There were no grand proclamations spoken across the vox, only silent fury from the eldar who fired without pause upon the ships of the Blood Ravens. Shields flickered and failed in certain sectors, allowing long scores to be dragged into the metal of all but the Litany of Fury itself. And while the messages were sent out, desperately, the rest of the Chapter were in Subsector Krasus at the moment, not Aralakh. And so the battle was fought, then and there.

=============================================

5th Company Fleet vs. Eldar Corsair Fleet
88 vs. 11

“Turn and charge them,” Tarkus boomed even as he headed for the teleportarium. “Adjust flanks to present the strongest shielding and armor against the destroyers! Status on the Noble Spear?!”

The vox was flooded utterly with communications, from ship to ship and from thunderhawk to thunderhawk. Filtered communications from dozens of mouths passed across his mind, but he needed only focus on the one, the one meant for him. That, and the vicious joy he felt but did not show as The Great Father's Fist reported that some of their thunderhawks had managed to slam into one of the enemy Hemlock Destroyers, while its breaching pods had penetrated into a second. The fight was not nearly over, but the enemy’s opening strike had not ensured their destruction just yet.

“Noble Spear’s weaponry is heavily damaged, Captain, their lance array is completely inoperable! Luckily the Eldar seem entirely focused on the Battle Barge. No sign of the Void Stalker battleship – wait, I think it’s appearing!”

Of course, only now, once the Blood Ravens had adjusted their ships to present against the foe, had the Eldar played their trump card.

“It’s past us, it’s attacking the planet, transports are heading for the surface!”

Tarkus grit his teeth, torn for a moment between one course and the next, before he sighed and made his decision. He stepped forward into the teleportarium, causing the servitor’s head to twist about and look towards him. Behind him came many more of his chapter, though now they knew they would be heading to a different target than intended.

“Destination?”

“The surface,” Tarkus boomed, sealing his helmet into his armor, the rest of his brothers doing the same. “Same place the xeno are heading.”

For a long, painful few seconds the servitor processed the request before jerkily turning back to the console, five arms and ten-fingered hands dancing across the surface. The Litany of Fury shuddered as the Shadows outside continued to fire on it, the venerable battle barge pushing itself into shielding position over the more vulnerable ships of the 5th Company, all the while the strike cruisers fought on against their own foes.

“Location locked: PDF Base. Designation: Nonessential. Processing, teleport protocol 783, beginning,” it droned out, flecks of dried blood beneath its eyes marked by sanguine anew as it struggled to calculate. “Starting, piercing the skein, mark.”

Tarkus grit his teeth, and felt his brothers around him do the same. Not all of them might emerge, but he could do nothing more than trust in the Machine Spirits, and have faith that the Litany of Fury would perform as well as it possibly could.

“Three.”

Cheering erupted on the vox as a boarding party disabled another Hemlock Destroyer, while another spoke in panic of xeno boarders on the Rage of Erudition. From here, he could hear the howls of Screaming Banshees, and let the fury in, the pure hatred for the alien fill him.

“Two.”

Tarkus breathed in deeply, and muttered beneath his breath.

“Let none find us wanting.”

“One.”

The universe began to fizzle and pop around them, accompanied by a chorus of screams and laughter.

“Mark.”

Time became space, and space became time. They hurtled as one, a litany of faith and fury on their lips, upwards through the immaterium yet downwards through realspace, flesh and ceramite bubbling but not.

5th Company Fleet vs. Eldar Corsair Fleet
94 vs. 42
Teleporting Deep Strike
65 – No Losses, Forces Somewhat Scattered
5th Company Land Forces vs. Eldar Raiders
33 vs. 35

As in orbit, upon the earth below, explosions reigned for a few brief moments. Tarkus simultaneously was exposed to the raw stuff of the Warp, and it he, but then the moment passed and the eldar before him were revealed. Deathdealer snarled in his hands as he fired, the rest of his brothers present unleashing their weapons on the disembarking eldar. Further in the back, a pair of transports sped down the mountain paths, firing all the while at the already horribly scattered PDF. A single blast of orbital bombardment, and the PDF base was in shambles. His mind processed all of this, and more. A mountainous region, the base split open down the middle, the eldar landing amidst yet sending more troops further on.

“Bring them all down brothers, but stay in cover!”

One marine, newly promoted, did not heed his warning fast enough, and he was forced to drag them down. It was not fast enough to prevent the first salvo of ranger rifles slamming through his shoulders and chest, but not enough to be fatal. As the marine gurgled indignantly, his second heart pumping in overdrive now that his main heart had been shot out of his chest, Tarkus sighed. Priming a grenade, he leapt over the fallen pile of permacrete and accepted the salvos which struck against him, and continued forward, tossing the grenade beneath the belly of a falcon transport. On the other side, a quartet of eldar guardians found their legs removed by the explosion of shrapnel.

High above, yet another Hemlock was boarded, its small crew slaughtered by but five marines, while the strike cruisers combined their fire on one of the Shadows. The Void Stalker turned, its tremendous firepower almost blinding in the void, but it could not yet pierce the shield and hull of the Litany of Fury, her entire bulk a bulwark, managing to maneuver and cut off the greatest of the enemy vessels from the rest of its brethren.

5th Company vs. Eldar Raiders
51 vs. 75
43 vs. 73

Tarkus bellowed his fury as he advanced, some of his brothers managing to do so with him, firing without pause all the while. Even as one marine’s head snapped back, twin rifle shots from the eldar rangers present slaying them instantly, he did not stop his charge. Finally, at the end, he upped his speed and leapt upon the hated alien, cracking one’s head open with the butt of his bolter, combat knife stabbing into the heart of another. The rangers, he knew, were fleeing before him, abandoning the guardians lest they be killed as well. Around him the PDF were practically a nonentity in the fight, their shots missing or hitting armor or shields, their meagre armors punctured with ease. It would be wholly up to the Blood Ravens to win this fight. More and more of the eldar were disappearing back towards the paths, fleeing before the crushing fist of the space marines.

In the void, the remainder of the Hemlocks fell silent, their guns ceasing to fire, their engines ceasing to flare. Thunderhawks raced back to carry their occupants onto a new fight, while one of the Shadows finally began to crack and fall apart. At the same time, the strike cruisers were forced once more to flee around the sides of their battle barge, shields broken and ships taking cursory damage to the hull. The enemy battleship was incredibly fast, however, and pursued them, flanking and changing its elevation to rise above and below. Such was its arsenal that it was more than comfortable firing upon all three ships at once, while its own defensive systems ensured that return fire was far less capable. The 5th Company’s own meagre escorts were destroyed as well, the Nova Frigate destroyed completely, the Hunter Destroyer’s structure cracked open like an egg.

5th Company vs. Eldar Raiders
25 vs. 69
82 vs. 31

Another brother fell, though the banshee that slew him was rent apart by chainsword. One Blood Raven beat an eldar dark reaper to death with the stumps of his own arms, relentless despite losing his hands and forearms to that same dark reaper’s merciless weaponry. Tarkus finally sighted the damn ranger pair, but even as he set his sights on them they flickered out of sight once more. The fight raged all around him, less and less eldar present than before, but the fight still refusing to improve. The transports had come back from wherever they had disappeared to, but instead of disappearing they fought on. Growling, he readied a krak grenade and made his move.

This time, the ambushing ships failed. Damion, while not skilled in the same strengths of his Chief Librarian, was still an Epistolary of the Blood Ravens. He had sensed the souls on approach, for too close were they now for the veil by which they had thus far concealed themselves from psyker sight. As such, when the trio of Aconites appeared, the Litany of Fury fired upon them with its bombardment cannon, the shells guided not by the auspex and sensors of the ship but by the Librarian’s direction. As such, one was simply blown apart as it dropped its holofield, a second was damaged enough that boarding parties could slam into its sides without issue, and the third simply turned about to try and flee before the bombardment cannon fired again and destroyed its solar sails and sublight engines, engulfing the tiny vessel’s rear in flames.

==================================================

The bridge of the Ascendant Star was in chaos. The Corsair Prince and his own guards dominated half, while the damned Farseer and her own followers dominated the other. The throne in the center had been cut in twain by their minor aborted duel, while those that were dedicated to keeping the ship actually in the fight struggled to perform their duties despite everything else. Lantyr snarled at the bitch, whose face remained completely concealed by her helm. A thin line of blood dripped from his cheek, while she held a hand against the weeping wound that his own blade had inflicted on her hip.

“We are leaving,” he insisted, “We have taken more casualties and losses here in one battle than in the entirety of my rule over the Rim Stalkers!”

Even though he couldn’t see her face, he could feel the sneer on the Biel-Tan bitch’s face.

“Not yet, the World Spirit’s remains are not yet fully through the webway gates,” the Farseer hissed. “Besides, did you not want a challenge? You have been complaining for years now about a real fight, rather than the merchants and outposts that I guided you to.”

Lantyr’s face purpled with fury, a vein visibly pulsing on his forehead.

“I have lost a third of my entire fleet, and only because you kept us from bringing our full strength to bear!”

“Scattering instead of presenting a single target for the Blood Ravens was the right course!”

Mestela gestured with her singing spear towards the viewing screens.

“Would you prefer that the whole of their fleet was right there, crushing us to pieces from all sides? Far be it for me to assume that the ‘great’,” she spat the word, “Prince Lantyr, the Void Ripper, would struggle so greatly!”

5th Company vs. Rim Stalkers
13 vs. 72
99 vs. 50

If it weren’t so infuriating, Lantyr would have relished in the stumbling of the Farseer, and that of her followers. So unused to proper combat, they couldn’t even handle minor collisions. But he could not enjoy it, because he knew exactly what it meant for his beloved ship to shudder as it had. The psychically reactive circuits throughout the ship were intimately connected to him, and as such even before the words were spoken he had felt the pain.

“Pulsar lance battery two offline!"

Then, before he could even respond to that, another of the crew spoke up.

"They’ve boarded the Tear of Blades! Captain Caerlath is dead!”

For the first time since beginning their partnership, he heard uncertainty in Mestela’s voice.

“What? But that’s impossible – they can’t have-,”

Snarling, he turned towards the pilots.

“Get. Us. OUT OF HERE! Tell the troops to abandon the rest of the damned markers, get as many of the soulstones they can, and get back into the ship!”

“No!”

He flipped backwards to dodge the thin whip of lighting sent his way, feet landing on the ceiling of the bridge before leaping forward. His blade slammed into the length of the single warlock that accompanied the Farseer, and even they were pushed back solidly. Rolling his head back to avoid the subsequent return strike that would have decapitated him, he stabbed the blade on the tip of his boot into the warlock’s stomach, twisting and ripping outwards to partially disembowel. The Farseer screeched at the sight, and in fear, as he advanced on her. Around him, his troops finally ceased their inaction, unleashing their own weaponry on the Farseer’s guards, and those of his retinue which had been foolish enough to fall for her schemes. She stumbled slightly, summoning her spear back, but it was not fast nor was she adroit enough to prevent the edge of his blade to rest heavily upon her neck.

“You do not command here, Farseer. We walk the Outcast Path. We are not lapdogs for the Craftworlds to order about! You have clearly forgotten that. We will return to the haven. Our deal is done.”

“But-,”

Lantyr leaned forward slightly, relishing in the blood that dripped off of her neck, glaring down at the shorter eldar.

“But nothing, Farseer. Plunder was had, you got some of your damned World Spirit remains. It is enough. I’ll not lose more of my forces for Biel-Tan, when they were the ones who cast me out!”

===========================================

Final Push
68 vs. 95
38 vs. 23

The webway gate shuddered, and then fell silent, whatever forces that had powered it up once again dissipating once more. Tarkus knew what it meant, and it burned at him to know of his failure. The cavern had been excavated by expedience, and eldar weaponry, and within it he saw around him the remains of the Exodite civilization which had once claimed this world. Faintly glowing obelisks, circles, and more, all of sparkling crystal. But very little of these remained either. Only the least of them were left, and considering the matter and various grooves and ‘absences’ in the cavern, much of what had lain here had been retrieved. No matter that they had slain many an eldar, they had not prevented them from achieving their greater objective, whatever it might result in.

“Destroy this gate. And the rest of this,” he waved at the fallen eldar bodies, the last who had failed to get into the gate, along with their various weapons and armors.

Tarkus stomped back out of the cave, gazed at the burning remains of the fallen PDF base, and opened the channel.

“Damion. Tell me you have better news than I.”

“That depends, Captain...,” the Librarian’s voice was cautious.

“I’m not in the mood for jokes, Epistolary.”

He felt, rather than heard, the faint shrugging of the psyker’s pauldrons.

“The rest of the Chapter is on the way, we did manage to capture a few of the eldar ships – don’t know how happy the Mechanicus is going to be, but the Void Stalker managed to escape, and both of our escort ships are gone.”

For a moment, he was seized by unrelenting fury at a single eldar managing to escape his grasp, their treachery allowed to continue for any longer. That yet more good human souls had been lost to them, whether astartes, serf, or otherwise. Then it was gone, beaten down by willpower and the promise to himself that while the battle was done, the chase was not.

“Also…,” Damion’s smile could be somehow heard over the vox, “The veil they were using to block our sight wavered. Whoever was maintaining it had a slip in concentration, if only for a moment. It is enough. I think, with the rest of the Librarius, that we can follow them.”

Tarkus didn’t smile, but his lips did do a sort of terrifying quirk that startled one of the newly promoted space marines as they walked past.

Results:
- x1 Nova Frigate, x1 Hunter Destroyer Lost
- 5 5th Company Blood Raven Marines Slain (x5 Gene-Seed Recovered)
- 13 5th Company Blood Raven Marines Significantly Injured, Cannot Be Used For Combat Operations This Turn
- 1 Badly Damaged Shadow-class Cruiser Captured
- 3 Somewhat-Undamaged Hemlock Destroyers Captured
- 1 Badly Damaged Hemlock Destroyer Captured
- 1 Shadow-class Cruiser Destroyed
- 3 Aconite-class Frigates Destroyed
- Battle Barge Litany of Fury has taken minor damage across hull. Lost x1 Thunderhawk Transporter, x2 Thunderhawk Gunships
- Strike Cruiser Rage of Erudition has taken significant damage to weapon systems, propulsion unharmed. Damage capabilities reduced, boarding abilities maintained. Lost x1 Thunderhawk Gunships.
- Strike Cruiser The Great Father's Fist has taken significant damage to weapon and shield systems, propulsion unharmed. Lost x2 Thunderhawk Gunships.
- Remainder of Chapter Fleets Assembling With 5th Company For Pursuit
- Warning: Reveal of Aconite-class Frigates means that Eldar Fleet likely exceeds previous estimations of size and compliment! Caution must be had!

Phase 2 (Choose One):
Note: This selection has been written in descending order of how much time it takes before pursuit begins, with the first starting immediately. Consider this when voting.

[] Leave Blood Raven Vessels To Guard Claimed Ships, Remainder Proceed In Pursuit With Librarius Aid (Write-In Ship(s) Left Behind)
[] Contact Mechanicus For Support, To Claim Vessels, Then Proceed In Pursuit With Librarius Aid
[] Contact Mechanicus For Support, Both To Claim Vessels And Supplement Fleet, Then Proceed As One In Pursuit With Librarius Aid
[] Contact Mechanicus And Imperial Navy For Support, To Claim Vessels, Supplement Fleet, Increase Firepower, Then Proceed As One In Pursuit.

Karak Eight Peaks: The Battle of Karag Nar, Part 4

Spoiler: Voting results [*] This wealth is the future of Karak Eight Peaks. Stay here with the Hoard. You want to rejoin the fighting. Clearing the greenskins out of Karag Nar in a timely fashion is crucial, as then everyone currently exposed in the Valley can pull back to defensive positions and at that point the battle is exposed greenskins against entrenched Dwarven siege engineering and that's the Dwarves' favourite kind of battle. But you're forced to admit to yourself that you're tired. Not just physically fatigued, though you're definitely that - or whatever you'd call it when your muscles have recently been filled with Waaagh energy and then deflated again. Not even just magically fatigued, having cast quite a few spells, some quite tricky, in a short amount of time. You're tired in your soul. Being used as a conduit first by Mork and then by Ranald, and for an amount of power you can't even begin to comprehend... you're fortunate to have not suffered worse, but what you are suffering is more than enough. You'll settle down here and wait for the Dwarves to reach you, and guarding this Hoard gives you a perfect justification in doing so. You consider the bed and quickly reject it, and are in fact tempted to set it on fire to rid the room of the smell of rotting leaves and fur. So instead you lean against a window and witness the rare spectacle unfolding below. The Colleges only knew the very basics of what an Anvil of Doom was capable of, and now you get to see it for yourself, as conducted by the oldest and most powerful of Runelords. Kragg the Grim did not research, rarely journeyed, and was very difficult to convince that anyone was worthy of the products of his art, so what has he been doing with his centuries of life? The answer, it seems, was crafting Runes for his Anvil of Doom. In the context of one of the Anvils, a Rune did not mean a carving upon an object, but an object in its own right - a piece of metal in the shape of a single Rune, but itself covered in dozens or even hundreds of smaller runes. Once fully crafted, it would begin to siphon magical energies from the air, and days or weeks or months later it would be ready. When properly positioned on an Anvil of Doom and struck by someone skilled in its use, the energies would be unleashed in the way dictated by its runes, the Anvil's runes, and the will of the wielder. For year after year, decade after decade, Kragg had shut himself in his workshop in Karaz-a-Karak and channeled his hatred of greenskins and Skaven and Elves and all other enemies of Dwarves, and all of his bitterness at the decline of the Karaz Ankor, into an arsenal for his Anvil, waiting for a reason sufficient to justify his presence. The lost hold of Karak Eight Peaks, once second only to Karaz-a-Karak in population and wealth and power, had finally given him that reason, and the Grobi in the Citadel and in the caldera beyond received the full force of his hatred and his skill. Lightning struck from above with pinpoint accuracy, and the ground at the Citadel's foundations split open and molten rock exploded forth. [Greenskin reaction to magical attack: 100.] Truth be told, you don't know if the tide of greenskins heading into the Citadel was part of an internal religious schism or them taking the shortest route between their current location and Karag Nar to try to avenge what Ranald did to Mork. But if it was the former, Kragg's unleashing of magical power nips that conflict right in the bud. Somewhere in the Citadel, someone - likely an Orc - has had a loud enough voice and a powerful enough blow to bring order to the chaos and cement his own leadership over all those present, and pointed them at the approximate cause of their suffering. Boiling forth from the structure is a gushing sea of Orcs and Goblins, and even as some tumble into lava-flooded ravines or are obliterated by lightning strikes, the majority keep going as the power of the Waaagh fills them with bloodlust. [Dwarven artillery: 92+20=112.] [Codrin's archers: 18+15=33.] [Kragg the Grim: 3+30=33.] [Greenskin leadership: 71+25=96.] [Karag Nar assault: ???] The constant rumble of thunder is joined by a volley of cannonfire and, unheard but just as brutal, the firing of Grudge and Bolt Throwers, and wood and rock and metal scythe through the charging forces without mercy. Though the site of Mork's mugging lay to the east and the source of the magical assault to the northeast, the battle lines of men pulls them inexorably southeast instead. From this distance an arrow is invisible, but a volley of thousands shouldn't be. So if the archers are firing they're not coordinated enough to form a volley, and the greenskin lines surge forward, now free of the lava and lightning that torments the Citadel. [Dwarven artillery: 43+20=63.] [Codrin's archers: 63+15=78.] [Kragg the Grim: 46+25=71.] [Greenskin leadership: 84+25=109.] [Karag Nar assault: ???] As the greenskins close to medium range, both the archers and the lightning seem to adjust their aim, and a volley cuts down hundreds and electricity jumping from Orc to Orc accounts for just as many. But this is the side of the greenskins that makes them a blight upon the world: propelled by the fury of the Waaagh and united in purpose to destroy their foes. Thousands fall and are trampled underfoot by thousands more and the discharge from the Citadel has not even begun to slow, fuelled by the influx from the caldera. Seemingly unstoppable, the press of bodies approaches the lines of men. [Dwarven artillery: 67+20=87.] [Codrin's archers: 12+15=27.] [Kragg the Grim: 90+25=115.] [Greenskin leadership: 29+25=54.] [Karag Nar assault: ???] With a terrible groaning that drowns out everything else, the earth tears itself open in front of the lines of man as the greenskins near, and hundreds, thousands tumble in as the press that continues all the way to the Citadel makes stopping or even slowing impossible, and the embrace of molten rock accounts for every one of them. The greenskins falter and a volley of bolts scythes through their exposed ranks, sending enough flying that those now foremost have enough room to halt their charge and a fraction of a second to reconsider before they are shoved forward by those behind. From this distance the activity can be summarized in seconds, but with the amount of time passing you're starting to worry about why you've yet to hear any activity closer to you. The assault of Karag Nar should be well and truly underway, and just from comparing the forces of Karak Izor to the greenskins you saw while scouting they should be making good progress. [Dwarven artillery: 62+20=82.] [Codrin's archers: 29+15=44.] [Kragg the Grim: 27+25=52.] [Greenskin leadership: 30+15=45.] [Karag Nar assault: 100.] The greenskins falter and their lines spread out across the ravine, seeking a way across even as the constant fire of guns cuts through them time and time again. The ravine does not stretch the entire length of the valley, and the outermost of the greenskins reach it and resume their close on the lines of man, but each second wasted is horrendously costly for them and you can see them begin to falter. Your worries for the fight below are proven groundless as a crunch of metal on metal and then confused voices in an almost familiar tongue reach you, and you finally turn from the view at the window to head towards the doorway. Skaroki and a score of Longbeards are inspecting the door's guards in a great deal of confusion as one tries to pry his axe from the chest of an unmoving figure that remains stubbornly upright, even as blood pours from its mouth. With a gesture you release the spell on it, and the rigor mortis of a simulated death is replaced by the Black Orc collapsing as his actual one approaches. At your instruction a deeply sceptical Longbeard delivers a similarly fatal blow to the other guard so you can release its ensorcellment as well, and they drag the bodies away to stand in their place. "The lower floors put up more a fight than we expected," Skaroki says as he enters the room with you, frowning at the disguised treasure. "But once they broke we swept through the rest of the mountain without trouble. Good thing too, by the sounds of it things are heating up outside." "There's an entire greenskin town in the caldera, and half of them are charging through the Citadel to try to get at us," you report, and Skaroki scowls down in the direction of your pointed finger. "They're faltering but damn close to our lines." "Nick of time, then." He unfastens a horn from his belt and you hold your hands over your ears as he blows a long, deep note, and within a couple of seconds it is taken up elsewhere by those that had been waiting for the signal. There's nothing left to do but watch and hope, and Skaroki seems to agree, finding the view your lenses offer to be stronger than his distrust of magic. If battle comes to Karag Nar, there'll be plenty of time to head down there while the rest of the forces of Karak Izor present hold the line. [Codrin's archers: 39+15=54.] [Kragg the Grim: 16+25=41.] [Greenskin leadership: 74+10=84.] [Codrin's mercenaries: 91+10=101.] The volleys of cannonfire are cut off immediately as the crews stop firing and, with the help of those that had been standing ready for this purpose, reattach wheels and ropes and begin to haul their precious cargo back towards the East Gates, leaving behind piles of unspent ammunition. Without the constant obliteration of their foremost, the greenskins seem to surge forward and with an enormous cry of WAAAGH they slam into the ranks of men, but to their surprise (and, admittedly, your own) the men hold. Perhaps they can see their payday just around the corner, or perhaps the attrition that you suspect Codrin has been encouraging has cut out the least worthy of their number, but whatever the reason, an incredibly varied assortment of weapons were ready to meet the charge and more Orcs fall to human weapons than men to Orcish choppas. [Codrin's archers: 8+15=23.] [Kragg the Grim: 87+25=112.] [Greenskin leadership: 44+10=54.] [Codrin's mercenaries: 98+10=108.] Codrin's archers were to be next to disengage, but you suspect them of jumping the gun as the greenskin tide surges forth again as they are freed of the arrows that had been tormenting them. But Kragg has no need to withdraw, and to your surprise his magic does not manifest to torment the greenskins but to bolster the men, and a roared battlecry is shared amongst the mercenaries as the Dwarvish enmity of greenskins floods through their mind and strengthens their arms. An instant of silence falls upon the battlefield as those Orcs closest to the men are struck down and none are willing to step forward to take their place, and the bloodlust of greenskins furthest from the enemy clashes with the cowardice of those closest, and for a second the combined shouts of thousands of greenskins commingles into an eerily familiar roar of frustration. [Mork's intervention?: 26.] [Greenskin leadership: 43+10=53.] [Codrin's mercenaries: 47+10=57.] [Kragg the Grim: 84+25=109.] The stalemate stretches, and another horn sounds on the battlefield and the men under Codrin's command pull back as one, leaving only the dead as the wounded are hauled up and dragged away. The chaos amongst the greenskins only increases as energy coalesces into an almighty force that strikes like the fist of an angry god, shattering the earth and crushing dozens of greenskins, and it takes you a moment to realize it's not Kragg: it is the literal fist of an incredibly upset God, and Mork's pummelling of those who are failing him does nothing for their faltering morale. You wonder how Kragg felt to have not disrupted the formation of greenskin magic, and you smile as you see him channel his frustration into bolts of lightning that strike into the thickest parts of the crowd that aren't currently being tended to by the Fist of Mork. There is a single nexus of order amongst the rapidly growing disorder, and as you aim the view of your lenses you're quite surprised to see it's another Black Orc. Perhaps he claimed ignorance of the plot inside Karag Nar, perhaps he promised Mork his service, perhaps he was just loud enough and strong enough to take control of the crowd and point them at the enemy. Whatever it was that allowed him to take control, he's doing his best to rally his forces as fear of both the men and of Mork shatters their resolve. [Greenskin leadership: 5+10=15.] And he fails, and as he surrenders to rage the swing of his choppa becomes just one more thing for the greenskins to be terrified of. With still more greenskins pouring out of the Citadel there's no retreat to be had there, so instead they shatter in every direction at once. [Titus' Halflings: 81+15=96.] [???: 66+15=81.] [Mathilde's watchful eye: 87] Those heading directly in your direction are very quickly given cause to regret that decision, as arrows, javelins, slingstones and darts mercilessly cut through them; you frown to yourself as you spot a thorn bush springing from the ground to entangle a mob of larger Orcs who had stuck together, and within seconds the immobile targets were peppered with arrows and slumped to the ground as the growth of the plant retreated once more. Having obeyed your own sensible impulse to keep out of the battle when exhausted, you're a little peeved to see that Panoramia had apparently decided not to follow your good example, not to mention your order. [Quarrelers: 30+15=45.] [Greenskin retreat: 37.] To the north, the sudden retreat seems to have taken those guarding Karag Lhune by surprise, and the disorganized fire barely slows their retreat up the stairs. Thankfully, greenskin cowardice reasserts itself and they rapidly about-face instead of taking advantage of the element of surprise they'd inadvertently acquired. [Eastern Gates: 65+20=85.] To the south, those foolish enough to try to find safety in the open Eastern Gates were very quickly convinced not to by the siege weapons that had remained in place against exactly this eventuality, and the withdrawing forces are left in peace. [Demigryph riders: 66+20=86.] [Winter Wolves: 92+20=112.] Amongst it all, both wolves and demigryphs prevent any of the routing forces from reforming, and you smile to yourself as you catch a glimpse of Esbern and Seija having a grand time amongst them. With death on all other sides, the Citadel clogged, and cavalry running rampant amongst them, the only escape is to their southeast: the Sentinels and Kvinn-Wyr. You doubt they'll find much better a reception there, and wonder how the resident trolls will react to the sudden influx. The battle is well and truly over, and a chuckle from Skaroki tells you he's realized the same, and he pats you on the back before heading downwards to let those standing ready against the possibility of invasion know to stand down. Later, there'll be meetings and celebration and ale, but for now things are near enough to settled. With another extremely dubious look at the Warboss' former bed, you instead clamber atop the pile of wealth to perch upon the second-softest thing in the room: a rolled-up rug, presumably from Ind or beyond. To the sound of the grumbling thunder of a fading storm, you quickly surrender to fatigue and fall asleep. --- When you finally wake, the immediate post-battle concerns will have been dealt with and there'll be a Meeting of War. How much will you report? [ ] The death of the Warboss. [ ] The death of the Warboss and the shattering of an Almost-Rogue Idol. [ ] The death of the Warboss, the shattering of an Almost-Rogue Idol, and the weakening of Mork. [ ] The death of the Warboss, the shattering of an Almost-Rogue Idol, and the weakening of Mork and strengthening of Ranald. Panoramia seems to have disobeyed your order and joined the battle. How will you react? [ ] No harm, no foul. Say nothing. [ ] You'd have done the same once. Tell her you understand, but treat her to a lecture on the risks and dangers of miscasts. [ ] She disobeyed a superior Wizard and her commanding officer. Lecture her harshly but inflict no punishment. [ ] This is a matter between Wizards, and while you're not of the Jade Order and cannot directly punish her, etiquette dictates that you report this matter to them. [ ] She disobeyed her commanding officer. Eject her from the Expedition. [ ] Other (write in) With Karag Nar taken and the Citadel's forces greatly weakened, the Expedition might be considered concluded. Do you concur? [ ] The job is done. Ale and riches for everybody. [ ] The Citadel should be destroyed before we can consider our position secure. [ ] The residents are weakened, taking the Citadel is now a possibility. [ ] Taking Kvinn-Wyr would mean we have every Karag flanking the Eastern Valley. [ ] Other (write in)

Karak Eight Peaks: A Second Interlude

Spoiler: Voting results [*] The death of the Warboss, the shattering of an Almost-Rogue Idol, and the weakening of Mork. [*] The residents are weakened, taking the Citadel is now a possibility. [*] You'd have done the same once. Tell her you understand, but treat her to a lecture on the risks and dangers of miscasts. For generations, Karak Azul has stood alone. Once the underground highways to Karak Izril and Karak Eight Peaks bustled with traffic, but with every other southern Hold long since fallen, the only reminder that the rest of the Karaz Ankor exists is the occasional hardy expedition from Karaz-a-Karak that dares the terrors of the Dark Lands to travel up the Naz Kadrin, and for the past few centuries, gyrocopters modified for range and piloted by the daring few who would risk the long voyage over unfriendly mountains. To the Dwarves of Karak Azul, the rest of the civilized world seems more like a pleasant daydream than a tangible part of their lives, and the only living beings outside their hold were greenskins, Skaven, and somehow worse creatures. So when a knocking came at external doors that hadn't seen a friendly visitor in living memory, there was a great deal of alarm. Thoom. Thoom. Thoom. The impact rang through the empty hall, and those standing guard - for unfriendly visitors were still a constant threat - exchanged glances. A protocol had been passed from father to son a dozen times over for how to answer a polite knock rather than an incipient siege, but the knocking had driven it from their minds. One ran off to tell all who would listen, and the other licked dry lips and wracked an uncooperative memory and hoped this wasn't some enemy trick. Thoom. Thoom. Thoom. "Friend or foe?" he asked, then repeated at a yell loud enough to penetrate the door, knuckles whitening on his axe. The response that came was in a language he knew nothing of, but it sounded like neither greenskin nor ratman. A chorus of footsteps announced the arrival of reinforcements, a motley collection of everyone who had been in shouting distance, most armed and some armoured and all ready to defend the hold. They spent some time deliberating, and as they did the knocking sounded again. Thoom. Thoom. Thoom. The crowd grew as deliberations concluded, and before long the King entered, beloved King Kazador, full of youth and vigour. He was never one to back down from a fight, and at his urging the door was finally pulled open - an act that hadn't been performed without a Throng standing ready to march out to war for three thousand years - and all present raised their weapons and prepared a battlecry. And then lowered their weapons, their cries going uncried. On the other side stood a sight none expected - a single lightly-armoured manling, sitting astride a wolf. The nonplussed Dwarves stared at the manling, and the manling returned their stares. Then he spoke the same phrase he had spoken before, and this time there was one that understood him. By the King's side, a Longbeard who often spoke of the travels of his youth was struck with shock greater than his fellows. King Kazador remembered that his advisor understands the manling tongue, and demanded to know what this strange visitor was saying. "He says he bears word," says the Longbeard. "Word from King Belegar, Ruler of Karak Eight Peaks." King Kazador snorted. "The latest claimant? Is he sending manlings to perform his tour this time, instead of coming in person to ask to be gifted a Throng?" The Dwarf nearest the manling had accepted a scroll from him, and stared down at the runes within. "'We have the East Gates,'" he read. "'We have Karag Lhune. Once more the valiant fallen are being recorded in the Hall of Oaths, and once more Clan Angrund blood stains the stone of our home. If you hurry, you might just arrive in time to share in what glory remains, before the manlings claim it all.'" King Kazador stared as the scroll was passed to the Longbeard, who peered down at it. "The seal is genuine," he said numbly. "Should I fetch my ink-" "Ink?" roared Kazador, shaken from his shock. "Didn't you hear what my Brother-King said? Get your axe! Get your helm! Rally every Dwarf that can see lightning and hear thunder! Someone get Kazrik, tell him to bring his best axe! Wait," he grabbed the Longbeard as he attempted to follow the orders. "Ask the manling, is Belegar married?" The Longbeard repeated the question, and the bemused manling shook his head. "Someone get Kazrina, tell her to bring her best axe! The Dwarves are on the warpath!" --- Kragg is very much the star of today's events, and though part of you is a little peeved that nobody but Ranald is going to know the full extent of what you risked and what you achieved today, you can't deny how spectacular the display you witnessed was. And though it wasn't done in complete safety - anyone foolish enough to try to congratulate Kragg has been treated to a long and upset diatribe on the hairline fracture his Anvil has suffered and the many long hours of work it will take to return it to anything approaching a satisfactory condition - the dangers of it are, from what little you know of Runic magic and Anvils, entirely limited to those in the admittedly considerable blast radius of the Anvil itself. You mentally compare it with some of the ways you've seen magic gone wrong, like your long ordeal with the Thorned One and what that blithering idiot Sunscryer did when you needed him to- when he was needed at Drakenhof. In that light, you suppose there's a point to be had. Kragg does seem to be eyeing you strangely, though. His glare at you has always been disapproving, but not more so than his background level of disapproval when staring at a world that contains a declining Karaz Ankor, so you've never taken it personally. This type of attention is new and concerning to you, and you wonder if he has an inkling of what happened. You know that Dwarves cannot feel the Winds of Magic (though from that glimpse snatched from the mind of Mork, you wonder if that's truly universal) but those skilled in Runecraft are known to be able to sense magic almost backwards. All Dwarves are naturally slightly repellent to magic, and Runepriests are able to tap into and consciously control that repellence, primarily for the purpose of combating enemy magics. But they are also to be able to sense magic as whatever it is in their nature that repels magic does so, in the same way a man in armour could tell when a projectile ricochets off their armour, and with practice might learn to tell between a stone and an arrow and a bullet. Exactly how much they can sense is beyond what even the Grey College has been able to determine, but from Kragg's looks you think you can add a data point to those ongoing investigations. The meeting comes to order, and opens with a toast to the fallen. Your own palate has only just started to grow beyond the point where you can identify what is and isn't ale, but to those with the taste for it the ale currently available is at best mediocre. It's the source of much grumbling, but the only alternative would be risking the 'good stuff' in a lengthy river cruise and an elongated underground wagon ride, so it's considered a necessary hardship. "Not how we saw the day going," King Belegar opens, to a round of agreements from all. "But we certainly rose to the occasion. Before we start studying, there's credit due and I'll not delay its payment. First, to the esteemed Runelord of Karaz-a-Karak, the thanks of Vala-Azril-Ungol for a display of Runic might of a calibre that I had thought lost to the ages." Again there is agreement, and Kragg's habitual frown twitches as he gives a single nod in response. "Second, to the dwarves of Karak Izor. They have believed enough in my Karak that many of their number are seeking to make it their home, and it is their eldest and wisest that have been where the fighting is thickest. Every lost Longbeard diminishes our race, and it is our duty not to let their sacrifice be in vain." A Khazalid murmuring you gather to be equivalent to 'hear, hear' rumbles from the Dwarves present. "Third, the siege engineers. Their numbers and their weapons hail from five different holds, but the craftsmanship of their actions today show them to all be carved from the same stone." Another rumble of accord. "And finally, and to my shame, most unexpectedly - the bravery of the line of men. All manner of Umgi answered my call to arms, but I never guessed them capable of receiving the charge of a maddened Waaagh with such fortitude. Their showing today would do credit to a line of Ironbreakers." You prevent an eyebrow from raising, knowing that the line of men had more than a little assistance in their actions, and instead of watching Codrin receive the praise for his men you're watching to catch the surly look Kragg shoots at King Belegar. Interesting. "All that said," King Belegar continues, "the time is over for patting of backs and it is now time for tugging of beards. Master Weber, though your acts may never be part of the songs they'll sing of our battles, I have been finding it difficult to even begin to tally the number of Dawi lives your interventions have saved. Were you able to rival your work in Karag Lhune?" If only you knew, you think. "If not rival, then at least add to that tally," you say. "The Black Orc Priest or Shaman that was attending to the Temple turned out to be the local leader, though I couldn't say for sure whether he was merely the Big Boss of Karag Nar or the Warboss of the entire Broken Toof Tribe. He was attempting an empowerment ritual for the Idol of Gork that was the shrine-" "Of Gork and Mork," Ulthar corrects. "In this case, just Gork," you respond, grateful that he'd inadvertently contributed to your partial truth. "That seemed to be a matter of contention for them, too. It seems the other of their Gods was objecting to being left out, and I was able to interrupt the Idol's empowerment just as their disagreement was coming to a head, and the power that Mork invested in trying to combat the Idol was lost - perhaps permanently - as the Idol shattered." The looks you receive are sceptical, but Kragg's brow is crinkled in thought, and he speaks up after a moment. "It's not impossible," he concludes. "Carelessness and impetuousness are part of their nature, and there was a great deal of energy active in Karag Nar." Silence stretches again as everyone reassesses. "Is that what provoked them?" King Belegar eventually asks. "The timing is right," is your scrupulously correct response. "Well, we knew that the assault on Karag Nar might provoke a reaction," King Belegar says. "Perhaps not this much of a reaction, but there are never guarantees when dealing with the Grobi. Ulthar, how was your end of the scouting?" "With the poison brewed by the Vornzhufokri, we were able to cause a good deal of infighting amongst those on guard," he reports. "However, the Black Orcs roused by the disturbances proved able to strike down the poisoned and restore order amongst the others. They were the obvious next targets, but many proved too alert to get a shot on them before the battle outside started and my Rangers withdrew." Skaroki takes it from there. "Victory was won, but not cheaply. The enemy were able to barricade a series of choke-points that cut us off from the majority of the Karag, and without the time to seek another entrance or wear them down, it turned into a bloody battle, and as you know, casualties were highest amongst the most experienced." "As events have shown, time was of the essence," King Belegar says grimly. "Once more, our thanks to Karak Izor." Skaroki nods in response, and heads turn expectantly to Codrin. "Now to the battle outside." "My archers," Codrin begins immediately, "will atone for their showing today." Ulthar frowns. "Can't expect manlings to take it in stride when heaven and earth take a side on the battlefield." "They are Stirlanders," Codrin responds. "Their ancestors kept their heads when the hungry dead snapped at their heels and the wind itself tried to tear the soul from their bodies. They will atone." None of these Dwarves are from Zhufbar or Karak Kadrin, so none have had to face the terrors of Sylvania, but they understand the sentiment and a series of understanding nods meet Codrin's words. "More happily, the other forces under my command have done themselves and this Expedition proud. We received the greenskin charge without a single step back, and bloodied them for the attempt." Pride is clear in his voice, and you wonder at what long-term effects there could be of the Runic bolstering he had unknowingly experienced. The rest of the battle reports are without surprises, with Durin taking pride in the hammering his siege engines delivered, the Knights speaking of the easy pickings of scattered greenskins they had taken their share from, and Titus shrugging off his own forces' contribution towards the end of the battle. With most of the surviving greenskins having fled into Kvinn-Wyr, the discussion naturally turns to its inhabitants. "That many trolls in one area cannot be living off moss and cave insects," Ulthar says. "The rock trolls do, of course, eat rock, but the common and river trolls would need live prey. Thaggoraki would eventually either fortify or retaliate if their forces were suffering constant heavy attrition, so the most likely possibility is that they're picking off Grobi. Needless to say, seeing them as their staple food would interfere with any attempts for the Grobi to enlist them." "So we consider them neutral," King Belegar muses. "Remaining on guard against them, of course, but they'd be as much an obstacle to our other enemies as they would be to us. The threat would not be an assault in force, but individual trolls wandering out." "And that's a threat that we can guard against," says Durin. "We've got forty bolt throwers, and I'm authorized to negotiate on behalf of Karak Norn should you wish to purchase our thirty for your long-term defences. A wall, or even just a palisade as it's only needed for early warning, and a series of towers or even just reinforced firing positions. By the time a troll's finished bludgeoning his way through the palisade the bolt thrower crews will be more than ready." "Leaving only the Citadel until the Eastern Valley can be considered secure," King Belegar says. "Titus, how's the test farms?" "Early days yet," the Halfling says, "but promising. A lot of our crops won't grow this far south but we've sent word back to Barak Varr for seeds from Tilea - we're about as far south as Luccini by my reckoning, and while we're not likely to get their rain, if we can find enough water to irrigate that won't matter. So it becomes entirely a matter of soil quality, and between the amount of corpses we've got for fertilizer and young Panoramia we should be able to make something of the Eastern Valley." "All the more reason, then. The Citadel. Between the battering it received from Kragg and the bloodying we gave its residents, things have changed. No doubt it's been claimed by some up-and-coming brute but they won't be as established as the previous one. Less followers means less defenders, less familiar with the Citadel means less effective sentries. Thoughts?" Nods and murmurs of agreement sound from most present, yourself included. "The Underway," Skaroki says bluntly. "Right now we can either defend Karags Nar and Lhune from below, or we can move into the Underway and defend the approaches from Kvinn-Wyr and Karagrin. Well enough. But the Citadel-" "Aye, the Underway under the Citadel links the Sentinels to the Cavern of Stars at the center of the Karak. We'll need to defend it from below as well as from the caldera. But we'll fill the Citadel from ground to stars with Quarrellers and Thunderers, and we line the precipice to either side of the Citadel with every siege weapon we no longer need pointing inwards from the East Gates, and it won't take long for even the Grobi to catch on that the caldera means death. From that point the only real threat will be from below, and that's preferable to guarding the entire Eastern Valley from attack from a Citadel in Grobi hands." "Will any object to extending the goals of the Expedition?" Ulthar asks. "Will they?" King Belegar repeats. You shake your head, as do the Dwarves present, as do the Knights after the moment of thought. The subtler turn their eyes towards Codrin, those less so their entire heads, and he's looking thoughtful. "Yesterday," he says slowly, "I would have been less sure. But today those under my command have either victory to keep them warm or shame burning in their gut. Feed them well today and fill tonight with ale and song, and tomorrow they'll march with you against any enemy." "That," says King Belegar with a smile, "is something we can do." --- You find Panoramia with the Halflings she disobeyed you to fight alongside, and you take a moment to watch her with them. They're up to their wrists in muddy soil in the small trial gardens set up behind the safety of the East Gates, and the only reason you can't call their conversation arcane is because you can understand arcane. Dirt is dirt, but they have found a great deal to discuss in their dirt, and you listen as they debate the effects of three-field and four-field systems, and speculate what the soil requires that the plants may be providing. A memory unearths itself of the farm of your childhood, of the West Field which would be planted one season and the South Field the next and never both, a ritual followed because it had always been followed. Any child that questioned it would be told that it was the way Rhya demanded, and if you didn't follow the dictates of the Gods you may as well be a filthy Halfling. You shake your head to rid yourself of the unwelcome memory, and clear your throat loud enough to break through the conversation. Only because you were looking for it were you able to catch the flash of panic on Panoramia's face before she excused herself from her fellow workers to come over to you. "Magister!" she says with aggressive cheerfulness. "The soil here has had a harsh time of it - I believe it would have hosted greenskin fungi for a few generations until it was exhausted. They can overcome that, but they have an easier time of it underground, and of course there's no shortage of caves here, so once the soil gave out it was abandoned." You say nothing, and Panoramia wipes her hands absently on her robes, where the fading of its colour suggests that she had done so and then had to scrub the stain out innumerable times in the past. "The Halflings don't have the Rhythm of Rhya, but they've got something called Phineas' Footsteps which is a child's skipping rhyme that dictates almost the exact same rotation. Isn't that interesting?" "Sleep well?" you ask. "Oh." To her credit, she doesn't even try to lie. "Grey Order, remember. We see all, we know all." "Magister, I'm sorry, but-" "But there was a battle and you couldn't just lie there and sleep while your little friends might have been bleeding and dying?" She's staring at you, and you have to keep yourself from laughing. It's easy for people to suspect you can read minds if what they're thinking is so obvious. "Panoramia. Druid name, right?" "Yes, Magister." "Parents Jade College as well?" "Yes. Ma teaches now, Da's Perpetual." Perpetuals were Apprentices-in-Perpetuity, those who had some magic but lacked either the power, the desire, or the aptitude to attempt to reach full Magisterial status, many finding comfortable roles in the Colleges as servants or secretaries or assistants or librarians. Or, apparently, as spouses. "So you grow up knowing you'll probably be magical, you got taught all the little tricks right from the start, you know to take your time and most Ghyran spells are happy to let you..." To Panoramia, magic was not a terrifying curse that appeared one day without warning and upended the life she thought she knew. It had been a constant her entire life, and even before her ability to touch and shape Ghyran had sprouted she had likely been surrounded by it and had known it intimately before her first spell. And Ghyran itself was very easy to let your guard down around. It encouraged life and growth, it thrived in happy little groves full of trees and animals and birdsong and flowers, it sprouted like a tree and flowed like a river. "I understand why you had to be there. But I told you to sleep for a reason. What's your worst?" "What?" But she knows what you meant. It was a common game among young wizards. What's your worst miscast? "My, um, my hand, it cramped up into a sort of claw shape. I couldn't move it for..." she pauses as she sees the look you give her. "For about three minutes..." "I summoned a daemon," you say, and you're grimly pleased at the expression on her face. "At the age of sixteen. Wisdom's Asp. It followed me from the other side of mirrors and it wanted so very much to wrap itself around me and bury its thorns into my skin. It stalked me for seven years until I managed to trap it." She stares at you in horror. "Don't you worry about that - they like Ulgu and Ghur and Hysh. No, mishandled Ghyran calls to Rotwyrms, giant insubstantial daemon-maggots that hunger for flesh." You look away, so Panoramia's horror doesn't dissuade you. "Just last month at Und-Uzgar, my shadow came to life and crushed to death the creature closest to me, which I'm very glad was a Skaven rather than any of my compatriots." You see her look down, and you follow her gaze to your shadow, which as always is flitting around obeying its own desires instead of the angle of the sunlight. "Yes, it's been like that ever since. Despite that, I consider myself lucky. During the Battle of Drakenhof, a Magister of the Light Order named Jovi Sunscryer fumbled something he was trying to do and exploded into flames of pure Hysh. Needless to say, he died. So did most of those unlucky enough to be living in that district. Are you starting to see my point?" You turn to face her again, and eventually she remembers to reply. "Yes, Magister." "I'm glad. If you really must be there, get one of your new friends to teach you the bow. Because if you keep casting when you shouldn't be casting, it won't just be you that suffers, it will be everyone around you. Understood?" "Yes, Magister." "Good. Off you go." She flees, and you sigh. You had to channel a bit of your Master- of your former Master for that, but if you ever met whoever taught Panoramia you won't need anyone's example to be properly scolding. Anyone that reaches Journeyman without being absolutely terrified of the consequences of mishandled magic hasn't been taught properly. You hope the Jades weren't stupid enough to have let her be Apprentice to her own mother. --- The day after the Expedition left Barak Varr, so did a convoy of wagons. The same the day after, and the day after that, and so forth all the way to today, and likely for quite some time into the future. An experienced baggage train can match an army on the march for speed, so they take no longer than you did to cross the same amount of ground. The day after the Expedition arrived at the East Gates, the first set of wagons arrived. The next day's were one day's travel up the road, and the next day's further still, and so on. Seven baggage trains in Death Pass. Seven travelling through the dark of the Underway. Seven wearing ruts into the formerly unspoiled wilderness of the valley. And if the coin-counters of Barak Varr had decided it was more economical to travel by road rather than pushed upstream by steam and Dwarven artifice, another fourteen stretched out along Blood River. That was gunpowder for cannons and bolts for crossbows and whetstones for axes and ropes for catapults. It was also tents and shoes and wood for fires and soap for washing and bandages for the wounded. It was drinking water, because even though shovels had rediscovered the aquifer days ago, it would take weeks for the water that Barak Varr had sent before that discovery to stop arriving. It was also food and ale, and though nobody had gone hungry or thirsty, under King Belegar's careful hand enough had been put aside just in case it was needed. And though one obvious need for food and drink was to sustain life, almost as vital was sustaining morale, and to that end all those carefully stockpiled victuals were to be put to use - and on top of that, many a gauntlet had been thrown down as Ranger and Knight and Huntsman alike set out to display their skill at hunting, so if there were any goats or sheep unfortunate enough to call the area home, they would be adding to the feast. Eat, drink, and be merry, for tomorrow's battle has been thoughtfully scheduled for late afternoon, leaving plenty of time to sleep off the hangovers. If Mathilde wishes to disclose the full events in the Temple, Ranald included, now is the last appropriate time. [ ] Tell Belegar. [ ] Tell Belegar and Kragg. [ ] Some other combination (write in) [ ] Remain silent. How will Mathilde spend the time before the celebration? The two with the most votes will win, but only one from each category. [ ] Join the hunting with Esbern and Seija [ ] Join the hunting with Maximilian [ ] Join the hunting with Ulthar [ ] Join the hunting with Codrin [ ] Join the hunting with Sigwald Kriegersen [ ] Join the hunting with Ruprecht Wulfhart [ ] Cook with Panoramia and Titus [ ] Cook with Karak Izor [ ] Cook with Clan Angrund [ ] 'Make sure the ale hasn't gone bad' with Skaroki [ ] 'Make sure the ale hasn't gone bad' with Durin [ ] 'Make sure the ale hasn't gone bad' with Johann What will Mathilde be doing during the celebration? The three with the most votes will win. [ ] Drinking [ ] More drinking [ ] Drinking games [ ] Being maudlin [ ] Eating [ ] Telling war stories [ ] Gambling [ ] Listening to Longbeards grumble [ ] Sparring [ ] Target shooting [ ] Put on a magic display (Petty and Lesser only) [ ] Play with a giant wolf [ ] Play with a demigryph [ ] Other (write in suitably celebratory activity) [ ] Valayan religious service [ ] Ulrican religious service [ ] Taalite religious service [ ] Hold a Ranaldan religious service [ ] Help move the Karag Nar hoard Shall Mathilde engage in Dwarven Shenanigans, should the opportunity arise? [ ] Yes to Shenanigans [ ] No to Shenanigans - On the topic of disclosure: You are not Ranald's only friend. He has Priests, some of those Priests are High Priests, and some of those High Priests attend the Grand Conclaves. If Ranald wishes it to be known that Mork is disadvantaged, he is able to make it so, and in ways that do not reveal your involvement. - While some Rangers will be scouting the Citadel today, if you wish to do so you will have the opportunity tomorrow. - Though the Colleges do their very best to dissuade it, by the time they reach Journeyman most wizards have cultivated the ability to cast Petty and Lesser Magics while drunk. - 'Spend time with X' is not a valid celebration activity. This is for Mathilde. - Dwarven Shenanigans largely consist of finding new and interesting ways to torment greenskins. If they are engaged upon, there will only be permanent consequences for anyone but the greenskins if they are judged to be hilarious. - No matter the vote, you will be spending time with Wolf in the coming update. - This has been the case since last update, but I forgot to include it in the update itself so just to make it official: discussion of what Mathilde should do with the Liber Mortis are on moratorium until further notice. Once Mathilde is no longer in an active warzone and able to take her time to consider matters, the topic will be revisited. - A much smaller in scope moratorium: what would happen if Mathilde used Ranald's Coin to lie to the Grey Order? Would they be made suspicious by not being suspicious? This is very much an unstoppable force vs immovable object debate, as the Coin really is that powerful but the Grey Order really is that paranoid, and the topic tends to keep going around in circles. Best to avoid having to find out.

Turn 23: Ashen Flight (Part Five)

Spoiler: Consolidate Gains, Focus on Value

[X] Plan Consolidate Gains, Focus on Value
-[X] Allow Apollo: Let one of the greatest warriors the Blood Ravens possess challenge this alien champion. He will have support, not just from Blood Ravens but from the Mechanicus forces as well.

-[X] Focus On Current Boarding: The eldar haven’t yet managed to destroy the ships that are being captured, but that might yet change. Plus, there is a bounty of vessels that need to be fully captured. Two battleships, cruisers, and escort vessels alike. Take these down fully, and the Mechanicus could focus fully upon the Haven Spire! [Write-In Priority Of Vessels For Boarding Teams]
--[X] Complete Capture/Secure Gains on Priority in Descending Order: Void Stalker Battleships, Eclipse-class Cruiser/Carrier, Void Dragon Cruiser
--[X] All other ships not fully in hand may be destroyed, internally scuttled, or successfully captured at the discretion of local forces, whatever is most efficient at removing it as a threat and to be able to redeploy faster to higher priorities.
--[X] Strike Cruisers Burning Seeker and Ravenous Spirit can drift back from the battle lines nearest the Haven Spire and work more to prevent Eldar from recapturing or otherwise denying captured ships

-[X] Forge Ahead: You can pull your brothers out from ships that are already captured, and lessen your presence on other vessels. Charge forth, letting the Battle Barges lead, and deploy directly onto and into the Haven Spire itself. Let the bombardment cannons tear holes that not even holofields can deflect or disguise. Take the Shadow-class Cruiser, and hunt the Farseer down. Slaughter the xenos entirely! [Write-In Priority of Boarding Teams For Towards Shadow-class/Towards Farseer/Towards Haven Spire Defensive Systems]
--[X] 1st Company not already on the Void Stalker Battleships, 5th Company, Chapter Leadership, unassigned specialists prioritize boarding on the Haven Spire
---[X] 1st Company tasked with capturing the Shadow-class cruiser first
---[X] 5th Company tasked with establishing a beachhead and disabling the Haven Spire's defensive systems

Ashen Flight
+050.M42+ To +055.M42+
+To The End, Always+

Teleportarium Precision: 67

He felt him coming, a soul bright with bitter shame and righteous fury, hurtling through the immmaterium. In an instant, Justinius seized upon it, and the Chief Librarian of the Blood Ravens alighted with psychic power that bled from his eyes in liquid tears which vaporized upon touching open air. In an instant, Apollo appeared upon the body-strewn deck, falling a final foot with weight enough to crush the skull of an eldar’s corpse. No others accompanied him, for there were more than enough brothers upon this ship, and other matters needed to be attended to. There were no words exchanged, only a pair of nods, and then both marines plunged onwards into the Void Stalker’s innards, weapons crackling with power.

==========================================

Fleet Battle
41 vs. 99 vs. 89

Engines flared in the void, and the fleets advanced once more. Boarding teams fought on in the ships that they were already within, while those that had escaped such proved their cowardice by fleeing away. At the speeds sustainable by the eldar ships, a many were able to retreat, yet it did not escape the sight of many that the ships of the Biel-Tan craftworld were deliberately separating their ships from the formations of those of the Corsairs. Even so, they fought on, scouring beams of light from devices both human and xeno brightening the darkness of space, tearing at shields and hulls alike, while entire hordes of torpedoes flew back and forth. Again, the great angry clouds of strike craft crashed into one another, but this time the doughty human fighters and bombers found themselves felled in terrible number. A Mechanicus light cruiser found itself swarmed, bombs seemingly without end cracking open its spine. All the while, the ships of Biel-Tan formed up around the Haven Spire itself.

Drifting Defense
94 vs. 15

It was obvious that they would come, in the end. Rather than allow defilement, or worse, actual study, they had been deployed by their fierce prince. Both Nightshade-class destroyers were fresh from the Haven Spire’s yards, and yet they were merciless in their approach. The warlocks on board cast rituals of clouding, while their holofields scrambled any attempt at the primitive human auspex from detection. It was a tactic well practiced and well used for generations, and yet in this one instance, it failed. A bellowed prediction from Nero Achillian, whose sight would not be denied, and the Blood Ravens fell upon such carefully laid plans with extreme prejudice.

When the Nightshades appeared, just before firing their salvos of neutron and vortex torpedoes, the Burning Seeker was there. Flying upwards, it was a spear of metal perpendicular to the far more fragile enemy vessels, crashing upwards through their comparatively unprotected bellies. At such close ranges, there could be no mistake. Then came the Ravenous Spirit, whose teeth had been blunted and broken, yet still possessed its armored prow. As one of the Nightshades attempted to turn about, knowing their fate yet struggling to avoid it, the Ravenous Spirit slammed into its rear, spinning it about and shredding its hull in the same instant. Only then did the boarding pods appear, crashing into their grievously torn hulls, carrying the roaring cries of the 4th Company.

Drifting Defense Boarding
34 vs. 20

This bounty was the Imperium’s. It was that of the Blood Ravens. And those that had come to destroy would only be joined to it.

=========================================

Boarding Efforts/Withdrawals
Ascendant Star: 32 vs. 78
Void Stalker 2: 27 vs. 5
Eclipses: 13 vs. 83
Void Dragon: 6 vs. 91

Blood Ravens fought, and Blood Ravens died. Upon the Void Dragon cruiser, teleporting warp spiders appeared from nowhere, cutting down entire skitarii teams, a vortex grenade tearing a trio of scouts into the immaterium forever. Upon the Eclipses, Howling Banshees unleashed their screams upon newly promoted marines of the 4th Company, led by an Exarch whose blades tore ceramite and flesh with equal abandon. Only an advancing squad from behind managed to push them back, dragging back marines locked into suspended animation while a desperate Apothecary Caesar extracted gene-seed. The defenders of the bridge stymied even the efforts of Apollo and Justinius, even as they ground down their foes without pause. All throughout this came the storming skitarii, the myrmidons, fighting and dying alongside their allies in even greater numbers.

And despite all of this, the Blood Ravens strode forward through the void.

“Engines on full, Brother-Captain!” Gabriel yelled, already striding for the Thunderhawks.

It was not verbally that Hadrian responded, but by his will. And through his will, the Battle Barges advanced, firing all weaponry as they went.

Forging Ahead
91

This was what Battle Barges were meant for. To advance under withering enemy fire, unrelenting, all to deploy their precious and deadly cargoes without delay or failure. And in this, they performed without peer. The Litany of Fury, the Omnis Arcanum, the Scientia Est Potentia, all three sister ships screamed their fury. Bombardment cannons fired alongside weapon arrays, and all the holofields in the sector could not prevent some from hitting their targets. The Haven Spire’s size, built such that it held its own shipyards, worked against it, a mass that could not be obscured. Great cracks appeared along its hull, though most were only cosmetic, while a great many defensive batteries unleashed themselves.

For naught.

For Hadrian Priscus, Captain of the 4th Company, had decided something. Eight Thunderhawks had not yet been separated across the fleets. As such, they remained under his command. The Omnis Arcanum, largest of all the Battle Barges of the Blood Ravens, just barely avoided crashing its bulk into the Haven Spire. But it was more than close enough for its weapon batteries to open at close range upon its opposites upon the Spire. Only then, clouding the field with a storm of laser and macrocannon, did the gunships deploy, shrieking into the holes torn open for them. Only once all eight had begun to fire upon the aliens who had come to resist boarders, meeting the howls of their Banshee’s and the stoicism of their Dire Avengers with hellstrike missiles, were the actual boarders deployed amidst the ashen ruins of the first responders.

Those of the 1st Company that could be drawn away, those of the 5th, they came, and came without pause or fail. Elsewhere, the 4th and 10th Company fought across the fleet battle, desperately struggling against their alien foes. Here would perhaps the greatest of the battles be fought, and thus Gabriel knew that here he could do the greatest damage. The grudge of Tarkus would never be sated, he knew, and so the Captain of the 5th deployed as well, growling his fury across the vox channels. The hatred of the 5th was only inflamed further by the litanies of Hannibal. It would be needed, for the Haven Spire was the home of the alien, here, and they would not give it up easily.

======================================

Preventing Retreat
17

“There will be no further attempts to board on the retreating vessels,” Cyrus snarled, “Focus on what ships that remain yet within our grasp. Let the Mechanicus and Battle Barges deal with them as they can.”

With Hadrian occupied in the fight over eldar station, it fell to the remaining Captain present to hold the rest of the Blood Ravens together. There would be no more effort expended on the rapidly retreating ships, all power given over to their flight. Not with all the Blood Ravens sent there too injured to fight or slain entirely. There remained yet two targets for them, however, and so the Thunderhawks flew anew alongside other boarding pods. The teleportariums thrummed, and so the 10th Company deployed itself. Both Void Stalker battleships had not retreated, had not been capable of it, leaving the twin leviathans isolated. Battered and surrounded as they were, there would be no relief for them save in victory.

The scope of Cyrus’ rifle swiveled to find an eldar guardian, their own gun knocked away but a knife in hand, stabbing down at a scout’s chest.

“You will never have the Fist of Khaine, mon-keigh! We will destroy it before you do!”

A cracking boom, and the scout wheezed as the corpse of their would-be killer slumped on top of them, sans head. Down the corridor, Cyrus sneered and stalked elsewhere, opening his vox as he went.

“Note for Librarius edification. Second Void Stalker battleship identified by crew as ‘Fist of Khaine’.”

Boarding Efforts
Ascendant Star: 50 vs. 69
Fist of Khaine: 53 vs. 90
5th Company Objectives: 90 vs. 73
1st Company Objectives: 94 vs. 18

On the accursed Haven Spire, a home and port for weary aliens after long years of plundering and pillaging, there was a great and terrible accounting. The 5th Company, driven by the fury of their Captain whose hatred for the eldar burned eternally, threw themselves without hesitation against the station’s defenders. Many of the aliens upon the spire had hastily thrown on their armor and weaponry, while others had fled wholesale. Tarkus, at the head of his company, spoke across the vox in a single endless denouncement, enflaming hatred as well as almost any chaplain. As he weathered dark reaper volleys and responded with grenades, he spoke of the endless treacheries visited upon humanity by the eldar. Smashing a howling banshee’s teeth in with the butt of Deathdealer, he told the tales of the many times that the eldar had personally brought death and ruin to the Blood Ravens. There was zero hesitation when warp spiders appeared, no shock at their sudden arrival, and they too died as he told the tales of Kronus and Tartarus.

Through long winding corridors, shaped and bent ever so slightly wrong, did the 1st Company and much of the Chapter’s leadership battle. A great number of apothecaries and much of the Librarius were present, gathering up the fallen and sending them back into battle at speeds that the eldar simply could not withstand. A veteran with one heart pierced was revived half-way into transition into suspended animation, gathering up their bolter and knife in the same motion. Gabriel fought alongside Hannibal who fought alongside Marcus who fought alongside Doukas. Captains and Masters all, a bloody red and black fist which tore apart the defenders. Even as they screamed in pain and fury, the eldar died. Walls were blown apart by missile and krak grenade, detonation packs and psychic blasts from the epistolaries shredding defenses set up over decades and centuries.

“Defend the cruiser, it is our only avenue of escape,” shrieked a panicking Striking Scorpion. “We cannot let the mon-keigh destroy it!”

As Marcus fell upon the eldar aspect warrior, Gabriel paused, his thoughts coalescing into a single truth after so much carnage and observation of the enemy.

“Chapter Master? You look perturbed,” Captain Doukas murmured even as he continued to fire his bolt pistol towards the enemy.

“This is far less than we should have faced,” Gabriel mused darkly. “The Haven Spire is emptier than any reasonable amount. They drew all of their fleet here, it should be full to bursting. Unless…,”

Reports, endlessly filtering over the vox, danced through his mind. Of entire passageways and chambers easily passed through by space marines. Of multiple ships outside the spire retreating from the battle, leaving the Void Stalker vessels behind. And, of course, that of the foe just now. Of escape, not dire holding actions or desperate resolve to protect the only home they possessed. Gabriel knew what was happening, and turned away from the fight, gesturing for Doukas to continue without him. He flicked through the channels of the vox until he found Damion once more, the Epistolary laughing as he set about doing some act of destruction or another.

“Brother Damion.”

The laughter cut off abruptly, the much younger marine’s voice choking slightly.

“Chapter Master.”

“The Farseer. Can you still locate them?”

Damion frowned atop the pile of eldar meat and ash, and fell to both knees hard enough to leave indents in the flooring, a hand going to his forehead as he concentrated.

“I…,”

Locating
71

“Yes! They’re...,” Damion trailed off, confusion audible, “They’ve moved. They’re no longer in the Spire. They’re in their Void Dragon vessel. I don’t…”

Gabriel growled, the bionics in his chest transforming it into an awful thing of grinding metal and inhumanly vicious exhalation.

“They are fleeing,” he roared. “They are fleeing aboard their own fleet, and attempting to escape! Chapter Master Angelos to all receiving, the eldar are attempting to flee! Advance and crush them!”

Scouts On Spire
24

“Chapter Master,” a new voice broke in amidst the wild influx of acknowledgements and war cries that flooded the vox. “This is Sergeant Taricles. Me and my scout squad have located scuttling charges in our sector. We do not know how many more remain on the Haven Spire, but it is many. We have disabled these ones, but this station is vast, and I do not know if we have the time or numbers to locate and disable them all!”

Gabriel ground his teeth, even as ahead the rest of the 1st Company broke into the docking bay where the Shadow-class hung suspended. Multiple massive explosions on the other side of the bay announced the presence of Skitarii, binary war cants audible even from where the Chapter Master stood. But more would be heard, as another marine elsewhere in the fight turned on their own vox so that more could be heard.

============================================

“Mestela!! What do you think you are doing!”

Apollo grunted as he tore Rogal’s Fist free of the eldar exarch which had charged him, glaring up at the bloodied Corsair Prince. The bridge was in chaos, as was expected, the most fervent and deadly of the corsair’s present in this single location. But a whispered word from Justinius who even now fought a trio of warlocks had made him activate his vox on full channel straight to the Chapter Master. He had not known why, but this information was more than worth it.

“You have proven yourself an unfit leader, Prince Lantyr. So many dead, dying? The Rim Stalkers have been offered a new way, a better way, and you…simply do not factor into it,” came the pleased arrogant tones of who could only be the Farseer. “And now, with the Haven Spire itself under assault, and so many ships lost? It was inevitable.”

“You…,” the Corsair Prince’s face purpled so darkly it was nearly black with his rage, “This was your plan all along! You…you provoked…this…this is…”

“Biel-Tan thanks you for your service to her, oh Void Ripper,” the sneer carried easily, “Die well.”

Final Withdrawal
18

Combined elements of Biel-Tan and corsair ships activated their engines, visible to all in the battle both upon the spire and on the two Void Stalker battleships, and turned away. Lantyr’s howling scream nearly split the eardrums of all those present on the bridge, his void sabre smashing downwards into the console in wild hacking strikes. Even as the Mechanicus ships did their best to pursue, a great envelopment of psychic energies held back for just such a purpose caused their targeting systems to go haywire. Just long enough for the Void Dragon vessel to disappear into the Webway, a passage opened up for the other vessels as well. Many carried the wounds inflicted on them, others were stuffed to bursting with those of the Rim Stalker’s warband who had been convinced to flee.

All that remained now were the most die-hard supporters of Lantyr, and they too were dying.

“Not even your kind are free from the treachery borne in your souls, alien,” Apollo called out, the maul sparking in his grip as he hefted it. “But fear not. I shall end you soon enough, and your troubles will be ended.”

When Lantyr turned to him, he revealed two orbs shot with color from twinned burst blood vessels, his lips peeling back to reveal an insane snarl. There were no mocking words, no exchanges of breath, for there was nothing in the prince’s mind left to do so. Only hatred, and the target before him.

“Come on then,” Apollo sneered. “Show me what passes for fury amongst your misbegotten kind.”

================================================

Hangar Securing
98

“Advance, advance now! Move forward brothers!”

Gabriel charged, now, along with the rest of the 1st Company and elements of the 5th towards the hangar, tearing apart what other defenders remained. Here and there, the epistolaries located other scuttling charges, but there was too many to deactivate, and many in places that only assault marines or psykers could reach. But they had enough time. Outside, the Omnis Arcanum was joined by multiple cruisers, the defenses broken enough in this sector by the 5th Company that they were unmarred by the Spire’s weaponry. It’s greater pulsar lance array fired, but for once missed, as a series of explosions began to ripple through the inner sections of the spire where none but a handful of skitarii had managed to reach.

“The Shadow cruiser is being secured, but what of the rest of the spire,” Doukas asked Gabriel, “Do we continue? If we brought in the 10th fully, we might have a chance.”

Even as they spoke, other skitarii began landing in transports, chemical injections and command phrases driving them to berserk fury to scream down the passages leading further in. Behind them came further techpriests who leapt upon the few scuttling charges that had been located. The news was disheartening, even then, for some had actually been hidden through outright psychic means by the Farseer and her own psykers, while others had been secreted by Biel-Tan troops. Gabriel frowned at the news, even more so at the casualty lists being circulated. It went unsaid that if they were unsuccessful, they might lose everyone and everything on the spire, and there were already explosions being noted from places where no one of the Imperium nor Mechanicus had yet stepped foot. It was already starting.

===================================

There was only the barest amount of grace left in the prince’s body, subsumed as he had been by his emotions let loose. Taut like a string, he danced and leapt about the room, pulling only the smallest cuts from Apollo’s armor and body, tiny trickling wounds that sealed or healed before the next could be dealt. It was a mistake to think that Apollo would not be capable of defending himself, of matching the speed of the prince, but one that the former Captain more than took advantage of. Crushed and mangled armor covered the eldar, his left hand by now smashed to pulp. Elsewhere across the bridge, more and more of the prince’s allies and brethren were dead. Ever more fire was focused not on crew, but on the prince himself.

Against so many more bolters, rapid firing lasguns, auto-tracking from skitarii, and worse, the powers of the Chief Librarian, it was inevitable. The injuries began to pile up, even as Lantyr managed to slay or sunder some of his foes. A 4th Company marine lost his head, a 1st Company marine his legs, a dozen highly advanced skitarii, and even one myrmidon techpriest. But he was tiring, and finally, Apollo snapped out with his power maul, the power field erupting around the eldar’s leg, exploding it from the thigh and down. Lantyr howled again, sent spinning to the floor and smashing into another broken console, bouncing over the body of his communications officer.

In the past, Apollo knew, there would be a speech here. A grand and uplifting thing, at least to him, which would be regarded with disdain by his fellows for such foolishness. He would mark it, report it to Kyras, and his legend within the Chapter would grow. Another weapon to use against his opponents, credence and credit lending his words more weight to do with as he wished. But that was then, and this was now. As Lantyr struggled to stand, blade waving in a still impressive defensive stance, he rushed forwards, planting his weapon directly into Lantyr’s chest, crushing the eldar and his soulstone in a single strike. The Void Ripper did not even manage to wheeze once.

No pride or glory for Apollo Diomedes. Never again, he swore silently, never.

He activated the vox.

“Objective achieved, Chapter Master. The Corsair Prince is dead, and the rest of the ship is ours.”

=======================================

“May their alien technologies fail them when they need them most,” Derillion growled. “My teams are moving as best they can, but they know they are lost. The first explosions were for reinforcing webway portals. There is nowhere else for them to go.”

Gabriel slammed his hammer into another howling banshee, but there were ever fewer aspect warriors now, only more and more guardians taking up what weaponry they could.

“We might need to remove ourselves from the spire, and let the treachery of Biel-Tan take its course, Archamagos. We already have a great bounty in captured ships and wargear.”

“But there could be more! What secrets lie in this place,” Derillion insisted, “It is so far from the Omnissiah’s light, their records alone of this territory could be of immense value!”

“Without the Litany of Fury or multiple choirs reaching this area again would be dangerous in the extreme, Archmagos,” Gabriel returned, “Is it truly worth it?”

“It could be, that is the issue!”

Decisions For Final Phase (Choose One)

[] Who Dares, Wins: There are already scuttling charges going off in the Haven Spire. But if the whole of the Chapter was used, it might be possible to save the Spire from being completely destroyed, allowing for more long-term examination. It would be dangerous, however, some of the station is already damaged including multiple internal components. Archmagos Derillion wishes to continue in this course, and would appreciate your support. (Warning, Chance of Significant Losses)
[] Take The Spoils: You have gained much, and lost much. Retreat fully from the Spire. Derillion might be personally upset, but the greater Mechanicus cannot possibly be anything but grateful for what you have gained for them this day. The battle is over, now is the time to regroup and resupply. (Operation Ends, No More Losses/Injury Chances, Move On To End Point)

Assets/Brothers Lost:
2 Unassigned Thunderhawk Gunships
35 Scout Marines 1st Stage (+11 Gene-Seed)
5 Scout Marines 2nd Stage (+3 Gene-Seed)
7 4th Company Marines Slain (+10 Gene-Seed)
3 1st Company Marines Slain (+4 Gene-Seed)
5 5th Company Marines Slain (+10 Gene-Seed)

Marines Injured:
8 4th Company Marines Heavily Injured
3 1st Company Marines Heavily Injured
10 5th Company Marines Heavily Injured
1 5th Company Marine Requires Dreadnought Internment

Eldar Ships Departing To Rejoin Craftworld Biel-Tan [?] (Almost All Ships Sustained Moderate To Significant Damage):
1 Void Dragon (Dragonship) Cruiser [Biel-Tan]
2 Shadow Cruisers [Biel-Tan]
1 Hemlock [Biel-Tan]
4 Shadow Cruisers [Corsairs]
1 Eclipse Cruiser/Carrier [Corsairs]
2 Hellebore Frigate [Corsairs]
3 Hemlock Destroyers [Corsairs]
2 Aconite Frigates [Corsairs]

Fleets Present In Unknown System said:

Blood Raven Assets
1st Company Fleet
4th Company Fleet
5th Company Fleet
10th Company Fleet

- Battle Barge Litany of Fury has taken minor damage across hull, damage to forward weapons.
- Battle Barge Omnis Arcanum has taken minor damage across hull, notable damage to prow and forward weapons.
- Battle Barge Scientia Est Potentia has taken damage across prow, forward weapons damaged, propulsion and shielding systems intact.
- Strike Cruiser Spiraling Fury has taken damage to engine systems and weapon systems, shielding systems unharmed.
- Strike Cruiser Burning Seeker has taken damage to hull.
- Strike Cruiser Rage of Erudition has taken significant damage to weapon systems, propulsion unharmed. Damage capabilities reduced, boarding abilities maintained.
- Strike Cruiser The Great Father's Fist has taken significant damage to weapon and shield systems, propulsion unharmed.
- Strike Cruiser The Howling Hatred has taken damage to weapon systems. Propulsion and shielding fully functional.
- Strike Cruiser Ravenous Spirit has taken significant damage to weapon systems, minor damage to propulsion systems. Shielding systems intact.

Basilikon Astra Fleet [Aspect - Serpentium]
1 Basiikon Emperor-class Omnissiah’s Piercing Sight
1 Basilikon Retribution-class Blade of Zerann [Engines Disabled/Weapon Systems Damaged]
4 Basilikon Mechanicus Cruisers
4 Basilikon Mechanicus Light-Cruisers

Rim Stalker Assets Still Present
Haven Spire [WARNING: Internal sabotage present! Eldar crew at Fanatical Morale! Exercise extreme caution!

Eldar Assets Captured In Phase 4
2 Badly Damaged Nightshade Destroyers
1 Damaged Void Stalker/Corsair Flagship Ascendant Spear
1 Somewhat Damaged Void Stalker Fist of Khaine
1 Badly Damaged Shadow Cruiser
1 Pristine Shadow-class Cruiser

Eldar Assets Captured In Phase 3
- 2 Undamaged Hemlock Destroyers [Corsairs]
- 1 Undamaged Aconite Frigate [Biel-Tan]
- 2 Badly Damaged Aconite Frigates [Corsairs]
- 1 Badly Damaged Hemlock Destroyer [Biel-Tan]
- 1 Somewhat Damaged Shadow-class Cruiser [Corsairs]
- 1 Somewhat Damaged Nightshade Destroyer [Corsair]
- 1 Damaged Hellebore-class Frigate [Corsair]
- 1 Somewhat Damaged Hellebore-class Frigate [Corsair]

Eldar Assets Captured Previously
- 1 Badly Damaged Shadow-class Cruiser [Corsairs]
- 3 Somewhat-Undamaged Hemlock Destroyers [Corsairs]
- 1 Badly Damaged Hemlock Destroyer [Corsairs]

Click to expand...

Click to shrink...

Karak Eight Peaks: A Final Victory

Spoiler [*] Fire [*] Explosives Tied vote. For a few moments your thoughts linger on the thought of a dawn Burning Shadows to eat at the flesh of any greenskins attempting to reinforce the Citadel. It may be that never before have circumstances aligned to make the usually finicky spell so potentially effective. But with any potential shamans out there cloaked in the still-lurking Waaagh energies and the groups too scattered to have any hope of checking all of them, the unknowns are too many and the stakes too high for you to put the success or failure of the assault on that single spell. So you instead move on to two more conventional options. "Two possibilities suggest themselves," you say with confidence. "As I saw with the Doom Diver wings and the hovels in the Hall of the Moon, greenskins construction tends to be flammable. From what I've seen of the caldera, most of the town is in various states of disrepair, the majority of it appearing to be entirely abandoned. With enough accelerant it would be possible to get a fire raging that will prevent any reinforcements from reaching the Citadel. The only problem is that depending how much time there is between ignition and inferno, some of the groups may be able to reach the Citadel. It's not very hard a deduction to realize we're likely to be attacking it, especially since the fastest ways to start a fire would involve the Grudge Throwers, which would make our involvement obvious." Ulthar frowns in thought. "They prefer pelt or hide, but there's not enough to go around with this many of them in one place. So they'd likely be using mushroom thread, which... well, I've used dried mushrooms as tinder to start fires in the past." "Could mix something up," Durin added. "Lamp oil and sawdust and a few other things in a barrel, wrap it in rags." "The Grobi are not ones to be caught unready for a fight, though," King Belegar mused. "What's the other?" "I've spoken to Durin," you say, and he nods. "A gunpowder charge could cave in the entrance to the Citadel from the caldera. The issue is of scale. Too little and it doesn't work, too much and the structural integrity of the Citadel is threatened. I'd have to bring an expert to place the charge, or it will be a choice between risking failure and risking the Citadel." "Could you?" King Belegar asks. "I could get through the Citadel alone, no problem. But with an expert? There's no Rangers with the right expertise, the closest is a Clan Huzkul Miner. He'd essentially be cargo. I believe it to be possible, but..." "But too many unknowns for guarantees." King Belegar sighs. "I'm afraid so." King Belegar stares into the distance, fingers drumming as he thinks. "The fire," he finally says. "I'd rather risk a fraction of the Grobi getting through than the Citadel being completely open. Do you have a back-up?" You run through the options. The gunpowder plan wouldn't be fast enough. The shadow plan requires morning. "Archers," you say. "Once the ranged weapon caches in the Citadel are destroyed, they could fire from the lip of the caldera at the approach to the Citadel." "I'd rather have them firing on the Citadel," Belegar grouses. "Hopefully it won't be necessary. Ulthar, Titus, Marksman Petrescu. Have your archers ready to deploy to support on assault on the Citadel, but at a hornblow they are instead to move to the edge of the caldera and prevent reinforcements. Durin. The destruction of those weapon caches is now doubly vital." "I've a few ideas," he says. "Put them in motion. Kragg, how's your Anvil?" Anyone else asking that would receive a several minute long diatribe on the difficulty of hairline cracks in gromril, but King Belegar received only a grimace. "I see. Do not endanger it unduly, but be at hand, just in case. Master Weber, does the fire plan require your personal intervention?" "Not necessarily." "Then I ask that you be ready to disperse any enemy magic. Marksman Petrescu, Grandmaster Wulfhart, your infantry will be the sword and the shield. The men who performed so well yesterday shall stand ready to receive any greenskin sally in response to the fire and the bombardment, but if they decline, those of the Wolf God are to go in and punish their cowardice. Grandmaster Kriegersen, be at hand and be ready. If the greenskins do sally, you may have an opportunity to repeat yesterday's rout. Any questions?" A rumble of nos. "Then let's get to it." --- The camp bustles with activity as the sun passes its zenith, and though the Dwarves swear by a light ale before battle, a light lunch is distributed to those who prefer a little more substance. Four of your five Journeymanlings sit with you as you spoon your way through your soup. "Don't give him any," you say without looking up, and Panoramia lifts her soup back up from where she had been lowering it for Wolf. "How did you-" "Grey Order," you reply instantly, and Panoramia rolls her eyes. "Familiar bond," Esbern says with a smile. "But she's right. Onion's no good for dogs." "Oh, of course." She looks up from the half-grown pup, which has turned his eyes to Maximilian. You wonder if he's able to understand enough of the world through you to know the bread has no such protection, or if he's just trying the next softest target. "Where's the other Goldie?" "Johann is with the cannon crews," you say. The other, unspoken reason is the rift between him and Maximilian. "It'll be important for the first few shots to be right on target. The rest of you will be on dispel duty with me." "I'm surprised you're not out there killing all the shamans in advance," says Maximilian, his voice teetering between admiration and jealousy. "Your previous work is all I hear about from most Dwarves I've spoken to." "The idea had crossed my mind, but the most important factor is preventing reinforcements. A few slit throats would have the greenskins on edge, might convince them to stop fighting amongst themselves." "You say it so casually," Panoramia says. "I'm familiar with slitting throats like you are with helping plants grow. In almost every situation, it's the best way I can contribute." "Do you ever wish-" Panoramia cuts herself off. But it's a fair question. "I wasn't born a Dame. If I didn't have magic, I'd be in a thatch hut on a tiny farm, probably on my fifth or sixth child right now, unless a plague or a famine or some roaming terror from Sylvania had carried me off." That's the easy part of the question, but it's not what she was asking. What if you weren't of the Grey? "I love Ulgu, but I probably would have loved any other Wind if I'd ended up elsewhere. The duties of the Grey Order are possibly the heaviest - except maybe Shyish." A nod of accord from all. Nobody envied the Amethyst Order. "I'd probably be happy amongst the Gold," you say, nodding at Maximilian. "Just before my Magister examination, I realized I could be happy if all I focused on was learning all I could - as long as I had someone else write my papers for me." You nod to Esbern and Seija. "And the Amber... I've spent a lot of days on the back of my Shadowhorse, and I've found the wild can be addictive. If I had thinking company instead of magic in the shape of a horse, I might want to spend my entire life there." Finally, to Panoramia again. "As for Jade... I visited your College, once. It was beautiful. It would be nice if the products of my work was the same." You pause as your mind flits through the other options. Bright Order Mathilde? Likely even more at home on a battlefield than you are already. Celestial and Light Order, though... no thanks. But you know better not to say those parts out loud. "But look." You wave a hand at bulk of Karag Nar, stretching high above you. "Karag Nar. In the past thousand years, the only humans to ever know that name would have been a handful of Dwarven history obsessives at the University of Altdorf. Now it's looking like humans are going to be living in it. Karak Eight Peaks won't be a historical footnote, it will be a home for Dwarves and for Halflings and for men. The throats I slit yesterday were ugly, but the better tomorrow they've bought is beautiful." Your mind goes back seven years, to the first time your actions had resulted in blood. "We deal death to the corrupt to prevent the suffering of the innocent." The moment stretches, as your fellow wizards allow you to spend another few seconds lost in memory. Then a wave of simple joy washes over you and you smile, knowing that Maximilian has finally surrendered some of his bread. "I should have stuck with the soup," he gripes. "Still, who serves onion soup before a battle?" You smile. "Nordlander trick," you say. "If someone has a gut wound, feed them onion soup. If you can smell it on their wound, they're beyond saving. The Halflings figured if they're going to be making a batch anyway, might as well scale up and give it to everyone." Panoramia grimaces down at her now-empty bowl, and Maximilian sighs and surrenders the rest of his bread to Wolf. "So," you continue. "The Expedition will be wrapping up soon. Plans?" "One of the Clan Angrund Dwarves was a smith in Zhufbar before King Belegar recalled them all," Maximilian says. "He's agreed to teach me, as long as we both survive that long." "Titus will be commissioning me," Panoramia says. "Help get the crops set up in the Eastern Valley. The soil's hard done by and there's concerns about the water, so it'll be a big job. He's going to give me a promissory note I can exchange in Eicheschatten, and that plus the Expedition pay will be my College dues taken care of." You look to Esbern and Seija, who exchange glances of their own. "Returning to the Empire with the Knights, most likely," Esbern says. "We get on well with them." "I might have a task here you could find interesting," you say. "But we can talk of that after the battle." "What about you?" Panoramia asks. You frown thoughtfully, your hand moving to scratch Wolf's belly as he curls up beside you. You've given the matter a fair bit of thought. King Belegar's made it clear you'd be welcome here, and that could be interesting. Perhaps he could use a manling advisor on his council, perhaps the ongoing war for the rest of the Karak could occupy you, perhaps you could set up a laboratory and investigate a few matters you've been meaning to look into for far too long. On the other hand, you've still got friends in Stirland, and there's the whole rest of the world out there, too. "Haven't quite decided yet," you admit. --- From the Citadel, a dozen pairs of eyes glared at the single Dwarf who walked across the Eastern Valley. Hands closed on weapons as they debated whether to sally out to strike at the insolent git. But the mountains, they knew, could sprout a volley of arrows without warning, and somewhere out there were those lionbirds with the metal humie gits on top. So they watched sullenly as the Dwarf took measurements, and a spark of curiosity arose as the Dwarf drew a line in the dirt with a foot. But the Dwarf returned back to the fortified Eastern Gate, which bristled with enough weaponry to intimidate a legion of Black Orcs, and they forgot about him. Not long after, the inner gates opened once more, and a caravan trundled out. Twenty covered wagons, some pulled by horses, some by oxen. The previous garrison of the Citadel had allowed themselves to be drawn in by bait such as this before, and each time they had been food for giant wolves or lionbirds. The current garrison was smaller in number, and more cautious for it. But they were no less greedy, and as the convoy plodded through the Eastern Valley, more and more eyes were fixated on it. "Food," one says. "Betcha they're fulla food." "Who cares what's in 'em," says another. "Lookit them cows. That's dinner." "Choppas," a third disagrees. "Proper glintymetal choppas. No more havin' ta use rocks." "Booze," says a fourth. "Stunties always have booze." "Why's they stoppin'?" came the question, and all those that were staring started to stare harder. "Gotta be worth a shot," one says, but a tide of disagreement rose to meet him. "Little 'umies with arrers." "Stunties with rock lobbas." "Lionbirds." A chorus of agreement. Nobody wanted to meet the lionbirds again. "They getin' closer?" one asks, doubtfully. [Approach: Intrigue, 89+17=106.] "Nah," says another. "They'z goin' ta Mount Crooked Moon, same as the others." "Least they sorted that git," one growls, and is met with agreement. "With his greenrock teef and havin' rats insteada proppa squigs. Ain't right." "Yeah, then they went after-" "We don't talk about 'im!" comes the instant reply. "Mork is proppa good, roight?" "Roight!" is the hasty chorus. "And Gork is proppa good too and that's the end of that." A round of very careful agreement. "I still reckon they gettin' closer," says one. "What'd they be gettin' closer for, ya git? Reckon they're comin' for a visit? Bein' neighbourly?" Snickers and grins all around. "I reckon," comes the thoughtful response, as a series of thwacks is heard in the distance. "I reckon that-" B-boom, two blasts sounding almost as one. "I RECKON!" he yells, and sighs as a pair of impacts shakes the Citadel, and screams of wounded joins the din. He scowls, and waits for the tumult to die down, until the only sound is the crackling of fire behind the Citadel. "Loik I was sayin'," he finally says. "I reckon they're gettin' close coz they gotta bunch of 'umies and a few of dem big shooty things in the wagons." --- [Orc reaction: 38+15=53.] The plan went off without a hitch, and the only concern is that they might have reacted while the few catapults and cannon were protected only by a few squads of men. But the Citadel did not disgorge its garrison and from Karag Nar came the remainder of those that would receive any charge: the sellswords and vagabonds and mercenaries, once thought the least reliable portion of the army, yesterday the heroes of the day, and today given a chance to prove themselves once and for all. From the King's Armoury, thousands of ancient silversteel pikes had been distributed to the men, and instead of their previous motley assortment of blades a forest of shining points stood between them and the Citadel. [Durin's accelerant: 60+20=80.] [Fire below: 7+40(Accelerant)=47.] [First group of reinforcements: 80.] Atop Karag Lhune, the sharpest eye and the finest telescope had been combined with a flagpole and a prearranged code. A single green flag had you grimace; the fire was burning, but one lot of greenskins had gotten through. Perhaps you should have sold the gunpowder plan better. Perhaps you should have gone with the shadow plan. But it was too late for what-ifs, and with the agonizing slowness of the time just before a battle, the forces of the Expedition spilled out of the East Gates and the mountains to arrange themselves on the battlefield. Now six thousand, seven hundred shining pikes dared the greenskins to attack. Perhaps they'd feel confident enough to do so, with reinforcements. [Orc reaction: 90+15+10(Reinforcements)] [Fire below: 40+47(previous roll)=87] [Second group of reinforcements: 70.] Underneath the green flag, one of blue. Blue for Clan Angrund, blue for success. The second set of greenskins had been stopped, and the archers were to remain in place. But the Citadel greenskins were encouraged enough by the first group, or so it seemed, as a fraction of a second after the battlecry of WAAAGH! had risen from a thousand throats or more, greenskins once more spilled out of the Citadel. It was time for men to demonstrate whether or not their performance the previous day was a fluke. But though the greenskin tide was worrying, this was not a crowd maddened by the demands of an infuriated God. This was greenskins that had weighed up a fight and decided they wanted to have it, and that made you worry what they had up their sleeves. [Greenskin shamans?: 79, 89. One Great Shaman, three lesser Shaman.] And, it seems, you were right to be concerned. Perhaps your reputation had reached even the greenskins, perhaps Mork had whispered in some ears to be on the look out, perhaps it was as simple as one magic-user recognizing another. Inside the Citadel an Ork thrust his head forward, uncaring of the pain as it hit the carved stone to either side of the arrowslit he had been peeking through, and a shockwave of green energy flew forth from the motion directly at you. ['Eadbutt: 36+20=56.] [Counterspell: 8+20=28.] Perhaps he was masked by the crackling energies of the Waaagh from the charge of a thousand Orcs, perhaps he was unusually cunning, perhaps you expected a longer wind-up time than a single headbutt. If you had nothing to rely on but your wits, you would have eaten a magical headbutt directly to the face. But the raw and wild magic was met by a rising wave of tamed Runic magic. The energies of the spell are shattered as a Rune on your belt glows red-hot and a similar fire burns inside the brain of the Orc that cast it. But that wasn't all the Citadel had in store, as while the Great Shaman screamed in agony as all knowledge of magical headbutts was cauterized from his living brain, three lesser shamans worked in concert to summon their God - or at least, one part of him. [Foot of Gork: 8+15=23. Miscast.] [Miscast roll: 2, 4. Calamitous Detonation.] And though your group of Journeymen and Journeywomen stood ready to counter whatever their greenskin counterparts had prepared, there was no need. If your little chat with Panoramia yesterday didn't get the message across, she was going to get an even better demonstration of what happens when someone bites off more than they can chew. An enormous explosion of green energy shakes the Citadel, and you grimly hope that it put paid to the overambitious spellcasters inside. [Codrin's archers: 92+15+5(Atoning)=112.] [Ulthar's archers: 86+15=101.] [Titus' archers: 70+15=85.] [Greenskin morale: 76+15+10(Reinforced)=101.] While the magical duel had been fought, the greenskin assault had been continuing. With mechanical efficiency, row after row of Orcish attackers had been cut down by brutally efficient volleys, and only an expert on fletching could tell you which volley had come from which archers, so alike in speed and accuracy were they. But the greenskins charged onwards undeterred, each row making it another few feet before being cut down to be followed by the next. Who but the terrible greenskins could ignore such losses and fight on? [Greenskin attack: 59+15+10(Reinforced)=84.] [Manling defence: 43+15+10(High Morale)+20(Silversteel Pikes receiving a charge)=88.] With a terrible earth-shaking crash, the line of greenskins finally hit the rows of men. Those first to strike the pikes were no more fortunate than all those that had met the arrows, but for every greenskin that impaled itself against a pike there was another shoving past him to swing a choppa at the man who held it. Orcish battle fury met the newly awakened pride of man, and neither would give an inch. [Great Shaman - 'Eadbutt?] [Lesser Shamans - 'Ere We Go: 35+15-10(Detonated)=40.] [Counterspell: 79+20=99.] [Induce miscast: 100.] Meanwhile in the Citadel, the greatest magic-user amongst them tied in vain to remember... something? His seared brain ached as again and again he reached for information he knew was there, but arcane fire had taken from him. His underlings were a little better off, and the two that survived tried to assist their fellows as best they can. The Waaagh energy that linked all greenskins solidified, and a tendril extended from the Citadel and was drawn towards the mob of fighting Orcs. You stare at it, feeling almost insulted. Surely this must be a trick. Not even greenskins would be so careless as to- but no, you can see clear as day that what you see in front of you is what there is. The shamans are trying to form an aethyric link between themselves and the Waaagh energy below them, and presumably once the link was formed they'd imbue it with magic and change its nature to one that would enhance the combat abilities of the Orc. It would be utterly trivial to reach out and sever the half-formed link, and you have to reach out and slap Maximilian's hand absently as he reaches to do so. With infuriating slowness, the link stretches forward... and just as it connects with the battlefield before you, you give it a poke. Just a little one. Not enough to dispel or even disrupt the spell. All it does is pierce the aethyric membrane in exactly the right place so that instead of a single line through which the shamans can send energy, the link has become an enormous straw through which energy can travel. And the magically-created aethyric link of Waaagh energy was a thousand times easier for ambient Waaagh energy to travel through than the air between the fighting Orcs, and on the other side, amongst the shamans, the air permeated with Waaagh energy from the previous explosion was a thousand times more suited to Waaagh energies than the battlefield outside, with thousands of Dwarves and unfriendly mages and the disapproving gaze of Kragg. In the space of a few seconds, every jot of Waaagh energy that had surrounded the fighting Orcs flew up the aethyric link and into the shamans' chamber. In the space of a few seconds, the shamans were filled with the bloodlust of thousands of fighting Orcs, and their bodies barely contained the energy long enough for them to gouge fatal wounds in one another with bulging muscles. In the space of a few seconds, every single Orc was robbed of the aura they had never known the absence of. In the space of a few seconds, the battle is won. Not a single man pauses to question his fortune as his adversary freezes in confusion and terror and the sudden disconnect from the Waaagh. Each cuts down the Orc in front of them, and then the next nearest, and then levels their pike and charges forward at those that had a moment ago been charging them, and barely a scrap of resistance is met before they disappear into the Citadel and out of sight. [Fire below: 87+40=127. Further reinforcement impossible.] --- "Any of them," King Belegar says. "Hell, all of them if they're willing. Any Dwarf who took a greenskin charge that well would never have to pay for drinks again, and those manlings did so twice. And that extends to you as well." "I'm honoured, your Majesty," Codrin replies. "But my home is in Stirland. But I believe a great many of the men will take you up on your offer." Codrin departs to pass on the message, and you watch him thoughtfully. As it turns out, the distribution of Dwarf-made pikes had been an implicit offer, and their performance today had Belegar make it completely clear: any of the manling vagabonds, wanderers and mercenaries that had fought as part of the Expedition were welcome to make it their home, and with it came an offer of employment: to patrol, protect, and watch over the East Gate and Death Pass. To the average citizen of the Empire, that might sound unappealing, but to anyone who had sold their sword south of Black Fire Pass, three routes dominated. The Silver Road, half of which fell under the aegis of Karaz-a-Karak and the second half under the predations of the greenskins of Mount Grimfang. Mad Dog Pass, taxed thrice over by Border Princes and raided with impunity by the Ironclaw Orcs of Iron Rock. And Death Pass, worst of all, dominated by the Red Fang Tribe of Black Crag and the varied and numerous inhabitants of Karak Eight Peaks. Any trader who could reach the distant lands of Ind and Cathay and Nippon and return would become rich beyond their wildest dreams. Most who tried became dead. Everyone who thinks themselves skilled or lucky enough to try it looks to the World's Edge Mountains and decides which of three terrible options they thought they had the best chance of surviving. But if one could bypass Black Crag, and if one knew that Karak Eight Peaks was retaken enough to secure the eastern half of Death Pass... Back at Barak Varr, you had assumed that King Belegar had been promising some share of lost wealth or ancient secrets to King Byrrnoth to secure his assistance. Now you realize that the forgotten treasures of the distant past were of no interest to him. No, the King of a trading hub would turn his gaze not to immediate profit, but to his map, and to those ephemeral and unreliable strings that represented the flow of goods from distant lands. Barak Varr did not need payment, because with one less murderous hurdle between Barak Varr and the distant east, Barak Varr would profit immensely. Doubly, triply, quadruply so, since this new route relied on going up the Blood River, which only Dwarven steam-artifice could fight the flow of. Caravans of food and water and sundry other supplies? If the Expedition succeeded, each would be repaid by a caravan of spices and silks and jewels, and each had no choice but to pass through Barak Varr. The final thing it needed was for King Belegar to have at his disposal a force that could worry about keeping the road open, rather than being locked in a war of attrition inside the Karak. With these men, he had acquired it. "Spoke to Kragg," King Belegar says, shaking you from your ponderings. "He said a whole lot about how only a greenskin could be stupid enough to allow the opening that they allowed you. But after that, he said that he had no choice but to concede that you were clever to exploit it the way you did, rather than just batting the spell aside. Needless to say, that's the highest of praise anyone, man or Dawi, is likely to get from him." He looks down in thought, and you follow his gaze. Where once the slave pit had been was freshly-quarried stone, and with typical Dwarven efficiency the area that stone had been carved from was to become a tomb for those who had fallen in the Karak's retaking. It was meant to be a stop-gap measure until a proper job could be done, but King Belegar had declared it would remain until the end of days, so that neither he nor his descendants could forget the price of the home he had retaken. "Expedition's done," he says. "Could keep it going a while longer and throw more lives against the other Karags, but I'd rather use the current high spirits to purchase lives instead of deaths. The men..." he pauses. "Hard to summarize them. There's the Stirland men, there's the Ulrican men, there's the Knights, and then there's the... everyone else. Wouldn't be a problem except the everyone else turned out to be hard as stone. So those that accept my offer will be the Undumgi." "Watchpost men?" you hazard. "Watchpost would be dokaraz. Mingol if it's built in the lowlands. Und is a watchpost carved into a mountain, which needless to say is the best kind there is, just as these men have proven themselves. Anyway, they'll be set up in Karag Nar. Immediate access to the East Gate, and they'll have outposts at Und-Uzgar and at the Underway entrance. The Winter Wolves will build their new chapterhouse at the top of the valley on the other side, they like it nice and cold and up a mountain is the only place you get that down here. The Ulricans are talking of making a home in the valley, under the theocratic authority of the Wolves - it's not set in stone yet, they're going to set up a sawmill in the valley while they decide if they like the place. I'll gladly buy all the timber they can cut from it, and if they decide to move on they'll have a little more in their coffers. Stirlanders are taking their pay and heading home to buy a slightly larger field and a slightly larger cottage. The Halflings were already in, and once the defensive wall against Kvinn-Wyr is set up they'll start building homes throughout the Eastern Valley. And Clan Angrund and Clan Huzkul and the Clans from Karak Izor will call Karag Lhune home." He sighs, a little happily and a little wistfully. "There'll be war on our doorstep, but such is the case for damn near everyone in these times. We'll keep pushing back what Grobi remain, and sure as the seasons turn, the Thaggoraki will make a play before too long. Karak Azul's lads will arrive any day, and there'll be plenty of work for them to do, and I daresay when word gets out that we've succeeded as much as we have, we'll be beard-deep in those seeking treasure and glory. "The question remains, however, of where your own self will be." You raise an eyebrow. "I told you you're forever welcome here and that won't change, but I daresay you seek more than just a mountain over your head and ale in your belly. Near half a year ago, you told me you were strollendreki. Seeking a worthy purpose. If you think you've found one, tell me what it is and if it's within my power I'll move mountains to make it so. Otherwise, I daresay there'd be plenty of distraction to be found here in my Karak, for as long as you desire it." He watches you for a moment, and undoubtedly sees the lack of answer in you. "No rush. The next few months are going to be a mess, and there'll be a thousand and one ways to keep yourself busy until then." Though the Expedition is coming to an end, something of this size does not stop on a dime. The full disintegration will take weeks or even months, and as King Belegar says, there's plenty of ways to keep yourself busy. Your choice here will not bind you to a future path, but they are a first step down them. The three with the most votes will be selected. [ ] Travel to Karaz-a-Karak with King Belegar for the striking out of several well-aged grudges. This suggests a future assisting Karak Eight Peaks with foreign relations, as a Spymaster focused on threats outside the Karak. [ ] Scout the rest of the Eight Peaks, to find out what other horrors are waiting out there. This suggests a future assisting Karak Eight Peaks with its reconquest, as a Spymaster focused on threats within the Karak. [ ] Join Karak Azul as they raid and scout in force the other portions of the Karak. This suggests a future assisting Karak Eight Peaks with its reconquest, as a battlefield wizard. [ ] You could help the Undumgi and the Ulricans establish themselves. This suggests a future assisting Karak Eight Peaks, as leader of the Undumgi and point of contact for the Ulricans. [ ] Write a series of papers on the magical phenomena you witnessed. Or better yet, get your Journeymanlings to do the actual writing. This suggests a future of investigation and study at Karak Eight Peaks, and perhaps helping Johann poke at Skaven technology. [ ] There's a lot of prime real estate currently unclaimed. Stake out a prime position for a wizard's tower. This suggests a future catching up on your pre-existing study topics. [ ] All this time away has made you miss your friends. Visit Anton and Wilhelmina. This suggests a future in Stirland, whether Roswita likes it or not. [ ] You're going to have a rough time explaining your windfall to the Bursars. Better to get that over with. This suggests a future performing an assignment the Grey Order thinks is suited to you. [ ] You've been out of touch for a while. Head to Barak Varr and then Altdorf, and catch up with what's been happening in the Empire. This suggests a future seeking employment on the Council of an Elector Count. [ ] Not every sellsword will accept King Belegar's offer of employment. Travel with them. This suggests a future as a travelling mercenary. [Mathilde acquires Skill: Waaaghbane: +20 to attempts to dispel and induce miscasts against any Little or Big Waaagh spells. -20 for greenskins to attempt the same to you.] - There are three months left in 2478. That time will be spent bringing this arc to a close and tallying up your gains. Your choices will not lock you into a course, but it would be wise to have paved the way at least slightly for what you end up deciding. The final lock-in vote will be very clearly marked as such. - If you choose an option that suggests remaining in Karak Eight Peaks, you will be able to try to convince Esbern and Seija to remain, whether to help tackle the Chiselwards spiders or to puzzle out your supposedly Lustrian eggs. - In the coming updates, your stat changes, trait selection, monetary payment, and accumulated Dwarf Favour will be sorted out, most likely one at a time. - If there's another path into the future you wish to see represented, let me know. - Remember how Stirland was: even if you choose a role, there'll still be time for side-projects.

Karak Eight Peaks: Expeditionary Epilogue 1

Spoiler: Voting results [*] There's a lot of prime real estate currently unclaimed. Stake out a prime position for a wizard's tower. [*] Travel to Karaz-a-Karak with King Belegar for the striking out of several well-aged grudges. [*] You could help the Undumgi and the Ulricans establish themselves. The sheer power of concentrated Runecraft in the hands of Clan Angrund, the spectacular display of the Anvil of Doom, the induced inversion of a Waaagh field. All sights unknown, as far as you are aware, to the Colleges of Magic. It feels wrong to let this opportunity slip away, and yet in such a pivotal moment in history there are more opportunities than any one person can grab, so the best you can do is have your flock of Journeymanlings jot down their observations so that they will still be available when you have time to fully translate them into something more suited to academia. With Esbern and Seija looking like they would soon depart, it could be that there would never be an opportunity to get this many perspectives on foreign magic. With that task finished, you travel with the three Knightly Orders and the mass of now-united Ulricans as they march out the East Gate, up Death Pass and through the Underway to the once-pristine valley that was soon to be colonized, the Demigryph Knights having agreed to help the Winter Wolves range out from what is to be their new home to ensure a lack of immediate threats and carefully gauge the inevitable less immediate threats. You decide to lend your own horse to this task. Thunder Mountain lies nearby, the mighty volcano that the Anvils of Doom were once forged in, and the possibility of Dragon Ogres atop it concerns you greatly. The only thing that keeps the terrible beasts in check is their reliance on revitalizing lightning, and if the constant storm of ash and volcanic gases serves to bypass this weakness, the colony might be doomed before it even begins. As it turns out, the cure may be worse than the disease. Your careful scouting reveals to you many Dragon Ogres living at the rim of the volcano, but each is sickly and listless. Their inhuman constitutions may allow them to survive the horrific environment, but they certainly aren't thriving, and it seems the volcanic lightning lacks at least some of what makes the power of storms so revitalizing to them. Though they remain quite capable of picking off individual greenskins to feed upon, you fancy the chances of the Winter Wolves against this enemy, and are able to turn away from them with a clean conscience. Turning your attention west, you range across quite a lot of empty land. According to conventional maps this is the Border Princes, but it is the southernmost part of it, sandwiched between Iron Rock and the Badlands. Those foolhardy enough to settle between the Howling River and the Blood River discover even poorer soil and drier weather than the rest of the region, and soon come to the attention of the Ironclaw Orcs. It doesn't take long to realize why most of the inhabitants of the Border Princes remain north of the Black Gulf. With the Blood River to act as a barrier and land that seems better worth the effort, you think that the Ulricans will have much better chances. You return to the valley, where already trees have begun to fall as the Ulricans turn their axes to timber instead of greenskin. The Barak Varr traders delivering supplies to Karak Eight Peaks have been talking to the Ulricans, and before you leave the valley the first Dwarf Monitor has docked at what's being called Ulrikadrin, accepting silver and disgorging tools and supplies. For now, the Winter Wolves will be living in tents, and as soon as the tools are put to use they'll be living in wooden bunkhouses, but as soon as the Knights make up their mind on some of the details, the residents of Karak Eight Peaks will be travelling here to carve paths and a suitable Chapter House into one of the peaks overlooking the valley. --- Back at Karak Eight Peaks, Karag Nar is the site of no small amount of grumbling and you wade in before it gets much worse. Though the men are currently sleeping on bedrolls in communal halls in the Karag, what their future situation will look like is still undecided, and in between making final preparations to leave Codrin is keeping the peace but making no long-term decisions for his soon-to-be former charges. You're not sure if some new leader would have emerged if things went on much longer, but you'd much rather not risk the future of Death Pass on a maybe, so you step in. Everyone, it seems, wants to stake a claim on a set of quarters adjoining the central staircase, and with no other landmarks in the entire mountain you can see why. You refresh your own scouting memories with some poking around, and in a temporary office you work on a MAP of the main branches of the Karag. You map out a market for visiting merchants, a dining hall for group meals, and an armoury for the tools of the Undumgi's trade, and put word out for anyone who wishes to stick around without combat in their future, and there's a handful - young mercenaries think they'll be happy to fight their entire lives, but old ones start to dream of a tavern or a grocer or some other peaceful retirement, and you carefully distribute some of the larger rooms to them. Some are of a religious bent, and you approve shrines to Shallya, Ulric, Myrmidia, Ursun, and the Lady. You also receive a few unexpected requests, and after a word to an equally bemused King Belegar, you plot out the future locations of shrines to Grimnir and Valaya. With landmarks more plentiful and more scattered, instead of fighting over the most central positions the Undumgi start making decisions based on their preferences. Some want a nearby tavern, some want a favoured shrine close by, some want to be a good distance from the shopping and the prayer. Before long everyone has a room that you've had the few literate Undumgi write the names of their owners onto in charcoal, and you have full blueprints tucked away in case anyone gets cheeky and tries to replace a name with their own. Soon, wood will flow from Ulrikadrin and supplies from Barak Varr will include trade goods, and people will be able to start making proper homes for themselves. Long term, you expect companionship to be a concern, but word of almost six thousand newly enriched, well-employed and very eligible bachelors will soon reach Barak Varr and start radiating through the Border Princes and heading towards Black Fire Pass, and with a little luck the problem will solve itself. [Total payment: 54.] [How did Mathilde's share do?: 37.] Speaking of payment, the first round of it has gone out. Belegar had expected to pay in ingots, but at you presenting the paperwork of your one-night gambling hall, he had grumbled in an extremely unconvincing way and then hurried enthusiastically off to rummage through the carefully packed heirlooms that had been passed down through generations of exile. With the careful oversight of suitably skilled Longbeards, for the first time in three thousand years a coin is struck bearing the Eight Peaks you had all fought for. Each of the ingots would make 60 silver coins, each similar in weight to the silver shilling of the Empire but a great deal purer in content, and 20 silver shillings were worth a gold crown. The final division of the ancient stockpile of silver, minus the amount Belegar saw fit to keep for his Kingdom, saw each share worth fourteen ingots. Any man foolish enough to trust the sums of an Empire moneychanger would receive 42 gold crowns for them, whereas their true value would be closer to 55. The striking out of money owed to and from the dead saw your own 'share' fall by about a quarter, but that still left three thousand, six hundred and seventy set aside in the safety of the King's Armoury for you to decide the fate of. The equivalent of fourteen thousand gold crowns, give or take. You try not to think about the Oath of Poverty you were supposed to be following, and start trying to make plans for the money. You've some available loopholes, but that does mean you'd have to predestine at least three quarters of it towards a single area. [ ] This is Dame Weber's money. The funds will largely go towards investment in Stirland - possibly your fief, possibly the EIC, possibly investing elsewhere within the province. [ ] This is Magister Weber's money. Make no attempt to push the funds through any of the available loopholes and spend it all in plain sight of the College. You would be beholden to spend it on ways at least nominally good for the Empire, and soon. [ ] This is Dawongr Weber's money. The funds will largely go projects within the Karaz Ankor - your tower for one, but also investing in the Undumgi or Ulrikadrin, or purchasing goods made by Dwarven artisans or sold in the markets of Barak Varr. [ ] This is tomorrow's problem. Let the money sit in the King's Armoury for now. Once you've decided what your future will be, then you can decide what to do with the money. --- To distract yourself from your unseemly wealth, you go shopping for a tower. ...okay, perhaps that only makes it seem worse, but it is something that needs to be done. As Karag Nar has demonstrated, there's a lot of real estate being snapped up right now and if you want something nice you better make a move early. [ ] Karag Nar penthouse The first possibility that leaps to mind is the uppermost dwelling of Karag Nar, with a beautiful 360-degree view and a commanding position. The Black Orc Warboss' reasons for taking it for his own are obvious, and though it will take some time and effort to clear out the possessions that hadn't been safely stowed in the King's Armoury, it is bursting with potential and would allow you to keep a careful eye on the Undumgi and Death Pass. [ ] Karag Lhune secondary peak The second possibility is the secondary peak of Karag Lhune that the greenskins positioned their Doom Diver battery atop. The landing pad atop it was made redundant thousands of years ago when a full hangar was built atop Karag Lhune, and it's just as redundant for modern gyrocopters as it was to ancient airships so it would be yours for the taking. The storerooms below offer plenty of room for expansion and you'd be conveniently close to the heart of the resurgent Karak. [ ] Citadel Tower Third, the Citadel is being repaired of the damage that Kragg and cannon dealt to it, as well as three thousand years of neglect, and though the two towers were once a key part of its defensibility, with the only enemy approach being within the caldera that height advantage should no longer be needed. It makes for a much more traditional Wizard's Tower than one in a mountain peak, and though it's currently part of the defensive line against the untaken parts of the Karak, that also means that there'll always be plenty of protectors on hand, and perhaps you'd like to be able to help repulse any attackers. [ ] Karag Nar temple Your previous 'tower' was nothing of the sort, and perhaps you wish to continue that trend. If so, the site of you and Ranald triumphing over Gork and Mork would certainly be equally auspicious. It's a convenient distance from the population centers of the Karag and has a nearby side-entrance you could properly conceal and keep for your own use. (note: if you don't choose this as a tower, you can still use it in the future for a shrine or some other purpose. Nobody but you, Belegar, and Kragg know its significance, and everyone else just sees it as a former greenskin temple an inconvenient distance from the rest of the Karag.) [ ] The Grand Abyss If you value secrecy over all else, you could go just as far down as you can up. Deep below Karag Lhune lies the Lhune Deeps, and below that is the Grand Abyss. The Dwarves never were able to plumb the extent of its depths, and that is somewhat concerning, but it would certainly be impressive to have a tower built atop a bottomless pit. [ ] Und-Uzgar Soon to be an outpost for the Undumgi, Und-Uzgar was the site of your shadow becoming outputtingly independent. Built into the side of Karag Lhune, it boasts a commanding view of Death Pass and the passage to the rest of the Karag will be excavated any day now. [ ] Eastern Valley tower Though it's soon to be filled with Halfling fields and cottages, they'd be happy for you to become their neighbour, and if you want to start from scratch you certainly have enough wealth and favours accumulated to build a tower of your own. [ ] The Silver Tower Legends of the Silver Tower have been told and retold a thousand times over - the place where plucky adventurers caused the downfall of the Gaunt Summoner. You're not entirely sure if this is the same Silver Tower, but you could make a claim on it even though it is built upon the as-yet unreclaimed Karagril. [ ] Other (write in) Perhaps you picture your tower somewhere as yet unreclaimed, perhaps you've got a different idea. Once chosen, there'll be a great deal of paperwork to fill out. Those few manlings allowed to live in Dwarfholds are typically given 'only' a lifetime lease, and for you to have an actual permanent claim to what you've decided upon takes a lot of carefully-worded documents that basically say 'no really, we mean it, forever'. --- King Belegar stuck around long enough to greet King Kazador and the Throng of Karak Azul, and was introduced with the subtlety of a thrown brick to King Kazador's daughter, Princess Kazrina. There's some grumbling that they've missed the actual establishment of the Karak, but are heartened that there's still six peaks left untaken and Ulthar steps in to pass on everything the Expedition knows of the other concentrations of greenskins and Skaven. A slightly smaller group splits off from the Throng, as for the first time in a dozen Dwarven generations the rest of the world is accessible to Karak Azul without incredible danger to life and limb, and they're not letting the chance pass. A third group is happily accepted into Karag Lhune - those of the lesser Clans of Karak Eight Peaks, who for three thousand years have longed for a return to the home of their ancestors rather than putting down roots where they were. In the coming weeks, others will join them from further holds, as many Dwarves have lived and died in exile rather than letting themselves find new homes among other holds. Both tragic and typically Dwarvish. Kragg has decided to stay just a little longer in Karak Eight Peaks, which is absolutely nothing to do with the arrival of Thorek Ironbrow, the closest thing to an equal Kragg has. The two very loudly criticize every detail of each other's work in terminology too arcane for you to begin to understand, and you're not entirely sure if this is a feud or a friendship, but either way Kragg seems to be enjoying himself, and he's finally surrendered his iron grip on the Gyrobomber that was to be his Anvil of Doom's escape route if everything went wrong. Without the incredibly dense weight of gromril weighing it down, it's more than capable of taking passengers, and with representatives from Karak Izor, Karak Norn, and Karak Hirn, you set off. You had thought your Shadowsteed a miracle of transportation, but even though the gyrobomber is built for cargo rather than speed, it must be covering ground at least twice as fast as you could, as well as easily capable of flying over terrain you'd have to ride around. It doesn't help that the 'passenger rack', though sturdy enough, offers little more protection from the elements than the back of a wagon, and does nothing to block out the noise of Dwarven machines. The pilot flies low to prevent the ambient air from freezing his passengers, so the view is as breathtakingly beautiful as it is terrifying, even though you're flying over the thoroughly unimpressive terrain of the Border Princes. As it begins to pall, the terrain changes to the endless green of the Forest of Gloom, and you keep your eyes peeled, knowing the next destination would be Karaz-a-Karak. You had braced for it, and still you find yourself stunned. You had seen drawings, and heard the boasts of Dwarves, but nothing prepared you for the reality. The Gates of Karaz-a-Karak stand four hundred feet tall, unadorned save for the Rune of Valaya similar to the one on your Belt. Once, according to history so far back as to be legend, the Gates stood open to welcome all to the capital of the Karaz Ankor, but when the earth shook and the Underway was shattered and greenskins and Skaven poured in, they were closed, and now only open when the Dwarves march to war. Visitors, you've heard, can enter through a smaller door that the Gatekeeper can open in the face of the gate, and the tallest visitors have found themselves having to crawl. You need not worry, for though the Dwarves have found the surface and below crawling with foes, they have found dominance in the sky. The airport of Karaz-a-Karak is a long row of landing pads protruding from each of a row of tunnels drilled into the mountainside, and though no other powers have followed the Dwarves into the sky, some of the strange weapons that bristle upwards and track your approach suggest that they are determined not to be caught unprepared when they do. Following the waved signals of some sort of conductor, the gyrobomber makes a smooth landing on one of the airpads. A careful eye is run over the pilot and cargo, which pauses on you for a handful of seconds, before the conductor waves an okay at the gate, which slowly pulls up. Inside, a set of attendants are carefully reracking the axes and hammers they had taken up in case the conductor had waved a different sign, and take up positions to push the gyrobomber inside once the passengers finally disembark on shaky legs and follow the conductor inside. On the inside, beyond a side tunnel that your gyrobomber will be trundling down to be stored deeper in the mountain, a gyrocopter lurks, fueled and ready to be pushed out and flown wherever needed at a moment's notice. Your conductor leads you past a dozen or more similar tunnels before finally leading you down a set of stairs, and you find yourself wondering at this strange, silent arrival, and then you arrive at an imposing (though not quite four hundred feet tall) gate and realize why. Tradition must be followed, and the way the Dwarves had reconciled that with the gyrocopters is the fiction that these visitors haven't even arrived yet. A Gatekeeper, runic hammer and all, waits at this miniature gate, and it is he that finally asks who has come and what their business is. "King Belegar of Karak Eight Peaks, here to see the High King," is the ritual answer. That is how King Belegar would have always introduced himself, and how each of his ancestors would have, so the news he brings remains uncommunicated, and though curiosity burns on the Gatekeeper's face he will not go against tradition. He hammers on the gate, and traces a rune with his hammer, and a smaller entrance opens in the larger gate. You wonder if it, too, only opens for war, or if the larger gate has never opened and exists only to mirror the one below. Your relative lack of height proves an advantage as you need only duck through instead of crawling, and on the other side of the gate you find... more stairs. With an internal sigh, you begin your long trek downwards. Clearly news would have to have been sent ahead, though you don't see the precise mechanism; you wonder if it is due to some clever invention of the Guild of Engineers or an ancient mechanism the Dwarves have always known. Either way, when the stairs finally give out and place you at the entrance to the famed Great Hall as if you had entered from the front, the doors open for your party. The Great Hall itself you had heard tales of, of its massive size and towering height, and sure enough you're able to see for yourself that an entire human town could fit comfortably within it. But despite its size the Great Hall does not hold the population of a small human town, or anywhere close to it. Even though every major Hold and Clan, and every minor Hold and Clan with ambitions to become Major, each has a representative in the Great Hall during its hours of operation, the crowd would be a poor gathering for the Marktag of a medium-sized village. It is a walk of considerable distance before you approach the nearest member of the small, sad gathering of the remnants of the Karaz Ankor, and the constant murmur of discussion echoes through the emptiness. No wonder they despair. The traditions they would never abandon are a constant reminder of how great they once were. The crowd falls silent and parts as King Belegar approaches, and recognition is on every face; each then scans those following him, and most then school their expression into stony impassiveness, but you catch despair on some before they manage. It takes you a second to realize what they're seeing - they're seeing what they expected to see. The leader of the Expedition has returned, and without Kragg. There surely will have been enough vengeance to strike off a debt or two, but then Kragg's loss will be written in in their place, and the Karaz Ankor would have receded a little more. You see only a single exception: the representative wearing the stylized sea-gate Rune of Barak Varr, whose eyes are locked on the silver crown atop King Belegar's head, two sapphires twinkling in the torchlight. The others in King Belegar's party break off to meet their counterparts, and a murmur of conversation begins to break the mournful silence as Belegar climbs the stone steps at the head of the hall. Atop them sits the Throne of Power, the one place the High King is permitted by tradition to sit. It is said to bear the Rune of Eternity, the sole work of the Ancestor-God Grungni that he was ever satisfied with. You cannot see it for yourself, because it currently also bears the High King, Thorgrim Grudgebearer, who stares impassively down at the approaching King. "What news of the Everlasting Realm?" the High King asks, and you're glad you've been picking up Khazalid because of course tradition would trump politeness. "The Queen of the Silver Depths is once more the home of Clan Angrund." The hold falls silent once more, the whisper from Dwarf to Dwarf rendered unnecessary by the simple proclamation. To you King Belegar's words were a puzzle until you remembered the ceremonial name of Karak Eight Peaks, but to the Dwarves behind you the words of King Belegar hung in the air and shattered what the Dwarves thought they knew about the world they live in. A lesser Dwarf might have asked King Belegar to repeat himself, but instead the High King's eyes flicked to you, and you saw his curiosity, and then to the others that had come and noted who they were standing next to. The Younger Holds, who the High King had been told had contributed significantly to the Expedition, and in response the High King had not sent his own forces, but something possibly more precious and definitely harder to replace: Kragg the Grim, and his Anvil. So the High King simply gave a nod, granting King Belegar permission to continue. "Crescent Mountain, Sunrise Mountain, and the Citadel have been taken. The Hall of Oaths and the King's Armoury survived. Death Pass is open." "The cost?" asks the High King, his eyes flicking to the crowd again. "There are still some that may or may not survive their wounds, but of the fifty thousand Dwarves that marched, the final tally will be about nine thousand Dwarves dead, seventeen hundred of them Slayers. Additionally, of forty thousand humans, three thousand died for the Queen of the Silver Depths." King Belegar sees the eye-flick again, and answers it. "Runelord Kragg has remained to study the hammer-runes found in the King's Armoury, and further contribute to the rest of the retaking." "And of Vengeance?" "The Crooked Moon and the Broken Toof were shattered. If they have no other branches, they are destroyed." "Our Rangers will watch for them." The Throne of Power features a lecturn to hold a single book of overwhelming significance: The Dammaz Kron. The High King lifts the book from where it rested alongside his throne, and runs a finger along the pages before opening it about a third of the way along its pages, and needs only leaf a few more to reach where he was looking for. "There are many Grudges from that time that cannot be clearly attributed," he says musingly. "And much of what happened are the acts of Skaven. But you have accounted for many an Old and heavy Grudge. The Elders wise in Grudgelore will measure your Vengeance against the Grudges and determine what will be struck out." --- The Great Book of Grudges, as all who know even a little of the Dwarves know, is the single tome containing every wrong the Dwarven Empire has yet to avenge. What even a little knowledge of their history would indicate is that no one tome could contain those Grudges with enough detail for those born long after those acts to avenge them. King Belegar was told to follow the High King, and King Belegar in turn told you to follow him, and the three of you walk out of the Hall and into a room that could be described as large were it not for the one you just left. Row after innumerable row of bookshelves of the Archives of the Karaz Ankor bridge the terse inventory of the Dammaz Kron with the exhaustive detail that would allow the Dwarves to know that vengeance has been done, and the room is a hive of busy activity, as a dozen venerable Longbeards each act as the center of their own swarms of younger disciples. As the High King orders the retrieval of the books on the Siege and Fall of Karak Eight Peaks, your eyes widen as you run your eyes over perfectly-preserved tomes of recorded history. The Light Order do their best, but the Colleges have only been around for a fraction of the Empire's length, and before that a hundred tragedies each shaved away a record of history. The Great Library of Mordheim died with the city, the Sieges of Altdorf each resulted in a freezing populace burning books for heat, the Imperial Library suffered attrition every time the capital moved and was stolen back and forth a dozen times during the Age of the Three Emperors, and Dieter IV sold a good deal of what little survived to reach him to anyone willing to pay. And if that wasn't enough of a reason for his soul to be damned, when he sold Marienburg its independence, it took the Great Library of Verena with it, and ever since the self-righteous custodians have delighted in denying entry to citizens of the Empire. The Vaults of the Great Cathedral of Sigmar are purged every time a more conservative Grand Theogonist takes office, and there's Witch Hunters out there who consider literacy to be compelling evidence of witchcraft, and even when some poor scholar escapes the pyre it's not always guaranteed their books will. A hundred hundred roadblocks between the average human and their past, but since the first founding of Karaz-a-Karak, every single event to ever befall the Dwarves has been carefully recorded and remains right here, carefully preserved by rune and artifice. Three thousand years ago the ancestors of the Empire had barely migrated, but every wrong done to Karak Eight Peaks had been recorded in exhausting detail, as demonstrated by the series of mighty tomes hauled over by the Dwarven attendants. The most venerable of the Longbeards begins to leaf through at the High King's instruction, who then turns his attention to King Belegar. "If you can keep the fight going until a Throng gets there, we may be able to double the harvest of avenged Grudges. How long can your foothold last?" "How long can yours?" King Belegar responds, and you fight to keep your expression neutral. The moment stretches as the two stare obstinately at each other. "The East Gate is taken and fortified. Karag Nar is completely cleared, Karag Lhune has only a colony of spiders that are deciding whether to starve or be shot until it is the same, and both are fortified against any intruders from below. The Citadel is taken, and the caldera has been burned clear and by the time I return there will be enough artillery mounted that anything foolish enough to show itself will die. Kvinn-Wyr is infested by feral trolls, as much an obstacle to our enemies as it is to us, and that flank too is being fortified. Karak Azul's Throng has reached us and King Kazador has sworn to me that each one will die before he lets his people be cut off again. Karak Norn is selling us war machines on credit. Karak Izor sent colonisers three months ago. Barak Varr is already counting their profits. There are manlings building houses. There are Halflings building houses. As far as I can see, Karak Eight Peaks has a brighter future than any Hold east of Black Fire Pass." He points at the Book, which stopped having its pages flipped as the Elder turned to watch. "That Karak is three thousand years dead. If the one that exists today holds no interest to you, I have no business here." The entire room is still, as all present turn to watch the confrontation. You included. You've never even heard of a Dwarven civil war, but you might be about to witness the beginning of one. [High King's reaction: 84] High King Thorgrim Grudgebearer is famed for being as implacable as the Dwarf Kings of old, and not a hint of what he could be thinking is visible upon his face as the silence stretches. Then he blinks once, and nods, and turns and leaves, pausing at the door to give a 'well?' look at the two of you, and you follow. --- The Council Chamber of the High King is adorned with a model of the Old World, with what looks like the accurate to-scale height of every mountain from the Sea of Claws to the Sour Sea. You find the easy landmark of Barak Varr and follow the Blood River to where its tributaries disappear into the valleys, and then you spot the now-familiar cluster of mountains you've been calling home. Seconds later the door opens once more and a red-faced and surprisingly young Dwarf enters at a run, the summoning apparently as unexpected as it was urgent. "This is Prince Gotri Stoneheart. The title is still being debated, but for now he is 'Sky-Thane'. Gotri, put a branch of the Aircorp in Karag Lhune." "Isn't it-" "Yes. It's retaken. Have the hangars been cleared?" "Aye," says King Belegar, too stubborn to show any bewilderment. "They'll need a branch of the Engineer's Guild to maintain them, so see to that as well." The rest of the details are shaken out in rapid-fire fashion, and mere minutes later you find yourself climbing the innumerable stairs once more. --- "I'd intended to tell of your contributions," King Belegar says to you, as the gyrobomber is hastily refuelled for an unexpectedly early departure. "Now I daresay that you'd find it no favour to have your name attached to mine in the halls of Karaz-a-Karak." "I thought it was about to be war," you admit. "Might have been close. Never could tell what he was thinking." But the message of your abrupt departure was clear - if King Belegar wanted to focus on tomorrow's victories, he would be denied yesterday's glories. It's hard to hear brooding silence over the sound of a flying gyrocopter, but somehow King Belegar manages it as the whirling rotors take the bizarre vehicle into the sky. You have to nudge him to get his attention, and he perks up as he sees behind you that every other hangar gate is rising, and as your gyrobomber starts to make the trip back to Karak Eight Peaks, dozens more fly in formation around you. --- [Joined the Expedition: +1] [Battle of Und-Uzgar: +2] Taking a watchpost without a fight and causing many deaths to Skaven +2. [Battle of the East Gate: +4] Defeating enemy heroes in battle +4. [Battle of Karag Lhune: +12] Sabotaged the Doom Divers +2, assassinating the Warboss +2, tripping the troll trap +4, preventing disaster in the Chiselwards +4. [Battle of Karag Nar: +5] Assassinating the Warboss +2, sabotaging Idol of Gork +3. [Battle of the Citadel: +8] Countering the Shamans +4, dispelling the Waaagh-field that empowered the Orcs +4. [Grudges Avenged: --] Nullified by Belegar-Thorgrim troubles. [Finished the Expedition: +3] [Total: 35.] [Dwarf Favour cannot be spent in Karaz-a-Karak] --- As before, the three with the most votes will win. You can vote for as many as you like. Selections here will not bind you to a future career, but can prove beneficial for them. [ ] There's a growing concentration of royalty here. Get to know King Kazador, and this 'Sky-Thane' Prince Gotri. This suggests a future assisting Karak Eight Peaks with foreign relations, as a Spymaster focused on threats outside the Karak. [ ] Scout the rest of the Eight Peaks, to find out what other horrors are waiting out there. This suggests a future assisting Karak Eight Peaks with its reconquest, as a Spymaster focused on threats within the Karak. [ ] Convince Esbern and Seija to stay long enough to deal with the spiders in the Chiselwards. This suggests a future assisting Karak Eight Peaks with its reconquest, as a Spymaster focused on threats within the Karak. [ ] Join Karak Azul as they raid and scout in force the other portions of the Karak. This suggests a future assisting Karak Eight Peaks with its reconquest, as a battlefield wizard. [ ] Claim the site where Ranald mugged Mork and build a shrine to Ranald there. This suggests a future assisting Karak Eight Peaks, as leader of the Undumgi and point of contact for the Ulricans. [ ] Write a series of papers on the magical phenomena you witnessed. Or better yet, get your Journeymanlings to do the actual writing. This suggests a future of investigation and study at Karak Eight Peaks, and perhaps helping Johann poke at Skaven technology. [ ] King Belegar is allowing you to use the King's Armoury. Recover your extant study materials from Stirland and tuck them away safely in there. This suggests a future catching up on your pre-existing study topics. [ ] Convince Esbern and Seija to stay long enough to hatch the supposedly Lustrian eggs and study and possibly train whatever hatches. This suggests a future catching up on your pre-existing study topics. [ ] All this time away has made you miss your friends. Visit Anton and Wilhelmina. This suggests a future in Stirland, whether Roswita likes it or not. [ ] You're going to have a rough time explaining your windfall to the Bursars. Better to get that over with. This suggests a future performing an assignment the Grey Order thinks is suited to you. [ ] You've been out of touch for a while. Head to Barak Varr and then Altdorf, and catch up with what's been happening in the Empire. This suggests a future seeking employment on the Council of an Elector Count. [ ] Not every sellsword will accept King Belegar's offer of employment. Travel with them. This suggests a future as a travelling mercenary. - The above says Mathilde is not entirely sure if this Silver Tower is the Silver Tower of Warhammer Quest. Neither am I. Can anyone shed some light? Edit: Turns out it's an Age of Sigmar thing. Still, the legends are generic enough that I'll leave them in. - This period is going to be pretty vague on the timekeeping. - If you make the money 'tomorrow's problem', that will mean deciding again in the future with only one additional option - spending the majority of the money in the performance of the duties you take on. - If there are other significant and publicly known achievements I've missed, let me know. - There's a Dwarf Favour pricelist in the Collection of Important Information threadmark. Opportunities will arise to spend it in the future. If it's not covered in there, ask. - This will be your last opportunity to convince Esbern and Seija not to leave with the Demigryph Knights.

Karak Eight Peaks: Expeditionary Epilogue 2

Spoiler: Voting results [*] Karag Nar penthouse [*] This is Dawongr Weber's money. The funds will largely go projects within the Karaz Ankor - your tower for one, but also investing in the Undumgi or Ulrikadrin, or purchasing goods made by Dwarven artisans or sold in the markets of Barak Varr. [*] Write a series of papers on the magical phenomena you witnessed. Or better yet, get your Journeymanlings to do the actual writing. [*] Convince Esbern and Seija to stay long enough to deal with the spiders in the Chiselwards. [*] There's a growing concentration of royalty here. Get to know King Kazador, and this 'Sky-Thane' Prince Gotri. The uppermost chamber of Karag Nar was once beautiful, and enough of that shines through three thousand years of neglect that you can't look past it. A 360-degree view, a commanding position atop what will be the human quarter of the Karak, fully exposed to the sunrise and sunset so there's no shortage of Ulgu, and far enough up the stairs from the inhabited parts of the Karak that anyone approaching could trip any number of alarms, alerts and precautions before they're even able to knock on your door. The bosspole is added to your growing collection of trophies, the Skaven skulls gathered up in a sack and delivered to the Halflings to be ground into bonemeal, and by the time you return to take care of the wyvern rib cage, Wolf has discovered it and is chewing on a rib that outweighs him with enthusiasm and vigour, unknowing or uncaring that all scraps of meat and marrow have long since rotted away. Your haul in silver is another concern, but if it never leaves the Karaz Ankor then it never really breached the Vow of Poverty, right? You've got an established relationship with the Dwarves and part of that is engaging in fair pay for fair work, which is an important part of Dwarven culture. A Magister's tithe is 5%, and you put aside 184 of the silver ingots to be delivered to the Grey College at a later date. --- Esbern and Seija return from Ulrikadrin in high spirits, having accounted for a Dragon Ogre between the two of them, and now each sports an armband of draconid talons. Johann has been scarce lately, and you suspect he's been making forays into the Underway, but with the Expedition disintegrating what little authority you had over him is gone, and at least he was good enough to give you his notes, which are densely written in a neat hand and surprisingly insightful. With Panoramia and Maximilian pulled away from your new friends, the meeting of the minds begins. [Amber insight: 49.] [Jade insight: 77.] [Gold insight: 97+10(Johann's notes)=107.] [Grey insight: 52+10(Windreader)=62.] [Dictating a paper: Learning, 76+20=96.] The first matter is on Runecraft in general, and unsurprisingly it's Maximilian's insights and Johann's notes that do the heavy lifting, but Panoramia delivers a few details and even Esbern and Seija have something to say. You're not writing a paper yourself if you can at all help it, but you're more than able to boil down the observations into pertinent and potentially useful information and leave it in Maximilian's hands to be converted into a paper later. [Amber insight: 37.] [Jade insight: 61.] [Gold insight: 61+10(Johann's notes)=71.] [Grey insight: 98+10(Windreader)=108.] [Dictating a paper: Learning, 95+20=115.] The Anvil is the next topic, and though you had a spectacular view, perhaps events on the ground were less conducive to careful academic study. The Journeyman's ground-level observations are each rudimentary, but each represents a tangent you're able to build upon and transform into a detailed description into how the power was unleashed, and are even able to make a few guesses into how it was manipulated. The matter of the bolstering of the Undumgi and the possible long-term effects is one you can only really speculate upon, but they're intriguing speculations. If only you could spend an hour with an Anvil... but you doubt there's any amount of assistance you could give to the Karaz Ankor that would make them okay with you spiriting away their deepest secrets to be spread amongst the Umgi. Quite happy with the matter, you move on. [Amber insight: 91.] [Jade insight: 71.] [Gold insight: 62+10(Johann's notes)=72.] [Grey insight: 1+10(Windreader)=11.] [Dictating a paper: Learning, 27+20=47.] [Amber dictating a paper?: 19.] {Panoramia? 44.] [Max? 16.] Unfortunately, at the third and final topic, you flounder. Perhaps it's a side effect of your unique exposure to it, but any attempts for you to describe the flow of Waaagh energy fall flat, and you keep finding yourself reaching for words that don't exist. Esbern and Seija take the fore, perhaps more used to the crude and animalistic energies of the Waaagh because of their familiarity with Ghur. All you can do is sit back and watch as the Journeymen put their heads together and come up with page after page of notes, but no matter how you try, or how they try, there seems to be no way of sewing together all of these data points into a single cohesive whole. As the conversation begins to get heated you step in to adjourn the topic, and can only hope that Maximilian is able to perform a miracle with the raw material he's been given. [Amber insight: 99.] [Grey insight: 71+10(Windreader)=81.] [Writing a paper: 4+20-10(Practical)=14.] [Dictating a paper: Learning, 44+20=64.] Only yourself and Esbern and Seija have seen the Dragon Ogres, so you put your head down with them to try to collate what you've seen into a hypothesis, but it only takes a minute of scowling down at the empty sheet of paper before you call Maximilian back and offer him coauthor credit to take care of writing the bloody thing. With that taken care of, you're able to make quite a few observations of the effects of the volcanic lightning on the Dragon Ogres, and reach a number of speculative theories as to what more conventional lightning provides that the volcano doesn't. [Writing a paper on Runes: Learning, 78+15=93.] [Writing a paper on Anvils: Learning, 2+15=17.] [Trying to salvage a paper on Anvils: 75+20-10(Practical)=85.] [Writing a paper on Waaagh: 37-20=17.] [Writing a paper on Dragon Ogres: 82+15=97.] When you next see Maximilian several days later, he's got quite a mixed bag of papers to share with you. "Observations on Runecraft Made During The Expedition To Karak Eight Peaks" is an eyebrow-raising page turner, at least to those who share your interest in the details of how magical energies can be gathered and manipulated, and you're delighted to be able to put your name on it as coauthor. Unfortunately, "Deployment of an 'Anvil Of Doom' During The Battle Of Karag Nar" is an absolute wreck of a paper, and it's clear that Maximilian misunderstood several fundamental details and then built on them. With a wince and a sigh you resign yourself to academic writing once more, and you explain to Maximilian where he went wrong as you rewrite pretty much the entire paper from scratch. He's quickly able to grasp the corrections and by the time you've filled the margins with notes and corrections he's eager to throw himself back into the fray, and the second attempt on the paper is greatly improved for it. Third, the paper on the Waaagh energy is as terrible as you had feared, and with your own understanding of it continuing to elude anything that can be expressed with Reikspiel, all you can do is consign it to the flames as Maximilian nods in solemn agreement. You've still got Esbern and Seija's notes, so perhaps you'll be able to return to the topic with a fresh perspective after some time has passed. The final paper, "Dragon Ogres and Volcanic Lightning", is a return to the quality of the first, and you're very pleased with how it turned out and are more than happy to give Maximilian part of the credit. You're also quite relieved to be detailing information as to why this isn't a possible existential threat to the Empire, which is quite different to how papers of this sort usually go. --- The Chiselwards is still a mushroom farm, albeit one under very heavy guard, as transforming the tunnels and chambers into residences is to wait until the spider issue is resolved. Each guard post has been reinforced with stone and cannon, and the report you receive from the currently on-shift commanding officer is concerning - constant observation, and probing attacks from the smaller spiders, while larger ones watch from out of range. This is a level of organization you wouldn't have expected from spiders, and from their frowns, Esbern and Seija think the same. The bodies are dragged clear of the firing lines once the probes cease, and Esbern and Seija carefully study them, then begin to cut into them with obsidian knives as the curious Dwarf who followed you hastily returns back to his post. "Juvenile?" Esbern asks. "No, look at the exoskeletal layers. Continuous growth?" Seija's concerning herself with the head. "Even for their size, the fangs are unusually large. And look - no autonomic envenoming reaction. Hunters, rather than trappers." "They've clearly got silk glands. Have there been any webs?" You pass the question on to the guards, and receive a shake of the head. "But from what you said they had a range. They're not trappers, they're not wanderers. They coexist. Sub-social hunters?" "Brain is small, but always is for bugs. It's distributed through the body." "It's grown, right?" Esbern asks again, sitting back from the cut he'd made along the spider's abdomen. "Molt marks, developed hairs... maybe not its maximum size but this is an adult, isn't it?" "Like you said, exoskeleton. Count the molt layers. It's an adult." "Then why's the ovary underdeveloped? Not even that, it's completely undeveloped. Late-life maturity?" "Not with this level of density. Check the others." "Female, female, female..." Seija flips a final unstudied spider. "Female. All similar size, too." "They're the same size. A litter? Did these all attack together?" The Dwarf in charge is very determinedly not watching, but he hears the question. "They're today's probes from all of the fortified points. We drag them out to the Halflings on shift change." Esbern sighs. "Damn it. I hate hives." "You hate anything that's not a mammal." "It's a hive?" you interrupt. "It's thinking like one," Seija confirms. "These ones are all the exact same size. For spiders, that means the same number of moltings, which means the same age. So siblings. If they attacked together they could be pack hunters, but they attacked different outposts. So either there's a lot that are the same age, or something about this birthing made them less valuable so they were sacrificed for information. On top of that, undeveloped ovaries is something you'd only see in adults if they were part of a hive with castes. These aren't breeders, so they don't develop the equipment for breeding. But if you want proof..." She stands and approaches the outpost, paying no attention to the Dwarves edging away from her. Ghur leaks from her fingertips, then lashes out at an observer far outside the torchlight. "Approach," she says, magic interlaced in her voice, but the creature remains impassive, staring back at her. "Groupmind. My spell doesn't work because the part that's doing the thinking isn't here." "Can you communicate with it?" "There's a spell called The Talking Beast, but I've yet to learn it. I'll need to send to Altdorf for the scroll. If you could write an authorization-" "Of course." "And get the Dwarves to deliver the message on one of their spinnythings, I can get started on learning it. It being a hive means we've got more time than I expected - they'll minimize activity and they won't fight over who gets eaten." --- King Kazador, you discover, is a simple fellow. He likes fighting, ale, and his children. More than anyone he reminds you of Anton's father, Anton Senior, the Baron of Blutdorf. After you introduce yourself to him, he spends a while trying to figure out what your titles mean without giving up and asking, and then he finally latches on to the half-remembered fact that a Dame is a sort of land-owning Thane, and he slaps you on the back, extends an open invitation to join him in battling the greenskins, which is tied for songs and drinking as his favourite activity, and loudly laments that you were human, because otherwise he'd try to marry one of his innumerable sons off to you. Behind him, his eldest son, Prince Kazrik, is visibly mortified and looks like he wishes he could disappear up his own helmet. "So, what sort of fellow is this Belegar then?" King Kazador asks. "Met him years back when he came to Karak Azul, which is no small feat. Or was, I suppose! Going to be easy as popping down to the Brewer's Guild for a barrel now, or so they tell me. Steamships up the Blood River, what will they think of next? But anyway, he came to Karak Azul and wanted a Throng to take the fight to here. Figured it was a fool's errand - maybe they don't keep track when they're wandering, but Karak Azul sure does, and from my count he's at least the tenth to try." With a grunt, he recocks his crossbow and slots into place a fresh bolt the Dwarf at his side had handed him. Just out of the light of the torches some of his Hammerers were carrying, goblins circled and tried to goad one another into being first to attack the intruders marching through their territory, and King Kazador's aim reducing their numbers by the minute certainly wasn't helping them find their courage. "More fool me, I suppose! We've heard of this 'Empire' of yours, but last time we walked the world your kind had barely started figuring out how to build huts in that overgrown valley. Didn't expect him to find a hundred thousand warriors, half manling and half from Holds that were barely mines when we last heard from them. What was I asking?" "What sort of fellow Belegar is," you reply distractedly, your pistol tracking a particularly agile goblin who was scampering up a stalagmite with a knife in his teeth. With the clean crack of quality gunpowder igniting, he falls backwards with a squeal. "Good shot." "Thanks." You scan the darkness for your next target, your Magesight making it simple as emotion draws the Winds to them and tiny slivers of Waaagh energy, too dispersed to do anything but give the greenskins' locations away, crackles through the air. "He's a dab hand with that hammer of his, he struck down the Warboss at the East Gates in a handful of seconds. But as a leader I'd say he's an organizer. Makes sure the right leaders are in charge of what they're best at, and makes sure there's enough supplies that everyone's fed and armed and ready to fight." A particularly sneaky Goblin covered in rock dust had been making his careful way to the rear of the Hammerers for the past few minutes, but as he finally saw a chance and leapt forward with a dagger in each hand, King Kazador's crossbow bolt caught him in the side and flung him backwards, and one of the rearmost Hammerers paused their advance to deliver the killing blow. "I've got people for that," he says. "But I suppose not everyone can be me. Sounds like my lad here." He slaps a hand down on Kazrik's shoulder. "He's a thinker, like his mother. Do you think Belegar'd get on with your sister?" Prince Kazrik mutters a distracted response, both hands firmly clutching his axe and focused more on the Goblins than his father's questions. "It sounds like that lass from whatdoyoucallit - Karak Izor? has had a head start. Still, I'd put money on my Kazrina any day. After all," he says, suddenly grinning. "Haven't ever heard of copper beating iron, have you?" Prince Kazrik groans at his father's joke, and you have to raise your pistol again to keep from rolling your eyes. Crack. "Good shot. Maybe there's something to this blackpowder business after all." --- If there's one thing Dwarves and Stirland Peasants have in common, it's how much importance there is placed upon the sprawling family trees. The first thing to do after you introduce yourself to Prince Gotri Stoneheart, who's currently up to his waist in gyrocopter parts, is to mention your encounter with his kin: Thane Thori Stoneheart, who had led the Dwarven force in the Drakenhof campaign. "Uncle Thori," he says instantly, only slightly muffled by his head being jammed into a massive contraption of iron and brass. "He spoke quite highly of you. Said Castle Drakenhof would still be standing if you hadn't taken over the manling forces." "Could be," you say. You don't like to remember that campaign too much, but you did remember not everyone was as keen as the Dwarves to push on to the end of the campaign. "And here you are again." He looks at you from between two sets of pipes. "Why did you join what had to seem like such a risky enterprise?" You shrug. "I was looking for purpose when King Belegar called for aid." "Just like that?" The Dwarf has turned his eyes back to the machine, and you hear a ratcheting as something is either tightened or loosened. "Just like that. What about you? Would have thought the heir to Zhufbar would stick closer to Zhufbar." "I suppose the former Spymaster of Stirland would know such things." He carefully withdraws himself from the machinery, one hand holding his beard safely against his chest to keep it from getting tangled. "Got to be friendly with the High King, and nothing like sending your firstborn to make him feel comfortable. Nobody outright says hostages, but..." "I thought the Old Holds got along better than that." "Hah!" he scowls and wipes his hands on a rag. "'The Old Holds', they say. We trace our Holds all the way back to the Golden Age, whereas the Young Holds only grew to prominence after the Time of Woes. So supposedly we're the template of what a 'proper' Dwarf is supposed to be. But if you actually look at those Holds, it's completely different. Barak Varr is as cosmopolitan as any city I've ever heard of, Karak Kadrin thrives on trade with Ostermark and Kislev - they just built a canal for the former - and my own Zhufbar is the cutting edge of invention and innovation. What does that leave? Karak Azul, who until literally this week nobody but Karaz-a-Karak had any contact with? As far as I can see, the only 'Old Hold' is Karaz-a-Karak, who are so very keen to tell everyone to get to dying so they can cross out Grudges that they can't see, or don't care, that the world is moving and it is going to leave us behind if we don't adapt. Thorgrim's better than some, but he only really cares about innovation if it's new ways of setting old scores." --- As well as the authorization for Seija's spell scroll, you bundle up copies of your completed papers. The Grey College isn't quite as focused on academia as some, but it still pays to keep your name in people's minds, and a few fresh insights from the far south should help give people the idea that you're blossoming into a perfectly valid candidate for Lord Magister. You also assemble your cargo of 184 silver ingots to be tithed, which in total weigh almost as much as you do, and once more mentally repeat your rehearsed explanation to the Bursar. You also have to decide whether you'll be remaining here or returning to the Empire in the near future, as the Grey Order does like to be kept abreast of such things. [ ] Remain in Karak Eight Peaks, either in the employ of Belegar or pursuing your research. [ ] Return to the Empire, either to seek employ there or to return to your holdings in Stirland. You've also got to decide whether to bring an additional cargo: the allegedly Lustrian eggs you purchased in Barak Varr. If you suspect you won't have time to properly hatch and investigate them, you could turn them over to the Amber College or the Imperial Zoo. [ ] Give them away... - [ ] To the Amber College - [ ] To the Imperial Zoo [ ] Keep them to be hatched. And then there's after your return, which will be tomorrow. Tomorrow. Wonderful devices, gyrocopters. Vote for as many as you like. The three with the most votes will be selected. [ ] Speak with King Belegar and King Kazador about the relationships and apparent rifts between Dwarfholds. This suggests a future assisting Karak Eight Peaks with foreign relations, as a Spymaster focused on threats outside the Karak. [ ] Scout the rest of the Eight Peaks, to find out what other horrors are waiting out there. This suggests a future assisting Karak Eight Peaks with its reconquest, as a Spymaster focused on threats within the Karak. [ ] Try to follow Johann, to see what he's getting up to. This suggests a future assisting Karak Eight Peaks with its reconquest, as a Spymaster focused on threats within the Karak. [-] Convince Esbern and Seija to stay long enough to deal with the spiders in the Chiselwards. This will continue in the coming turn, and will not take up a selection. [ ] Join Karak Azul as they raid and scout in force the other portions of the Karak. This suggests a future assisting Karak Eight Peaks with its reconquest, as a battlefield wizard. [ ] Claim the site where Ranald mugged Mork and build a shrine to Ranald there. This suggests a future assisting Karak Eight Peaks, as leader of the Undumgi and point of contact for the Ulricans. [ ] Though your future relationship with the spiders is still unknown, they do appear to be a new species and you do have a number of corpses available. Have Esbern and Seija help you autopsy the creatures for a paper. This suggests a future of investigation and study at Karak Eight Peaks, and perhaps helping Johann poke at Skaven technology. [ ] King Belegar is allowing you to use the King's Armoury. Recover your extant study materials from Stirland and tuck them away safely in there. This suggests a future catching up on your pre-existing study topics. [-] Convince Esbern and Seija to stay long enough to hatch the supposedly Lustrian eggs and study and possibly train whatever hatches. Esbern and Seija are currently occupied with the spiders. [ ] All this time away has made you miss your friends, and you'll be practically next door in Altdorf. Visit Anton and Wilhelmina. This suggests a future in Stirland, whether Roswita likes it or not. [ ] Make a full report on the geopolitical troubles among the Dwarven Empire, even though some of it was said to you in confidence. This suggests a future performing an assignment the Grey Order thinks is suited to you. [ ] You've been out of touch for a while. Linger in Altdorf after you visit the College and catch up with what's been happening in the Empire. This suggests a future seeking employment on the Council of an Elector Count. - Prince Gotri is a young firebrand, take his words as his personal opinion rather than a 100% accurate Word-of-God statement. - College Favour will be tallied in the coming turn. - You can vote to remain in K8P and still take options that suggest work in the Empire, or vice versa.

Karak Eight Peaks: Expeditionary Epilogue 3

Spoiler: Voting results [*] Remain in Karak Eight Peaks, either in the employ of Belegar or pursuing your research. [*] Give them away... - [*] To the Amber College [*] Claim the site where Ranald mugged Mork and build a shrine to Ranald there. [*] King Belegar is allowing you to use the King's Armoury. Recover your extant study materials from Stirland and tuck them away safely in there. [*] All this time away has made you miss your friends, and you'll be practically next door in Altdorf. Visit Anton and Wilhelmina. Another cycle of Dwarven paperwork has made you almost gleeful to escape the Karak, and as your transport makes its way over mountains you look forlornly down at your still-aching hand. Your permanent ownership of the location required one set of papers, and that it was to be a religious site was another set of papers, and that it might be a site where alcohol was to be drunk was an equally formidable set, the Dwarves taking drinking almost as seriously as religion. That the site could be both a Shrine and a Tavern was not a problem, as apparently Temples to Valaya in her aspect as the Ancestor Goddess of Brewing were quite similar. Thankfully, by the time you reach the Empire, your hand has fully healed. Gyrocopters are not unknown in the Empire, but they are certainly rare enough to draw stares. When one lands in the poorest and most violent district Altdorf has to offer, that counts for double. You disembark to dozens of curious stares, but the colour of your habitual robes has all but the boldest quickly pretend to have been looking elsewhere. People in general know not to bother a Wizard going about their business, but people here learned very, very quickly that the Grey College that lurked in the dilapidated heart of the district was absolutely not to be bothered at all. Even when you start unloading your weight in silver, eyes remain firmly turned away, and a nearby street merchant selling fried meats of unidentifiable provenance is offered a month's profit for the loan of his cart, and a swarm of street urchins and beggars are very careful not to get too close to you as they each gather armfuls of the now unwanted meats. As you wheel your weight in silver through the streets, you're entertained to see the same set of events play out on a dozen different faces: eyes alighting on an enormous stack of silver and widening in greed, then those same eyes spotting that a Grey Wizard was in possession of that silver, and that person freezes on the spot as self-preservation and greed go to war. Self-preservation always wins. Those with more greed than sense have long since been weeded out of the neighbourhood. The doors you wheel the cart through have not seen an overambitious thief in many years, though urchins on dares scamper in on a regular basis. Most emerge without incident after lingering long enough to show their bravery, a few meet Grey Wizards to make reports to their secret employers, and once in a while one will not be seen again - at least not until they've advanced enough in their Apprenticeship to be allowed out unsupervised. Each of the Colleges have their own way of calling to those who resonate with their Wind. The normal way to gain access to the Grey College is to walk through the corridors in a maddening array of zig-zags in a path that seem to fold in on itself, but though Wizards love that sort of thing, sometimes practicality must win out. A storage closet near the door is home only to a single broom that has long surrendered its grip on its bristles, and you carefully wheel your cargo into it and close the door behind you. A few seconds later, you open the door again and wheel the cart out into the Grey College's storerooms, filled with all the mundane fuels required to run an institution: quills and inks, paper and papyrus, chalk and slate. Out the door, down the corridor, a few nods and exchanged greetings with those you pass. A few eyebrows are raised, but only just - yours might be a contender for the strangest cargo for the Grey College to receive this week, but only just. The Bursar's Office is the name for the financial mechanisms of the Grey College, that's simple enough. The person one speaks to in it would, one could reasonably assume, be the Bursar. But the Colleges inherited the traditions of the University of Altdorf, and as such its names have only a tangential relation to reality or consistency. The Bursar's Office is the foyer for several actual offices, and the staff that one would speak to are an assortment of non-magicals, Perpetual Apprentices, and Magisters with very specific mindsets, and they would be speaking on behalf of the Bursar as an institution. There is, somewhere, an actual Bursar - the Grey Wizard responsible for the entire financial apparatus of the College - but even when one says that they have spoken to the Bursar, they usually would not have actually spoken to them, or even set eyes upon them. As the unexpected delivery of a woman's weight in silver makes its way up the chain of command, you feel both terror and elation at the realization that that's about to change. It's often said to new Apprentices that many of the greatest deeds of the Grey Order will never be spoken of, and while that was true for the Empire at large, the exception was among other Grey Wizards. Algard and his Towers of Screaming Death, which reliably draws in Chaos warbands who seek the forbidden tomes supposedly encased within and walk right into Imperial Army ambushes. Kurtis Krammovitch, double agent turned triple agent turned quadruple agent turned unofficial diplomat to the Hedgefolk, who technically breached the Articles but fought sorcerers and necromancers for new recruits in areas where the College's influence didn't otherwise reach. Walther Kupfer, who fomented civil unrest from the slave pits of Clar Karond and caused inter-house feuds that still periodically explode into violence to this day. And Wilhelmine von Bucht, who shattered the House of Goellner when they thought their trade empire had made them too powerful to tax, who dismantled every Smuggler Guild from Middenheim to Fortenhaf, who concealed the Imperial Regalia and forced the just-deposed Dieter IV to retreat to Talabheim without performing one final theft. Who in the twilight years of a successful career settled down to serve her College as Bursar. Who is now sitting across from you and offering you a nice cup of tea. Lady Magister Wilhelmine looks anywhere from thirty to fifty, her hair the pure grey of Ulgu rather than the interspersed whites of age, and it rather unnervingly wriggles from time to time as it tries to escape from the bun it's been forced into. Her frame is thin but not quite gaunt, and she has the air of a friendly aunt, seeming nothing like the figure of legend that inspires even the most arrogant of nobles to meet their tax obligations. As you sip on the tea - mild, with a hint of mint - she turns the bar of silver over in her hands, running her fingertips over the imprint attesting to its origin, weight and purity. She also has in front of her the paperwork you filled out to go with it, and though she only appears to have glanced at it you're sure she knows every detail you entered. "Not the first windfall you've come into," she notes. "No, Lady Magister. The Memoirs of Asarnil proved unexpectedly popular." "I assume you did take the usual Vows at some point, yes?" "Yes, Lady Magister." "We do rather focus on how funds are obtained. Our own dear Ulgu could make quite a terror of any that put their minds to the acquisition of wealth, as I'm sure you're aware. I'm likewise sure your acquisitions will remain benign, and there will be no need for any of those little loopholes to become a noose." She taps the silver with a fingernail. "This isn't a warning. If we didn't have faith in you, you would not bear your current rank, and truth be told the silver will come in handy - our wedding present for the Emperor was not cheap. This is simply a reminder to help you retain that faith we have in you. As the Wolfship captain said to the midshipman: if a fish jumps aboard there's no point throwing it back overboard, but don't get so used to the taste that you find yourself baiting hooks. Is that clear?" "Yes, Lady Magister." "Lovely. I'll be watching your affairs with great interest. Oh, and if you could do me a small favour?" "Yes, Lady Magister?" "Do tell Magister Johann to stop playing silly buggers. He can poke at the ratties if he really must, but it's unseemly to play pretend with our allies." --- It still feels unreal to think of Magister Regimand Speiseschrank as your peer rather than your Master. He's tucked deep into an armchair in the entrance hall, apparently engrossed in a tome, but you notice that your mind says he is reading a book rather than going through all the usual steps of identifying the object in his hands and coming to a conclusion of its own. You really should get around to learning Cloak Activity when you have a spare month or two, but time is always scarce and the Colleges frown on attempts to interfere with its passage. You slip into Substance of Shadow and take the seat opposite him before revealing yourself in a mirror of the way he used to appear to you as a Journeyman, and of course he doesn't give you the satisfaction of jumping. "You should learn Invisibility," he says, still supposedly engaged in his reading. "Next time I might not do you the courtesy of dousing the nearest lantern." "There's a lot of things I should be doing," you retort, and with barely a flicker the spell dissolves and Regimand is looking directly at you, the book nowhere to be seen. "I daresay they would be. Have you seen the second layer of nastiness yet?" "Whiskers and warpstone? Oh yes. How many of those little messages are there, anyway?" "A few. Most of the big ones you'll probably never need. There's a big one a bit further south from your current playground, but it's going on twenty-five centuries without a whisper and thank Sigmar for that. One's just a how-to-stop-a-Waystone-from-exploding that we keep tucked away so those Journeying don't get it into their heads to seek them out, but can still deal with one gone bad if they trip over it. There's one for if you're stupid enough to go to Lustria, one that basically says 'don't touch the mummy gold, idiot' after an overambitious twit came home proud as punch of a sceptre he'd stolen from a pyramid - we jumped into the fastest ship in Altdorf Harbour and nipped across the Sea of Claws and threw it in the general direction of the Skaelings, and a week later every sailor in Marienburg is telling stories about the Curse of Zandri wandering up and down the Norscan coast. I've heard there's two in the Dark Lands, but never been curious enough to go poking around there. Terrible place. Oh, one for the Blighted Marsh to say get the hell out of the Blighted Marsh without giving the full story." He scratches his chin in thought. "I think that's all the major ones. Or maybe just the ones I know about. Far as I know, the rest are all 'run away and call for help with this codeword' warnings for specific Black Magisters - problem with them is that so many of them end up blowing themselves up in some godforsaken nowhere, but we can't take them off the books because every now and then one will re-emerge after thirty years and start raising hell." He frowns. "What was I- oh yes, rats. Honestly the best advice I could give for those bastards is find some Dwarves and point them in the right direction. They know what they're doing." "You're a font of wisdom," you grumble, and he smiles. "So, have you been up to anything apart from getting in scraps with the greenskins?" "I have, actually. Are you still semi-retired?" "As much as always," he says evasively. Perhaps he actually is, or perhaps he's getting up to mischief he can't discuss in Altdorf; he 'semi-retired' twice during your Apprenticeship, and the first ended with three different chaos cults declaring war on each other and butchering each other in the streets of Altdorf as the Watchmen waited to arrest whoever was last standing, and the second with the 'tragic accident' of a noble who turned out to be a puppet of the Lahmians. "Well, if you're looking for ways to spend your time, I've got a few boulders to catapult into the academic landscape." You hand over your papers and he immediately tucks in, and you sit back to wait impatiently. "The general Runic insight is solid, nothing earthshaking but there's good information there and a lot of it. Good read, too." Another period of silence, and you've only got his gradually raising eyebrows to gauge his reaction by. "They hardly ever bring those Anvils to battle, and I've never even heard of some of those abilities. Damn cagey Dwarves. This one's a cracker, too." The third one is a great deal shorter, but the information goes over just as well. "That title would give a lot of generals heart attacks. Good information, damn good information. I daresay these will see some widespread reading. If this is what's going to come out of that place, it won't just be the diplomatic sorts that want you to stay put. Tie a rope around whichever of the young'uns you got to write these for you before someone else snatches them up." The other topic is your slightly less heavy cargo: the eggs you bought in Barak Varr. Regimand makes a crack about feeding them on magic beans, but settles when you tell him they've been looked at by Amber Journeymen. The Ambers being what they are, they don't exactly have a mailing address. Most who have cause to contact them have to go through a number of steps involving totems and burning herbs, and the process for their Brothers and Sisters in wizardry are only slightly less aggravating. He agrees to pass them along with your compliments, and you wonder when or even if you'll hear anything back about your strange gift. [Timely Tithe: +1 College Favour. [Diplomatic Benefits of K8P: +4 College Favours.] [Economic Benefits of K8P: Pending.] [Strategic Benefits of K8P: Pending.] [Wrangling Journeymen: +2 College Favours.] [Observations on Runecraft During The Expedition To Karak Eight Peaks. Subject: Uncommon, +0. Insight: Confirming +1. Delivery: Compelling, +1. Shared credit, -1. Varied, +1. Final Rating: +2.] [Deployment of an 'Anvil Of Doom' During The Battle Of Karag Nar. Subject: Rare, +1. Insights: Revolutionary (Lightning and Lava), +2. Delivery: Compelling, +1. Shared credit, -1. Precious, +1. Final Rating: +4] [Dragon Ogres and Volcanic Lightning. Subject: Rare, +1. Insights: Revolutionary, +2. Delivery: Compelling, +1. Shared credit, -1. Tactically Relevant, +1. Final Rating: +4] [Lustrian eggs: Pending.] --- You checked in on the Grey College's current understanding of the situation in Stirland before you leave, of course, but you try to reserve judgement until you arrive. Part of you is still quite bitter about how your employment in Stirland ended, but you're doing your best to not find joy in her failures or misery in her successes. The guards at the gate of Blutdorf salute as you pass, and you wonder if it's institutional memory from your command over the Watch, memory of your time as Spymaster in general, standing orders from Anton, or just general respect paid to a Magister. It's been less than half a year since you were last here and everything is as you remember it, and once more you find court in session, except this time Anton is sitting on the rather modest throne instead of a seat set beside it. Thankfully, Anton's father had stepped aside rather than passing on his title the usual way, and was undoubtedly making an utter menace of himself to the deer and boar of Nattern Forest. Just as last time you were here, you wait for him to finish his current adjudication (moving field markers was a serious charge, but equally serious was attempted disembowelment with a pitchfork in retaliation), and just as last time his call for snacks keeps the grumbling to a minimum as he adjourns court when you make yourself known. His hug is just as warm as you remember, and he chatters his way through current events, most of which you've just heard the reports of. His straightforward summaries cut to the heart of most of the matters with more conciseness than even the tersest intelligence report, and you wonder if he's growing more astute or if you're just more prone to taking him seriously, knowing the diplomatic feats he's been capable of. "Fort Redemption is the new Wurtbad, they're saying," he says as the two of you look over a map of Stirland. "She's brought Southern Stirland to heel and the selling off of the Hunter's Hills are going well, and after the Countess disappeared she brought Nachthafen and Pfaffbach under her control. The Black Guard love her, Central Stirland has never felt safer, and the road Abelhelm had made has been a boon for trade. But she's completely ignoring Western Stirland, and you more than anybody knows what the problem with that is." "Oh god," you groan as Anton rummages through a pile of scrolls. "Don't tell me the Stirlandian League is back." "Even better," he says with a grin, and passes you a scroll. Your eyes widen at the seal stamped into the wax, and you unroll it to find a contract very similar to ones you've signed. "Baron Anton Kiesinger II, in his capacity as the Baron of Blutdorf, ownership of a stake of 16% of the Eastern Imperial Company?" "I saw how Wilhelmina was as Steward, she's scary when it comes to trading and finances and whatnot. So when she started clashing with the West Stirland Riverine Company - you remember, with Franzen and Wolfsbach? I told them it'd probably go really badly, and they spoke to her, and the Countess is paying a fortune for those handguns she's trying to introduce so she jumped at the chance to be bought out of the EIC. They got half each, and that meant that the EIC had the entire Old Dwarf Road, and with the Countess away the EIC has a free hand throughout the demesne so that gives them the Nuln Road all the way to Ramsau. And of course I'm not going to ignore the advise I just gave to Petra and Artur, am I? So when Wilhelmina came to town with that look in her eye, I didn't just get out of her way, I jump aboard. I cracked open the treasury, bought 16% of her share, damn near gave Da a heart attack. But then just as the Countess is getting mad at Nuln for the prices for all those handguns - which the EIC is being paid to ship, by the way - Wilhelmina has a word with her and gives her the idea, what if Stirland made the guns? And you know, Blutdorf already has a crossbow factory, it's got a Guild of Engineers, it's a safe distance from Sylvania, so where better? So Wilhelmina turns around and gives me back all that money I bought her share with, and we've just broken ground on a handgun factory that's going to have an exclusive contract to supply the Army of Stirland." You look down at the map and consider the economic kraken he's describing, and you wonder if maybe it's a good thing this isn't your problem any more. --- You remain in Blutdorf long enough to catch up entirely with Anton's life. It seems that his inheritance has made him one of the most eligible bachelors of Stirland, and he's rapidly being backed into a corner and only Wilhelmina's ruthless advice has kept him from just marrying one at random to stop the sharks from circling. The closest he has to a preference is a perpetually frazzled graduate from the Imperial Gunnery School of Nuln, who has cropped red hair, a missing ear, and a patent on a very interesting variation on the Repeater Hand Gun, with only a single barrel and a revolving chamber for holding the rounds themselves; when the girl isn't looking you compare the design with your own Dwarven revolver, and wonder if it's parallel evolution or if the girl has been looking outside the Empire for inspiration. More conventionally, there are marriages within Stirland. Specifically, the Count of Halstedt has a daughter, and the Baron of Marburg has a niece. A glance at the map confirms your suspicions: the former would spread the EIC into an overland trade route with the Moot, whereas the latter would allow the EIC as much a stranglehold over the Stir as they had over the Aver. You frown at the map in thought, trying to decide how much you disapprove of Wilhelmina's string-pulling. It could be argued it was in his best interest - after all, 16% of the EIC's profits were Anton's profits. "Or," he says nervously, "I could just marry you." You almost laugh off his words, but Anton doesn't generally joke about such topics, and your surprised stare spurs him to continue. "It's like with Wilhelmina and trade. There are things I," he waves his hands vaguely in the air. "I don't understand, and I know I don't understand them, and I'd much rather just let someone who I trust that does know what they're doing take over. Probably whoever I end up marrying is going to be able to get me to do just about anything they want to, so I might as well marry someone that can already do that and hasn't done anything bad with it, right?" There may have been moments where you imagined what it would be like to be proposed to, and none of them were anything at all like this, but nevertheless you're at least a little touched. Anton faced a future where his life was probably going to fall completely under the sway of a woman, and in his straightforward way he had decided that you were the most trustworthy woman for the job. You let him know that you'll think about it, and he hastily says that that's perfectly okay, and even if you say no that it would be okay, and he shouldn't have even said anything, and you just smile and hug him until he calms down again. --- The thought keeps your thoughts well occupied on the way up the Nuln Road. With painful memories now insulated by your graduation and the Expedition, you can admit that you had more than a little bit of a crush on Abelhelm, and if things had been different... well, things probably wouldn't have been different, he was a Witch Hunter and he was your boss and he had a daughter only six years your younger, but maybe they could have been... but now you'll never know, and that's the end of it. So with the age of thirty just over the horizon, where did that leave you? What prospects did you have in your life? A bunch of Journeymen, two of which were involved with each other, one was actually a Magister, and you're still annoyed about that, and two that seem at times like they're more a decade younger than you than merely a few years. Beyond that, a huge number of men who were rightfully terrified of you, and a number of Dwarves who... well, maybe the idea wasn't completely unthinkable, but from what you've heard they don't even have, well, urges, it was entirely a matter of duty and clan instead of drives and entertainment. Maybe some bold adventurer could seek their fortune at the Karak, or some clever trader could travel up Death Pass, or a counterpart from one of the more tolerable other Colleges could be drawn by the discoveries to be made, and maybe any of the former could just happen to be suitably close to you in age and suitably easy on the eyes... but that's a lot of maybes. Maybe romance just isn't in the cards for you. Abstinence isn't mandatory for the Grey College, but nor is it discouraged, and many a Grey Wizard goes through life without romantic entanglement. Some say that eventually, becoming sufficiently attuned to Ulgu would steal those desires away. Even if that's not the case, it could definitely get in the way - it's easy enough to say that anyone scared off by a few flickery candles and a wandering shadow wasn't worth having anyhow, but could the same be said if you sink deeper into Ulgu's embrace and they forgot your face every time they looked away? So maybe a bird in the hand was worth any number in the bush. Maybe a marriage of understanding with Anton would be mutually beneficial. He may not be an intellectual juggernaut, but he's kind and he's likeable and he is, at times, shockingly competent. Maybe Baroness Weber would be a suitable addition to your growing list of titles. You're relieved when you arrive and can table the entire debate and focus on spending time with Wilhelmina. The EIC headquarters has grown, swallowing up the townhouses to either side, and from the foyer you can see a hive of efficient activity buzzing away, easily the equal of any of the ones you raided during your one-night take-down of the Stirlandian League. The man at the desk doesn't glance up from his papers. "Do you have an appointment?" You smile. "A standing one, actually." "Who with?" he asks, boredom dripping from his words as he finally deigns to look up, and recognition and then panic flashes across his face. "Magister Weber! Of course, I apologize, at once, I mean-" The stammering man leads you through the building and you're gratified at the awestruck faces as you pass. You've never had much direct involvement with the EIC, but apparently the Dämmerlichtreiter owning 36% of your employer leaves a certain impression. "Mathilde!" Wilhelmina cries, enveloping you with a hug as enthusiastic as Anton's. "Thought for sure you'd end up cornered in some Godsforsaken corner of that Dwarf warren for years. Already run out of greenskins to fight?" "Two down, six to go," you reply with a smile. "Eight Peaks has an Aircorp now, so I figured I may as well drop by, see how Stirland has fared." Fared without you, is the unspoken meaning, but Wilhelmina grasps it nevertheless. "To her credit, she jumped right in and took right up stomping the hell out of Sylvania where you left off. But hell, that's all she's been doing, and she's been burning money to make it happen. A lot of that money has ended up in my pocket so I can't complain too much, but if she didn't have the Hunter's Hills to sell off she'd have run dry long since, and even then there's not many that want to buy at the price she wants to sell, so she can't be too far off skint." "A ripe situation," you comment, eyes going to the map on her wall, larger and more detailed than Anton's. Everything west of Halstedt is stamped with the familiar sigil of the EIC. "Couldn't be riper. She made an Exciseman her Steward. An Exciseman! Anyone trying to smuggle goods through Stirland is catching hell, sure, but it takes more than that to keep it all running, and I should know. He's farmed out the taxation rights! Sure, with proper restrictions so it's not quite the bad old days, but when the one that buys those rights is me, suddenly the EIC can undercut every poor bastard from here to Kirchham who still has to pay tolls and tariffs. I'd call it highway robbery but I've got three lads here and two in Altdorf triple-checking that every single step of it is completely legal, because sooner or later she's going to realize she handed me Western Stirland on a platter." You stare past Wilhelmina at the map. As the reign of Dieter IV quite thoroughly proved, if someone's stupid enough to cut their own purse, there's no law against picking up the trail of gold they leave in their wake. But as the very same example also proved, there comes a point where enough's enough and something must be done. Does your old friend's burgeoning trade empire approach that point? Has she just boasted of the entire plan to a Grey Wizard, whose remit is to crush such overreaches? Some of your thoughts must have shown on your face, because Wilhelmina turns solemn and follows your gaze. "I pay every tax she hasn't been stupid enough to sell me, and all the ones that go to Altdorf. She had a stake in all of this and it was her idea to sell it. I'm not skinning the sheep like the Stirlandian League - more trade than ever is flowing, and the ledgers are open to you if you want to confirm that. If you think this crosses a line, go ahead and bat your eyes at Anton or wave your sword at those silly buggers along the Aver and you've got the percentages to stuff the djinn back in the jar. But the way I see it, with the Countess selling everything she can get her hands on, there's plenty worse than me that could have bought it." She's not wrong. If Roswita wants to turn trickles of income into lump sums now, that's a decision her title grants her the authority to make and there's hundreds that would come running to fill the vacuum if Wilhelmina stopped being the one to benefit. Wilhelmina is a known quantity, a decent person, and not least of all, almost entirely at your mercy. "I saw Anton on my way up," you say conversationally. "Gone into business with him?" "You're damn right I have," she says, grateful for the change in topic. "Abelhelm sent him off to round up the usual assortment of Tilean pikemen and he came back with a dragon. Abelhelm sent him to sort out that taxation mess in Flensburg and he redraws the political map and founded a riverine monopoly on the side. He got Nuln and Zhufbar to try to one-up each other with cannon. I can't talk to a Dwarf or a Wissenlander without that coming up! The largest concentration of cannon in history, and yeah they got the job done because you would have murdered them if they didn't, but they were there in the first place because of that boy in Blutdorf. So absolutely, the moment he had the key to the treasury, I took however much he could scrape up from it and handed over 16% and I wrote the difference off with a smile." "Put like that, it does make sense." If someone could be a threat to you, give them a stake in your success. It's a very trader-y way of doing things, but you can't deny its effectiveness. "Thoughts on his marriage?" "Remember when we first arrived at Eagle Castle and he seemed like a sheep among wolves? That's what he really is when some tart starts cooing and flashing skin. He doesn't know what to do about it so he gets nervous and he'll agree to anything in the hopes that things start making sense again. I was half tempted to snap him up myself and see if the second lot of children come out better than the first, but in the end I just pointed him at ones that'd actually have some give rather than being all take." "The Moot Road, the Aver, and a gunsmith." "Benefits for everybody. I like the idea of having the EIC stamp on ten thousand rifles instead of that bloody Nuln sigil, but a crack at that Ostermark channel or the bounty of the Moot would be nice too." --- You linger in Wurtbad long enough to catch up with Wilhelmina, hear the latest set of disappointments her sons have inflicted on her, and pass on a few tips. The tidal wave of silver in the hands of returning Stirlanders is definitely the sort of tip she can use. All those brave souls will be wanting land to settle down on, and it just so happens that an Elector Countess had been trying to sell land for long enough that she'd dropped the price a few notches. If she was aware of the triumphant return of Codrin and his ilk she'd know to keep a hold of it a little longer, but it just so happens that she had decided against retaining the services of the stunningly talented Grey Wizard who happened to have that information. You indulge in just a little schadenfreude as Wilhelmina gobbles up vast tracts of the Hunter's Hills, which are soon to take a massive leap in demand, and not one to miss a trick, Wilhelmina also strikes a deal with the Stirland mint to supply high-purity Dwarven silver for them to debase into rather more than the sixty coins Dwarves would make of it. Land for gold, silver for land, gold for silver - a level of alchemy beyond the arts of the Gold College. Wilhelmina is also fascinated at the possibilities of a resurgent Karak Eight Peaks - not for making the long trip to the Far East, for even with Death Pass safe the Dark Lands remain just as treacherous, but for being on hand to supply equipment to those who dare the trip and skim the choicest goods from those who succeed before anyone else has had a chance to apply their markups. Once you've established yourself, you'll certainly have to consider helping the EIC build a branch in the Karak - the information that you could haul in and send back to the Grey College would be even more valuable than the fortunes to be made. You also raise the matter of your outstanding debt to Stirland, and Wilhelmina's able to put your mind at ease. Not only does the contract explicitly disallow any early calling in of the amount owed, it also can only be sold after first refusal is offered to the EIC, and at a substantial discount. Roswita can either deal with you paying off the debt at a leisurely pace, or she can eliminate a significant chunk of it and deliver it into the hands of an organization that you and yours have a stranglehold on. You're once again reminded how terrifying Wilhelmina has become in matters of finance. When your visit comes to an end, you enlist Wilhelmina's help in retrieving some of your most sensitive belongings from the Sunken Palace. You don't know how your gallons of snake blood would react to the prolonged vibration of a gyrocopter ride, and you're more than a little concerned that you do know how said snake's prison would react, so for the first time in quite a while you'll be restricted to more mundane methods of transportation - albeit with fresh horses at every waystation and then a Dwarven steampship down the Skull River and up the Blood can be considered mundane. That does mean you'll have time enough to decide what your answer to Anton will be. You don't love him that way, but nor did the other women; Reinhild was the closest, and the only attraction she held to Anton was that she'd talk about guns instead of all the other topics Anton's circling suitors would bring up, and Anton understood guns. Aristocracy normally means not marrying for love, and often never finding it. Perhaps love could take care of itself between him and you, and even if it didn't, it wouldn't be the worst fate in the world to spend your life with someone you merely liked. Or perhaps Anton should hold out for a storybook ending... but he has proven very bad at holding out, and you know that storybook endings don't always, or even often, come true. [ ] Marry them... - [ ] Reinhild Gerber With only a clever mind and an ambitious blueprint. - [ ] Stefanie Krebs Delivering a stranglehold on the Aver. - [ ] Cordula von Halstedt Linking the EIC to the Moot. - [ ] Wilhelmina. She said she's thought about it. Give her a push and promise to call in a favour or two with the Jade College. [ ] Marry me... - [ ] Soon. Gyrocopters are wonderful things. You could spend weekends at Blutdorf, or he could spend them atop Karag Nar. - [ ] When I return. An engagement ring and a promise for when you return to the Empire. [ ] Stay single. Marry for love. Anton's achieved miracles for others. Maybe he could do so for himself. [ ] Stay out of it. Without any input from you, he's likely to end up following whatever Wilhelmina advises, making this a de facto vote for the 'Marry Them' option. And once that topic is taken care of, the arguably more significant but considerably less fraught matter of your future at Karak Eight Peaks can be ruminated on over your long return. You've committed to sticking around but not said anything of the capacity in which you'd do so. The Undumgi could use a leader, and you could be that leader, and under your stewardship a trade boom in Death Pass could bring incredible profits not just for the Karak, but also Barak Varr and the Empire. On the other hand, none of those profits will be possible if the Karak falls again, and you could certainly be a powerful combatant against the threats to the Karak, either inside or out. Or you could be the first line of defence against the less direct threats to King Belegar's dream - especially since you've seen triumph after triumph against the strange energies of the Waaagh. Or maybe you'd prefer no role at all, and simply remain on hand for the direst emergencies while you catch up on your backlog, which is only slightly lightened by the unloading of the strange eggs. Intrigue Advisor, Internal Focus Your focus will be on monitoring, infiltrating, and sabotaging the forces in the six untaken Peaks, as well as those that dwell underneath the Karak. The Marshal will focus on dangers outside the Karak. Other candidates for this position are Halken Stonebeard, Longbeard and Eldest of Clan Angrund; Dreng, Hammerer of Clan Huzkul and former ranger; and Titus Muggins, leader of the Halfling Fieldwardens. Intrigue Advisor, External Focus Your focus will be on dangers outside the Karak. Obvious dangers such as the greenskins of Black Crag and Iron Rock and the Dragon Ogres of Thunder Mountain, but also the potential dangers of those few human neighbours close enough to be relevant, such as the Border Princes. The Marshal will focus on dangers inside the Karak. Other candidates for this position are Prince Gotri and his Aircorp, Master Rein Helsturm of the Winter Wolves, and Prince Kazrik, for building ties with Karak Azul. Stewardship Advisor, Trade Focus You will be in command of the Undumgi and Karag Nar, and will be first point of contact for Ulrikadrin. You would be responsible for protecting the incredibly vital route back to Barak Varr; the side benefit is that if Death Pass is a safe passage, trade caravans to the Far East become merely very risky instead of insanely dangerous, and the Karak would stand to benefit hugely. Other candidates for the position are Princess Edda Grimbrow, who would emphasize a traditional Dwarven artisanal economy; Miner Durgrim Redmane, who would emphasize a mining-based economy; and Priestess Hluodwica Stoutheart, who would emphasize an agricultural economy. Keep in mind that these parts of the economy will still be functioning even if they aren't emphasized, and you will be able to choose whether you bring them under your purview or allow them to function independently. Court Wizard, Magic Focus You will be the first responder when anything inexplicable, unexpected or eldritch happens. Though this is the Learning 'slot', this is an active warzone, not an established industrial center climbing the tech tree. This will be a role focused on responding to and finding solutions for problems nobody else understands. Other candidates for the role are Prince Gotri, Engineer, and Kraggi Senior, Runesmith. No Role You will have no direct responsibilities, though you will be on hand if all-out war breaks out again, and would likely spend your time catching up on your backlog. The Grey College will likely start prodding you to start making yourself useful before too long, unless you kept it mollified with research papers or odd jobs. [ ] 'Head Ranger' (Spymaster), Internal Focus [ ] 'Head Ranger' (Spymaster), External Focus [ ] Steward [ ] Court Wizard [ ] No role - On the topic of marriage: age concerns are for people who don't have Jade Wizards in their rolodex. - A true love happy ending is not impossible for Anton, but as Wilhelmina has attested, the vultures are circling and Anton has no defences against them. - Please keep it reasonable. Mathilde has been put on the spot a little here, but this is not a 'Shipping War'. This is a fictional life we are writing the story of together. Everyone here is trying to make the best decisions they can. Nobody here is your enemy. - I'm not outright declaring a moratorium, but I do think it would be best to put the 'how many points do we spend on a sword' topic to bed until there's a voting option related to it. - help the updates just keep getting longer - Those dead set for or against marrying Anton don't have to worry about strategic voting: 'Marry them' vs 'Marry me' will be tallied first, then preferred marriage candidate/time is counted separately.

Turn 25: Scouring Fury (Part One)

Spoiler: Plan: Rearm and Refuel (Alternative)

-[X] Assign Battle Brothers:
--[X] 25 to 5th Company
--[X] 20 to 4th Company
-[X] Assign Veterans To 1st Company
--[X] 10 5th Company Veterans
-[X] Assign New Fleet Additions
--[X] 1st Fleet: 4 Gladius, 2 Hunters, 2 Transports (1x Ravenous Spirit, 1x Spiraling Fury), 9 Gunships (7x Omnis Arcanum, 1x Ravenous Spirit, 1x Spiraling Fury)
--[X] 4th Fleet: 4 Gladius, 3 Hunters, 2 Novas, 2 Transports (1x Burning Seeker, 1x Legacy of Polonius), 10 Gunships (8x Scientia Est Potentia, 1x Burning Seeker, 1x Legacy of Polonius)
--[X] 5th Fleet: 3 Gladius, 2 Hunters, 2 Novas, 2 Transports (1x Rage of Erudition, 1x Great Father's Fist), 12 Gunships (7x Litany of Fury, 3x Rage of Erudition, 2x Great Father's Fist)
--[X] 10th Fleet: 2 Gladius, 1 Nova, 1 Gunship (Faith's Horizon)
-[X] Korianis Hunting - Greenskins
--[X] All of the Chapter except 5th Company, heavy support from Chapter Librarium to locate the Orks
-[X] Deathwatch Desperation - Rise of the Alien
--[X] 10x Veterans (squad formerly assigned to Meridian)
-[X] Deathwatch Desperation - Dire Demands
-[X] Assign the freshly constructed Raven Aegis Talismans to Nero Achillian and Justinius Probalis
-[X] Use 1 Minor Favor to gain 8 Thunderhawks (3 transports, 5 gunships) from Governor Derosa
-[X] Replace the scout squad on Meridian with 9 fresh scouts and a veteran and if the returning 9 scouts are promoted to full battle brothers, assign them to the 4th Company.
-[X] Training
--[X] Chapter Main: Ballistic Skill with Hadrian
--[X] Chapter Secondary: Strength with Hannibal Palrun
-[X] Apothecary
--[X] Implant Test-Slaves with Gene-Seed to harvest At Start Of Next Turn - 100 Gene-seed
--[X] Implant Neophytes [2nd Stage] (95 Total)/ Psyker Neophyte [2nd Stage] (6 Total) with Gene-seed - 101 Gene-seed
-[X] Chief Librarian
--[X] Anti-Anti-Psyker Study
-[X] Master of Recruits
--[X] Enact Blood Trails Upon The Following Of Your Recruiting Worlds (Meridian/Junius)
-[X] Forge [675 BP Total]
--[X] Scout Armor x40 [320 BP]
--[X] Relic Construction
---[X] Scout Armor for Cyrus Octavius [20 BP]
--[X] 10x Lascannons [80 BP]
--[X] 10x Plasma Cannons [80 BP]
--[X] 10x Plasma Guns [60 BP]
--[X] 10x Melta Guns [60 BP]
--[X] 1x Power Sword [5 BP]
--[X] 5x Tarantula Sentry Gun (Multi-Melta) [50 BP]

Spoiler: Start Of Turn Summary

Gene-Seed Matters
100 Implanted Into Test-Slaves/Harvest Completes At
101 Gene-Seed Used On Neophytes
185 For Start Of Turn

Recruitment (Advances During Last Turn To Start Of This Turn)
Planets Chosen: Meridian+Junius
Aspirants Gained: 231
Psyker Aspirants Gained: 12
Aspirant Advances: 231 -> 168 Neophytes [1st Stage]/12 -> 8 Psyker Neophytes [1st Stage]
Neophyte Advances: 168 Neophytes [1st Stage] -> 146 Neophytes [2nd Stage] / 8 Psyker Neophytes [1st Stage] -> 5 Psyker Neophytes [2nd Stage]
Specialist Leaning Neophytes Recognized: 0 Apothecary Neophytes /4 Techmarine Neophytes / 0 Chaplain Neophytes -> 4 Specialist Neophytes [2nd Stage]
2nd Stage Neophytes Require Immediate Gene-Seed Implantation In Turn 26 Or Will Risk Implant Failure As They Age

10th Company Matters
Neophytes [2nd Stage] -> 95 Gene-Seed Used: 95 -> 74 Scouts [1st Stage] 21 Gene-Seed Returned To Storage
Scouts [1st Stage]: 74 (Just Promoted) / 37 (Already Established) -> 24 to Scouts [2nd Stage] (111 Not Even Close To Up For Promotion Yet) 13 Gene-Seed Returned to Storage
Scouts [2nd Stage]: 85 -> 85 Battle Brothers (Unassigned)

Conclusion: 74 71 Scouts [1st Stage]/ 24 Scouts [2nd Stage] Currently In 10th Company

Razor Squad Changes Members: 9 Scouts [2nd Stage] Returned To Company. Promoted To Battle Brothers. Assigned as per vote to 4th Company. 9 Scouts [2nd Stage] Pulled From Lists To Replenish Razor Squad.

6 Psyker Neophytes [2nd Stage] -> 6 Lexicanum

Warning: Gene-Seed Implantation Awakens Latent Psychic Abilities In Implantees. 3 Scouts [1st Stage] Awaken As 3 Lexicanum.

1st Company Matters
Talon Squad Delivered To Deathwatch. Ordo Xenos Appreciates It.

Crafting Matters
2 Avatar Shards Used For Raven’s Aegis Talisman Creation [Success/Success]
Scout Armor x40 [320 BP]
10x Lascannons
10x Plasma Cannons
10x Plasma Guns
10x Melta Guns
1x Power Sword
5x Tarantula Sentry Gun (Multi-Melta)
Relic Construction: Relic Scout Armor For Captain Cyrus

Training Matters
[Ballistic Skill (5 to 6) 443+66+Hadrian(25)=534/600]
[Strength (4 to 5) 240+29+Hannibal(25)=294/500]

Scouring Fury
+060.M42+ To +065.M42+
+Let Your Fury Scour The Xeno Forevermore+

“In the name of the Unknown Primarch, go with honor,” Gabriel intoned gravely.

His bionics lent his voice with a deeper vibrato than most throats of flesh might have managed. In the far ranges of the system, far away from the fearful eyes of most Imperial citizenry, the Chapter Master of the Blood Ravens gazed down at the members of Talon Squad. For many long years they had scoured the Hive World Meridian, guardians and hunters in one. It was one thing to hunt down the feral orks, hive gangers, and myriad filthy mutants and xenos that managed to live out amongst the spired world. It would be another entirely to be thrown into the maelstrom of battle that called insistently for ever more bodies. Captain Marcus stood next to him, helm held underneath one arm, his eyes gazing across each battle brother with deliberate care.

He was carefully memorizing their faces, for it was more than likely that they would never be seen alive again.

“We commend you to the Death Watch, Sergeant Alexos. You go now into the darkness. May you bring the Emperor’s light to His foes.”

Sergeant Alexos nodded, and though he still bore his helm Marcus could easily see the stern cast of his features beneath through memory.

“None shall find us wanting, Captain.”

Against the star-speckled black of the void, a black thunderhawk embossed with the sigils of the Deathwatch rested easily in the flight deck of the Litany of Fury. A pair of Kill Marines stood in silence by its opened doors, escorting the representative of the Ordo Xenos. The man himself carried himself wearily, as if even the weight of the Inquisition’s symbol around his neck was some back-bending weight. Still, the Interrogator approached, a servo skull floating just over his shoulder hefting a small stack of dataslates in its delicate appendages. He does not bow to the Chapter Master, though whether it is because he does not deign to give the proper respect or is in simply that much of a hurry is unknowable.

“Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos,” the Interrogator smiled with glittering metal teeth. “The Ordo Xenos gives their thanks for your response to their call. The war against the endless hordes goes on yet, and the bodies help. As to your other request…,” he gestures, sending the servo skull over to the Chapter Master. “It was an intriguing one. We do not often call others upon our wars…but then these are trying times. All of the following are either targets too great for a single kill-team, or ones that have proven surprisingly resistant to our efforts. Any and all would be…most welcome if destroyed.”

The Interrogator then gave the Chapter Master and Captain facing him the slightest of nods. There was not even a flicker of horror at the grotesque sight of the 1st Company’s Captain.

“May the Emperor watch over your efforts.”

“He watches over us all, Interrogator,” Marcus responded flatly.

“Indeed. Now, we must be off. Aliens to kill. Always aliens to kill.”

The Deathwatch Strike Cruiser departed soon after, ten Blood Ravens held within its depths. Only the Emperor knew if they would be return in the flesh, or as mere commendations written upon vellum.

Talon Squad (1st Company) Departs To Deathwatch.

====================================

“Try again,” Justinius said with remarkable patience.

Before him, ten whole Lexicanum focused their combined energies, near-perfect in their linking. Yet, the strange materials of the destroyed eldar anchorage remained inviolate. The study was, for lack of a better phrase, apocalyptically frustrating. For all that the general trust of psykers and their abilities amongst the chapter had waned heavily after the heresy of Kyras, amongst those who actually were psykers there was a steady pride for their powers. The only other possible result was shame, and so pride it was. Some were quiet about it, others boastful. Less now, after all these years. But nothing was quite so disquieting as the strange creations of the dark eldar. To be stymied at the one thing for which near every moment was spent controlling, training, exercising?

Unacceptable.

All throughout the Ultima Librarium Sanctorum, the whole of the Librarius outside of the Epistolaries had assembled to bend their not inconsiderable abilities to one task. And, to Justinius’ growing irritation, they were failing. Months of work, all to learn a lesson that had already been learned when the kabal had been assaulted in the first place. Certain materials and torn apart portions of that xeno space station, weapons wielded by its defenders, the very armor of their leaders and champions slain in battle. All had been carefully catalogued, some slated for destruction, and others still for study. A study that, at the moment, seemed entirely fruitless.

But Justinius was relentless. Every single Librarian in the chapter was. It was simply in their nature.

“We have years and years yet, my brothers. Continue your work.”

Study Will Take 2 Entire Turns [Current+Next]. All Non-Epistolary Librarians Unavailable Until Start Of Turn 27.

==========================================

(Relic Construction: Scout Armor [-20 BP] [1d100=98. Relic Construction Extreme Success!)[/center]

“Cyrus.”

“Martellus.”

“Explain.”

The eldest techmarine that the Blood Ravens had gestured down towards the matte grey armor which lay upon the slab between them. There was no expression visible due to his helm, but there was a small amount of excitement in his voice. Behind him, his servo arm twitched and danced. Cyrus kept his arms folded.

“It was by the grace of the Omnissiah that the Deathwatch came when they did, and that you have such a storied history among them,” Martellus began. “And they provided certain materials to complete the project.”

Delicately, he carefully lifted the armor, and privately marveled within his helm at the visible surprise on Cyrus’ face when he did. For the light bent around it, and the armor itself ceased to be the grey of the slab but rather they dark red of Martellus’ armor where it touched his. As he lifted it higher, the finely articulated arms of the set shifted again as it raised above Martellus’ shoulder, taking on the cast of the wall behind them. The entire thing, in truth, had almost no real color in and of itself. The cloak upon its shoulders was, even compared to the armor itself, practically invisible if one did not watch the lighting as well as a space marine could.

“Cameleoline,” Cyrus said. It wasn’t a question. He knew what it was.

“I know that Deathwatch sharpshooters favor the material, and you well know that our scouts use camo-cloaks. You yourself bear one. But this,” Martellus ran his fingers through the material of the cloak on the armor with care. “This is more than that. I’ve personally coated the whole of the armor plates, and actually managed to create a deliberate mixture in the ceramite plates during the forging, the fabrics woven with the more advanced.”

Cyrus actually nodded, his lips pursed as he examined it himself after a gesture from Martellus.

“Interesting. This is based on Deathwatch Scout Armor, is it not?”

The glare from his cybernetic eye grew brighter as his remaining organic eye narrowed.

“You gained access to their designs?”

Martellus raised his hands, palms facing towards the Master of Recruits.

“Only through conversation. The Deathwatch was willing to speak to me of it, considering how many of our brothers we have sent to them. Especially considering your own respected tour with them.”

Cyrus grunted.

“I thought you were having Calus and Daedal work on this project.”

Martellus’ scowl could be felt through the expressionless mask of his helm.

“They are working on other projects at the moment.”

At that moment, doors to forge’s side room opened, revealing two techmarines arguing between one another. Behind them several servitors dragged a pallet that groaned under the weight of all the weapons and creations upon them. Melta guns, lascannons, plasma guns, and plasma cannons. There was even a power sword sitting upon a rack amongst it all. Both paused upon seeing them.

“Ah…,” Daedal began. “Master Martellus. We were just coming to find you to report our project completion.”

Calus swept his hand over the various weapons.

“Everything has been crafted as you order, Master.”

Martellus nodded curtly, leaving Cyrus to his prize, and approached. However, before he could do more than run his eyes and various subsystems over the offerings, checking for flaws, he paused. Slowly he turned his head back and forth across the pallet.

“Where are the turrets, techmarines?”

He turned to loom over Calus, even as behind him Daedal made frantic throat cutting motions.

“We…you normally personally take care in the turret construction, Master, and-,”

Daedal slumped, an impressive feat of agility and articulated movement inside of his armor.

“I was clearly busy!” Martellus shouted, gesticulating wildly towards the now empty slab. “Do you know how much time it takes to personally infuse individual cereamite plates with high grade cameleoline? Let alone making high grade cameleoline?! Cyrus, you-,”

He paused, seeing that the Captain of the 10th Company had already left, his armor in tow. Sighing, a noise made into a growl by his helm’s rebreather, he turned back to his juniors with clenched fists.

“I want to see five multi-melta equipped tarantula turrets. And until I get them, I don’t want to look at either of you. Dismissed!”

“Yes, Master Martellus,” the techmarines shouted, turning and moving at battlefield pace to escape the wrath of his gaze.

Martellus sighed as he heard their bickering start up again before the doors slammed shut once more.

Relic Created: [Shadow Hunter's Raiment: Cameleoline-integrated high grade armor with accompanying camo-cloak. Contains sound-dampening materials, as well as additional thermal reduction technology for stealth purposes. Integrated targeting links of the armor are specially adapted for integration with Cyrus Octavian's own cybernetics. (+1 Ballistic Skill, +Further Improved Stealth Capabilities)]

===============================================

The whole of the Blood Ravens, what remained of them aside from the 5th Company over Zerann, set out immediately. The greenskins had been sighted all over the sector, including Subsector Aurelia. That, especially, could not be allowed. A trio of kroozers here, a swarm of over twenty smaller ramships there, all of which had infested various asteroid fields or simply hung in the black. Nothing that could, individually, possibly win out against the combined chapter fleet. But there were times for defense, static or otherwise, and times to hunt down the vile alien. From the remnants of raids on various colony worlds, the corpses left behind on defensive stations barely held by their void armsmen, the materials were gathered. While the various Lexicanum and Codiciers did their vital work in finding ways past the anti-psyker technologies of the dark eldar, the highest of their order within the Blood Ravens set to work. Though they numbered but three, their potential fourth’s presence required with the rest of 5th Company, they did their duty as space marines.

Their greatest, the Chief Librarian Justinius, student of Jonah Orion, led the hunt through the warp. Assembled about him were the Epistolaries of the Blood Ravens. So few, compared to how many there once had been. But they had strength in them yet. Within an isolated chamber within the Omnis Arcanum, they began the ritual. The corpse of a slain ork weirdboy, left behind after a successful hunt led by Captain Cyrus, proved the focal point. For in the realm of the beyond, the stinking searing presence of the greenskin’s unique energies could be sought. It was a dangerous thing, to peer past the veil, but a needed one. With the orks spread across the whole of the sector, there was little point in trying to be everywhere at once. Even if the chapter had been at full strength, they would not have been able to challenge the orks properly. Not with the enemy’s numbers and their tactics, despite how strange the latter word was to even consider when viewing greenskins.

So, instead, they sought them by their souls. Through the screaming, raging, utterly unique emerald lightning storm that was their ‘WAAAAGH!!!’ energies. A seemingly infinite pool, one that fed and was fed by the very existence of the alien. Epistolary Nero’s bionic eyes shorted out many time as he gazed into the warp, while the ears of Epistolary Trajan bled as the howls of the warp’s myriad denizens attempted to deafen him. But between the two, hexagrammic symbols scrawled upon steel formed a focusing circle around the feet of the Chief Librarian. Within him, psychic power glowed like a blinding nimbus, his eyes blinded to the material realm but painfully open to the empyrean ocean. And in that moment, he was surrounded, the whole of the Omnis Arcanum was as it traveled through the warp. Daemons aplenty squalled and seethed at his very existence, hungry to devour him, yet he plunged on. Those that made the attempt were burnt away, or strangely confused by the blinking beacon in the farther distance held within the Litany of Fury.

For weeks, this went on, exhausting the librarians and even causing distress to the serfs. The increased attention from unholy beings was beginning to wear upon the psyche of their mortal servants in the extreme. Strange warp eddies buffeted the chapter’s ships, nearly causing the total disappearance and loss of Burning Seeker. At another time, another strike cruiser entirely appeared alongside the fleet, its heraldry that of the Blood Ravens but with no identifying codes to its name. It bore the most grievous of damages, and no hails were returned, before the warp shuddered again and it disappeared once more. In the weeks afterwards, there were not even any records to be found within the auspex systems. Only in the memories of the space marines did it remain, servitors and serfs alike professing total ignorance.

Until.

Until in the far distance, an entire year into the chase, there was a flicker that became a flash that became a staccato series of continual blooms of green stormsound. The Blood Ravens slid out of the warp gratefully, for the chase had been long, with little combat to show for it. The vast majority of the time spent had been in training. Training across the decks of the ships, from the barked orders of Captains and veteran sergeants. But as the battle barges emerged along with their attendant fleets, the bittersweet fruit of success was borne to them by the reports on the auspex. Valiant work on that of the cogitators and logic engines determined that the Blood Ravens had chased their foe out into the deep black. Beyond the Sector itself, in a strange place between solar systems, planets and worlds entirely. The only illumination around aside from the ships of the Imperium came from distant stars and the roaring flames and ramshackle industry before them.

It was a massive moving asteroid, the back of it stuffed with more engines than were possessed by the Blood Raven fleets combined, the front haphazardly carved in facsimile to a leering orkish skull. The taken asteroid was larger than most any ork ‘rok’ that had ever been sighted in the Blood Raven records. It was practically a supermassive space hulk in terms of size, but where most space hulks combined hulls and eras across thousands of years and multiple species lines, this monstrosity was completely of greenskin creation. A trio of cityscapes constructed of smog belching pipes and haphazardly attached buildings stuck out at random locations. Certain portions of the rock had been carved away entirely, revealing a vast hollowed out creation, while dozens of holes punched through were clear departure points for swarms of attack craft and even shoals of smaller greenskin ships. Like flies surrounding a greater beast, they alighted on or within it in equal numbers with those departing. Large rusted and garishly painted skeletal apparatuses were implanted across its body, within which the nascent bodies of various ork ships could be seen under construction.

Whatever it was, it thundered through the void without a care for anything at all.

“By the Emperor,” Justinian whispered through grit teeth.

In the gaze of those who could properly perceive it, it was a sickly green sun of energies, one that twitched and blazed without pattern or sense of sanity. One that prickled and suddenly turned, a mirror to the activity erupting across its surface as the Blood Ravens were detected. Out and away from the rituals of the Librarians, Gabriel Angelos stared out at the foe across tactical screens. Behind him, and placed high upon the command throne for the ship as was befitting his position, the Master of the Fleet sat and absorbed the information flooding into his mind through the connectors. Hadrian, Captain of the 4th Company, grit his teeth.

“It is turning towards us, Chapter Master.”

“Of course it is,” Gabriel growled. “This, then, is how they managed to escape retribution for so long. A mobile shipyard. Like a parasite, feasting with its swarms of ships and using them to boost their own numbers.”

“Aye, Chapter Master,” Hadrian said, though his voice was somewhat absentminded as he ordered the powering up of weapons across the entire fleet. “The damned thing is the size of two Ramilles-class star forts smashed together. Your orders?”

Gabriel’s lips thinned as he considered the ponderously turning abomination of scrap and rock.

“We should…what is it doing?”

Exerting enough energy from its reactors to erupt likely multiple lesser ships, and with a screech of metal on stone that should by all rights have split eardrums had the void not protected them, the jaws of the asteroid base slowly began to open and close. Teeth the size of frigates crashed into one another again and again. Then, squalling through the vox channels…or rather every channel possible, came an absolute cacophony of boisterous phlegmatic laughter.

“AHAHAHAHAHAHAH! Looks like the skrap is coming to us this time, boyz! Get yer shootas and choppas ready! Oy! You hear me over there, ya freaks!?!”

Despite the sheer impossibility of the distance, a wild mishmash of weapons batteries opened up across the frame of the entire structure. Vast amounts of ordinance were fired in every direction, including back down upon the asteroid as certain missiles failed and twisted back in and on their launch sites. A threat display, brutish but telling in its scope. It was heartening, to see the sites of their lance batteries as they stabbed beams of light into the void. It was disheartening to see how many the enemy actually possessed. Still, there was some small boon that was noted by the auspex scans and bridge crews. Considering the numbers of the reorienting greenskin ships turning towards the astartes vessels, only one conclusion could be reached.

At least some significant part of the orkish fleet which was based at the mobile shipyard, those who partook of the raiding which had gained the ire of the Imperium in the first place, were not present.

There was no point in ordering their forces to prepare for battle. In a twisted manner, both sides were forever made and ready for war.

“Da Doom-Eater iz gunna chomp you all!”

Hunting Action (With Librarius Assistance) Extremely Successful!
- Source Of Attacks: Supermassive Constructor Hulk/Planetoid Located In Dark Space Between Systems Just Outside Korianis Sector
- Self-Identified As: Da Doom-Eater
- Size Equivalent To 2 Ramilles Star Forts In Mass
- Multiple ship-constructing facilities prevalent.
- 14 Pockmark Docking/Entry Bays Scattered Across Planetoid.
- ‘Maw Of Gork (Or Mork)’ Melee/Consuming Characteristic At Front.
- Total Defensive Weapon Compliment Unknown
- 3 Construkta Yards [Alpha/Beta/Gamma]
- Current Known Defensive Fleet: 14 Brute Ramships/9 Onslaught Attack Ships/12 Ravager Attack Ships
- No Kroozer Tonnage Ships Or Above Detected
- Raiding Fleet Elements Not Currently Present
- Unknown Internal Fleet Compliment If Any

Blood Raven Fleet Present:
1st Company Fleet
4th Company Fleet
10th Company Fleet

Phase 1 Orders [Choose One]:
[] Remain At Range: The defensive fleet is coming full steam ahead. Trust to the maneuverability of your own ships to take them apart, while remaining out of range of the ‘Doom-Eater’ weapons. While they outnumber you significantly, even should they succeed in their various boarding procedures, your ships are manned by chapter serfs, defensive turrets, and of course the Blood Ravens themselves. This may allow the ‘Doom-Eater’ to activate further systems or deploy further forces, but is your mission not the depletion of the orkish fleet regardless?
[] Push Forward: Their defensive ships are pathetic, and should be blown past to immediately get the fleet into bombardment range of the enemy…station. At its current size, outright planetary bombardment munitions and tactics are a distinctly viable weapon for once. This will allow, unfortunately, the stations considerable defensive weaponry to fire upon the fleet, of course. But that is the nature of bombardment missions. Plus, the sooner you can get your battle brothers onto its surface, the sooner its various systems can be destroyed. Like, say, weapon systems. Or propulsion. And so on.
[] Retreat For Now: The best defense the xenos had was their distance and the sheer unknown factor anchorage. But now you have found it, have complete auspex scans of it, and can certainly find it again now. A pure void battle like this calls for the Imperial Navy, and you could return to gather more forces to you. On the other hand, now that they know their secret base has been found, they may grow bolder in the time it takes you to return here with other forces in tow.
[] Write-In

Turn 19 - 2479 - The Rebirth of Karak Eight Peaks

Spoiler: Voting results [*] Windreader > Windsage: Your magical senses see more than your normal ones. +2 Learning, even more able to see and understand emotion and magical effects in others. [*] Avatar: You're growing worryingly familiar with being used as a conduit by deities. ??? [*] Take an active hand in the EIC [*] Donate it to whoever ends up leading the Undumgi. -[*] Recruit Maximilian -[*] Recruit Johann Magesight, you reflect on the long road to Barak Varr, is underestimated and underappreciated not just by non-wizards, but also most of those who share the sense. They see it only as their ability to see the Winds they manipulate, instead of delivering an entirely new and unique set of senses to understand the world. Magic doesn't just blow according to its whims, it also gathers around living beings in a reflection of their nature and emotions, and doesn't rely on sufficient light or low ambient noise levels to function. You've used ambient Ulgu as night vision, you've spotted enemies in the dark by the swirl of Winds their emotions generate, you've seen the Winds curdled into necromantic energy and shaped and twisted by the Waaagh and stripped of agency and funnelled into Dwarven Rune magic. You're beginning to suspect you've reached an understanding of the Winds beyond what most Magisters could ever achieve, and even beyond most of the more practical Lord Magisters. The information you can gather from a glance matches descriptions of what Volans was said to be capable of, or even what Teclis described as possible for the Elven Mages of Ulthuan. And it's not just the normal Arcane energies you're beginning to understand, if the Winds could ever be described as 'normal'. Ranald has been a near-constant presence in your life for some time now, but you've also felt the intervention of Sigmar (though only for smiting His enemies, and not for healing His worthiest servant...), born witness to a battle between Ranald and Stromfels, and been in the presence of Gork and possessed by Mork. The Colleges teach that Divine Magic is entirely different to Arcane Magic, and cannot be understood through its lens, but you're beginning to wonder if that's actually true. But then again, perhaps it makes sense that nobody else has pursued this line of enquiry. Most other Gods would either consider the very question ingratitude at best or heresy at worst, and the exceptions would be Gods like Verena who would instead pass on a single orthodoxy that was not to be questioned. But Ranald as you know Him is different. The Trickster, the first of His faces you had come to know, would delight in your seeking of answers to what so many would consider unanswerable questions. The Protector, who made Ranald worship so touchy and who you'd tried to enshrine in the Stirland Watch, would approve of challenging the power structure that would so unfairly deny knowledge to those who could benefit from it. The Gambler had put His thumb on the scales for you many times, including when you were investigating the nature of magic and had almost suffered Shyish discharge to the face or an ill-timed ambush from Wisdom's Asp, and had also put everything on the line alongside you and profited as the two of you robbed Mork of a portion of His power. And the Night Prowler... well, what better to steal than knowledge of the nature of the Gods? Perhaps it makes sense that you are in a position to answer questions that so many haven't even dared to ask in the relatively short history of the Colleges of Magic. --- Hexenstag is a day feared in much of the Empire. In each year, only twice will both Mannsleib and Morrsleib shine full in the night sky, and Hexensnacht is one of them. Priests of Morr go into the graveyards to keep the dead resting soundly as the barrier between the living and the dead is at its thinnest, and everyone else barricades themselves in their home and hangs up charms to protect themselves from any dead that wander the night, both those still encased in rotting flesh or yellowing bone and those whose souls wander freely. Some wish only to conclude unfinished business, but all too many have been twisted by malice or malign energies and seek the suffering of the living. You have not had to fear them since the time in your Apprenticeship when you learned to weave Ulgu into a blade, but though you fancy your own chances against any wandering ghost, you're more than a little curious as to how they'd like an explosive shell through their incorporeal chest. The Dwarf Monitor delivering you and your cargo up the Blood River has a rotating turret-mounted cannon mainly to deter bandits, be they human or greenskin, but you don't doubt that the always-practical Dwarves wouldn't hesitate to use it to repel more exotic boarders. Word from Eight Peaks is that the Council isn't quite ready in time for the new year, but will be ready to convene very shortly after your scheduled return. Some of the Councillors raised an eyebrow, not just from you but from the Dwarves of Barak Varr, who took a very keen interest in the Hold not only because of what it represented for the Karaz Ankor in general, but also for the trade route it sat astride. The Diplomat was to be Prince Kazrik, who'd be considered inexperienced by human standards, let alone Dwarven ones - but it would, of course, cement the goodwill that Karak Azul felt towards Eight Peaks. Military matters were to be split between Dreng, a formerly-Clanless wandering Ranger who had proven himself on the Expedition and been accepted into Clan Huzkul and the Hammerers, and Sky-Thane Gotri, the radical Prince, engineer and pilot from Zhufbar. You'd expected the Eldest of Clan Angrund to have been given one of the positions, and that the other wasn't Ulthar showed that he'd decided that Eight Peaks was secure enough for him to return home. The Steward had long-term implications for the Hold, and you'd considered taking it as leader of the Undumgi and capitalizing heavily on trade with the Far East that Eight Peaks would have made so much safer, and you had expected that the position would have gone to a Miner to capitalize on the many mines that had made the historical Karak rich. Instead it had gone to Princess Edda, who you'd bonded with during the quieter moments of the Expedition over a shared enjoyment of your species' equivalents of a certain genre of literature. Perhaps King Belegar felt the Karak's future would be better with a more balanced mix of the traditional Dwarven industries. Or perhaps the choice was political. Princess Edda wasn't shy about her desire to upgrade her title to Queen. Did the King want to gauge the Princess' abilities to decide if she'd make a suitable wife? Was he supplying her with power ahead of the marriage so he'd have a natural ally among the council? Or had he decided against marrying her, and the position was a consolation prize to maintain his good relations with Karak Izor? The representative of Dwarven faith was a name you were surprised to recognize - Gunnars, the Priest of the Dwarven God of the Dead who'd cleared you of suspicion of lingering Morkish influence at a glance. King Belegar trusted him, and you felt that his stamp of approval of you had proven his competence, but you would have expected a Priest of Grungni or Valaya or Grimnir before one of Gazul. Was this because of a pre-existing bond between the two? Because no prominent Priests of the three main Ancestor Gods had joined the Expedition? Or did King Belegar feel like the main spiritual priority of the Karak was not the prayers of the living, but the tombs of the dead? And finally there was, of course, yourself. A human on the council would raise an eyebrow among the more conservative Dwarves, and a human wizard would raise the other. The Dwarves, of course, had no tradition of a Court Wizard, and normally a scholar or a Runesmith or even an engineer would round out the Council instead. There was certainly an argument to be made that when the Karak was an active warzone (or more of a simmering one, as most of the fighting had given way to scouting and the occasional probing attack from the greenskins and a worrying silence from the Skaven) it meant that a Court Wizard could definitely come in handy, but most Karaks wouldn't even want a wizard on hand to investigate magical phenomena, they'd want a Runesmith to end or at least contain it. The Council wasn't quite as nontraditional as it could have been. Both Halflings and Winter Wolves had been considered for a Marshal position, and the civilian leader of the Halflings, Priestess Hluodwica, had put her name forward for Steward. The presence of royalty from three other Karaks would definitely pay diplomatic dividends. Compared to a scenario where Dwarves had been as much a minority on the Council as they were in the Karak, the Council definitely could have been more radical. You wonder if King Belegar had simply selected what he considered the best candidates for the job, or whether he had deliberately struck a balance that would endear him to the Young Holds without outright insulting the Old. --- As your cart plods sedately through the Underway between Ulrikadrin and Death Pass, you try not to internally seethe at the limitations of flesh and blood horses. You could make the trip yourself in a single day, but even at the relatively hurried pace that the Barak Varr caravaneers kept to you were still looking at a journey of over a week. More than once you'd glared at the delicate contents of your own cart and tried to figure out a way for a Shadowsteed to carry it safely, but there's just too much of it and you certainly couldn't guarantee that none of it would get jostled. Surrounded by darkness only occasionally broken by cart-mounted lanterns, your thoughts turn to a specific Book. Though your joining of the Expedition should have put your internal debate on hold, you'd found your thoughts returning to it again and again. With your quarters picked out and your research materials en route, the time had come to finally decide one way or the other - would you read the Liber Mortis? The reasons not to were pretty convincing. One might be able to make an argument that simply reading the Book didn't count as 'study' under Article 7, but such was the reputation of the book that if anyone ever found out about it, no amount of technicalities could protect you. Though it was Otto von Drak allowing Vlad von Carstein to marry his daughter that had cemented the grip of Necromancy over Sylvania, it had been Frederick van Hal that had introduced it centuries earlier, and the Liber Mortis documented every spell and insight. Copies of even single chapters of the book could transform even the pettiest of necromancers into existential threats to Stirland. The idea of the unedited original in the hands of a Wizard would give the Grand Theogonist conniptions, and many in the Colleges would agree with him. But on the other hand, when Mannfred von Carstein had led an army of the dead upon Altdorf in the Third Vampire War, Grand Theogonist Kurt III had brought forth a copy of the book from the vaults of the Grand Cathedral and read an incantation from its pages, and Mannfred and his army had been forced to retreat as the spell unravelled the terrible magics holding the undead together. As far as you know, that copy still lay in the vaults because even the Sigmarites were forced to concede it could be a powerful force for good, and the Extremely Redacted Liber Mortis (Approved Edition) was standard reading amongst all but the most hidebound of Witch Hunters. Frederick van Hal had not taken to necromancy from madness or a lust for power, but because the Skaven had been overrunning Sylvania and nothing else seemed capable of stopping them. At the very least the insights it contained could be a powerful tool against the undead and possibly even the Skaven, but it could also contain deeper secrets on the nature of magic itself. Necromancy used Shyish to shield the wielders from the corruption of Dhar - what else could be made possible by using one magic to manipulate another? Your mind chases itself in circles as it tries to weigh the unpredictable benefits against the unknowable consequences. [ ] Resolve to read the Liber Mortis. [ ] Resolve to seal away the Liber Mortis. [ ] Resolve to rid yourself of the Liber Mortis. --- You finally arrive, and are able to unpack all of your things into your spacious new 'tower' atop Karag Nar. What it currently lacks in furniture it definitely makes up for in potential, and you could either build up to replace the peak of Karag Nar with a more conventional tower, or down into the mountain below for what practically amounts to unlimited room for expansion. With time to spare before the first meeting in millennia of the Royal Council of Karak Eight Peaks, you finalize one of the decisions you came to and bring your first employees of the role into the fold. Maximilian is delighted to have paying work to go alongside his metalworking apprenticeship, as materials aren't cheap and, as you're keenly aware, neither are College dues. Johann is less enthusiastic but a lot more entertaining, as you put just enough of a hint on Journeyman that he suspects that you know but he doesn't know that you know. You'll start pushing him to visit Altdorf and 'graduate' soon, thus restoring the truth without him having to come completely clean and jeopardize relations with the Dwarves. The Council meeting itself is extremely straightforward, as the almost complete lack of existing infrastructure means almost everyone can be immediately put to work on building said infrastructure. Dreng is to fortify the Eastern Valley to allow forewarning and the swift slaying of any trolls wandering out of Kvinn-Wyr, Prince Gotri is to adapt the former airship hangars atop Karag Lhune into a proper base for his Gyrocopter squadron, and Princess Edda is to see to the construction of suitably sturdy trade carts and the acquisition of draft animals to match, so that Eight Peaks can start sending trade caravans instead of merely receiving them. Karak Azul would normally be the diplomatic priority, but between their reconnection to the rest of the Karaz Ankor and Prince Kazrik's position as diplomat, they could scarcely be happier. So instead he is heading for Barak Varr - until the Halflings manage a successful harvest, Eight Peaks will continue to be completely reliant on regular resupply from them. Gunnars is instructed to continue his current task, which was the establishment of a vast tomb underneath Karag Lhune. The fallen of Angrund are being preserved and protected until they can finally be interred in the tomb of their ancestors, but the traditions of the Dwarves dictate that those that fall in battle far from their Holds are buried there, and King Belegar intends for them to have a tomb worthy of their sacrifice. Your own task is straightforward, and indeed has already begun - the investigation of the spiders of the Chiselwards. King Belegar is skeptical but open to the possibility that they might be convinced to leave peacefully, and failing that, he wants to know how long it would take to starve them out as well as any tactical or strategic insights you can give in case it does come down to a war of extermination. Esbern and Seija aren't formally a part of your payroll and are performing the matter out of a mix of respect for you as their superior and personal curiosity, but King Belegar authorizes their pay for the task anyway. He had asked you beforehand whether the traditional Dwarven rates for Dwarven Journeyman and Masters were suitable for Zhufokri ones, and as the sum they'd receive worked out to slightly more than you'd been paid as a Journeyman as Spymaster of Stirland, you assured him it was. Mandatory Actions: Pick one from each category. Journeyman Maximilian de Gaynesford, Gold Wizard [ ] Allow him to spend all his time on his metalworking studies. [ ] Have Maximilian learn a skill: specify what from who. You may pay for a trainer. [ ] Have Maximilian learn a spell: specify which. [ ] Current Task: Have Maximilian perform or assist with spider autopsies. [ ] Current Task: Have Maximilian investigate the properties of the spiders' webs. [ ] Current Task: Have Maximilian investigate the properties of the spiders' venom. [ ] Have Maximilian attempt once more to write a paper on Waaagh energy. [ ] Have Maximilian write a paper on a subject you dictate. 'Journeyman' Johann, Gold Wizard [ ] Allow him to spend all his time investigating the Skaven. [ ] Have Johann return to Altdorf and 'graduate'. [ ] Have Johann learn a skill: specify what from who. You may pay for a trainer. [ ] Have Johann learn a spell: specify which. [ ] Current Task: Have Johann perform or assist with spider autopsies. [ ] Current Task: Have Johann investigate the properties of the spiders' webs. [ ] Current Task: Have Johann investigate the properties of the spiders' venom. [ ] Have Johann write a paper on Waaagh energy. The Eastern Imperial Company Your outstanding debt: 1,300 gc Your share of EIC profits: 100 gc / turn Current Focus of the EIC: Handgun Factory in Blutdorf [ ] Call in 1 favour for Dwarven expertise for the Factory's safety [ ] Call in 2 favours for Dwarven expertise for the Factory's efficiency [ ] Call in 4 favours for Dwarven expertise for the quality of the products [ ] Use your good name to help the EIC expand into Zhufbar. [ ] Talk to Titus and Hluodwica to help the EIC expand into the Moot. [ ] Establish an outpost of the EIC in Karak Eight Peaks. [ ] Instil corporate policy: information gathering (news). [ ] Instil corporate policy: long-term financial good of the Empire. [ ] Instil corporate policy: medium-term financial good of individual Provinces. [ ] Attempt to build your own information network within the EIC. Personal Actions: choose between four and six. Any chosen beyond four will come with risks - please specify 'additional' tasks. Current Task: Investigate the Chiselwards spiders. [ ] Be on hand for Esbern and Seija's attempts to communicate with the spiders. [ ] Perform an in-depth series of autopsies on the spiders. [ ] Study both living and dead spiders with your Magesight. [ ] Investigate the properties of the spiders' webs. [ ] Investigate the properties of the spiders' venom. Self-Improvement: [ ] Ask an acquaintance to train you in a skill: specify who and what. [ ] Hire a trainer to come to Eight Peaks and teach you: specify what. (costs favours for Dwarf trainers, money for human ones) [ ] A library is basically an external brain. Add to yours. (no action required, money and favour cost listed on charsheet) [ ] Travel to the Grey College and attend lessons there. (1 College Favour per class; 100gc can be paid instead for non-magical classes) Karag Nar Penthouse: each turn, you get ONE free choice in this category. [ ] Purchase furnishings so you can stop sleeping on a bedroll and can unpack your things: -20gc. [ ] Have a tower built atop Karag Nar: -100gc for 1 room, bonus to room's purpose. [ ] Have additional rooms excavated underneath your Penthouse: -50gc for 2 rooms. Setting up rooms for specific purposes will have to wait until new rooms are constructed or excavated. Karak Eight Peaks, friendly: [ ] The Undumgi are to select a leader from among themselves. Get involved in the process so you can investigate the candidate and influence their decision. [ ] You have acquired the possession of the Temple where Ranald mugged Mork. Set up a shrine and spread knowledge of it throughout Karag Nar. [ ] You have acquired the possession of the Temple where Ranald mugged Mork. Set up a shrine and keep it for yourself. [ ] Settlers, traders, and prospective wives will begin arriving soon. Start building an information network amongst them. [ ] Crime is inevitable, so it may as well be organized crime. Send word to Heideck and make sure that when an underworld emerges, it will be a Ranaldian one. [ ] Set up quarters and a basic laboratory for the Journeymanlings and any other visiting Wizards: -100gc. Karak Eight Peaks, hostile: [ ] Kvinn-Wyr is full of trolls. Investigate this for yourself. [ ] Travel underneath Kvinn-Wyr and investigate Karag Mhonar. [ ] Some of the richest parts of the historical Karak were under the Citadel. See who currently resides there. [ ] Scouts found mauled Skaven corpses under Karagril. See what's going on. [ ] Greenskins currently occupy Karagril. Find out what tribe they are and who rules them. [ ] Investigate underneath Karag Lhune: the Lhune Deeps and the Grand Abyss. Research: [ ] Investigate the constantly-dripping blood of the Wisdom's Asp. Current accumulation: 12 gallons. [ ] Instead of seeking the secrets of the blood, simply see if it can be weaponized in some way. [ ] You've got Ranald's Coin around your neck. Study it to see if you can gain an insight into Divine Energy. [ ] Send to the Grey College for the appropriate scrolls to learn a specific spell: specify which. [ ] Investigate how Pall of Darkness interacts with your sharpened magical senses. Publish or Perish: [ ] Collate the information that the Army of Stirland collected during the Purge. [ ] Attempt to write a paper on the Waaagh energy and magic witnessed during the Expedition. [ ] Attempt to write a paper on your personal understanding of countering Waaagh Magic. [ ] Dictate a paper on your personal understanding of countering Waaagh Magic. [ ] Attempt to write a paper on the Black Orc Warboss' worship of Only Gork, and what you saw of the Rogue Idol ritual. [ ] Dictate a paper on the Black Orc Warboss' worship of Only Gork, and what you saw of the Rogue Idol ritual. [ ] Write a paper on Mathilde's Multidimensional Aethyric Projection. Personal Relations: each turn, you get ONE free choice in this category. [ ] Spend time assisting with a fellow councillor's task: specify who. [ ] Spend time investigating a character without their knowledge: specify who. [ ] Wolf is growing fast. Train him. (increases his intelligence, may deepen Familiar bond) [ ] Spend time in Stirland helping Anton with his love life. [ ] Get in touch with Julia and find out if she'd be interested in passing on information to you. Other: [ ] Commission a Runic item with Dwarf favour. (specify a general type of item; favour expenditure will be decided by future vote) [ ] Commission an enchanted item with College favour. (specify a general type of enchantment; favour expenditure will be decided by future vote) [ ] Other (write in) Ranald's Coin - specify which face it will be set to [ ] The Gambler: specify an action this will apply to. A +20 bonus to up to two dice rolls resulting from a single chosen action. [ ] The Night Prowler As long as you are outside of private property and within a town or city, nobody will question your presence and nobody will be able to find you if you do not wish them to. [ ] The Deceiver: describe how this will be used. Lies you have developed beforehand will be delivered perfectly. The listener may believe you to be mistaken, but they will never believe that you are lying. Cannot be used to tell truths. [ ] The Protector When you act in a way that defends an individual or group from a danger that you did not cause, they will become aware of what you have done and will believe you acted selflessly in doing so. [Income Acquired: 60 Dwarven gold coins/turn, equivalent to 78 Empire crowns.] - Needless to say, the moratorium on discussion of the Liber Mortis is lifted. This vote will permanently decide the matter. Remain civil. Even if you think other people's arguments are flawed. Even if your preferred choice isn't winning or doesn't win. - If the decision is made to read the book, she will do so in her spare time during the coming turns. Mathilde will take all possible precautions to keep from being caught while doing so, and keeping it hidden away when it is not being read. This will not take actions and will not be part of future votes. - If the decision is made to seal away the book, short of a scenario that at least matches Mannfred's imminent conquering of Altdorf or a major and fundamental change in her character, Mathilde will never consider reading the book ever again. She will take precautions that will make it nigh impossible for anyone else to discover it during her lifetime. - If the decision is made to rid Mathilde of the book, a future vote will be held to decide between destroying or hiding the book, or having it sent to the Colleges or some other authority. If chosen, Mathilde will take precautions to make it impossible to track the sending back to her. Between her training and her magic, she is capable of it. - Approval voting is allowed. - It is expected that a Councillor will spend the equivalent of two to four actions per turn on their task. Actions chosen for your subordinates will count towards this. Recent success will mean investing the minimum amount of time is okay; recent failure will bring more attention to you, and you should err towards spending more time on your work. - Letting your Journeymanlings do their own thing too often will be frowned upon. They are your employees and they are being paid, make use of them or fire them. - It has been a while since full turns, and readership has definitely grown since then. As with previously, I'll have the vote open for 24 hours, and if all goes well, those results will stand. If it's a mess, I'll restart the voting and the first 24 hours will count as the discussion period, and future turns will have a 24-hour moratorium and then 24 hours of voting. I don't want to slow the pace of updates down, so I'm hoping that things will work out in that first 24 hours. Feel free to discuss how the voting should be, but be aware this isn't a debate on how it should be. In either case, the result on the vote on the Liber Mortis during the first 24 hours will stand. - Voting for the actions taken will be in Plan Format; don't forget Ranald's Coin. - If there's any actions you feel are absent from the list, let me know. - The plan vote is separate to the Liber Mortis vote; if you make a vote for both topics, ensure that they are in the same post.

Turn 25: Scouring Fury (Part Three)

GM Note: Hope I got everything! Sorry for the delay, but man this was a lot of stuff at once.

Spoiler: Plan: Search And Destroy

-[x] Board And Pull Back
--[X] Invasion Targets
---[X] Slaying Warboss if he can be located. If not, head to Construkta Yard Gamma.
----[X] Gabriel Angelos, Apollo Diomedes, Honor Guard, 15 1st Company marines, 1 Scout Sergeant and 9 Scouts from the 10th Company, 1 Apothecary, Chaplain Uther Volkoss and 1 other Chaplain, Techmarine Quarius Zergan and 3 other Techmarines, 3 Rapiers (Heavy Bolter)
-----[X] Goad and insult the Warboss through the vox as you travel, either to have it reveal its location or to come to you.
---[X]Construkta Yard Alpha
----[X] 1st Company leadership, 10 1st Company marines, 45 unassigned marines from the 10th, 2 1st Company Dreadnoughts, 1 Scout Sergeant and 9 Scouts from the 10th Company, 2 Apothecaries, Chaplain Ravias and 1 other Chaplain, Techmarine Hestior and 3 other Techmarines, 2 Rapiers (Heavy Bolter and Laser-Destroyer)
---[X] Construkta Yard Beta
----[X] 24 1st Company marines, 40 unassigned marines from the 10th, 2 1st Company Dreadnoughts, 1 Scout Sergeant and 9 Scouts from the 10th Company, 2 Apothecaries, Chaplain Antonius and 2 other Chaplains, Techmarine Calus; Techmarine Daedal and 2 other techmarines, 2 Rapiers (Heavy Bolter and Laser-Destroyer), lead by Hannibal Palrun
---[X] 14 Pockmark Docking/Entry Bays
----[X] 10th Company not assigned with other forces, 1 Apothecary
--[X] Left defending the fleet
---[X] 4th Company, Chief Apothecary Nero Gracchus and 1 Apothecary, 1 Chaplain, Master of the Forge Martellus Ravias and 3 Techmarines, All Tarantula sentry turrets

Scouring Fury
+060.M42+ To +065.M42+
+Let Your Fury Scour The Xeno Forevermore+

“Defend your fleet, Captain Hadrian,” Gabriel announced gravely. “The 4th Company will remain aboard with you, along with others. Wait until we are deployed, then pull back from the station. Destroy all the enemy vessels that challenge you.”

The Chapter Master was already moving as he spoke, outright sprinting towards the drop pods which were already being prepped and boarded. Through vox channels his orders spread throughout the Blood Ravens, and across the fleet the space marines responded. Behind Gabriel came Apollo and the rest of the Honor Guard, some diverting towards drop pods and others to the doughty assault rams that would be required for certain hard points. Elsewhere, much of the 1st Company did the same, while the 10th Company’s great numbers split in waves to various directions. The orders were clear. The ork’s monstrous vessel’s close-range weaponry was far too dangerous to the fleet. And yet, its construction yards could not be allowed to complete their pace.

“I’ze gonna stomp you all, me and me boyz. Gonna eat all yer scrap, and spit it out all propa orky!”

It was, no doubt, ludicrously frustrating to the techmarines who were aware of the issue that the orks could simply throw together piles of scrap and complete cruiser tonnage vessels in a fraction of the time that the Omnissiah’s shipyards could manage. The constant ranting from the ork did not help, especially considering how the damned creature’s signal was somehow still capable of blowing past every attempt at blocking it. Only through muting it could one find respite, but even that was a potential risk considering the non-negligible chances for intelligence on the enemy.

“So, where are we headed, Chapter Master?” Doukas Laskaris asked, his breath even as they strapped into the drop pod.

Outside, marines of all sorts were entering their own vessels with cacophony clangs. Over a dozen separate litanies of hatred and fury echoed out from various squads and sergeants. Chaplain Uther Volkoss’ voice rose above it all, a ceaseless benediction of absolute destruction in the Emperor’s name. Great slams announced the arrival and strapping in of the rapier machines. Apollo was curiously silent within his helm, saying nothing at all or even acknowledging Laskaris, the marine who held the position that he had once so prized and lorded over others.

“We descend, all of us, to the station. To find the ork’s leader amongst the rabble. Objective secundus, should he prove…recalcitrant to face-to-face engagement-,” Gabriel’s voice was swallowed by the adamantium thunderstorm which rattled the entire bay.

Over a dozen drop pods descended at speeds enough to gain brief coronas of fiery heat, accompanied from behind by the slower and heavier assault rams. The marines within shuddered from the immense vibration, but it was only a second’s pause before Gabriel began speaking once more, his voice as calm as before. From other vessels, the 10th Company began its own deployment, making use of a great amount of munitions to cloud the primitive auspex arrays of the orks as Captain Octavius followed Gabriel’s orders.

“Construction zone gamma is where we will apply ourselves, should we fail to locate the warboss within the time limit.”

Then Gabriel keyed his vox to the whole of the chapter, a right reserved for only those in the highest of the chapter’s authority.

“Blood Ravens! We are unleashed upon the foe! LET NONE FIND US WANTING!”

A crackle emerged from the vox, then, just for a moment, and rose high enough in volume to momentarily drown out even the ork’s bellowing.

“LET NONE FIND US WANTING!”

Initial Operations
Deployment Alpha Drop: 57 vs. 5
Deployment Beta Drop: 21 vs. 65
Deployment Gamma Drop: 76 vs. 48
Deployment Delta Drop: 35 vs. 23
4th Company Clearing: 94 vs. 72

=========================================

4th Company Clearing
94 vs. 72

Hadrian Priscus was not the most patient of space marines. This was known. He was aggressive in combat, sometimes to the point of worry by his peers. This was also known. From a mere veteran sergeant of the 5th Company he had been propelled into Captaincy not just of the 4th Company but mastery of the Blood Raven’s fleet as a whole. A staggering amount of responsibility, especially for a chapter so badly winnowed by traitors and xenos alike for over a decade. Here, now, the flagship of his company was under total threat by ork boarders. It was not the greatest of the ships in the fleet, but it was certainly the only one currently boarded in such number and severity.

This would not stand.

He expressed this feeling by leaving the command throne of the Omnis Arcanum to its machine spirits and bridge crew, and heading to the teleportarium along with much of his command squad. Near the reactor rooms of the Potentia, cyborks guffawed as they gunned down serfs and servitors. Their leader, a hulking creature with steaming pistons on its shoulders laughed especially hard as he thumped through a hallway of land mines. One enormous power klaw raised up, dragging heavy grooves into the ceiling, while the other arm fired out long cables of lightning which lashed back and forth against the walls.

It died as Hadrian Priscus came yelling out of the warp in a flash of light and crackling energies at a full sprint. His left pauldron slammed upwards into its jaw, sending it reeling backwards and exposing a throat into which he fired both plasma pistols into. He fired twice with each, vaporizing meat and metal in equal measure. The ork did not even register it was dead until it had fallen on its back completely and he had stomped his boots through its skull as the space marine charged at the orks behind. Somehow, through the impossibilities of the warp, he had somehow managed to teleport five seconds ahead of the rest of his troops, despite leaving at the same time. The librarians would idly posit, if they ever heard of it, that his aggression had somehow translated into the effect.

“GET OFF OF MY SHIP!”

By the time deployment to the station below were complete, the Potentia was entirely freed of its boarders in time to join with the rest of the chapter fleet as they retreated to a safe range from the ork’s superheavy guns.

====================================

Bay Destruction Efforts
30 vs. 45

“Come on, you xeno scum! Come on!” The newly promoted scout yelled from atop the fallen cargo crates.

The amount of bolter fire being exuded down the corridor was rather significant. Several of the neophytes had formed firing lines, others making use of heavy bolters supplied to the company long ago. Though they were not yet full marines, they had enough strength in pairs to lift and set up the devices. Cyrus grit his teeth as he listened to scattered reports from the rest of his troops. The 10th Company had gone for the scattered and smallest targets, and yet the sheer volume of orks was proving to be a ridiculous roadblock for them. Only one bay had been removed from the hands of the enemy, and that was the single one that he had personally attended to.

“Get ‘em boyz, push ‘em out into the void so we can watch ‘em float!”

Growling, he spun past the makeshift cover that was a dead pile of orks and fired. The ork nob that had been marshalling the latest assault upon the bay that the 10th Company had taken for itself faltered, as one tended to do without a head, before falling backwards. Across the station, the scattered company had been forced into retreat after their initial attempts at infiltration. That, Cyrus could stand. What was beginning to grow frustrating was how all of his forces had been corralled into the bay. The exit out to the void was closed by, of all things, a pair of preposterously thick metal slabs. Of course the orks would not believe in proper shielding. Even so, Cyrus had made it a matter of life or death to his brothers to activate the mag-lock functions of their boots and fasten their helmets completely.

Ork Response To Delta Attempts
82

“Captain, more orks are moving in! Auspex and deep penetrating augur scans show increasing numbers of orks coming our way!” A scout’s voice came on the line, terse and strained beneath the audible bolter fire. “No major signs of leadership beyond nobs, but the numbers are…considerable!”

He could see it too, now that he glanced at the display being shown through his own cybernetic eye. Not insurmountable, given time, especially considering the explosives being left behind by retreating squads. But the efforts of the Blood Ravens were, in this at least, largely unsuccessful.

Sighing, Cyrus tapped his command vox channel. It was worth trying, at least, even if it was unlikely to be heard amongst the maelstrom of comm chatter.

“Chapter Master, this is Cyrus. We are pinned down. Objectives are currently left largely unfulfilled. Will attempt to make a push soon, however.”

Instead of a response from any Blood Raven in particular, Cyrus winced as his ears were nearly set to bleeding as the ork’s unknown leader spoke again.

“Hurr hurr! You fink you boyz is smart, huh! Comin’ fer me spawny ‘oles! Well nuffin doin’! Boyz! Get in dere and gut dese ‘spacey marines’ already! You gots ‘em right where ya want ‘em!”

Cyrus was not prone to much displays of emotion, and later he would recriminate himself greatly for rolling his eyes within potential sight of the scouts. But that would come later, and for now, there was fighting to be done.

=========================================

Construkta Yard Beta Targeting
98 vs. 12

The average space marine was a terrifying entity to face. The sheer breadth of their arms and armor, its capabilities, augmented by their own superhuman physiology, was often enough to cow entire planets with the threat of just a single company of marines. The Blood Ravens had used this, as had hundreds of chapters, as a basic tactic for years in subduing rebellious worlds. The chaplain was an altogether different sort of fear. Eschewing all but the color of pitch black night upon their skull-encrusted forms, purity seals streaming across their body, while a skull helm glared out imperiously at the world beyond in contempt and holy hatred. From within their helms did their voices boom, extoling their brethren to even greater heights, heights that they sought themselves to prove example and leader in one.

Hannibal Palrun, Master of Sanctity, exemplified all of these qualities as he tore apart the orks facing his battle group.

Alone.

While the marines around him went to work destroying key struts identified by the techmarines, the dreadnoughts firing heavy weaponry into the disgusting semi-automated construction drones, Hannibal fought. There were approximately five tunnels leading into the badly shielded shipyard, the flickering electric dome above the only thing preventing all within from simply disappearing into the void. Four had been destroyed, while the fifth had been left open at Hannibal’s order, not simply because it would provide the only escape route. The orks, never ones to give up on a fight, had come streaming through the easiest path to get to the fight desired. A fight that Hannibal gave them.

Alone.

In a wider area, an open field of battle, he would have been torn apart a dozen times over. He knew it, the orks knew it, his brothers knew it. But so long as the tunnel forced the orks into a narrower line, he became as if the Primarch Dorn himself. For all that the Imperial Fists had denigrated the chapter, that even their legendary Darnath Lysander had shamed them for their attempt at honoring him, Hannibal stood. His mind churned on such thoughts, the poetry of war and those who fought in it. No, perhaps not Dorn, he concluded to himself. This was not the Eternity Gate, but Hannibal felt more connected to the legacy of Sanguinius and the Blood Angels than ever before. Yes, that was it. That was it! The Blood Ravens knew not their Primarch, and so it fell to the Chaplains to pursue the betterment of their brethren in the name of all of those who had served the Emperor loyally! In all of them, from Corax to Dorn, to the Gorgon and the Great Angel!

“FACE ME! FACE ME AND DIE!”

His black armor was redder than the standard paint of the Blood Ravens, so soaked with ork gore it was. Gouges, carved by an entire dozen mega-nobs, had nearly peeled it open before being struck down. Half of his skull helm had been blown away by a series of ork rockets buffeting him, but his eyes still saw clearly through the smoke. Thunder Blood was in his hands, and with it he shattered bones, bodies, and possibly outright souls of the foul xenos, to the point that he alone began to push them back. Behind him, he heard the sounds of his brother chaplains marshaling them men, his brothers, to join him as they had done all they needed to, to ensure the destruction of the entire shipyard, to bring it shattering down and explode all that remained within.

But they were unneeded, because the orks, facing this massive entity once covered in black now near completely crimson clad in the blood of his enemies turned and ran. Not all at once, not entirely. But the mega-nobs had died. The nobs behind them had died. The boyz in between the first group of nobs and the next had died. And though it was a trickle at first, it soon grew into a flood. There was no fight in this tunnel, only death, and that was no fun at all. The orks streamed away, to find a place where there was a chance, a hint, a ghost of a possibility at winning. For there was none to be found here.

Chest heaving, the largest standing marine in the entire chapter outside of the dreadnoughts roared his outrage that the xenos would run, roared his exulting of the Primarchs and the Chapter, roared his approval to his brothers that they had done so well in their tasks. Generally, he just roared. Eventually, however, this ceased, and he paused to glance at the abattoir that had once been a passable tunnel by orks standards. He turned, battered but unbroken, and shook his crozius to clean it. Craters were left in the scrap and rock walls, floors, and ceiling where he had struck most harshly.

“Come, brothers, remove yourselves from this place, and unleash the detonators!”

“Wot kinda spacey marine iz you?!” The damndable ork’s master yelled over the primitive few speakers left in the hallway. “Sum kinda fancy mega-nobby-marine?! Boyz, you get back dere and kill dat red boy a’fore ‘ee gets any fasta at killin’ ya! E’s already goin’ too fast!”

Hannibal merely sneered through the red coating him.

“We move, brothers!”

Departure From Objective
54 vs. 34

There were orks that were either brave or stupid enough to come after them in the tight quarters as they departed. But upon seeing Hannibal, or rather the latter seeing them, only death followed. The terminators assigned to his battle group saw to the blocking off and effective defense of the others as they proceeded. Eventually there came a series of continual explosions as an entire section of the Doom-Eater was torn apart by plasma bombs and detonation packs, a significant amount of it already damaged by prior destruction and targeted heavy weaponry. The calculated collapse of stone, rock, and further movement of their force deeper into the station ensured the total success of their given objective.

Objective Success Response
11

“I’ZE SAID GET IN DERE ALREADY, DE’RE IN ME BLOWY GUTS!”

‘Blowy guts’ as it turned out, was an obvious armory, or at least what passed for such things amongst the greenskins. In truth, it was a massive pile of, grenades, grenade and rocket launchers, general explosives, and guns ranging from ‘pistols’ to outright cannons that might be better fitted to a dreadnought. As such an obviously desirable place for greenskins, there were openings everywhere. Some even in the ceiling. It had been, after all, at least several minutes, and so the cowardice of before had already faded in its entirety as orks began to flood into the room, forcing the Blood Ravens within to take up a tight defensive posture. They seemed to come from every direction, some clawing their way up out of the ocean of weaponry all uneasily stood upon.

“Don’t run your rapier over those, they’ll explode!”

“Oh, so you want me to stay my rapier on top of these, Daedal?!”

“Calus you are about to run it over grenades!”

“I know what I’m doing!”

Hannibal, calling this time for his fellow chaplains to join him, roared into the fight.

Not alone, but surrounded by his brothers.

As it should be.

=================================

There had been casualties, and knowing that they were brand new brothers did not help matters. Captain Marcus growled as he fired his graviton pistol at the onrushing hordes. This place was clearly the first of its kind, and thus the most heavily defended. That was the only reason he could come up with to explain why it was staffed by so many cybernetically-enhanced orks as well as possessing limited ork mechanized support. Stomping killa kans made their way forward, their armors and innards crumpling as he fired his pistol, but there were more than he could kill alone. The newly promoted brothers of the 10th Company were, for all that they were no longer scouts, not nearly as well equipped as the rest of the 1st Company. Terminator armor was near inviolable in the current fighting, as near as he could tell, leaving them as more exposed. Even considering their armor, the volume of fire being unleashed at them was enough to make even slightly less armor than that of a terminator or dreadnought potentially not nearly enough. That had just been in the deployment, the dropping of troops and then marshalling them forward. Some marines hadn’t made it out of their drop pods at all, though none were of the 1st Company.

And yet, some things still too precedence.

“Romallius! Status!?”

The apothecary seemed entirely unconcerned despite having his stomach nearly disemboweled by an ork power klaw. By now it had scabbed over entirely, but that his armor had gone with the claw was not a good sign. He raised himself up from his cover, gesturing at the vials he now carried with him.

“All gene-seed recovered, Captain. We may begin at your discretion.”

“Very well,” Marcus nodded before rising over the rubble, lifting his power sword above his head. “Brothers! Advance!”

Construkta Yard Alpha Targeting [Main Force]
68 vs. 56

So began the grueling push. The orks had put turrets in the walls. Turrets in the floor. Turrets in the ceiling. An enormous pair of metal slabs that could have been bent into whole groupings of tanks were shut, keeping the void out, but beneath it was a half-completed brute ram-ship. Clearly, Marcus knew, the enemy cruisers had already been nearly done before the Blood Ravens had even arrived. But the sheer speed of construction was worrying. Even while the Blood Ravens began to advance, the vanguard being made up of the dreadnoughts and terminators of the 1st Company, swarms of meks and gretchin servants slapped on hunks of rusted metal and bolted spikes of metal to hold it all together. The speed was worrying, and gave an obvious reason as to how the orks had managed to construct their fleets in such swarms, take losses against patrolling Imperial Navy vessels, and yet replenish their losses so quickly.

Resources in, ships and raiders out, all combined into one station.

It needed to be destroyed.

All of it.

The rapiers fired at the ship above, the oversized chains and bracing towers holding it in place shuddering under the blows, while other terminators unleashed cyclone missiles onto larger concentrations of oncoming ork waves. Marcus was amongst the very front, as was his wont, joined by the chaplains and the rest of his command squad save Romallius. Even the dreadnoughts, Brutus and Cassius, advanced. Heavy flamers burnt the way open, while missiles and a dedicated scout squad took advantage of the darkness. Explosions began to ripple out, slowly, before abruptly triggering all at once as Scout Sergeant Tantus emerged from the smoke, the former 1st Company marine patting out some smoldering embers on his camo-cloak.

Construkta Yard Alpha Targeting [Specialized Force]
85 vs. 33

“Sergeant Tantus,” Marcus greeted him, the bodies of the dead forming a thick meaty carpet for the Blood Ravens to stomp across. “Report.”

“Various ammo stockpiles have been mined, Captain. A good set of explosives will do it, hopefully.”

Marcus nodded, turning to glance at the approaching techmarine Hestior. The servo-arm hung limply from its harness, sparking wildly from where it had nearly been wrenched free by some ork or another. Still, the light from the marine’s helm was undimmed, and though his fellow techmarines were in similarly damaged condition none were in a truly dire state. Marcus would take it, far better for them to be battered than beaten.

“Hestior?”

“Brother-Captain Marcus, we’ve done as you asked. Servitors have carried the explosives and connectors as required, and we’ve managed to locate the servos and what passes for proper electronic systems to the doors,” Hestior nodded.

All those present turned, however, and began firing as a unified whole against a charging mob of nobs. Several of them wore thick plates of metal over their bodies, but plasma and flamer burnt them regardless. Their leader, the largest, stood taller than even Hannibal Palrun, and in fact lasted the longest getting to them. Marcus advanced, slapping aside its attempt to strike with an oversized chain-axe with his power sword, before placing his graviton pistol against its chest and pulling the trigger. The ork coughed, an expression of confusion on its face, before its gravity-pulped bones and organs began to slough out of its throat in a torrent stream as the artificially modified pressures within its body.

“Good,” Marcus breathed calmly. “Once we are out of the danger zone, detonate all charges and open the doors. Let them taste void.”

Battlegroup Tactical Retreat
53 vs. 78

The vox squealed in time with the speakers in their thousands across the entire construction yard. Worse, its generally crater and bowl-shaped architecture, shot through with towers of metal and stone, somehow managed to amplify the volume of the speaker further.

“You ain’t getting’ away, you stinkin’ grots! You fink I can’t figgur out wot yer doin?! Tryin’ to destroy me construkta yards!? No! Boyz,” the ork roared over every channel of communication. “GET ‘EM! DA MINUTE DEY GET OUTTA DERE, DAT WHOLE PLACE GOES BOOM! AND NOT DA GOOD KIND!”

Marcus growled and speared his blade through the stomach of another ork before driving it upwards through its skull.

“They are welcome to try, ork! Blood Ravens, with me!”

And so they began to pull back. Steadily, every inch granted to the enemy paid for in blood, they pulled back. Unfortunately, there was a blood price for the Blood Ravens as well. A marine, not even yet fully promoted to a proper company, fell as his head and neck disappeared into a red mist. The chortling ork kommando who had fired the weapon that did it found Sergeant Tantus responding in kind. The rapiers reversed, keeping themselves aimed towards the enemy the whole while, firing well into the range where the machine spirits grew testy and strained. One techmarine, one of the new ones just recently returned from Mars, bent down to help lift up a pair of marines into the hands of the rest of their squad. He would never rise up again, as a pair of zzap gun cannon shots split him open from behind, erupting along with his power pack and the grenades on his person ensuring that not even his gene-seed could be returned.

Still, the Blood Ravens forced their way through, picking up those too carried to continue just yet, healing those who could be healed, and retrieving the dead as best they could. It was a bloody affair, all around, and by the time the Blood Ravens got into the tunnels, others would fall. In the end, though, worse than all of it, the bay that had been chosen as the rally point was compromised. From five different directions including the path back to the construkta yard. The doors would not close, either from rust, lack of machine spirits, or something else. Still, the orks came, furious at the desecration to their precious machinery which had been so badly destroyed. They were led by a Big Mek whose personalized klaw whirred with five separate cutting implements shoved into one, the crackle of power fields flickering over each one.

“Captain,” Tomb-Brother Brutus suddenly said, seeing the horde at the same time as Marcus. “Tell your brothers to detonate the charges to the bay.”

“We cannot, Brutus!” Marcus shouted above the din, firing again and again at the heaviest armored foes coming towards them. “If the bay doors are blown open as of now, we may all be thrown into the void by the suction! Hestior, get the gate closed or none of us shall be able to escape!”

He cursed as the energy shield protecting the Big Mek deflected even his own arcane technological weaponry. Brutus was silent in voice, even as his heavy flamer continued to trigger until there was a quiet beep as it finally ran empty.

“Then I shall close it.”

And then Brutus advanced, the dreadnought steaming forward as its engine core and the marine within became truly as one. It was magnificent, Hestior would later say, the massive engine performing as if it the marine within was fully alive for one brief terrifying moment. Gone was the stuttering, the plodding and delayed nature that many dreadnoughts displayed, the marines within in their half-lives almost never as responsive as Captain Thule had become. The way it moved, shifted, spun, slaughtered, its claws reaching out and rending, its very bulk being used to tackle and smash the orks aside. Brutus arrived at the poorly constructed gateway before reaching out and grasping the edges of its panels. Then, even as Marcus realized what the tomb-brother’s plan was, began to pull them shut behind him, facing the onrushing horde of meks and their servants alone.

“Brutus!”

“Trigger the explosives, Captain,” the marine within broadcast calmly.

The Big Mek reached him first, spinning power-fielded buzzsaws beginning to tear open the coffin. With its other arm, a rivet cannon began to shunt foot long columns of superheated metal directly joints of the greater frame, disabling one of the arms entirely as it was shorn off of its mooring.

“I’ze gunna make you into some real shiny gubbins, you big’un!” The mek cackled.

“Unlikely,” Brutus spoke before reaching up and grasping its head with his remaining arm, beginning to squeeze as the ork began to scream.

The doors, finally, slammed shut, blocking the way and isolating Brutus on the other side. Marcus tore apart another pair of nobs before finally, gritting his teeth, sent the acknowledgement signal to Tantus and Hestior. A cacophony of explosions echoed out in the distance, the entire superstructure shuddering as the second of its construkta bays was destroyed. Unlike others, this one had been protected largely by its own bay doors, the shield only sparking to life as necessary while the power was fed elsewhere when not needed. This, of course, was what had been discovered by scout and techmarines working in tandem. When the doors opened, the shield was to activate, unless the cables feeding the shields were previously sabotaged.

On the other side of the doors, Marcus knew, everything for a considerable distance and in multiple tunnels was being thrown out into the void. The explosive decompression was…considerable. What measures the greenskins had put into place for such an occasion, if any, never seemed to materialize. But the distance was enough, debris wedging itself into the right holes and ork bodies sufficing otherwise to plug entire hallways and tunnels, such that the Blood Ravens only heard the ominous creaking of the doors that had been pulled shut. Then the secondary explosions as the incompletely installed reactors in the enemy ship began to erupt in a chain of controlled detonations.

“Brother Brutus!” Marcus called out on the vox, even though he knew it was a vain hope. “Tomb-Brother, respond if you are able!”

There would be no response, and the conditions beyond meant that opening them again would be potentially catastrophic.

Growling, Marcus set amongst the orks with a vengeful fury, one that his brothers emulated with gusto. Only when their thirst for blood was slaked, the orks pulling back to regroup, did he trigger the vox again.

“Chapter Master, this is Captain Marcus. Objective complete, the bay is inoperable to the orks.”

This time, he did not bat an eye as the ork’s leader spoke again.

“You boyz…iz really starting to piss me off!” It bellowed, before its voice turned gleeful. “Now dis is a good foight! Harharhar!”

Marcus turned, knowing by now that by some measure or another the ork’s were capable of tracking their movements. Either by report, camera, or otherwise. Perhaps just the damage left in their wake.

“If the Chapter Master does not kill you, ork, I will do so myself,” he whispered.

==================================================

There had been fewer in their detachment. Perhaps that was why the resistance they encountered in the initial deployment efforts were so anemic. Perhaps it was that his brothers were simply that much of a nuisance that they required significantly more orks to be drawn towards their numbers. Gabriel did not have it in him to have the hubris of thinking that they would be utterly unopposed in their efforts, or that he was somehow an opponent such that his presence along could defeat the natural belligerence of the greenskins. And yet, they advanced. Finding, at first, no foes to fight at all after the initial surge against their intrusion.

Challenge And Response
13

“Face us, ork!” Apollo shouted at the walls, studded with speakers, metal struts, and bullet holes besides.

For a wonder, the ork responded.

“Hurr, yer a foighty bunch aintcha! You fink you can get me, come n’ get me! But I ain’t stoopid, ya grot, I’ze da cleverist dere is! Boyz! Get over to dat place wot with the shooty bang…agh, just follow da sparks!”

A series of grime and filth-covered light panels abruptly began to glow where they stood, before trailing off into the various branching hallways. The sounds of orks, already all around them, with fighting and dying audible across every single vox channel, began to intensify. Shootas being fired into the ceiling, metal-shod boots and cybernetic limbs scraping and thumping against the ground and walls. Gabriel, for his part, turned and raised an eyebrow at the somewhat shorter Apollo. For his part, Apollo did look chagrined for a moment before hefting his supposedly Primarch-forged mace.

“Well, at least there will be xenos to slay,” he muttered.

Gabriel’s eyebrow simply rose higher, even as the first orks began to round the bend of the hallway from both sides.

“FOR THE EMPEROR!”

Response To Response
90 vs. 71

Doukas Laskaris, of all of them, moved the fastest. In the Ghoul Stars, speed was life. A moment’s hesitation or the slightest slowing of one’s movements, and death would come in a thousand different ways. As such, with his gifted blade humming with anticipation, the Captain of the Honor Guard thrust himself into battle. His command was just slightly larger than an average squad, and yet they held one end of the hallway all to themselves. Bolter fire, grenades, and repeated excursions into the mass foes to break their momentum, all of this and more was given to the greenskins, the gift of experience in fatal form. On the other side of the hallway went Gabriel and Apollo, and with them went death. From the middle, facing one in each direction, the rapiers deployed themselves. At pre-arranged signals, those fighting retreated and dove to the sides, an outpouring of fire shredding the orks in great number before ceasing to cool barrels and reload ammo.

It was at that point that a massive explosion rippled through the station, and the call of confirmation came through that Hannibal Palrun had completed his work. Followed shortly by a call from Captain Marcus of the 1st Company. There had been little word from the 10th Company for some time, other than a terse call much earlier, and nothing sense. But there was nothing that could be done for any of them, for the xenos came again, the tides of assault continuing the entire time.

The greenskins poured in a stream, but it was stoppered by the fury of the Angels of Death. For a moment, at least. And that was enough. Wheeling about, the rapiers turned as one and fired. The heavy bolters built into their frames tore apart the ceiling and walls, collapsing them upon themselves. A few primed krak grenades did the rest of the work, cutting off the assault from that direction. Then, wheeling about, the Honor Guard joined the Chapter Master and cut their way forward.

Further Challenges
41 vs. 66

Again, Apollo yelled for the greenskin’s leader to face them, and again the ork only bellowed laughter and directed more forces toward them. Once, Doukas gave an attempt, extoling their own strengths and the pathetic weakness of the foe. The greenskin took the taunts to that well enough by directing a mob of mega-nobs towards them, hulks of rusting cybernetic monstrosities coated in fresh blood from some place or another. At one point, there was even a bounding swarm of squigs that had been implanted with lightning-covered electrical coils. Which happened to explode remarkably like certain types of grenades built to disable advanced robotics and powered systems. Miniature squiggoths, more boar-like than the towering elephantine monstrosities that could be seen on the fields of battle, came trundling through the tunnels next. Their hides were such that only power weapons and the heavy bolters could damage them, regular bolters and even chainswords could do little to them other than annoy.

“This isn’t working,” Apollo snarled as he beat another onrushing ork over the head with his mace, the sparking of its power field blowing everything above the waist into red mist and bone chips. “The ork refuses to meet us in battle!”

“Now dat dere is a lie, dat one,” the ork bellowed in response. “I’ze been fightin’ ya, all of you beaky spacey marines! Dese boyz is me weapons! Dere shootas is me screams, da mek’s klaws are me toofs! Hahaha! Them…squiggy fings iz…sumefin…me angry…tongue? Nah, dat’s stoopid. Dere my squiggies, dat’s what counts! YER FOIGTIN ME AND I’ZE FOIGHTIN YOU! NOW ENOUGH GABBIN!”

In some areas, the hallways narrowed to the point that the Blood Ravens had to redirect, not nearly large enough for rapiers or terminators to push through. Elsewhere, they emerged into open bays and caverns hacked out of the rock and metal, confounded by ork mobs and machinery. Damage began to accumulate upon even terminator plate after long enough periods of time. Chaplain Uther, at one point, was perforated in thirty-seven distinct places as a squad of surprisingly quiet flash gitz fired their custom weaponry at and through his back and legs. Remarkably, Uther managed to turn about, finish beating the ork kommando who had fired its oversized shotgun into his chest, and slay them as well before collapsing to the floor. It was only through the aid of the apothecary that he was pulled to his feet.

Gabriel shook his head.

“You are correct. We advance elsewhere,” he said firmly. “To the secondary objective.”

“Sekun…oy! Don’t you go near me construkta yard! Ya already got two of ‘em, ya greedy grot!”

The demands of the ork were, predictably, ignored.

Secondary Objective Push
38 vs. 27

Lesser in number, perhaps, but the Chapter Master was no mere foe. Nor was Apollo Diomedes. Or Doukas Laskaris. Uther Volkoss felt no pain, and demanded no aid but the screams of his enemies. Falkor Ryll, the apothecary of the Honor Guard, had long ago began to fight at the front as well. By now his white armor was drenched in the blood of the foe, all the while the terminators of the 1st Company covered them with overlapping lanes of fire. They ground forward against the tide, and parted it through fire and fury. At the front of them all was Gabriel. Godsplitter struck with all the force it could possibly manage, and before him, the orks died. An ork’s power klaw outright shattered as the Great Father’s own terminator armor rebuffed it.

“Oy! Stoppit! Yer breakin’ all me fings and me boyz!”

In a remarkably short time, they found their way to the last of the construkta yards. All of them had taken notable armor damage, scuffs and breaks here and there, but none had fallen who could not get back up. For now, at least. Falkor and his brother apothecary did admirable work to ensure this was possible. Here, there was no ship under construction. Or perhaps the as of yet fallow mountain of scrap metal was meant to be transformed into one later, but it remained land-bound and untouched by struts and cranes still. The reason for that was more than self-evident, its entire crew of meks and gretchin had joined in with the orks already swarming the yard to keep it protected.

“That is…a lot of orks,” Doukas noted.

“That it is, Captain,” Gabriel hefted his hammer in hand. “Sergeant Augum?”

The scout sergeant hefted his shotgun and glanced back at his single squad of scouts.

“It would take…considerable time, Chapter Master, even if we could.”

“We could retreat for now, try to link up with one of the other battlegroups,” Doukas offered, ignoring the outraged turn from Apollo at the thought of running. “Then return.”

The Captain of the Honor Guard had been a part of an Explorator Fleet. He was used to having to use somewhat less ‘courageous’ techniques to defeat number parity. Besides which, the orks were not pausing to let them speak, already charging at the tunnel they had emerged from. The first few dozen were turned to chunks by the rapiers, but even their magnificent beings could only hold and bring so much ammo at a time. Worse, there was absolutely no sign that the ork was inclined to join them. Even, Gabriel was beginning to muse, if he desired to. There was something there, niggling in the back of his head, absorbing the reports of his chapter, the bellows of the ork to all of the battlegroups, the timing, the internal machinery displayed…

Tactical Realization
75

“Chapter Master, what are your orders?”

“The Arch-Maniac of Calverna,” Gabriel said instead, the thought sparking with the ring of truth. “Yes.”

He twisted to avoid an incoming rocket with a gretchin attached, letting it detonate meaninglessly in the distance. The plasma pistol in his free hand bucked as its payload flew into the face of the ork who had fired the rocket in the first place.

“Chapter Master?”

“One of the most notorious ork leaders in the galaxy, not to the point of Ghazghkull, but considerable for the equipment of its forces,” Gabriel continued. “The orks we have faced are substantially well equipped, number a disproportionate amount of cyborks and mega-nobs, with even their more basic mobs bearing minor bionics here and there. Even their squigs.”

He fired again, this time striking a smoking squig that exploded in the barrel of the launcher it had been stuffed into, causing an explosion that took out ten orks at once.

“And his words,” he said coolly, above the cacophony of three rapiers and fifteen terminators firing at once. “His tools, his body, his yards. The Doom-Eater isn’t just the station. He is the Doom-Eater. Somewhat more lucid than the Maniac, though this place is nowhere near the size of a forgeworld.”

The vox squealed once more.

“Ahurr…ahurrahahah…HAHAHAHA! Oi, yer a clever one, you iz. Dat’s roight!” The ork laughed from every direction. “I’ze Ghurzgot Doom-Eater! And dis is MY KILLY-NAUGHT!”

At his voice, the orks slowed their charge, for just a moment, listening in what looked almost like religious ecstasy.

“Dem boyz is me blood, cause dem boyz is me WAAAAGH!! We’ze gonna eat up all da gubbins in da ‘ol ‘ooneverse, and spit out shoots and ships! We’ze gonna get a big enuff fleet, and we’ze gonna go back, and we’ze gonna stomp all dem buggies!”

Thump. Thump. Thump. The orks began to stomp their feet and bang their weapons upon the ground. And as one, they began to ululate.

“Doom-Eater! Doom-Eater! Doom-Eater!”

“Dat’s right! Now gettem’ boyz!”

Spoiler: Collected Results Of Phase 2

Blood Ravens Fleet Retreats To Distance, Ork Fleet Has Pursued!
Construkta Yard Gamma Under Assault! Battlegroup Primaris Requires Aid To Complete Objective, Otherwise Forced Into Holding Position!
Construkta Yard Alpha Destroyed! Battlegroup Secundus Available For Further Orders!
Construkta Yard Beta Destroyed! Battlegroup Tertium Pinned Down By Massive Enemy Response! Cannot Fulfill Orders, Locked Into Holding Position!
1 of 14 Bays Claimed/Disabled! Battlegroup Quartrus Pinned Down By Notable Enemy Response! Will Attempt To Continue Previous Orders Unless Ordered Otherwise!
Warboss Identified: Ghurzgot Doom-Eater! Major Characteristic Identified: Wired Centerpoint - Cannot be pulled from centralized location within superstructure from which he directs his forces. Must be located and found.
- Warboss Tactical Possibilities: Exterminatus Weaponry/Deep Strike Teleporters/Strike Force Penetration Through Mundane Means
- Tactical Consideration: Orks show high amount of 'advanced' weaponry and armors, and significant coordination through Doom-Eater communications.
- Tactical Consideration: Orks are dedicating high numbers of forces towards Battlegroup Tertium, drawing forces away from assaulting Battlegroup Quartrus And Primaris.
- Tactical Consideration: Battlegroup Secundus is capable of heading towards and aiding any one battlegroup, further separation of individual battlegroups inadvisable.
- Tactical Consideration: Battlegroup Primaris is in danger of being overrun in larger spaces due to volume of fire potential. Extremely effective in close quarters tunnel fighting. Currently able to funnel foes attacking them into a tunnel.

Current Possible Tactical Targets Of Station:
- Engine Sectors Alpha/Beta/Gamma
- Anti-Orbital Defenses Include: Looted Imperial Broadside Cannons/Scattered Orkish Lance Turrets/Ork 'Heavy Gunz'/Ork 'Gunz'/Ork Torpedo Bays
- ‘Maw Of Gork (Or Mork)’ Additional Characteristic Revealed: Fleet Deployment Capabilities
- Construkta Yard Gamma
- Depths Of Doom-Eater [Precise Location Of Warboss Unknown]

Battlegroup Primaris
Gabriel Angelos, Apollo Diomedes, Honor Guard [Captain Doukas/Chaplain Volkoss/Apothecary Falkor]
15 1st Company marines
1 Scout Sergeant and 9 Scouts from the 10th Company
1 Apothecary
1 Chaplain
Techmarine Quarius Zergan and 3 other Techmarines, 3 Rapiers (Heavy Bolter)

Injured But Functional
Honor Guard Chaplain Uther Volkoss
4 1st Company Marines
1 Techmarine

Battlegroup Secundus
Captain: Marcus Crixus TH
Company Champion: Uriel Hamul TH
Epistolary: VACANT
Apothecary: Constantius Romallius TH [24 Gene-Seed Reclaimed]
Chaplain: Ares Actus TH
10 1st Company
31 Unassigned marines from the 10th
2 1st Company Dreadnoughts
1 Scout Sergeant and 9 Scouts from the 10th Company
2 Apothecaries
Chaplain Ravias/
Techmarine Hestior/2 other Techmarines, 2 Rapiers (Heavy Bolter and Laser-Destroyer)
1st Company Tomb-Brothers Cassius

Injured But Functional
9 10th Company Marines [Unassigned]
1 Chaplain

Fatalities:
1 Techmarine
14 10th Company Marines [Unassigned]
1st Company Tomb-Brother Brutus

Battlegroup Tertium
Hannibal Palrun
24 1st Company Marines
40 unassigned marines from the 10th
2 1st Company Dreadnoughts
1 Scout Sergeant and 9 Scouts from the 10th Company
2 Apothecaries [4 Gene-Seed Reclaimed]
Chaplain Antonius/2 Chaplains
Techmarine Calus/Techmarine Daedal/2 Techmarines, 2 Rapiers (Heavy Bolter and Laser-Destroyer)
1st Company Tomb-Brothers Adrandus/Anchises

Injured, But Functional
10 10th Company Marines [Unassigned]
2 Techmarines [Non-Notable]
3 1st Company Marines

Fatalities:
N/A

Battlegroup Quartus
Captain: Cyrus Octavius
Epistolary: Trajan Maphar
Apothecary: Marius Astophiles [10 Gene-Seed Reclaimed]
Chaplain: Augustine
1 Apothecary
6 Scout Sergeants
Scouts [2nd Stage]: 0
Scouts [1st Stage]: 60
Neophytes [2nd Stage]: 125
(Specialist Neophytes [2nd Stage]: 0 Apothecary/2 Chaplain/9 Techmarine)

Injured But Functional
14 Scouts [1st Stage]
1 Scout Sergeant

Fatalities
21 Neophytes [2nd Stage]
5 Scouts [1st Stage]

Phase 3 Orders:
With the 4th Company And Fleet Out Of Range, Orders Cannot Be Delivered To Them!
Techmarines In Communication With One Another, Have Offered New Possibility!
[] Battlegroup Orders
-[] Primaris: Hold Position And Attempt To Pursue Objective OR Retreat Towards (Write-In) OR Pursue Depths Of Station To Locate Warboss Within
-[] Secundus: Head Towards And Aid Battlegroup (Write-In) OR Pursue New Tactical Target (Write-In) OR Pursue Depths Of Station To Locate Warboss Within
-[] Tertium: N/A [Currently Locked Into Holding Position]
-[] Quartus: Breakout And Continue Objective Attempts OR Retreat Towards (Write-In) OR Pursue Depths Of Station To Locate Warboss Within

AND

[] Techmarine Orders [Requires All Techmarines To Work On One Or The Other Due To Difficulty Of Actions]
-[] Disruption: The techmarines believe it may be possible, thanks to the haphazard nature of ork technologies to engineer a method of feedback and overall disruption that would disable much of the Warbosses capability of communicating with its forces and affecting it's ability to point them, or even order them about properly. It would, if successful, provide an immediate aid to the current fighting forces.
OR
-[] Location: The techmarines are sure that the sheer amount of information and power required to ensure the Warboss is somehow connected thus can be tracked down. Perhaps. If they can trace it, they can find the heart of this damn place and allow the whole of the Blood Ravens to fall upon the enemy's leadership. It will take time, however, and restrict them from fighting as they coordinate through noosphere and vox.

Turn 25: Scouring Fury (Part Four)

GM Note: Here we go.

Spoiler: Plan Consolidate

[X] Plan Consolidate
-[X] Battlegroup Orders
--[X] Primaris: Retreat Towards Battlegroup Tertium
--[X] Secundus: Head Towards And Aid Battlegroup Quartus
--[X] Quartus: Pursue Depths Of Station To Locate Warboss Within when Secundus links up
-[X] Techmarine Orders
--[X] Disruption

Scouring Fury
+060.M42+ To +065.M42+
+Let Your Fury Scour The Xeno Forevermore+

Disengage From Gamma
75 vs. 56

“We are of no use here,” Gabriel shook his head, ignoring the storm of slugs being thrown their way. “We shall move to assist Hannibal, and return with greater numbers.” Gabriel glanced to the whirring of servo-harnesses and muttered mixtures of gothic and binary. “Techmarine? How goes it?”

Disruption Pulse
30

“Working, Chapter Master,” Quarius muttered back from the huddle of his Mars-trained brethren. “Worry not. We can work on the move.”

Not a single one of the Blood Ravens’ group actually turned their backs to the enemy. Despite the scoring to their armor, the sheer volume of fire beginning to shred purity seals. The scouts used their better armored battle brothers as scant cover, tossing smoke and frag grenades. Not that the former did much to dissuade the orks from firing with everything they could into the tunnel. The frag and krak grenades, on the other hand, did aid matters. As did the advanced targeting cogitators inside of the rapiers as they were piloted by the techmarines.

“Oy! You get back dere and get dakka’d!”

“If only you were able to wrest yourself free and fight us yourself, ork!” Apollo called over his shoulder as they began to collapse the tunnel entrance.

“Why I oughta…I’ze gunna smash ya one way or annuver!”

There were other ways towards the objective, ones that could be taken later. The entire station was a total warren, and without the Blood Ravens deliberately shattering tunnels to close them they’d find a way. The orks alone could blow holes to let them through. Even now, drills and explosives could be heard in the distance. But they could not get through fast enough. Not when the Blood Ravens actually began to push themselves, to exert their wearied armors into a thumping run at full speed. The rapiers blazed at full speed with the techmarines begging their machine spirits to push just a little harder, their treads tearing up the ground beneath and casting up vast dust clouds behind the entire battlegroup.

Pushing Towards Tertium
55 vs. 13

“Hurr…dere you are! Gettem!”

Down one of the longer hallways, its ceiling high enough for a fully grown squiggoth to come through, a great number of walls burst apart as thickly clad ork nobs came rushing through. At their head was an entire mob of mega-nobs, klaws clacking and sparking with lightning and fire. There were over a hundred of them. Many fired their cannons into the air, or in their general direction. Others simply ran as fast as they could. Behind all of them, a war trukk on spiked wheels came roaring through, running over a dozen orks and dozens more gretchin as it came on. It was topped by a frankly impossibly heavy gun that should have crushed the chassis from simply carrying it.

“ERE WE GO! ERE WE GO!”

Gabriel did not slow down. None of the Blood Ravens did.

“MAY NONE FIND US WANTING!”

==================================

Tertium’s Holding
100 vs. 38

The red giant breathed heavily from where it stood atop the bodies. The smaller red ones loitered about by it. Each step was heavy with sticky gore, crunching shattered guns and heavy weaponry beneath their feet. With one hand it loosely held a sparking crozius arcanum, larger than any other carried in the chapter. In the other it held an ork by the throat. An especially large specimen, who snarled weakly in the grip before the fingers tightened and bone within was suddenly forced without. One had to squint, at this point, to see the floor of guns beneath the new layer of bodies. Or the layer of bodies on top of that. The rapiers and dreadnoughts had punished all who had sought to swarm, while the tight single core of chaplains had ensured every attempted breakthrough had failed. All while the techmarines had busied themselves in the very center of the formation.

Those of the 1st Company thumped about, tracking back and forth from within their terminator armor. But for a moment, it was unneeded.

Hannibal Palrun, gore-strewn, clad in the crimson of his enemies, tightened his grip on his crozius and slammed it down on the ork’s head. The power fields erupted, exploding the upper torso entirely and sending limbs flying. At least a third of his power armor was gone at this point, revealing dirt-brown tribal-marked flesh in arms thick with muscle, a spots of a torso covered in scars. One of the last marines to ever be recruited from Typhon Primaris had been fighting orks since he was born. But never had he extorted such a toll. And though Typhon Primaris was now a truly dead world, some quiet and hidden part of him hoped that he had honored his ancestors with the amount of dead in the here and now.

But then there was the sound of bolter fire. Heavy bolters. Shouts of fury and hate. The crack-boom of a thunder hammer and power mace. Slowly, the whole of battlegroup tertium turned to face the newest hallway. The orks had been relentless, attacking from at least three different directions at once with varying levels of intensity that ran from high to unbearable. The tunnels they came from changed seemingly by the minute as each individual mob was chivvied into place by Doom-Eater. Until stopping for the past blessed sixty seconds at least. The sounds of fighting increased in volume and intensity further and further until it came to a halt.

“Chapter Master,” Hannibal greeted the leader of all Blood Ravens as he turned the corner.

Immediately, the techmarines of both groups joined together into an even larger mass, babbling amongst themselves with the arcane secrets of the Omnissiah.

“Hannibal,” Gabriel raised an eyebrow. “You are well?”

“For the moment,” the Master of Sanctity nodded, the red lens in the remaining half of his helm impossible to pick out from the crimson offal coating the rest of him.

The walls squealed and shuddered as the alien mind within spoke.

“Oh, fer th’ moment ‘ee says. You fink yer so cunnin’, you could out-cunnin da cunningest!? I knew where you were goin’! Figured I’d need to push up a lot o’ boyz ta getcha all now!”

All around them things rumbled, roars and warcries echoing out of not just some of the passageways but all of them. Whooping screams and animal grunts from squigs came screeching out into the air. Thumps of metal feet and the clang of axes and swords against the walls undercut it all. But more than anything was the classic scream of their kind regardless of time and place.

“WAAAAAAAAGGH!!”

Hestior looked at Calus and Daedal who were by now shouting at one another. Then at the rest of the marines present. Technically, there was no truly senior techmarine present. All three had not, by the best reckoning of the Master of the Forge, achieved enough to be deserving of the title of Senior Techmarine. But perhaps, after this, that might change. As one, the grouping shifted, forcing the entire combined battlegroups of Blood Ravens to follow in order to protect them. A part of the wall, or rather one section of the walls with several missing portions of its surface, was the target. Wildly sparking wires, shattered and otherwise damaged speakers, and the corpses of five mega-nobs.

Completely Mobilized Response
25

Before there was a tide, push and pull, as more orks came and the survivors of each push retreated to gather more of themselves. But this was an ocean. From gretchin the size of a space marine’s boot to towering mega-nobs, the walls crunched and shattered as more dreadnought-sized squigs came bursting through. Killa kans with cackling pilots burst wholly new entrances with their drill-bit arms, while a gaggle of rocket-bearing orks blew open another wall so that their brethren could come screaming in. Twelve distinct Big Meks with their own customized weaponry led their cybork creations in extreme number behind them. Wild-eyed painboys arrived as well, their abominations of flesh and insane creations bouncing and slavering behind them.

Withstanding The Green
10 vs. 10

“Hestior!” Gabriel called even as he was swarmed.

“Almost there!”

Calus reached back and plunged a hand into the corpse of one of the mega-nobs they’d dragged with them, widening the opening with his other so that Daedal could reach in with his servo-arm’s finest manipulators.

“There it is! You were right Hestior!”

“I know I was! Now plug it in!”

Apollo snarled as he slammed his power mace into the leg of a killa kan, twisting the grip back so that it rose up and cracked open its center to reveal the squealing grot pilot within. But before he could get to the suddenly fearful creature, he was slammed by a blast of green lightning and the smell of stinking ozone and suddenly departed the materium as a Big Mek struck him with some arcane creation or another. He reappeared twenty seconds before he left, grappling with a half-formed creature of the warp twenty feet in the air before being caught by a group of orks with rockets strapped to their back and driven into another mass of greenskins. None would realize this until after the advanced command systems of the Chapter Master’s armor briefly registered two Apollo Diomedes in the same battlefield at the same time - for a brief instant at least before the laws of reality reasserted themselves to close the loop.

“Zoggit! Why won’t da warpy-porta work propa!”

“Hestior!”

Pulse Generation
46

“Almost!”

“ALMOST NUFFIN! GET IN DERE BOYZ AND KILL ‘EM ALREADY! SEND IN DA KILLIEST BOYZ!”

Withstanding
41 vs. 28

A marine, newly promoted from scout, not granted placement into a company, grit his teeth as he took the chain-axe. The guffawing nob which was halfway through disemboweling was silenced, rather suddenly, as he grasped the haft of the axe and shoved his bolter into the nob’s mouth. After emptying it, he was nearly silent as he removed it, forcing himself to stand properly and keep firing after a quick reload. Nearby, another brother flew backwards as a rocket exploded at point blank range, denting a wall as he slammed into it. Though the entire front of his armor was torn open and shredded, he stood immediately back up and continued firing. In the distance, Apollo came snarling out of a pile of squigs and threw Rogal’s Fist into the head of the mek that had forcibly teleported him before bull rushing through more bodies to retrieve it.

“HESTIOR!” Gabriel boomed as he tore out a mega-nob’s legs out from beneath him with his hammer and then brought it down onto their chest.

Pulse Generation
81

“Do it, do it now!” The techmarine yelled, activating the cobble together device even as he said so.

Multiple linked cybernetic implants buzzed with newly introduced power pulled from loose cables in the walls, the bodies of the mega-nobs twitching with the motions even as the flesh remained dead. Those wires still connected to the walls and speakers thrummed with power, excess electricity crackling and popping around them as they fed back in on themselves. The communicators screeched, and a synchronized pulse of rumbling feedback began to bounce from speaker to speaker. Techmarine Daedal and Calus collapsed as their armor systems – connected as they were to the device – shorted out temporarily, their bodies flailing in disturbingly congruent manner to the corpses of the mega-nobs. The effect was immediate, however. With each screech from the speakers, over a dozen orks stumbled mid-step, or even mid-swing of their weapons. Fingers squeezed off of triggers, voices faltered. They staggered not as one but as a falling avalanche.

Unified Brotherhood vs. Disrupted Horde
69 vs. 35

“Forwards, Blood Ravens!” Gabriel shouldered aside an ork as he pushed onwards.

“For the Unknown Primarch!” Hannibal boomed.

“Die in the Emperor’s Name!” Apollo called out.

“Someone help me up,” Calus hissed. “My armor’s locked up!”

“If you’d shunted it like I did,” Daedal shrugged as he helped his brother up, “You wouldn’t have-,”

“Shut up!”

=====================================

Holding And Receiving
97 vs. 69
74 vs. 88

Cyrus, of course, had heard the order. But he had not followed through, not yet, when he’d heard of the techmarine’s plan. The scouts could not be afforded, nor could the neophytes, for recklessness unless absolutely necessary. So they had held position. The orks had seemed busy elsewhere anyhow, turning about to stream, presumably, in the direction of the Chapter Master. The loudest and most vicious targets. Who had, he also needed to presume, been purposefully antagonizing the foe. As had been planned. But considering the fact that those under his watchful had performed as they had, he felt…satisfied, if he was being honest.

Pride, though he would never admit it.

A rippling cascade of planted explosives, mines, detonator packs, and more, planted in the middle of the battle. Something that he would have, he knew, only ever trusted himself to manage. Or perhaps his best scouts. But, led by the 1st Company marines, masquerading as mere scout sergeants, a great many squads had performed well. Very well. Some might even be up for actual promotion after this fight. Might. Maybe. Probably not. In any case, he was still waiting. Patience was difficult for some to maintain amidst a fight, but not for him. He had plenty of sluggish targets on one hand, and his rifle with the other.

Though the new arrival was making things interesting as well. Or, at least, impending arrival. He had said nothing to his scouts, desiring to see their reactions honestly, but that did not mean he couldn’t listen through the command vox channels.

“Push forward, brothers!”

Marcus Crixus was an…interesting choice for Captain of the 1st Company. In terms of veterans, it should not have been him. Either Cyrus, or Tarkus, perhaps. But no, they had been destined for other things, and despite everything, the young Captain had acquitted himself well. The fact that the 1st Company still existed at all was evidence enough of that. He’d earned his place. By sheer dint of surviving what he had if nothing else. His voice, thread and hoarse, was amplified rather purposefully by his helm, was the only sign that could be detected for his scars. Phosphex was a fearsome thing indeed. And now, pouring blood from his chest and legs, he threw aside a painboy to be caught by some of his other marines as he finally intruded upon the bay.

The reactions from his scouts was about as expected. Some cheered wildly and rose up from behind cover. Foolish, and he made a note to reprimand them later. Others stuttered out their firing accuracy, distracted by the new arrival and failing to make proper accommodations to fire upon those greenskins turning about to fire upon the newcomers. Some, however, he noted, did as was best. They modified their target choices, shifted position to ensure maximum effectiveness, or otherwise turned to aid their fellows who had already been injured or otherwise. A scant minority focused their attentions on those who had failed this impromptu test, showing remarkable initiative and possible command leanings. Another note, to speak to those he noticed.

“Bring those injured along, I will not leave our brothers behind,” Marcus rasped, hefting a battle brother to their feet. “If they must be kept from combat, we will do so in an area that they can properly defend.”

The orks flushed from the bay, retreating as the new arrivals and those already present cut apart the current attacking force from two directions. But they would be back. They would always be back.

For a moment, Cyrus paused, and considered Thaddeus’ words from the Aurelian Crusades.

And then dismissed them. Such earnest hope had been burnt out of him two centuries ago.

For now, as ever, there was only war.

“Rally and regroup, initiates,” Cyrus broadcast. “Ready yourselves to break from the bay and head inwards. Our mission is to find and eliminate Doom-Eater himself.”

Marcus pulled his blade from the guts of another ork and nodded to him. Of the scarred ruin within there was no sign, his helm still kept securely in place. Cyrus wasn’t sure if it was vanity, that he kept himself covered at nearly all times, but he wouldn’t speak against it here and now. Even if he was of the opinion that space marines should be capable of examining the sight of the price the galaxy demanded of the Emperor’s space marines.

“Cyrus,” the Captain nodded to his elder, “Good to see you and the 10th Company is well.”

“As well as they can be,” Cyrus shrugged, making sure to keep an eye out on the entrances to the bay. “We have taken casualties, and there will be dead to be reclaimed later on.”

There was not much else to say to each other, Cyrus too taciturn and Marcus too quiet, but there was not much that needed to be said either. For there came a rumbling and thumping, a staccato of primitive weaponry firing, all the while the cry of the orks began to echo once again from the tunnels and walls. Orders needed to be given, brothers granted as much aid as the apothecaries could manage. The techmarines, of course, were busy with something else, communicating solely with their brothers across the superstructure in other battlegroups. Even now, they’d begun attaching stolen cables into the walls, even ripping of the speakers off its mooring and jamming their hands into it. A small cloud of servo-skulls surrounded them as they worked.

“Stoopid beakies! Don’t you lot know when yer out-kunnined? Getting togever like dat just makes it easier ta dakka ya! Bigger targets mean a better foight! Now get in dere boyz, and dakka dem! And leave the shiny gubbins for da meks, we’ze gonna needz ‘em ta fix up me hallways n’such!”

Heavy clomping feet announced the arrival of Tomb-Brother Cassius, his hull somewhat pitted and scarred after a series of explosions from an entire herd of sort of acid-blooded squig. Though many had died before getting close enough to be properly dangerous, the sheer numbers had proven to be their greatest advantage. Not enough to slay the entombed revenant, but the damage was still annoying for Cassius to deal with.

“I have been alive for three and a half centuries, and never have I heard such an annoying ork,” he posited before pivoting to pick up and throw a piece of rusted metal to bisect the first of the ork’s pouring out of the tunnels.

“Annoying?! You stupid fat killa-kan stompy little grot! I’ll show you annoying! I’ll-,”

Blessedly, and with the thanks to the Omnissiah going up from all of the techmarines, there was a sudden sparking and blinding electrical eruptions from the walls. Speakers, clearly put in place obsessively to enforce the orders of Doom-Eater, began to explode after releasing massive sonic booms that rattled them in their frames. Just as was occurring elsewhere, with only a few seconds of difference, the disruption pulse sent orks to their feet. Cybernetic implants that burned with pain and allowed the roars of Doom-Eater passage not just through metal but meat suddenly sparked where they were lodged in thick skulls and painfully adjusted vertebrae.

And, best of all, the short-circuiting had resulted in the complete destruction of the sound system.

There was nothing to be heard from Doom-Eater.

“My ears once burned with phosphex, down to the bone,” Marcus commented as the combined battlegroups began to shift into one and head towards the hallways. “Yet his voice continues to grate at them as if they were never gone. I shall thank him for that when I find him.”

“If I do not find him first,” Cyrus glanced at him.

“Best of luck,” Marcus nodded as they all began to move.

“I don’t believe in luck.”

=================================================

Starborne Warfare
43 vs. 17/54 vs. 70/89 vs. 60/39 vs. 35/12 vs. 3/90 vs. 76/65 vs. 25/27 vs. 54/47 vs. 30

Shattered wrecks slowly tumbled through the void. Howling voices that once guffawed and jeered with every motion and rattling boom of their cannons were silent. The Potentia, mightiest of the 4th Company Fleet, and one of the remaining battle barges of the Blood Ravens, hung surrounded by the corpses of a great many vessels. It bled, heavily, but its burning still blazed defiantly within its adamantium skin. Carefully, achingly slow, the rest of the Chapter Fleet peeled back the self-made cocoon. Various experimental fuel mixtures still leaked into the void, the ships that once made use of them cracked and broken. With pushes of purposefully reduced yields in explosions, the tugging of thunderhawks with attached clamps, the battle-scarred hulk was once more exposed to distant starlight. Potentia’s bombardment cannon was bent, but such damage was not difficult to repair.

Deep within, its master stalked through blackened corridors scored by slug throwers and the exotic weaponry only orks could craft in their maddened minds. A dozen wounds that would be considered severe even for space marine physiology struggled to clot together. A mixture of melted slag and vaporized bone was all that remained of his left arm past the shoulder, a mek’s strange melta cannon misfiring as it died striking the blow. All around them, the corpses of dead servitors and serfs lay amongst the bodies of the orks who had come to kill them all. Despite the entreaties of Nero Gracchus, Hadrian Priscus refused to be remanded to the apothecarium as had many of his company. Some would require healing for some time, others perhaps some bionic replacement, while three would require dreadnought placement. Many tarantula sentry turrets had been damaged, but their ability to hold entire corridors had proved invaluable. Even now they were undergoing repairs.

“Captain, please, your primary heart is in its third set of cardiac arrest, and your Larraman’s is struggling to pick up the slack of the rest of your wounds,” the apothecary pleaded, his white armor liberally splattered with those who he had killed in the name of preserving his brothers.

“Not…yet,” Hadrian snarled, stomping forward tirelessly even as multiple squads moved about on the ship, their movements reported through the company-wide vox.

The Chief Apothecary sighed.

“At least let me take the metal shard out of your skull?”

Hadrian paused, only for a moment, and turned slightly so that the foot-long spike of metal that had just barely penetrated through his skull – only to miss the brain by a centimeter – could be torn out of both his head and helmet.

“There, are you happy now?” Hadrian sniffed, though his rolling eyes were hidden behind the lenses of his helm.

“Well no, the fighting has been over for an hour now and you haven’t actually allowed me to get to the business of healing you, so…,” Nero trailed off as an ork rose from the piles of its dead.

Roaring wordlessly, a reloaded kustom kannon whirring as it spun up in its hands, the nob managed to fire fifty full rounds before Hadrian reached it. Blood practically spat out of his back as the rounds went through his already compromised rib plates. In response, Hadrian reached forward with his remaining hand and wrapped it around the barrel of the kannon, gritting his teeth as he forced it upwards and against the ork’s skull. A trail of rounds continued to spit into the ceiling for the first strike, and the second, before beginning to slack for the third and fourth. It stopped entirely by the sixth. Hadrian, on the other hand, did not stop until the tenth. By then the nob, the last ork alive from the screaming fleet that had come charging in, gleeful to attend to Hadrian’s broadcasted challenge that they come for a real fight, was long dead. Brain and bone covered the wall, slowly scorching black as the cheery red heat from the barrel rested against the pulp.

Only then did the Captain of the 4th Fleet turn around and face Nero as he pulled off his helmet and let it drop to the floor.

“There. Now it’s done,” Hadrian nodded. “Tell our fellow vessels to continue freeing the Potentia of our victims, order Martellus and his techmarines to commit to repairs as best they can, and get these filthy xeno corpses off my ship.”

He collapsed to his knees, leaving dents in the floor from the force of the motion.

“Until I am revived,” he continued as blood began to dribble out of his mouth in multiple streams, “Command is to be granted over to Martellus, as all things considered he is probably best for keeping the ships in as best condition as possible. Second command to you, third to Trexus.”

Finally, the enemy dead, their ships ruined in their hubris to come after a true challenge that he had offered, Hadrian fell forward onto his face and ceased to suppress the orders of his sus-an membrane. His body curled slightly as it fell into its coma as Nero stood over him, one hand still raised to ask another question that would go without answer. Then the Chief Apothecary looked around in the hallway, then back down to the Captain. Sighing again, he reached down and hefted the man up and began to drag him away.

“Marines like you remind me of Aramus sometimes,” he muttered, “Oh, I’m fine Nero, let me just run at the Greater Daemon, and the Hive Tyrant, and the Warboss! What’s that? Mortal wounds? You can fix me up can’t you, Nero?”

A twitch of his command vox and a few servo skulls came floating by.

“Tell Brother Julian that when I get there, the Captain is to be his full responsibility. I will take over for everyone else.”

They shot away as fast as they came.

“Oh no! I decided to keep hitting Araghast the Pillager while Cyrus set his bombs at our feet! Gordian’s gone, so now it’s up to you Nero!”

No one paid his muttering any mind as he went on his way. Thankfully for Captain Hadrian, he remained comatose for the entire journey.

============================================

Penetrating The Doom-Eater’s Innards
92 vs. 7

Long ago, at one point or another, the Blood Ravens had sought out a Primarch to be held up as their own amongst the gloried histories of all other chapters. This had happened multiple times. Once, when it appeared that some of their marines were afflicted with the Black Rage, the excitement that they might be of Sanguinius was exultant despite the issue that brought the possibility about. This was proven false, with bitter quiet anger on both sides when those mutated were ended. At another time, it was thought they could be of the Dark Angels, for some reason or another that none alive can recall. The stability and purity of their gene-seed was remarked upon for many a time. Another possibility was the Raven Guard, perhaps though this was a bit desperate in a search for connection by their shared heraldry. While all three were disproven or otherwise abandoned as theories, each time the Blood Ravens had marveled at the chance. Though it was gone now, it appeared, for just a time, that the Raven Guard might yet have some connection in some small way.

Cyrus would scoff at this, and say it was merely good scout work.

It was his scouts that found many a tunnel that led deeper in, found passageways that led to secondary reactors and supply depots. It was his scouts that, with the enemy so eagerly distracted with the louder thumping of the 1st Company, found weapons and vehicles aplenty. Staging areas were set with explosives to detonate as the orks marshaled themselves, flanking maneuvers while Captain Marcus drove the terminators further in. Occasionally, as the orks readied themselves for a charge against the 1st Company lines, they would be assaulted by shotguns and tossed grenades from behind. Hallways used to try and assault Marcus’ formations from the side found themselves collapsing.

They slipped as if living shadows deeper and deeper in the massive station, watching as the disheartened and disorganized orks began to butt up against one another.

Boss Against Boss Against Boss Against Boss Against Boss
33 vs. 57 vs. 93 vs. 74 vs. 69 vs. 85

Rather violently, as it turned out.

For so long, the booming voice of Doom-Eater had come from every direction, including within. Overpowering, to the point that many a rather large ork – if they were those originally within the galactic plane – who would long ago have begun desiring leadership under their green hands were only just beginning to awaken to the baser brutal greed of their kind. With Doom-Eater abruptly unable to order them in everywhere, bellowing in their ears until they bled, without pause, the scouts discovered small but growing sites of battle between orks challenging each other for operational authority. Their hoots and grunts were easy enough to translate, given their Captain’s training, and so the scouts reported back that multiple leaders were already starting to emerge.

A massive mega-nob, practically the size of a dreadnought, fired with twelve different grafted weapons on its body across a staging chamber into the chamber of an insane painboy’s twisted menagerie that came slavering out in mutated streams.

Two nobs who could grapple with a fully armored terminator marine in terms of size instead wrestled each other. Their mobs, numbering dozens and dozens of orks behind them, tore into each other with everything in reach.

Stompa’s came bursting out of the walls at one point, tearing into each other as the ork pilot’s within the giant machines battered each other over some grudge or another long suppressed.

On and on it went, all the while the Blood Ravens skulked deeper. Or at least, the scouts did. The 1st Company found itself relegated as an attention grabber, forcing the orks closer and closer in against themselves. There was something to be said about so many terminator-clad marines providing such convenient targets. When the orks could manage dominance over one another, or were simply currently without a nearby challenger, they were a foe ready to fight. On more than one occasion, Captain Marcus slew two leaders at once as the Blood Ravens entered as a third member into ongoing two way fights.

Tracking The System Paths
5

The only problem, as it turned out, was that ork technology was incomprehensible. Completely so. Cable junctions led into the walls and then emerged unknowable locations elsewhere. Power stations ran dangerously hot but the actual direction of the energies sent were unknowable. Sometimes it looked like the orks had actually plugged generators into themselves for some reason, which to the consternation of the techmarines was somehow producing even more energy. Shunts and breakers were stuck into the walls at random intervals with the insane sensibilities of the ork meks. They pored over workshops and broken machinery, as well as the strange cybernetic implants of so many of the orks, but found little success.

The disruption pulse had fed in upon itself, turning the redlining generators and electrical systems in on one another. Larger systems, independent with their own generator systems, were somewhat unaffected. The guns on the outside of the station, for instance, perhaps its engines and certain shield production points. But without the system actually still running, there was no clear path to follow whatsoever. The benefits were obvious, they knew, but even so they were still struggling to find their way. All that was left was ‘deeper’, towards the core of the mixture of metal and stone. Where they found, of course, more and more orks. Some scouts posited that they simply needed to keep trying to find the largest concentrations. But the fighting was getting worse. As the hours stretched on, the biggest and strongest orks were beginning to properly assert themselves for the first time in years. Unrestrained chaos became, rather counter-intuitively, organized in so much as solidified groups were beginning to form.

“This isn’t working!” One scout cried out as he frantically pumped his shotgun again, firing the last round it possessed. “I’m running out of ammo but they keep coming!”

“Triggering detonation packs!”

“Minefield is depleted to ten percent, that hallway is a charnel house but they’re not stopping.”

“Ork leader self-identifying as ‘Megaboss Krakskull’ has completed asserting his authority, his slugga and shoota boyz are starting to cut us off from proper reinforcement routes.”

“Neophyte Grant has lost the ability to use his legs, he will require an apothecary to put his bones back together. We are retreating currently.”

“I’m out of sniper rounds, he’s got solid plates of looted adamantium protecting his skull! We’re pulling back to sector eighteen.”

Tendrils of scouts were repulsed, twisted in upon themselves, and finally began to reverse themselves out of their own accord. The unyielding fist of the 1st Company found its progress slowed, though not entirely halted just yet. Elsewhere, upon a field of corpses, the other joined battlegroups stood unbroken. Some marines were injured, surely, but none more dead. Some would require rather significant healing, but for now their hearts thumped with still pulsing righteous fury. Cyrus, for his part, grit his teeth after setting off another series of explosives to collapse a ceiling onto another horde. He knew he was starting to run out of those supplied by the chapter. Improvised explosives were not something he was unfamiliar with, and it was not as if the orks did not have plenty of such things on their own.

Identifying Other Targets Properly
67

The only way to push something as massive as the Doom-Eater through space was fuel and reactors in tremendous quantities. If they could not find Doom-Eater himself, perhaps they did not need to if they could simply destroy the entire superstructure. Main reactors which jumped and bounced in their housings. Fuel depots ready to be injected for that extra bit of speed. Giant cylinders that leaked where copious amounts of invented fuel mixtures sloshed. Internal factories where new weapons were manufactured. Control stations where gretchin and grots ran about to load ammo into the weapons that could damage and destroy even a battle barge. Big mek’s whose entire life’s work had been producing zzap kannons that could blast apart escort ships, each centered in their own little bubbles of influence and creation. Of course, there was also the idea of simply to keep pushing. To keep searching. The ork was possibly at the very, very center of the entire place. The only issue was actually getting there. The further into enemy territory, the more chance of risk without reinforcement. Of being surrounded and cut off. A dangerous proposition either way, for it was unknown what personal defenses and abilities the warboss might possess. Especially considering the size of the horde he was leading. On the other hand, if they could strip the stations' defenses enough, they might just be able to kill off the entire thing rather than continuing to risk themselves trying to find it's heart. Something to contemplate as he continued to isolate and kill as many orks as he possibly could.

Spoiler: Collected Results Of Phase3

Blood Ravens Fleet Has Defeated Ork Fleet Entirely! Currently Undergoing Repairs, Likely To Be Able To Return To Doom-Eater Proper Soon!
Construkta Yard Gamma Assault Abandoned!
Bay Assaults Abandoned!
4 Ork Leader Have Established Themselves!
Primaris And Tertium Free To Pursue New Objective!
- Warboss Tactical Possibilities: Exterminatus Weaponry/Deep Strike Teleporters/Strike Force Penetration Through Mundane Means
- Tactical Consideration: Orks show high amount of 'advanced' weaponry and armors, and significant coordination through Doom-Eater communications.
- Tactical Consideration: With communications disrupted, ork leaders are establishing themselves and beginning to quarrel with each other. Without Doom-Eater’s ability to continually enforce authority, chaos currently reigns within the depths. No sightings have been made of Doom-Eater ‘loyalists’, only the new ork factions who seem happy to fight each other as much as the Blood Ravens.
- Tactical Consideration: Multiple new targets identified and located for sabotage and assault movements.
- Tactical Consideration: Ork Warboss location seems indeterminable at this time. The Disruption Pulse ruined the systems that might otherwise have tracked his location. Even so, scouting teams have pushed deep into the Doom-Eater. There is only so much left of the station left to explore and scout before he must be found.
- Tactical Consideration: Casualty numbers are rising. Space Marines can withstand much, but require rest and healing if hurt enough. Injured marines are more susceptible to further injury, possibly death. Effective strength of remaining battlegroups is beginning to fall. Objectives must be chosen carefully. Strength in numbers will be of use, considering the numbers of orks being brought fully to bear as Doom-Eater's populace of greenskins is now fully roused.

Major Operational Consideration: Two obvious paths present themselves. There may be others. The first obvious path is to continue pushing for Warboss Doom-Eater. The later is destroying The Doom-Eater. The former may involve further casualties after trying to extract after the killing. The latter may involve further casualties in attempting to complete the objectives required.

Current Possible Tactical Targets Of Station:
- Engine Sectors Alpha/Beta/Gamma [Increased Accuracy And Knowledge Provided For Sabotage Attempts]
- Anti-Orbital Defenses Include: Looted Imperial Broadside Cannons/Scattered Orkish Lance Turrets/Ork 'Heavy Gunz'/Ork 'Gunz'/Ork Torpedo Bays [Increased Accuracy And Knowledge Provided For Sabotage Attempts]
- Energy Shield Projector Points Located, Destruction Would Allow Bombardment If Anti-Orbital Weaponry Removed. [Increased Accuracy And Knowledge Provided For Sabotage Attempts]
- Reactor Hearts Alpha/Beta/Gamma/Delta Located! Main Power Providers For Entire Doom-Eater's Weapons And Defenses! [Increased Accuracy And Knowledge Provided For Sabotage Attempts]
- Construkta Yard Gamma
- New Feuding Ork Leaders: Megaboss Krakskull/Supa Dok Purgu/Mekaboss Brekabrak/Ghraganap
- Depths Of Doom-Eater [Precise Location Of Warboss Unknown]

Battlegroup Primaris
Gabriel Angelos, Apollo Diomedes, Honor Guard [Captain Doukas/Chaplain Volkoss/Apothecary Falkor]
15 1st Company marines
1 Scout Sergeant and 9 Scouts from the 10th Company
1 Apothecary
1 Chaplain
Techmarine Quarius Zergan and 3 other Techmarines, 3 Rapiers (Heavy Bolter)

Injured But Functional
Honor Guard Chaplain Uther Volkoss
Honor Guard Captain Doukas
7 1st Company Marines
2 Techmarines

Battlegroup Secundus
Captain: Marcus Crixus TH
Company Champion: Uriel Hamul TH
Epistolary: VACANT
Apothecary: Constantius Romallius TH [24 Gene-Seed Reclaimed]
Chaplain: Ares Actus TH
10 1st Company
31 Unassigned marines from the 10th
2 1st Company Dreadnoughts
1 Scout Sergeant and 9 Scouts from the 10th Company
2 Apothecaries
Chaplain Ravias/Chaplain
Techmarine Hestior/2 other Techmarines, 2 Rapiers (Heavy Bolter and Laser-Destroyer)
1st Company Tomb-Brothers Cassius

Injured But Functional
17 10th Company Marines [Unassigned]
10 1st Company Marines
1 Chaplain
Chaplain Ravias
Uriel Hamul
Marcus Crixus
Ares Actus
1 Techmarine

Fatalities:
1 Techmarine
14 10th Company Marines [Unassigned]
1st Company Tomb-Brother Brutus

Battlegroup Tertium
Hannibal Palrun
24 1st Company Marines
40 unassigned marines from the 10th
2 1st Company Dreadnoughts
1 Scout Sergeant and 9 Scouts from the 10th Company
2 Apothecaries [4 Gene-Seed Reclaimed]
Chaplain Antonius/2 Chaplains
Techmarine Calus/Techmarine Daedal/2 Techmarines, 2 Rapiers (Heavy Bolter and Laser-Destroyer)
1st Company Tomb-Brothers Adrandus/Anchises

Injured, But Functional
24 10th Company Marines [Unassigned]
2 Techmarines [Non-Notable]
3 1st Company Marines
3 Scouts of the 10th Company
1 Chaplain
1 Techmarine

Fatalities:
N/A

Battlegroup Quartus
Captain: Cyrus Octavius
Epistolary: Trajan Maphar
Apothecary: Marius Astophiles [10 Gene-Seed Reclaimed]
Chaplain: Augustine
1 Apothecary
6 Scout Sergeants
Scouts [2nd Stage]: 0
Scouts [1st Stage]: 60
Neophytes [2nd Stage]: 125
(Specialist Neophytes [2nd Stage]: 0 Apothecary/2 Chaplain/9 Techmarine)

Injured But Functional
20 Scouts [1st Stage]
38 Neophytes [2nd Stage]
1 Scout Sergeant
3 Techmarine Neophytes

Fatalities
21 Neophytes [2nd Stage]
5 Scouts [1st Stage]

Battlefleet Blood Raven

1 Gladius Frigate Destroyed [4th Company]
Minor Damage Across All 1st Company Escort Ships
Burning Seeker Has Taken Notable Damage (Starboard/Port/Rear Weapon Arrays/Engines) [4th Company]
Spiraling Fury Has Taken Minor Internal Damage [1st Company]
1 Faith’s Horizon Gunship Thunderhawk Destroyed [10th Company]
2 Howling Hatred Gunship Thunderhawks Destroyed [10th Company]
3 Omnis Arcanum Gunship Thunderhawks Destroyed [1st Company]
Minor Damage Across Remaining 4th Company Escorts
Minor Damage Across 10th Company Escorts
1 Nova Frigate Destroyed [10th Company]
1 Gladius Frigate Destroyed [1st Company]
Legacy of Polonius Lance Array Destroyed, Will Require Repairs.
Scientia Est Potentia Has Taken Significant Damage To Hull/All Weapons Arrays/Command Deck. Multiple points in hull penetrated by boarding torpedoes and drills. Currently undergoing patching and sealing. [4th Company]

Captain: Hadrian Priscus [UNAVAILABLE DUE TO INJURIES]
Company Champion: Trexus Nubius [Bears Power Axe/Power Fist Dual Combination] TH
Epistolary: Nero Achillian [Bears Psychic Hood/Raven's Aegis Talisman] [Farseer/Daemonologist]
Apothecary: Caesar
Chaplain: Ateren [Powerful Bionic Arm/Leg]

Company Strength: 77% Strength (53% Effective)

Additional Members
Chief Apothecary Nero Gracchus/Apothecary
1 Chaplain
Master of the Forge Martellus Ravias/3 Techmarines/

Veteran Sergeants:
- 5 1st Company Veterans TH
- 5 4th Company Veterans

Injured And Functional
30 4th Company Space Marines
All Tarantula Sentry Turrets

Injured And Non-Functional
20 4th Company Space Marines
Captain Hadrian Priscus [Left Arm Requires Bionic Replacement]

Dreadnought Notation
3 4th Company Space Marines Interred In Dreadnought Frames [3 Dreadnought Frames Used, 1 Remaining In Armory]
- Brother Relian
- Brother Aeneas
- Brother Polites [Newly Revived]
- Brother Turnus [Newly Revived]
- Brother Mezentius [Newly Revived]

Phase 4 Orders:
[] Battlegroup Orders
-[] Primaris: Pursue New Objective (Write-In)
-[] Secundus: Continue Current Tactical Objective [Scouting For Warboss] Or Pursue New Objective (Write-In)
-[] Tertium: Pursue New Objective (Write-In)
-[] Quartus: Continue Current Tactical Objective [Scouting For Warboss] Or Pursue New Objective (Write-In)

Turn 20 Results - 2479.5

Spoiler: Voting results [*] Plan Citadel Focus -[*][Max] Current Task: Have Maximilian teach the We written Reikspiel. -[*][Johann] Allow him to spend all his time investigating Clan Mors. -[*][EIC] Instil corporate policy: always be scrupulously honest when dealing with Dwarves. -[*][Social] Wolf is now fully grown, and is a very large dog or a regular-sized wolf. Train him. (increases his intelligence, may deepen Familiar bond) -[*][Penthouse] Have a tower built atop Karag Nar: -100gc for 1 room, bonus to room's purpose. -[*][Free] Request the translation item yourself (does not cost an action; converts 3 College Favour to Dwarf Favour). -[*] Help the We establish their new nest below the Citadel. -[*] Spend time assisting with a fellow councillor's task: Gunnar, assist him with human burial rites. -[*] You have acquired the possession of the Temple where Ranald mugged Mork. Set up a shrine and spread knowledge of it throughout Karag Nar. -[*] Write in: You've mapped the territory of Clan Mors. Help Johann with his investigations there, with an eye to covertly disrupting the Skaven ability to deal with the spiders while you're there. -[*] The Gambler: Clan Mors investigation/sabotage To say that you draw a few stares as you lead a procession of enormous spiders across the Eastern Valley is an understatement. Despite the entire Karak being forewarned to avoid any messy misunderstandings, the only people who didn't stop to gawk were the ones calling for other people to get here quick so they could join in the gawking. The We seemed equally uncomfortable, both from the amount of stares they get and from being exposed, and you reflect that this may be the first time any of their species has walked under the open sky. You also get your first glimpse of the three Egg-Layers, which resemble an Arachnarok spider in size but completely lack fangs, and the innumerable dog-sized Web-Weavers clinging to the Egg-Layers like a coat of armour. The Hunters flank the skittering procession, though that they're facing forward instead of outwards is a gesture of trust. Through the gates of the Citadel and down a stairway went the We, disappearing into the depths of the tunnels beneath. The Dwarven fortifications had been quickly dismantled and remade under your supervision deeper underground, guided by your earlier scouting of Clan Mors' territory. Now what was once the King's Hall had been reclaimed, though Belegar had declared that the Hall of the Moon served in that role in the resurgent Karak, and some new purpose would be found for the old Hall. Just below that, accessible only through a newly-fortified junction that would protect and also carefully watch the Hold's newest allies, was the Hall of Pillared Iron. The room had only a single entrance and the pillars that named it would serve well as anchor points for the Web-Weavers. The junction wall stood ten feet tall and would become taller still in the following weeks, but the Hunters could come and go along the roof. You doubted any of the We would go up rather than down after the Dwarves had proven so uncooperative to attempts to make a meal out of them, but a second guard on the stairs down made it impossible for them to do so unnoticed and therefore put the minds of the Dwarves at rest. The item you had commissioned of the Amber College arrived quickly, and freed up Esbern and Seija to continue on their journeys. They say they'll linger in Ulrikadrin for a time and turn their extensive notes into a proper paper, and as you skim their drafts you're pleased to see yourself listed as a contributor. The paper focuses almost entirely on the social and biological cooperation of the We, which reaches a level of cooperation that matches that of hive insects and has never previously been found in arachnids. It would have been a coup if you had beaten them to the punch, but you still get some of the credit and there's still plenty of room for new papers that go deeper into the psychology and anatomy of the We. So it now turns to Maximilian to take the lead in building a relationship with the We, or at least whichever portion of the We is wearing the ivory circlet like a bracelet on its pedipalps at the time. [Maximilian teaching the We: Learning, 62+16+10(Patient)+7(Library: The Empire of Man)=95.] [The We learning on their own: 80.] It's slow going, but Maximilian sticks to it and as weeks pass the We grow to understand what he's saying and develop an understanding of writing. On top of that they begin to understand the concept and then the language of spoken speech, and begin to develop a basic understanding of spoken Reikspiel, not just from Maximilian but by conversations amongst themselves using the circlet. They're still completely incapable of speaking without magical assistance, their mouthparts being completely unsuited to the task, but with an adequate supply of chalk and a convenient wall to write on, they're able to make themselves understood when they feel the need. The Dwarves ensure someone fluent in the language is on the nearby fortifications at all times, and slowly begin to grow accustomed to their comings and goings, possibly helped by how often they return with a paralyzed and bound Skaven hanging from their pedipalps. [Preliminary Observations on the Eusocial Cave Spider, By J. Esber (Amber) & J. Seija (Amber), M. Mathilde Weber (Grey). Subject: Rare, +1. Insight: Shattering, +3. Delivery: Competent, +0. Contributor, -3. Thorough, +1. Exotic, +1. Final Rating: +3] --- Your skimming through the books you've acquired on Morr and the beliefs of his faithful gives you enough of a theoretical framework to justify the insights into burial practices you've picked up from the Liber Mortis. Before the Skaven arrived and Frederick picked up Necromancy to combat them, Frederick was as deeply involved with the Cult of Morr as one could be without surrendering his rank of Baron. When the Plague swept through Sylvania and left more dead than living, he was ordained despite his title and given access to the full secrets of the God of Death, including how one could deal with more dead than could practically be put to rest individually. With his knowledge, you can piece together the fragments and hints you find in a dozen other books to come up with a plausible explanation of how you inferred the ritual of the ossuary. Though carefully guarded by Gunnars and his acolytes, the human fallen have had no protection against the march of time, and now carefully labelled skeletal remains lie in neat rows, waiting to be put to rest. And though they weren't nearly as common as those dedicated to the more warlike Gods like Ulric, Sigmar, Myrmidia or Taal, among them were those dedicated to Morr. You meet with Francesco Caravello, and as well as congratulating him on his newfound leadership and passing him your now-redundant Torc of Fire as a sort of symbol of office, you also ask him to go amongst the Undumgi and find out who among the fallen were sufficiently devoted to the Death God for your purpose. A few days later you have your list, and make your way to Gunnars. Gunnars listens intently as you outline the general concept. Those suitably devoted to Morr are posthumously given the title of Lay-Priest, which can not only be done as an emergency measure, but is also explicitly allowed in the absence of Priests of Morr by followers of Morai-Heg, Gazul, Quinsberry, the Lady, and the Ancient Widow. They are then entrusted with the souls of their fellows, and are then entombed with them in a mass ossuary, where each type of bone has its own compartment rather than each compartment holding a single corpse. While a proper burial would be safer for the souls of the lost, better they be banded together for protection than linger for months or years without being put to rest. Though they understand that human funereal traditions are different than Dwarven ones that consider the first three days after death to be the most important and dangerous ones for the spirit of the departed, they still seek to put the departed to their rest in as timely a manner as possible. The pair of you work together to come up with a plan for reworking the excavated tombs into suitable ossuaries, with much careful review of the relevant parts of the Morrite tomes you bring to bear. Swift and efficient Dwarven stonework makes the plans a reality and Gunnars and his acolytes are able to set to work performing the morbid but necessary task of grouping the dead together so that each room contains at least one of the Lay-Priests. This method almost allowed Frederick Van Hal and the few surviving Priests of Morr to put all of the fallen to rest, and the history of Sylvania may have gone very differently if the Plague hadn't been accompanied by a rain of warpstone meteorites that attracted the attention of the Skaven. With months or even years shaved off the task, Gunnars is able to call for a halt on expansion of the tomb complex and leave several unused rooms for further expansion. As Kragg is sequestered away on a separate task, Thorek takes a break from his raiding with King Kazador to apply and empower the necessary runes and the doors of the tomb seem to melt into the stonework. --- While performing the work of Morr, you make sure not to neglect your relationship with your own God. You and Ranald might have a fairly unstructured relationship, but it's good manners to set up a shrine to your God whether it's strictly necessary or not, and besides that the Karag currently lacks one for those that aren't quite so close to Him as you are. Remembering the fate of the idol of Stromfels, you gather up the inert chunks of the Idol - obsidian, thankfully, as you've heard of idols made of dung - and consider their amount and size. The colour of the rock makes it obvious what the idol should be, but it's easier said than done and you're no artist. Thankfully, being in a Karak means it's never going to be difficult to find an able stonemason, and you enlist the help of those with unexpected free time on their hands after the tomb's requirements had been reduced. They're not all that familiar with cats in general, but you show them an etching in one of your books on the subject of Ranald and they nod and get to work. Under your careful eye they first chisel and then sand the separate fragments, and only begin to put the entire thing together at the last minute, with drilled holes and carefully-applied molten iron to hold it all together. The grey of the iron-pinned faultlines is a pleasing effect on the black of the obsidian, and a protective lacquer goes over the top to prevent rusting. The stone cat stares smugly down at you from its perch, tail curled along its body, and you're rather pleased with the effect. [Anything unexpected? Piety, 9+25=34.] The rest of the job is a matter of gathering up the remaining religious paraphernalia of the Orcs and storing them away securely for use in later religious displays, and as you're packing up the last of it a soft sound has you turn your head and, inevitably, you see a cat just as black as the obsidian one perched atop the idol's head, chewing its happy way through what looks like a substantial slice of cured ham. You roll your eyes and continue your work, and as you approach the door with the last crate, it opens to reveal Oswald Oswaldson. "Magister!" he exclaims. "I was just looking for- have you seen a cat?" You indicate behind you with a jerk of your head. "No, I meant- oh, there she is. Get down from there!" With the shrine revealed to one of the foremost and definitely the chattiest of the Undumgi, you likely need do nothing more for news of it to spread. "This sort of thing is why you got demoted, Corporal Snuggles," Oswald scolds as you carry away the last of the former furnishings of the Shrine. With that job taken care of, you follow Oswald's lead and spend some quality time with Wolf, who's through with growing and would match you in height if he put his paws on your shoulders. He's certainly clever, knows a great deal of commands, and shows a great deal of skill in finding people who might have excess food to share as he wanders freely through Karag Nar and the Eastern Valley, but as far as you can tell he doesn't yet show the advanced intelligence that a bonded Familiar is capable of. And though he certainly doesn't hesitate to bark at your command, he's yet to expand his vocabulary past that. Your books on the subject suggest this isn't unexpected, as the mental development of a Familiar need not correspond to its physical ageing, as plenty of animals who become Familiars do so as grown adults. So far, apart from the magical power you can see flowing between you and him and his habit of obeying orders you haven't actually given yet, he seems no different than an ordinary dog - though he does, of course, exceed them all in the realms of Being A Good Boy. So you make a point to spend time with him between your other responsibilities, and every time a day's end, the need to consult part of your growing library, or the desire to check on the construction of your tower takes you back to Karag Nar, Wolf happens to be around the base of the mountain to join you on your climb back up to the penthouse. Then one day you were on your way to visit the local EIC delegations but changed your mind at the last minute, and you feel an odd sense of urgency as you start your solitary climb up the stairs, and next thing you know there's a skittering of claws on stone as Wolf bolts through the entrance to Karag Nar and to your side, taking the stairs three at a time until he reaches you. As you scratch him behind the ears, you run through your memories and sure enough, never before has he failed to be there waiting when you were heading home - until you didn't know that's where you were heading until the last minute. Link of Psyche, the books called it. The ability to convey complex thoughts over any amount of distance, and the sharing of mental resources to improve problem-solving abilities. You must have been subconsciously broadcasting your return each time, and Wolf had picked up on it and joined you for the climb up to your home every day. What a good boy. [Link of Psyche acquired: +2 Stewardship, +2 Learning.] --- With the EIC expanding into the Karaz Ankor, one very important thing needs to be communicated very clearly: Dwarves don't think like us. Dwarves have no truck in concepts like 'close enough' or 'acceptable levels of corruption' or 'it's just business' or 'proportional response'. The price of rocking the boat being higher than the cost of whatever institutional graft is taking place is no protection when one is dealing with Dwarves. Put your promises in writing and then stick to them. Because there's very little as bad for business as a Dwarf Clan that's been wronged, and it can be difficult to make a profit with an axe where your face used to be. It turns out very easy indeed to gather the materials for the speech you'll be putting on twice, once here and once in Stirland. All you have to do is walk into any tavern in Karag Lhune - and there's more than a couple now that the Dwarf population has begun moving into the Chiselwards in earnest - and announce that you want to hear about times that unfaithful dealings by humans received its just deserts, and all you have to do is prepare your notebook as those present argue about who has the best stories and then jot down notes as the flood of anecdote begins. The most infamous tale is, of course, the one where a Dwarf clan was shortchanged tuppence for the construction of some type of fortification, and after they quite politely pointed out the shortfall and were told in no uncertain terms that no monetary reconciliation would be forthcoming, the entire Clan went to war, battled the local army and won, and tore the fortress to the ground. You heard five different versions of it, few of which agree on details, and are not entirely convinced that it happened; but if it did, you don't have much sympathy to whoever it happened to. Contrary to what some might think, it's hard to get on the wrong side of a Grudge by accident. Even the most cantankerous and hair-trigger of Dwarves will make their problem clear before they skip straight to the violence, and if you believe that their case against you is unjustified the matter can be escalated to their Clan Elders, then to the Hold's Loremasters, then to the King of their Hold, and even to the High King if you believe it necessary. It's only when one wrongs a Dwarf and makes it clear they will make no redress whatsoever that the Dwarves go to war. But though the tale might be an exaggeration, it very definitely gets the message across, as do the dozen other tales you gather from the taverns and the relevant laws and precedents pulled from your library. First to the local EIC representatives, who are still getting established here, and then to a full meeting of representatives from every branch of the EIC, you very thoroughly lay out not just what not to do, but also why not. You describe the Book of Grudges, and cite several examples - not from the Dammaz Kron, which describes only the most terrible of wrongs done to the Dwarven race, but from the local Books of Grudges maintained in each of the hold, which records every unsettled score. One in particular seems particularly relevant: an unsettled debt between Zhufbar and the Asoborn tribe, where tribesman made a delivery of a cartload of wild grains in exchange for three good axes, only for it to be later discovered that the grains were mouldy and cut with sawdust. After the destruction of Castle Drakenhof, several Grudges against the Vampires were struck out as settled, but so too were several accumulated Grudges against the rulers and population of Stirland - and then, when it was judged that the Grudges struck out were almost but not quite sufficient, they kept going back until they found a Grudge of just the right severity, and only then were the sins of the long-dead Asoborns forgiven. Judging by the horrified stares you get, the message has been successfully communicated. What you didn't tell them was that the sins of those Asoborns would likely never be pursued, or at least not until the more important Grudges against greenskins, Skaven, Chaos Gods, Chaos Dwarves, Ogres and Elves were settled first. A little terror would be good for them. [Instil Corporate Policy: Stewardship, Breakpoints 40/80: 64+18+4(Library: The Karaz Ankor)=86.] While in Stirland, you also make a small detour to follow up on a request from King Belegar, but what you thought would be a simple job turns out very frustrating indeed. Finally, in a tavern in Nachthafen you get an answer. "Codrin Petrescu's sort of a Sylvanian joke," says the barkeep, who has been seeing a lot more business from Stirlandian soldiers than Sylvanian locals of late. "Though it's a matter of opinion how funny it is. If an outsider wants to know who did something or who's responsible for something and you want to give them the runaround, you tell them 'Codrin Petrescu' and point them to the next village along. The next village will hear the name and know to point them to the next village, and so on. If you know the old language, the name sort of means, erm... forgive my language ma'am, but 'in the forest, son of my privates'. Like, um, if a man answers a call of action against a tree?" You're familiar with the general idea, having been sent looking for a left-handed grounding rod a time or two yourself. You hand over some silver in gratitude for the straight answer, and make your way back to Eight Peaks feeling very unamused indeed. --- Johann is a tricky fellow, and if it weren't for the institutional backing of the Grey Order he might have been able to slip several significant secrets by you - first his intentions with the Skaven, and second his actual rank. With both of those cleared up, are there more layers of lies to peel through, or is the way clear for Johann to start proving himself? Part of you would rather write him off completely and have him firmly ejected from the Karak in favour of someone who doesn't play games, but considering the effort you've put into him already, you might as well see what he's capable of when he's finally given a free hand to engage in his preferred vocation. He's taken to wearing gloves and long sleeves ever since he returned from Altdorf. "New fashion trend?" you ask as you make your way down the stairs of the Citadel. "In certain circles," he replies evasively. "Are you sure you want to go down there unarmed? I've seen you shoot, and a gun might come in handy." "Gunpowder would give me away, and we don't all have Ulgu to keep our secrets." He pauses as you reach the fortification; with this many armed and armoured Dwarves around, Chamon is heavy in the air, and he calls it to himself with a series of gestures. The first is Aethyric Armour, then a second fills his skin with radiance for a second and then solidifies, and a third fills the air around him with tiny metal balls that reflect the torchlight. For your own part, a moment of concentration suffices to wrap the flickering shadows around you like a cloak, and you feel reinvigorated as Ulgu flows over and through you. "You're sure you don't want help? Substance of Shadow, or even Shadowcloak-" "You've got your tricks, I've got mine," Johann says as the door to the occupied Citadel closes behind you. "And yours would disrupt mine." "Suit yourself." The two of you continue in silence through the darkness, lit only by the tiny flicker of golden light Johann holds in his gloved hand. "If Substance of Shadow makes you incorporeal, do you still need to breathe?" "Selectively incorporeal," you reply in a low voice. Whispers travel further than you'd think. "You quickly learn to retain your ability to interact with the air." "Interesting," is the only reply, and you narrow your eyes at him in the darkness, wondering what he's getting at. As you approach the Clan Mors guard post you previously noted, he falls obligingly silent and snuffs out his light. There's some sort of illumination peeking out from a side-passage, which just about allows normal eyes to see the silhouettes of the Skaven guard post. Your more robust Magesight sees not just them, but also terror and confusion running riot through each of them, and the noxious glow of warpstone in three long gun barrels and the terrible rotating mechanism known as a ratling gun. A few gestures has Substance of Shadow taking you into its familiar embrace, but Johann has declined your offer of the same safety. What plan did he have- He's running. He's running at the Skaven. There's a cry of alarm and the fear and confusion intensifies as he jumps the barricade to land on top of the rat that just cried out, punching it senseless with his gloved knuckles. A second rat swings a sword and you're sure this is going to be the extremely stupid death of an extremely stupid wizard, but instead of the now-familiar sound of metal sinking into flesh there's a solid clang of metal on metal. Johann turns and punches that confused rat with an impact that echoes through the tunnels, and a third swings a halberd only for the silver balls orbiting around him to mass up to deflect the blow, then three break from formation to punch into and through the attacker like bullets. Some of the Skaven are already running when a Fangleader emerges from the side tunnel to investigate the commotion, and he levels a warplock pistol and pulls the trigger, and all he gets for his trouble is a click. Then Johann is on him, and with a clanging that echoes through the tunnels his fist batters at the iron chestplate until the Fangleader coughs blood and collapses. "Right!" says Johann, sounding quite pleased with himself. He looks around the guard post, picks up, examines, and then discards a jezzail, and gathers the enormous bulk of the ratling gun in his arms. "Not a bad day's work, this," he says brightly to you. "Anything you wanted?" [Looting spree: Intrigue, 40+19+20(Ranald's Gift)=79.] [Information? Intrigue, 84+19+7(Library: Skaven)=110.] [Sabotage? Intrigue, 40+19+20(Ranald's Gift)=79.] As a matter of fact, there was. A series of similar trips net you a good half-dozen jezzails that each pass whatever inspection Chamon allows Johann to give and a warplock pistol. Carefully tucked away in a lead box you accumulate a pouchful of warpstone-impregnated bullets, warpstone-enhanced gunpowder, and the warpstone tokens they use as currency and that are apparently eaten by Skaven magicians for a quick boost, and in a second slightly thicker and carefully watertight box you set aside a strange throwing star that seems to be constantly coated with some sort of warpstone poison, no matter how many times you wipe it off - apparently a trophy of some sort, as it was displayed on a wall in a bunkhouse next to one of the guard posts. You manage to find the likely source of that throwing star soon after, as while you were waiting for Johann to return from dropping off some more acquisitions, you spend a good fifteen minutes staring at a guardpost on the Karag Yar side of Clan Mors territory, trying to figure out what about it has you feeling like something was seriously off. Then you shifted to prevent an oncoming cramp and the Skaven who had crawled right up beside you screamed in shock and you screamed back and both of you scrabbled away from each other on all fours. A long, hideously embarrassed silence later as the guards call suspiciously out at the darkness later, a voice speaking surprisingly good Reikspiel calls out. "I pretend that didn't happen and too-too-quiet man-thing does same, yes?" "Deal," you finally respond, staring into the darkness and trying to figure out why your Magesight insists there's nothing out there. "Good-good. Man-things never so quiet. You have skill. Have good hunt of the Traitor Clan. May I kill you last." A skittering in the darkness is your only indication that whatever it was has retreated, and you exhale and try to convince your heart to stop beating so damn fast. The Grey College taught you to never take the best vantage point, because everyone else would; take the second-best instead. It seems Clan Eshin teaches the same. --- In the end you and Johann spread a fair bit of havoc amongst the Skaven, and if they were at all inclined to a retaliatory raid against the We your regular punishment doled out to their patrols prevented it. Fighting alongside Johann, you quickly learn the secret of his straightforward approach to combat as he has to replace outfit after outfit as his clothes suffer from what his skin shrugs off: from the neck down, his entire body is gold. "Got the arms done while I was in Altdorf," he tells you in between raids. "Last outside part I had left, except for the head, which, yeah. 'Don't gild your head until you can take on arbitrary amounts of hungry peasants' is what they say. And wow did Dwarf gold make it easier - and I'm beginning to like Dwarves, because human rulers would get sniffy if you want their goodwill payable in precious metals but King Belegar was perfectly fine with it, gave me an absurd amount of silver and a letter of introduction to the Barak Varr mint." The Johann that kept secrets was a pain, but you think you could get to like the Johann that punches rats. [Opportunity uncovered? Intrigue, 51+19+7(Library:Skaven): 77.] [Rolling...] You put the cherry on the top of your expeditions as you stumble across the coordination point of all the guard posts on the Citadel side of the Clan Mors outskirts, which you've yet to visit any chaos upon because they're too far from the fighting to have interesting weapons but not important enough to be worth the effort of killing. This time, however, there's very much an exception: a Chieftain, those two steps down from the very top of the Skaven military hierarchy. You don't speak Queekish, but some things are universal and a desperate underling trying desperately to justify his failures while punishment is kept temporarily at bay only because the authority figure likes the sound of their voice so much is one of them. That the Skaven don't feel the need to illuminate most of their territory makes this trivial, and the underling's stammered excuses are cut off as he watches the knife on the Chieftain's belt seemingly rise up of its own accord and bury itself in said Chieftain's chest. Silence reigns for a handful of seconds, and just as you're out the door and away the Chieftain finally slumps over and the clatter of armour alerts the Stormvermin standing guard nearby. They reach the obvious conclusion and deliver quick but misguided justice to the underling, neatly removing a rung of the local hierarchy without them realizing the magnitude of the problem that their newest neighbours are capable of being. --- In the hours snatched away from adventure and responsibility, with Wolf curled up resolutely at your feet to anchor you to the life you know instead of the life of a long-dead Sylvanian Baron, your reading of the Liber Mortis continues. He speaks at length about a foreign Prince named Vladimir, who you recognize almost at once as the vampire who would eventually take the name Vlad von Carstein. To your surprise, Frederick suspected his nature almost as quickly as you did, reading along in the present with almost fifteen centuries of hindsight. But Frederick's response was of curiosity rather than horror, and you have to remind yourself that this was before the name Von Carstein even existed. To the Empire of Frederick's time, vampires were not a persistent existential threat. They were, what? An obscure navigational concern on the Lustrian coast? A historical ruler of a multispecies society who managed to carve a civilization out of the Badlands for a time? A historical footnote in Nehekharan civil wars, no better or worse than all the other variety of strange undead? Perhaps most pertinent of all: they were immune to the Black Plague. Frederick had tended to the dead and dying all but alone, as those few souls brave enough to stand by him died doing so early on. Vladimir was the only constant face in the worst time of Frederick's life, providing conversation and companionship where he otherwise would have none. And when the ratmen came pouring up from underground, sweeping across Sylvania and slaughtering the survivors of the Plague so they could gather up the malignant green rocks that fell from the sky, and Vladimir offered a solution... of course Frederick wondered what Vladimir's intentions were. But he also recognized that what Vladimir was offering was the only way that Sylvania and its surviving people could continue to exist. Vladimir didn't just offer a book to Frederick, but remained at his side and walked him past every one of a thousand traps and triggers that it contained and helped him parse the few diamonds of wisdom hidden in a sea of knives. Frederick seemed to have no more talent with magic than most, but what little he did have he cultivated to handle Shyish, which had been his constant companion since the Plague first arrived in Sylvania. And when that tiny ember of potential grew to its full potential, which was barely that of a smouldering slow-match, he took it and pressed it to the readily-available gunpowder of Dhar. And instead of sacrificing himself to put the dead to rest, he pressed them into service to protect the living. You're not entirely sure you wouldn't have done the same. [Learned skill: Dhar manipulation.] [Learned skill: Von Carstein lore.] --- You've fulfilled the task that King Belegar gave you and then some: the We not only have an artifact that allows one to communicate verbally, but additionally all of them understand spoken Reikspiel and can write in written, with chalk clutched in their pedipalps or in a pinch, a leg scrawling in the dirt. The only remaining question is how they'll be worked into the strange community they've become a peripheral part of. Will they be left to take care of their own affairs and dealt with by the Diplomat, Prince Kazrik? Will they liaise with the Citadel guards and thus fall under the purview of Dreng? Or should you remain the point of contact for these strange neighbours? [ ] [SPIDER] They are foreign allies and thus the responsibility of Prince Kazrik. [ ] [SPIDER] They are military assets and thus the responsibility of Dreng. [ ] [SPIDER] They are the very definition of 'miscellaneous weirdness' and thus the responsibility of the Court Wizard. [ ] [SPIDER] No recommendation. Being the point of contact for the We will open up a new category of interactions, but will not cost actions unless actions are spent on them. This largely decides whether anything We-related is your problem or someone else's. You also had a strange encounter with Kragg the other day, who had singemarks through his beard and seemed uncharacteristically energized. He prodded you to go into the Eastern Valley and had you spar with one of the more skilled of the Undumgi as he watched, then he asked if you wanted to 'hit hard, hit fast, or hit when they're not looking'. As soon as you answered he departed again, at a remarkable turn of speed for his age. [ ] [KRAGG] Hit Hard [ ] [KRAGG] Hit Fast [ ] [KRAGG] Hit When They're Not Looking Then there's the matter of your newly-constructed tower. There are bigger towers and there are better towers but if you count from ground level, it might be that there exists no taller tower in the world. But as pleasing as the view is, you've still got to decide the purpose this tower will be put to. [ ] Tower of Dawn and Dusk - with ritual and material and expert consultation, make your Tower like a tuning fork for Ulgu. Bonus to enchantment, rituals, spell learning, spell making, and power stone creation within the tower. 250gc, 5 College favours. [ ] Tower of Utter Neutrality - with rune and material and a great deal of care, make your Tower completely magically neutral. Large bonus to studying anything magical, small bonus to studying everything else from higher Magesight contrast. 250gc, 5 Dwarf favours. [ ] Tower of Oh Dear - with a series of very prominent buttons easily accessible from anywhere in the room, be able to drain all magical energies in three heartbeats. Near-complete immunity to miscasts and any other conceivable magical threat. 200gc, 3 College favours, 3 Dwarf favours. [ ] Tower of Serenity - Perfect temperature, perfect level of background noise, perfect conditions to get those bloody papers written. Or for someone else to do it for you. It even has a rune to keep your drink warm. Every turn, writing or dictating 1 paper costs no actions. 300gc, 3 College favours, 1 Dwarf favour. [ ] Tower of the Burning Shadow - to your sorrow, Burning Shadows cannot be cast on a mountain. To your delight, there's a way around that. There may not be a practical purpose to this, but deep in your soul you know you want to turn the entire shadow of Karag Nar into acid. 150gc, 4 College favours. If there's some other purpose you had in mind for a tower, please request it. Future towers can be built, and extra levels can be added to this tower. Please keep your towers thematically consistent. [ ] [LIBRARY] No purchase. [ ] [LIBRARY] Write-in. [ ] [RUNE] No purchase. [ ] [RUNE] Write-in. [ ] [ENCHANTMENT] No purchase. [ ] [ENCHANTMENT] Write-in. [ ] [SHOPPING] No purchase. [ ] [SHOPPING] Write-in. - Kragg is occupied but Thorek is around, so if you don't mind it not coming from Kragg you can commission another runic item. - Four hour moratorium on library/rune/enchantment votes. - The 'shopping' category is for any other miscellaneous whatevers you want to get Mathilde's hands on; the request that prompted it was for firearms.

Turn 21 - 2480 - Old Friends

Spoiler: Voting results [*] [SPIDER] They are foreign allies and thus the responsibility of Prince Kazrik. [*] [KRAGG] Hit Hard [*] Tower of Utter Neutrality - with rune and material and a great deal of care, make your Tower completely magically neutral. Large bonus to studying anything magical, small bonus to studying everything else from higher Magesight contrast. 250gc, 5 Dwarf favours. [*] [RUNE] No purchase. [*] [ENCHANTMENT] Grounding Rod [*] [LIBRARY] Snakes And Swords [*] [SHOPPING] A Marksdwarf Pistol. Sword Training Imperial Greatswording - Extensive/Esoteric Imperial -250g Bretonnian Greatswording - Extensive Bretonnian - 100g Snake Juice Aethyr - Extensive/Antiquarian Imperial - 200g and 2 College Favor The Warp - Extensive Imperial - 100g Romance Romance Novels, Varied - 50g Karag Nar is, by Dwarven standards, not the most beautiful of mountains. If it stood alone perhaps it would be held in higher esteem, but among the Eight Peaks it was left fighting for fifth place. The towering might of Karag Zilfin, the majesty of Karag Lhune, the Silver Tarn of Karagril, the understated beauty of Kvinn-Wyr... how could Karag Nar compete? Perhaps that's why the Dwarves didn't object to you changing the silhouette of Karag Nar by installing a tower atop it, but to you it's shot Karag Nar up to number one. It has a Wizard's Tower. Your Wizard's Tower. While the creation of a tower atop a mountain itself is no mean feat, creating it to suit your needs is so much more so. Between their distrust for loose magic and their affinity for stone and metal, the ability of the Dwarves to shut all magic out of a particular location was far beyond that of the Empire. The College approach would be iron or lead, and in extreme circumstances a Gold Wizard to forcefully negate magical energies with Chamon. If that proved insufficient, the deep vaults underneath the largest Temples of Sigmar were the last resort, carved into natural stone and guarded by fanatics. The oldest Dwarfholds predate the first arrival of Chaos in the world, and their Ancestor Gods are why they survived. Grungni taught them to delve deep tunnels under the strongest mountains, Valaya taught the Runes that would repel the terrible energies, and Grimnir led them in battle against the demons that sought to destroy what the ephemeral energies of the Warp could not reach. Even after so much of the knowledge of their Ancestor Gods had been lost, they remained more than able to design and build a tower proof against the eddies of the Winds of Magic. Their first recommendation is a few hundred feet of natural stone, but failing that, there are ways and means. Limestone for the exterior, which gave the tower a pleasing greyish-white colour; but limestone remembers that it is the compressed skeletons of long-dead shellfish and corals, and thus has an affinity for Shyish. Beneath that, a thick layer of granite, which not only bears the weight of the tower but also remembers the heat of the volcano that birthed it, so is prone to absorbing Aqshy. And the innermost layer is marble - imported from Tilea and painfully expensive, but marble's long partnership with the human arts has given it a faint affinity for Azyr. Three layers of stone, each only permeable by one wind. Any human Wizard would deem this sufficient, but between the granite and marble, cut so thinly as to be transparent, a tiny layer of meteoric graphite, crystallized by the temperature and impact of its introduction to the world. It remembers the void between the stars where Chaos does not reign, and thus rejects the winds. And this is merely a good start for Dwarven runecraft to build upon. With Kragg occupied, it seemed best to approach Thorek about the magic-dampening runes, but just in case you send word through the Longbeard who bears the responsibility of ferrying food and ale to the workshop he has shut himself in. To your surprise Kragg emerges, blinking in the light and scowling, and after he climbs Karag Nar he glares at length at the tower as if it personally offended him. "It will have to do," is all he says, and every night he emerges again and frowns up at the sky. When Morrsleib is judged to be sufficiently waning, he clambers up temporary wooden gantries built sturdier than some cathedrals and carves a single massive rune so deep into the limestone that it penetrates into the granite, and in its place, drop by molten drop, gromril is introduced. Not the pure gromril that characterizes the greatest of runes and the mightiest of Anvils, but a touch of gromril, a little gold, and a lot of lead, mixed together in a clay imported from Cathay called kaolin. This was not to be a delicate and beautiful masterpiece; this was an oversized bastard of a rune that needed to be tough enough to weather every extreme the world regularly threw at mountain peaks. You missed some sleep to watch as much of the process as you could, as normally runecraft of this calibre would be sealed away in workshops far from prying eyes. As far as you could tell, the entire process was a matter of incredibly intricate chiselwork and very carefully measured angles and setting up a temporary forge on the bare rock of the mountaintop to keep the bizarre alloy hot enough. And as far as you could tell, absolutely nothing magical was happening, right up until the very last night. With the sturdy but replaceable hammer he was using instead of his usual one - even when you're as careful as Kragg, you don't carry a tool up the side of a tower unless you're okay with dropping it - he carefully massaged the last drop of cooling metal into place, and leaned back against the ropes of his harness, giving a single, satisfied nod. And in the space of a heartbeat, the entire tower changed. To mundane eyes, nothing at all had happened, but between one instant and another the tower went from a mundane assemblage of different materials with varying amounts of background Winds, to a single unified object. You'd call it a magical object, except if anything it's the opposite, as the background magic that had clung to it puffs out in every direction, gently but firmly repelled. You'd hoped to find some answers about the nature of runic magic, but instead Kragg had only given you more questions. --- The work inside had largely been the work of a small swarm of Thorek's apprentices, who had thought themselves well accustomed to a harsh taskmaster but found their perspective suddenly and dramatically corrected by Kragg's eternally unsatisfied supervision. Instead of a single almighty rune, dozens ran through different parts of the Tower in something that could only be described as runic plumbing. The easy solution would be to make the floor slightly sloped, but Dwarves didn't believe in easy solutions for what was to be a Master's workshop, and instead of mere gravity a series of magic-repelling runes lined the top and bottom of each wall, propelling any loose magic towards a central drain where more runes would draw it downwards. Regular energies would be whisked away to be used elsewhere or discharged if unneeded, and any that weren't the eight Winds would be ejected outside into the open air. Not an ideal solution, but Dhar blew in from the Poles every day, and if you produced enough Dhar in this room that even the slightest of effects could result, you were doing something seriously wrong. The finished interior of the room was rather disorienting at first, with marble floors and walls and ceiling, and the effect gave you a strange sense of vertigo - the Magesight equivalent of the ringing in one's ears when there was no actual noise to be heard. A gesture and a flick of your hand scattered wisps of Ulgu, and they drifted downwards to the floor and then were blown inexorably towards the central drain to be whisked away. Perfect. Unfortunately, this latest work cannot be fulfilled by the timber of the Ulrikadrin. You make a trip to Barak Varr, and after a perusal of their weapon selection and an addition of a second pistol to your arsenal - this time one with custom bullets and spiral grooves down the barrel, the most accurate a one-handed weapon could possibly be without magical intervention - you make your way to the warehouses. Here, timber is left to age until suitable for use in ships - not Dwarven ships, but of the foreign ships that dock there and would be willing to pay to purchase appropriate materials for maintenance and repairs. The side-effect of that ageing was that the energies of the wood had faded over time, becoming magically inert instead of still showing the Ghyran of peaceful woods or the Ghur of wild forest. Working the wood introduced another snag, since even though the Dwarves were more than skilled enough at joinery that nails weren't necessarily needed, they still used metal to work the wood and more time had to pass for the Chamon to fade from the wood. That gave you all the furniture that would be needed. There was a glow-rune in each wall providing unnervingly even light, so no need for flames and their Aqshy. Tools were trickier - metal meant Chamon and your enchantment cantrips would introduce Ulgu, so you'll have to make do as best you can with glass and stone. Finally the work is done, and the only magically active items the room will ever see are yourself and the mysteries you aim to unravel. Compared to that, your other addition to your magical arsenal seems almost inadequate: the closest thing the Empire had to a mass-produced magical item, the humble earthing rod, or grounding rod to the Golds. Some prefer iron, others swear by rowan, and bone always has a few morbid fans. The more ostentatious gravitate towards jade and gold. But for you, simple, humble copper - light enough to keep on you, will bend rather than break if you fall on it, and just sturdy enough for use as a cudgel in the direst of circumstances. It would be overstating things to call it a product of enchantment, for it possesses no actual magic of its own, just an array of carefully-carved runes to make it even more conductive to magical energies than it naturally is. If you fumble a syllable or cramp on a gesture and a spell is about to become a snarl of chaotic energies located inconveniently within your torso, thrusting the rod into rock or soil was slightly better than using bare flesh and more reliable than prayer. Particularly nasty miscasts were prone to melting the runes, but grounding rods were easier to replace than torsos. --- Six months prior, the Council's reporting was done on the march, and you'd assumed that would be the norm. Today it's taking place in a room off the Hall of the Moon, where the previous meeting was held. Nobody else seems to be showing any sign of surprise. Is this normal for Dwarven Councils, that they just go with wherever the King convenes it? You could ask, but you haven't cultivated an image of Grey Wizard smugness just to implode it by showing ignorance of cultural minutiae. Instead of the plain wooden table that stood in the room previously, there's an enormous slab of pockmarked stone, the actual pockmarks filled in with some sort of clear resin so the surface of the table remains flat. After a moment you recognize it - a section of the original ceiling of the Hall of the Moon, which once showed the constellations of the night sky in a pattern of shimmering jewels, long since vandalized and looted by the greenskins. This close, you can see the scratches where claws or weapons had been jabbed upwards to pry the precious stones free. The restored hall outside the room might be looking to the future, but this table showed Belegar had no intention of forgetting the past, either. "Right," Belegar says as he takes his seat at the head of the table. "Only the Engineering Bay is appropriate for a good eyeballing, so we'll not do the usual circuit." Okay, so the walking is the norm. Mental note: added. "Speaking of, go ahead." He gives the nod to Prince Gotri, who glances down at his notepad before placing it on the table and leaning forward. "Right, so, I know I was the one that brought up the elevator thing-" "Here we go," Dreng mutters. "-but that doesn't mean there's a word for the whole debacle that isn't shoddy." He earns your glare for that, and he quails and mutters something apologetic - the Khazalid word for 'shoddy' also means 'man-made', and politeness would dictate he finds another way to express his displeasure. Dreng takes full advantage of the opening. "If you'd prefer I let the fungus bloom until it had replaced every greenskin killed in the Battle of Karag Lhune-" "I'd prefer that you didn't start a fire underground like-" "Enough!" Belegar interrupted. It wasn't quite a yell, but it definitely made it clear that yelling was an option. "Gotri. Factual report." "The fungus in the elevator shaft was, and as of half an hour ago, is aflame. I don't know where it's drawing air from, but it's turned the entire Karag into a chimney and my hangars are the opening." Belegar's eyes turned to Dreng. "And you?" "With the spiders gone, we're moving everyone in. We're moving women in. I tried having the fungus examined but some of it is razor-sharp and when we hauled the Loremaster back in he only had one rope still intact. It couldn't be left unchecked." "A sound motive, but you're no longer a Ranger. You don't take the best solution you can at the time, you communicate and use all resources at hand." Dreng's face twitched as a grimace was suppressed. "As you say, your Majesty." "Prince Gotri, I take it this means the Engineering Bay remains incomplete?" "We've got all the tools and materials on hand, but even when the smoke looks clear it'll have a Dwarf hearing colours and seeing sounds." "Dreng, how'd your acquisitions go?" "Karak Izor is building up too - with the amount of their population that came here, they want those that remain to punch as hard as possible. But the Hornhold came through for us - with Prince Ulthar's best wishes, just over fourteen hundred handguns." "Prince," says Belegar. There's a question in his tone, but he doesn't elaborate. Dreng pauses, searching for words. "Karak Hirn is in good spirits. Unified." "Ah." There's none so tight-lipped as Dwarves when there's scandal in the air. "I assume you've distributed them as needed?" A nod. "See to the fire. There should be a ventilation cross-shaft near the top, if you can get that open it should draw the smoke. Failing that-" he pauses, thinking. "How is the Underway guard?" "Well-stocked and uneventful," Dreng says, unsure. "No, how far is it?" "A third of the way to Karagril, right up against Kvinn-Wyr, all the way to Karak Azul." "Scouted?" "No tunnels bigger than my fist." "Send a team of miners to see if they can trace back the air current. The Underway of my ancestors shouldn't be able to draw that much air, see where it's coming from. Let the fire burn itself out, and the moment it's out, any Dwarf of yours that knows a spanner from a spaniel, second them to Prince Gotri." "Aye, your Majesty." "Prince Kazrik, Princess Edda. How fare the Ulricans?" They exchange glances, both seeing if the other is going to speak first, and as their gaze meets they look away again. The Princess sees your curious look as she searches for something else to look at and flinches away, failing her attempts to fight a blush as she realizes you were watching. "They're digging Clanholds," Prince Kazrik reports happily. "Well, not literally, they're building them out of trees. But they've been doing wonderful business with those trees and the first harvest has done well." "Speaking of- no, first, tell me of business with the Ulricans," he says to the Princess, who's just managed to regain her composure. "As Prince Kazrik said, their lumberyard is doing splendidly and they were more than happy to build on that profit with wagons." Prince Kazrik, you note. His proper title, but she couldn't help but emphasize it, in that 'look how completely formal my relationship with this person is' way. "They also agreed to take care of the stables on their end, and are importing," she glances down at her notes, "an 'Averland Longhorn' to help with that?" "A type of cow," you say. "Tough, intelligent. Good for milk and for pulling carts." She scrunches up her face. "Milk comes from goats. Anyway, we're completely off Barak Varr wagons now, and they're bringing it up the Blood River and unloading it at the Ulrikadrin docks." "Grand. And our harvest?" Princess Edda shuffles her papers. "The Halflings didn't have a full four seasons, but the Tilean grains thrived and that's the main thing - as long as we're self-sufficient for bread we can import fruits and vegetables. We're also set up to plant our own grains on the slopes between Karag Lhune and Karag Nar, that the Halflings say are too steep for them." "Right. Prince Kazrik, head to the Hornhold and send my warmest regards, and keep an ear out. Have a quiet word with me before you go - there's some business that may not have reached Karak Azul. Princess Edda, head to Barak Varr and sound them out on the topic of buying their monitors. I want guns afloat between Ulrikadrin and Iron Rock, and if our supplies are moving on our own ships, it should slow the bleed of goodwill. Gunnars, how goes construction?" "Completed," he says, the word thick with satisfaction. King Belegar raises an eyebrow. "You said two years." "I did, and it would have been if it weren't for Master Mathilde. She's familiar with the Empire's Morr, and helped me put the human dead to rest in a timely fashion. All those who fell in the Expedition are now safely at rest." "Of course you would be - the Sylvania business. If I give you my thanks any more often it'd save time to just leave them in your care permanently. Gunnars, see to the Temple of Grungni. Karak Azul may be able to supply expertise. If the desecration the greenskins performed cannot be reversed, find how best to seal it and we'll need to build a new one elsewhere. Master Mathilde, how's the business with the spiders?" "They've settled in nicely in the Hall of Pillared Iron. The circlet from the Amber College allows whichever is wearing it to speak Reikspiel, and they've also learned to understand it without the circlet and have learned to write in it, too." "You're sure they won't be any trouble?" "They know Dwarves don't make for an easy meal. If we run out of Skaven and greenskins we'll have to revisit the issue, but until then they're delighted to be able to establish a long-term home behind our defences. As allies go, they're pretty low-maintenance." "Ally," King Belegar says, still trying to wrap his mind around it. "Prince Kazrik, how's your Reikspiel?" "Well, I learned some as a beardling, but..." "Dreng, you're point of contact for... our new allies. Keep an eye on them, but as long as they're keeping themselves fed at the expense of our enemies I've got no problem with letting them. Master Mathilde, any luck locating the former commander?" "No," you admit. "He seems to have been using a false name." King Belegar frowns. "Why?" You shrug. "Sylvanians who leave Sylvania often leave family behind. If he enlisted with the Empire, he might have used a false name to protect them." Perhaps not the most likely possibility, but most of the answers wouldn't sit well with the Dwarves. "Alright then, needs must. You've still got contacts among Stirland's rulers?" What? "Some," you say cautiously. "Visit them. I need one to come down here and accept a commemoration on behalf of the Stirlandians that joined the Expedition. I've asked those Gorzhufokri to pass word to their Knight friends. Three Knightly Orders, the Ulricans, the Undumgi, the Stirlandians, the Halflings, and yourself. Eight blades for Eight Peaks." "Yes, your Majesty," you say automatically, your mind whirring as you try to decide how you'll tackle it. "I want the entire Old World to hear that drawing blood for my Karak is well rewarded. News travels damn slow among the manlings and I want to give it a kick. Oh, speaking of..." He sorts through the papers in front of him. "Letters of introduction from your Colleges. Arrived well in advance because they accounted for manling travel times but it went by gyrocopter from Barak Varr." He slides them over the table to you and you pick them up and flip through them. Amethyst, fine. Bright, probably fine. Celestial. Blast. "Needless to say, they fall under your jurisdiction. The Journeymanlings running around currently haven't been a problem, and I'd like that trend to continue. Any other business?" You look up from the letters. "Eshin," you say simply. There's a chorus of Khazalid expletives. "Where?" King Belegar asks with a sigh. "Under, or possibly in, Karag Yar. Uncorroborated intelligence from a single source," and if they took that to mean interrogation rather than you and an assassin accidentally terrifying each other, that's on them, "but it seems Mors' ambition finally took them too far and they're on the outs. That's probably why there's three other Clans here - they're scrabbling for the credit in wiping out the traitor, and to take some of Mors' tunnels for their own." "Explains why there's been no push-back from the Skaven - they're focused on internal matters. Right, that changes matters. Dreng, Prince Gotri, we're not nearly as established as I'd like but if the rats are occupied I want to move before they're not. Start winding up. This time next year, I want us ready to march on Karagril." --- The Colleges all have their own customs, but on some matters there's consensus and formal letters of introduction to foreign leaders is one of them, and each is bland as it is lacking in information. Journeywoman Adela Burgstaller of the Bright Order, Journeyman Hubert Denzel of the Celestial Order, Journeywoman Gretel Maurer of the Amethyst Order. Each claimed to be in good standing. All genuine, too. You don't trust the seal on the envelopes, but you do trust the tiny little indications that nobody under the rank of Magister is supposed to know about and the ones that should be present are and the ones that shouldn't, aren't. Well, well. More underlings. That should be interesting. And probably less emotionally fraught than Stirland could be. Mandatory Actions: Pick one from each category. Journeyman Maximilian de Gaynesford, Gold Wizard [ ] Allow him to spend all his time on his metalworking studies. [ ] Have Maximilian learn a skill: specify what from who. You may pay for a trainer. [ ] Have Maximilian learn a spell: specify which. [ ] Have Maximilian study your Skaven firearms. [ ] Have Maximilian study your Eshin throwing star. [ ] Current Task: Have Maximilian help the new Journeymanlings get settled in. [ ] Previous Task: Have Maximilian perform or assist with spider autopsies. [ ] Previous Task: Have Maximilian investigate the properties of the spiders' webs. [ ] Have Maximilian attempt to write a paper (choose which from 'Publish or Perish') [ ] Have Maximilian write papers on subjects you dictate. Magister Johann, Gold Wizard [ ] Allow Johann to spend all his time investigating Clan Moulder. [ ] Allow Johann to spend all his time investigating Clan Mors. [ ] Allow Johann to spend all his time investigating Clan Skryre. [ ] Allow Johann to spend all his time investigating Clan Eshin. [ ] Allow Johann to study the Ratling Gun. [ ] Have Johann study your Skaven firearms. [ ] Have Johann study your Eshin throwing star. [ ] Current Task: Have Johann help the new Journeymanlings get settled in. [ ] Have Johann learn a skill: specify what from who. You may pay for a trainer. [ ] Have Johann learn a spell: specify which. [ ] Previous Task: Have Johann perform or assist with spider autopsies. [ ] Previous Task: Have Johann investigate the properties of the spiders' webs. [ ] Have Johann attempt to write a paper (choose which from 'Publish or Perish') The Eastern Imperial Company Your outstanding debt: 1,100 gc Your share of EIC profits: 100 gc / turn Current Focus of the EIC: Handgun Factory in Blutdorf (Grand Opening in 18 months) [ ] Call in 1 favour for Dwarven expertise for the Factory's safety. [ ] Call in 2 favours for Dwarven expertise for the Factory's efficiency. [ ] Call in 4 favours for Dwarven expertise for the quality of the products. [ ] Call in 10 favours for all of the above. [ ] Establish an outpost of the EIC in The Moot. [ ] Establish an outpost of the EIC in Zhufbar. [ ] Establish an outpost of the EIC in Barak Varr. [ ] Strike a deal to have the EIC purchase and resell Ulrikadrin timber. [ ] Strike a deal to have the EIC supply and control the shops of Karag Nar. [ ] Instil patron deity: Ranald. [ ] Instil corporate policy: information gathering (news). [ ] Instil corporate policy: long-term financial good of the Empire. [ ] Instil corporate policy: medium-term financial good of individual Provinces. [ ] Attempt to build your own information network within the EIC. Personal Actions: choose between four and six. Any chosen beyond four will come with risks - please specify 'additional' tasks. Current Task: Summon a Stirlandian representative to accept a commemorative blade. Also, more Journeymanlings! [ ] Send a letter to Roswita. Job done. (does not cost an action) [ ] Visit Roswita in person, and travel with her or her representative back to Eight Peaks. [ ] Visit Anton in person, and travel with him back to Eight Peaks. Self-Improvement: [ ] Ask an acquaintance to train you in a skill: specify who and what. [ ] Hire a trainer to come to Eight Peaks and teach you: specify what. (costs favours for Dwarf trainers, money for human ones) [ ] Travel to the Grey College and attend lessons there. (1 College Favour per class; 100gc can be paid instead for non-magical classes) [ ] Attempt to learn a spell from College-supplied scrolls (specify which) [ ] Gain enough control of your unruly shadow to still it temporarily. [ ] Practice shooting while invisible. Karak Eight Peaks, friendly: [ ] You have set up a Shrine to Ranald. Expand it into a Temple to the Night Prowler - an underlit and disreputable pub for those who value privacy to gather. Guaranteed cloaked stranger in every corner. Costs 100gc. [ ] You have set up a Shrine to Ranald. Expand it into a Temple to the Gambler - a gambling hall with clean cards, guaranteed unloaded dice, fresh sawdust in the fighting ring, and a lottery every Festag. Costs 100gc. [ ] You have set up a Shrine to Ranald. Expand it into a Temple to the Deceiver - a pawn shop filled with strange knick-knacks, odd devices, foreign books, and a shopkeep that knows more than they should. Costs 100gc. [ ] You have set up a Shrine to Ranald. Expand it into a Temple to the Protector - a clean and respectable tavern for Undumgi to visit after they finish their patrols. Costs 100gc. [ ] Settlers, traders, and prospective wives are arriving. Start building an information network amongst them. [ ] Crime is inevitable, so it may as well be organized crime. Send word to Heideck and make sure that when an underworld emerges, it will be a Ranaldian one. This cannot be tracked back to you. [ ] Crime is inevitable, so it may as well be organized crime. Send word to Heideck to send individuals who will construct an underworld under your command. This will be concealed, but could be tracked back to you. Will be under your control; 2 organisations cost 1 action per turn. Karak Eight Peaks, hostile: [ ] Kvinn-Wyr is full of trolls. Investigate this for yourself. [ ] Travel underneath Kvinn-Wyr and investigate Karag Mhonar. [ ] Travel through the Underway into Karag Yar, to investigate Clan Eshin. [ ] You've mapped the territory of Clan Mors. Go down there and cause some havoc. [ ] You've mapped the territory of Clan Mors. Go down there and see what you can acquire. [ ] Clan Moulder are set up under Karagril. Investigate. [ ] Greenskins currently occupy Karagril. Find out what tribe they are and who rules them. [ ] Investigate underneath Karag Lhune: the Lhune Deeps and the Grand Abyss. Research: [ ] Investigate the constantly-dripping blood of the Wisdom's Asp. Current accumulation: 14 gallons. [ ] Instead of seeking the secrets of the blood, simply see if it can be weaponized in some way. [ ] You've got Ranald's Coin around your neck. Study it to see if you can gain an insight into Divine Energy. [ ] Send to the Grey College for the appropriate scrolls to learn a specific spell: specify which. [ ] Investigate how Pall of Darkness interacts with your sharpened magical senses. [ ] Investigate how the We communicates with... itself? [ ] Investigate the Skaven firearms, including the warpstone alloy bullet and the warpstone-impregnated gunpowder. [ ] Investigate the Skaven throwing star, that somehow remains constantly sticky with venom. [ ] The Second Secret of Dhar teaches how to collapse it upon itself. Practice upon local Dhar taint, and see if this works with Warpstone. [ ] Try to establish a relationship with the Cult of Verena, with the intent of offering them access to your rarer tomes in exchange for copies of some of their own. Enchantment: [ ] Enchant an item with a Relatively Simple or easier spell (specify what and which) Publish or Perish (if Max is writing papers you dictate, two of the below can be selected for a single action): [ ] Collate the information that the Army of Stirland collected during the Purge. [ ] Write a paper on the Waaagh energy and magic witnessed during the Expedition. [ ] Write a paper on your personal understanding of countering Waaagh Magic. [ ] Write a paper on the Black Orc Warboss' worship of Only Gork, and what you saw of the Rogue Idol ritual. [ ] Write a paper on Mathilde's Multidimensional Aethyric Projection. [ ] Write a paper on the physiology and venom of the We. [ ] Write a paper on the social structure of the We. Karag Nar Penthouse: each turn, you get ONE free choice in this category. Additional selections cost actions. [ ] Have a tower built atop Karag Nar: -100gc for 1 room, bonus to room's purpose. [ ] Have additional rooms excavated underneath your Penthouse: -50gc for 2 rooms. Setting up rooms for specific purposes will have to wait until new rooms are constructed or excavated. Only one construction or excavation can take place at a time, but you can do one of each. Building downwards will increase by 1 each time; second set of excavated rooms will be 3 rooms, third will be 4, and so on. Building upwards can be added upon; towers can be added on to or additional towers can be built. The distinction between the two is entirely cosmetic. Personal Relations: each turn, you get ONE free choice in this category. Additional selections cost actions. [ ] Spend time assisting with a fellow councillor's task: specify who and how. [ ] Spend time investigating a character without their knowledge: specify who. [ ] Wolf is fully grown and a Very Good Boy. Train him. (increases his intelligence, he may learn to speak Praestantia) [ ] Wolf is fully grown and very magical. Deepen your familiar bond. (may unlock a new familiar ability; risks obsession) [ ] Get in touch with Julia and find out if she'd be interested in passing on information to you. [ ] Help the new Journeymanlings get settled in and get to know them, to see if any are worth bringing into your growing Wizard workforce. [ ] ADVENTURE TIME, KIDS. Take them on a series of terrifying forays into the Underground. You know where it's safe, but they don't know that. Ranald's Coin - specify which face it will be set to [ ] The Gambler: specify an action this will apply to. A +20 bonus to up to two dice rolls resulting from a single chosen action. [ ] The Night Prowler As long as you are outside of private property and within a town or city, nobody will question your presence and nobody will be able to find you if you do not wish them to. [ ] The Deceiver: describe how this will be used. Lies you have developed beforehand will be delivered perfectly. The listener may believe you to be mistaken, but they will never believe that you are lying. Cannot be used to tell truths. [ ] The Protector When you act in a way that defends an individual or group from a danger that you did not cause, they will become aware of what you have done and will believe you acted selflessly in doing so. SECONDARY VOTE Currently, the format of the quest goes Actions/Report/Actions/Report. Would you prefer a dedicated social update for Mathilde to visit and interact with her friends and colleagues? This will change the format to Actions/Social/Report/Actions/Social/Report, so each turn will take three updates instead of two. After the Actions, you would vote on who Mathilde spent time with this turn, with an as-yet-undecided amount of winners. This will not change the action economy, nor will it increase the amount being written per day. [ ] Yes to social turn. [ ] No to social turn. - To represent her existing collection, I've bumped Mathilde's romance category up to Extensive at no additional cost. - You've technically been given a lot of leeway in how you deal with Stirland, but that doesn't necessarily mean that there won't be consequences for cheekiness. - There is a four hour voting moratorium. Technically not on the Secondary Vote, but remember if you're voting on multiple issue, all the votes need to be in the same post. - There is no wrong answer to the Secondary Vote, it is a matter of preference. Feel free to discuss it, but do not treat it like a debate. - If the Secondary Vote results in a majority saying Yes, the first turn with the new format will be Turn 22. - I'm sure that someone asked me about something and I said I'd add it as an action in the next turn but I've forgotten what it was. If that was you, please remind me. - Mechanic change: Dwarf Favour can now go negative. If it remains negative for three years, it will be paid for from your Dwarf Rep, at a rate of 2 Dwarf Rep:1 Dwarf Favour. - If a Dwarf Favour debt is about to come due, various risky methods of generating more will become available.

Turn 21 Results - 2480 - Part 1

Spoiler: Voting results [*] Plan Redshirt v2 -[*] [COIN] The Gambler -[*] [JOHANN] Current Task: Have Johann help the new Journeymanlings get settled in. -[*] [MAX] Previous Task: Have Maximilian investigate the properties of the spiders' webs. -[*] [EIC] Instil corporate policy: long-term financial good of the Empire. -[*] Visit Roswita in person, and travel with her or her representative back to Eight Peaks. -[*] Investigate the constantly-dripping blood of the Wisdom's Asp. Current accumulation: 14 gallons. --[*] Apply Coin -[*] Ask an acquaintance to train you in a skill: specify who and what. --[*] Gunnar, Greatsword Practice -[*] Travel to the Grey College and attend lessons there. (1 College Favour per class; 100gc can be paid instead for non-magical classes) --[*] Attempt to learn multiple spells. -[*] [FREE] Have a tower built atop Karag Nar: -100gc for 1 room, bonus to room's purpose. -[*] [FREE] ADVENTURE TIME, KIDS. Take them on a series of terrifying forays into the Underground. You know where it's safe, but they don't know that. [*] Yes to social turn. Seven. Years. For seven years the mystery of the liquid pouring from your box of mirrors has itched at the back of your mind. There was always some new battle to fight or skill to learn or enemy to study, and it kept being nudged off your list of priorities. Well, no more. You've cleared your calendar and you have a perfect laboratory just waiting to be used. Now you will crack the hell out of this mystery. [Preliminary Observations: Learning, 18+26+20(Tower)+20(Ranald's Coin)+4(Library: Daemons)=88.] Fact: The liquid is pouring from a box wherein a Wisdom's Asp is trapped between life and death. Ergo: The liquid is either the blood of the Wisdom's Asp, or flesh that has transformed to a liquid state when shorn from the Asp. Fact: The Wisdom's Asp is a warp entity; by some definitions this would make it daemonic, but it is not one in the sense that it is not aligned with any of the Daemonic Powers. Note: Thus this investigation does not breach Article 7, and thus is legal under Article 5. Fact: Warp entities are made of the energies of the Aethyr, that the unlearned call the Warp, that are solidified into a body by the will of said entity. Expectation: Anything severed from a warp entity will usually revert to the original state of energy. Fact: The liquid oozing forth from the Wisdom's Asp shows no sign of reverting to an energetic state. Theory: The Asp being neither entirely dead nor entirely alive prevents the full degeneration of the warp energies. Experiment: ... You pause, and frown at the vials of liquid held in the rack before you. If the Wisdom's Asp's state was responsible for the liquid remaining as a liquid, it would have to maintain some sort of link to it. There existed ways to sever links like that, but as they would be equally able to sever the link between body and soul, they were feared and restricted. Okay. Any more easily testable theories? Theory: The liquid no longer retains any influence from the Asp, and is merely acting according to its nature. Fact: The known nature of raw warp energy is to enter the world from the Chaos Wastes, and dissolve into the Eight Winds. Question: Is this entirely due to the nature of warp energy, or is part of this reaction inherent to the locations near the poles? Question: How else can warp energies cross into the physical world? Candidate: Summoning portals. Fact: Warp energies from summoning portals typically dissolve into Winds or curdle into Dhar. Candidate: Daemonic invasions. Fact: Warp energies from daemonic invasions typically dissolve into Winds or curdle into Dhar. Candidate: Morrsleib. Fact: Warp energies from Morrsleib universally curdle into Dhar. You frown again, staring at the liquid. Fact: The above candidates all involve the barrier between the physical world and the Aethyr being thin or pierced. Question: Is there any known example of warp energy entering the physical world without that barrier being thin or pierced? Your memory says no. You climb down the stairs and consult your library, which also says no. Question: How could warp energy enter the world without the barrier being thin or pierced? Fact: The Wisdom's Asp does not pierce the barrier between the physical world and the Aethyr. It moves between the two via the medium of mirrors. Are mirrors inherently magical? You're pretty sure they're not, but just to be sure you wander through the market hall until you find a merchant that lets you borrow one and stare intently at it for a while. Definitely entirely mundane. Okay, then. A property of the Asp, rather than a property of mirrors, making it the only scenario you can imagine where warp energy can enter reality with the barrier still in place. Question: Would the liquid change in nature if it was exposed to a thinning or piercing of the barrier? Experiment: Expose the liquid to the light of Morrsleib. The terrible green moon was feeling cooperative, and this experiment only required a couple of days to be carried out. The effect was rather more dramatic than you expected, and you're glad you decided to ride a significant way out into the barren mountains instead of performing the experiment within the Karak. Result: The liquid curled into Dhar. Theory: Warp energies only dissolve into Winds or curdle into Dhar when the Aethyr and the physical world were close. Under the sole influence of the physical world, warp energies instead become liquid. Fact: In conventional magical theory, there is no liquid form of magic. There is 'free' magic in the form of the Winds and Dhar, and there is solidified magic in the form of warpstone. Fact: In pre-Teclisean alchemy, the Winds were considered the fifth element, separate to Air/Earth/Water/Fire. Theory: Perhaps this model can be used to describe the phases of magic. Aether equals warp energy. Wind equals Winds. Water equals this liquid. Earth equals Dhar? Fire equals Qhaysh? Vice versa? Hmm. Fitting Qhaysh and Dhar into alchemical theory would be a crowd-pleaser among the Gold Order, but you're not sure they should count as separate elements. Fact: In conventional University of Altdorf physics, matter is said to have three stages: gas, liquid, solid. Perhaps this can be used as a metaphorical model for magic. Theory: Gas equals Winds. Liquid equals this liquid. Solid equals warpstone? Solid equals power stone? Question: Is warpstone a Dhar power stone? That was... an intriguing question, but not the topic at hand. You go back a step. You're finding yourself frowning at the liquid a lot. For all that you had resolved to finally do some experiments, you seem to be staring at it while writing notes a lot instead. So... under this model, can energy be considered a phase of matter? If it could, then warp energy could be made to fit into it as well. You consult your library, but find a major hole in the subject of conventional physics. You flip through your books on Chamon and find something called a 'periodic table', and scowl at it. Typical Gold Order, over-complicating everything. How are you meant to make your model fit that many elements? You turn to Dwarven chemistry, and though they don't answer your questions about energy, you do find some interesting information about liquids. Interesting, but surely wrong. Water boils at the temperature water boils at, right? You don't have to search long to find a thermometer, and your kettle is right there. One reading later, you descend all the way through the mountain and into the Underway, and commandeer a stove built into the Kvinn-Wyr fortifications. As bemused Dwarves warily watch you, you boil a cup of water and frown at the thermometer. Well, there you go. One new entry to your mental notes. Okay, so water boils easier at higher altitudes. The air is thinner at higher altitudes, too. Less air being around meant that the water being transformed to steam can do so more easily because it's less crowded. So... when the physical world does not dominate, there's less 'real' around and the warp energies are free to... boil into the Winds? But when there's too much 'real', then it can't boil... or perhaps it's the other way around? Warp energies directly transform to a gas but when there's too much 'real' it condenses? So... how much denser is liquid than gas? Well, as your kettle experiment showed, gas doesn't have a standard density, but you should be able to get a general estimate... Oh. You look up from the Dwarven textbook at the vials. Then you go and get much smaller vials. --- You say a little thankyou to Ranald that you did find your way into Dwarven chemistry textbooks before you got too far into experimentation. You trusted Kragg's work to contain whatever happened, but considering you'd be in there when it did, that isn't much comfort. With a much smaller sample, you resume. Experiment: Weaken the barrier between the physical world and the Aethyr. Erm. Experiment: Weaken the barrier between the physical world and the Aethyr without breaching the Articles. Candidate: Deliberate miscast. Yikes. No. Candidate: Divine intervention. ...maybe later. [Careful Experimentation: Learning, 32+26+20(Tower)+20(Ranald's Coin)+6(Library: Winds of Magic)=104.] Candidate: Extended channelling of Ulgu. Yes. With the room constantly lit from all directions and no foreign magic allowed to enter, you have only the Ulgu you carry within you to call upon. A worrying situation if going into battle, but it will suffice for the task at hand. Channelling magic to a specific point is one of the first things an Apprentice learns, but it's rarely needed after that as one does not accomplish anything by simply holding Ulgu, they shape it and project it. At least, not usually. It takes a few minutes to remember the mindset required, and you gently propel the Ulgu into your arm, then your hand, then your finger, until it glows under your Magesight as, confusingly, a dark bright grey. Magesight, you're reminded, isn't actually sight. You just interpret it that way. You grit your teeth in concentration as you push the magic past the first knuckle. You don't need a lot of magic total, you just need a lot of magical density. A tiny pinprick in reality rather than a gaping hole. It wavers as it is pushed past your second knuckle, and you redouble your focus. As the Ulgu is pushed into the very tip of your finger and fog begins to boil off it, the very small sample of the liquid starts to crawl up the vial towards it. No, not entirely - part of it is, while the rest remains very stubbornly at the bottom of the vial, furthest from your finger. The pearlescent light of the liquid shimmers, then for a fraction of a second you see it fracture- tshink And you recoil backwards as the vial shatters. You examine the sharp pain in your finger, and frown at the tiny scratch from the fragmented glass. Then your frown fades as you observe the significantly larger cloud of Ulgu orbiting your finger, and glance around the room to see Winds of all colours still spiralling through the air, beginning to slow as the undeniable runic pull begins to draw them in to be whisked away. --- Okay, so. Result: When sufficient magical concentration was reached, the liquid flash-boiled into an apparently equal amount of each Wind. Result: A portion of the Wind was attracted to magical concentration, the rest repulsed. Ulgu, or perhaps a precursor to it, was present in the liquid before phase change. Presumably each Wind is. Result: Liquid to Wind conversion results in significant amounts of Winds. Note: Keep liquid far from any reality-weakening event. Note: Keep liquid from the light of Morrsleib. ...damn your curiosity. Question: Does the light of Morrsleib instantly curdle the Winds after they are converted, or does it cause a fundamentally different conversion? [Damn Your Curiosity: Learning, 71+26+4(Library: Warpstone)=101.] A longer wait, but you can be patient. When Morrsleib's baleful light once more shines, you are ready and your Magesight keen. Result: Liquid-to-Dhar conversion was direct. At no point were the Winds present. Ergo: Multiple transformations are possible. ...oh. You probably didn't have to wait after all. Experiment: Does warpstone (in the form of Skaven 'warp tokens') cause the same transformation as Morrsleib? Result: Yes, though physical contact was required. Not currently possible to test if this would also apply to unprocessed warpstone. Summary: A concentration of a Wind can cause the liquid to transform into significant amounts of all eight Winds. The seven Winds not used for this division are scattered with significant force. Summary: An immediate use presents itself: allowing prolonged spellcasting in Winds-deficient areas. Summary: Warpstone or the light of Morrsleib can cause a different transformation into equally significant amounts of Dhar. Summary: It seems likely that other transformations could be possible. Summary: It seems very likely that Dwarven Runecraft could make very efficient use of the liquid. You bite your lip in thought as you go over your notes. You really do need to come up with a better name than 'liquid'. It could be possible to perform more experiments in the time you've put aside, but instead you're going to go make significant changes to how the liquid is being stored. --- "'The sword thing'?" Gunnars asks as he wipes sweat from his face. "I've never seen any other Dwarf with a sword." "Ah." He looks thoughtfully at the wooden sparring blade in his hand. "Do you want the short reason, or the full cultural dissection?" "Definitely the dissection." You drink deeply from a waterskin, glad you're sparring in an as-yet unused room of Karag Lhune rather than the merciless sun outside. "Dwarf culture is inherited," he says simply. "Well, all culture is, I suppose. But ours is inherited with purpose." He moves to a ready position and you copy, and the two of you begin to circle. Dwarves liked to absorb the first blow and counter, but they were also keenly aware that many enemies had a greater reach, and a skilled Dwarf could just as easily dart forward to negate that. Gunnars was definitely skilled - not quite as skilled as Sir Markus, or perhaps just not as demonstrative. Gunnars' concern was the souls of the dead, and primarily that meant his role as a Priest, rather than a member of the Order of the Guardians. But with a century, even a side-job adds up to a lot of experience. "Grungni has an axe. Valaya has an axe. Grimnir has two." He lunges forward, and you're stepping back before you notice he cut it short. Now he's outside the range of your blade, and closing could give him an opening. "And hammers?" you ask, considering your next move. "Hammers, picks, even crossbows. Tools for metalworking and mining and hunting." He steps back as you step forward, and then you jump back as he darts forward again. You measured it just right - he's back inside your reach, and you're outside his. "We have been at war for..." he pauses to think, but you don't take the bait, and he smiles. "Four thousand, four hundred, and seventy-seven years. Axes are our weapons, but our tools must also be weapons." "Cannon?" Forward, jab, step outside the swing, step inside and argh- "We both go to our Ancestors, I think," he says, rubbing his neck where your blade had impacted - or rather it had impacted his beard, which seems to have absorbed a lot of the blow. Your ribs aren't so fortunate. "Morgrim's weapon." "Engineering," you gasp. "Aye, now. This is many years of mining later. First, some said that only the stone thrower Morgrim invented was acceptable, while others pointed to Morgrim's rope and pulley that allowed for the invention of the bolt thrower. Then the damned elves and their flying beasts settled the argument, though with much grumbling. The flame cannon was next, using only techniques Morgrim invented instead of any actual components. But when the Skaven came boiling out of the ground, the flame cannon was accepted, but again, this was seen as a further step from our Ancestors. The cannon met with less resistance, though there were still those that said that bolts were good enough for Morgrim. That opened the door for the Handgun, and the argument started again, because there were those that saw Morgrim as the Ancestor God of Siege Weapons, rather than Engineering. But even orcs these days are wearing steel, so most reluctantly accept them, but still there are holdouts that stick to the crossbow alone. The gyrocopter... hard to argue with the first near-clear lines of communication in millennia, but argue they did, and still do. Drakeguns, steamships, trollhammer torpedoes, every new weapon is resisted bitterly by those that point to our Ancestors and their axes." "Still not hearing about swords," you manage, as the pain of breathing starts to fade. "Everything I just mentioned brings something new to the Hall. A sword doesn't do anything an axe can't. So there, at least, we can follow our Ancestors and their axes." "Except Gazul." "Except Gazul, and Zharrvengryn." [Teaching: Martial, 38+??=??.] [Learning: Martial, 29+20+7(Library: Greatswords)=56.] Gunnars is not the sword teacher Sir Markus was, but he has the patience and endurance of stone, and piece by careful piece you start to build a hybrid style combining the mighty swings and probing jabs of the Imperial Greatswords with the careful footwork and patient observation of the Order of the Guardians. It's not quite there yet, but it's close. He's also remarkably difficult to draw into any sort of personal conversation. He'll happily talk at length about Dwarven culture or current events or anything else, but though you've become slightly closer to him, you don't feel like you've learned any more about him as a person. [Skill increased: Advanced Greatsword (2/3)] --- Johann greeted the arriving Wizardlings, showed them to the Wizard quarters, had an account set up for them at the newly-opened EIC general store, and was generally constantly on hand to be a friendly welcoming big brother to the out-of-their-depth little darlings. In short, he was the perfect Good Magister to pave the way for your Terrifying Magister. When you decide to put your own projects aside to inflict yourself upon the Wizardlings, you had word passed through Johann that someone important wanted to meet them, and he didn't for a second hold back in inflating your reputation. The D채mmerlichtreiter. The S채ngerkritisch. The woman that cowed the nobles of Stirland into obedience, killed Castle Drakenhof, and cut a bloody swathe through the greenskins of Karak Eight Peaks. History's first and only Court Wizard to a Dwarfhold. The one and only Mathilde Weber. You're keenly aware that you don't quite have the height to properly loom, but between the greatsword, Abelhelm's hat, your unruly shadow and your growing reputation, you can still manage a striking first impression. Aww, the Bright Wizard is standing at attention. "Adela Burgstaller," you say conversationally. "What brings you to my mountains?" "Journeying, Magister!" She's definitely had some military training. Not surprising, the Brights always have been close to the army. "You could Journey anywhere from Wissenland to Ostland. Burn some Beastmen, kick over a bandit camp or two, find a roadwarden patrol or a local captain to latch onto and have a relatively comfortable time of it. Instead, you're here. Why?" You consider her as she summons an answer. Many Bright Wizards have red hair, but hers seems to be natural rather than the result of Aqshy attunement. But she hasn't fully avoided the touch of fire - her pupils are normal but appear lit from behind with the smouldering red of flames, and wisps of smoke occasionally drift out from her eye sockets. Slightly taller than you, damn her, slim, bordering on willowy, sensible black robe but with just a touch of tasteful lace trim. With that name, she's no noble, so a burgher family. "Engineering, Magister," she finally responds. "Mind your step. Dwarves are generous to their friends but brutal to thieves, and if you get caught trying to take what they don't want to give, I won't do a damn thing to save you and the Bright Order will apologize to me for my trouble. Clear?" "Yes, Magister!" "Armament?" "Aqshy, Magister!" Acceptable answer. Fire solves a lot of problems. You glance at her belt and raise an eyebrow. Not a grounding rod, that's... you'd call it a staff, but it's barely the length of your forearm. "Your work?" "Yes, Magister!" You frown at it, trying to make sense of what you're- ah. "Don't they tell you not to try that in the Bright College?" "They did, Magister." "And you did it anyway." You're only vaguely familiar with the general principles, but one of the intermittent steps to creating a power stone was gaseous. Not nearly as good as the finished product, but every now and then someone with more ambition than sense gives it their damnedest, realizes they're not quite there yet, and makes the best with what they've got. This girl has entrapped the gaseous Aqshy inside a wand. What better for channelling Aqshy than Aqshy? Hideously dangerous, but when you were at her stage, you had developed a habit of avoiding anything reflective out of necessity. You move on to the next Wizardling. The Celestial, unfortunately. "Hubert Denzel." "Yes, Madam." "I am a Knight and your name tells me you're of the peerage, but here and now we are two Wizards." You didn't actually know every noble house in the Empire by heart, you had the Grey College send all the information that the letters of introduction didn't. Unusual, though. Most Middenheim noble houses wouldn't let a scion tainted with magic continue to bear their name. "What brings a Celestial Journeyman to a Dwarven Karak?" "Glory in battle, Magister." No military training, but he's got steel in him, and steel on his hip, too. He's definitely leaning into being a Wizard - billowing cloak and a star on his hat. Some muscles on him, which must have been tough to maintain at the Celestial College. No visible signs of Azyr's touch, but it did trend towards the ephemeral. "Has Ulric given you the fangs of the wolf, then?" The information from the Grey College didn't actually cover his faith. Journeymen aren't worth watching that closely. But either he was an Ulrican and will take your question the straightforward way, or he was a non-Ulrican Middenheimer and will take your question as a barb. You find out which he is while giving the impression you always knew. "Yes, Magister. I bear His lightning." You doubted the mainstream Cult would agree with that interpretation of magic, but whatever kept him going. "Have you been trained in that blade you're wearing?" "Since my fifth winter." Ulricans. Though at least that's better than the standard Celestial twit. Last but likely not least, she of the Amethyst College, and you're glad you observed them from a distance because her appearance does tend to take one aback at first. Shyish can be cruel, and if you had to guess, Gretel Maurer had been in the coltish and gangly stage of puberty when it had visited itself on her, and the Shyish-induced withering of muscle had frozen her there and resulted in the unnerving impression that she had limbs significantly too long for her body. "May shadows guide you," you intone. "May death pass over you," she replies in an unexpectedly musical voice, and you fight back a smile. The Grey and Amethyst Colleges didn't actually have ritual greetings for each other, but Apprentices and Journeymen of both liked to pretend they did to mess with the other Colleges. ...then again, the joke had been going on for at least twenty years by now, so maybe it actually was a ritual greeting at this point. "What brings you to my mountains?" "I seek wealth," she replies plainly. Your smile widens. "Honesty is a virtue. Your weapon?" "I bear Morr's Scythe." That she doesn't summon it to demonstrate shows her good sense, and that she uses that name rather than the secular ones reveals something else. You pass an open-palmed hand in front of your face, from top to bottom, and surprise causes her to hesitate for a fraction of a second before she returns the ritual greeting. Not quite a cult secret - sticking to cover stories is important, but so is not committing an actual blasphemy - but it did imply a familiarity with Morr that you certainly had, albeit secondhand. "Fire, lightning, death," you muse. "That sounds like an arsenal to me. Let's go." "Magister?" Hubert asks. "Don't want to take you too far from what you know," you say, false kindness dripping from your tone. "So let's pretend we're back at the Colleges and go on a field trip." --- You're beginning to feel like a mother duck. Three separate magical lights bob through the air behind you from the tail of increasingly nervous Journeymen nearly clinging to your back as you lead them through the Underway. You'd taken them through the Citadel, partly because this was the clearest part of the under-Karak but mostly so you could casually say hello to a passing giant spider and get a cheery wave from its pedipalps back while your ducklings stared. "Pop quiz, class," you say with a smile. "What do you call a rat with a gun?" You get silence back, but there's silence and then there's silence. Two significant silences, one bewildered silence. Oh, Celestial College. Why must you be this way? "Two correct answers, one dead wrong. You're letting your College down, Hubert." "What? But, Magister-" "Take Beastmen, swap the livestock for rats, give them their own god, a terrifying affinity for magic and technology and magical technology, and you've got... don't tell him girls, he has to learn on his own. Okay, I'll give you a hint. The cognomen ex virtute of Emperor Mandred was..." "The Beastslayer?" Hubert asks, and you groan. "The Skavenslayer. I'll run you through this real quick so try not to let the existential terror hit you too hard. There exists under every city on every continent the network of a sprawling and more-or-less-but-mostly-less unified rat-man civilization called the Skaven. They worship the Horned Rat, who might be the-one-with-the-diseases but we're pretty sure is separate, they use warpstone to cheat at technology and give the Dwarves a run for their money, and they probably number in the billions. They've been grinding the Karaz Ankor away for four thousand years and believe me, the Karaz Ankor is not easily ground. The only reason we're not all doomed is they constantly fight amongst themselves, and in fact the reason you've never heard about them before is because them thinking we don't know about them makes them feel secure enough to fight amongst themselves even more. Any questions so far?" Except for shoes on stone, you hear nothing but silence. "Alright, let's have some class engagement. Gretel, Clan Moulder. Go." "Um. One of the four Great Clans. They use warpstone and breeding and surgery to try to make bigger and stronger creatures to fight for them." "They're under Karagril. Been selling wolf-sized rats to anyone that's buying, including Goblins. The upside is that they're between Karagril and Black Crag, so there's no concern of the greenskins in Karagril receiving reinforcements, hence why we'll be marching on it next year. Adela, Clan Skryre." "Oh, they're the technology one! They use warpstone to power guns and devices that shoot fire or lightning!" "I hear enthusiasm. If you like that sort of thing, talk to Johann and let him know you've been read into the Conspiracy of Silence. They're in Karag Zilfin. Gretel, Clan Eshin." "Assassins. They're the most loyal to the central authority of the Empire." "You forgot the obligatory 'they use warpstone to' part. It's poisons with them. They're under Karag Yar. Adela, Skryre was an easy one, so here's a tough one. Clan Mors." A pause. "They're... one of the Warlord Clans?" "Are you telling me or asking me?" "Asking." "You're right. Arguably the Warlord Clan. They're disturbingly unified for Skaven and they just about rivalled the Great Clans for power. Hubert, can you spot the most important part of that sentence?" "...past tense?" "Bingo. They've been very naughty rats and now it's open season on Clan Mors. They're underneath the centre of the Karak aaaaaand..." You've been dropping your voice gradually as you walked and you drop it all the way to a hush now. "They're right over there." Three lights snap out, and while you give their eyes a chance to adjust to the darkness you lean in to speak in Hubert's ear. "You've just been blindsided by all this. If you want to sit the practical portion of today's exercise out..." "I will show His enemies the mercy of the wolf," he says, and his voice barely quavers. "Good man." You raise your voice just enough to reach all three of your ducklings. "Once your eyes adjust, formulate and execute a plan of attack on this guard post. If everything goes to hell I'll step in, but while you're not going to die today, you might get stabbed today and it sucks, so do your best to avoid that. I do not grade on a curve. Your time begins: now." As the eyes they're reliant on adjust to the darkness, they begin to see the guard post up ahead, lit faintly by dozens of crude tallow candles. You've no stomach for needlessly tormenting an enemy when you could dispatch it instead, but getting these ducklings blooded without losing one takes priority, so you've set this one up ahead of time. For the past week, any rat at this guard post that stepped into the darkness unwittingly volunteered to help you work on your greatsword techniques. They quickly learned to avoid that, and now the rats are already on the verge of fleeing and lit up enough for your ducklings to see them, and also so their night vision is ruined so the Skaven can't see your ducklings. On top of that, their position on the far side of Clan Mors' many rivals means they're poorly armed. As the ducklings confer, you shape Ulgu and melt into the shadows, listening in on their halting and hesitant plans. "Okay, Magister," Adela says, "I think we're-" She turns and looks right at you, but of course that doesn't mean she can see you. "Oh. Um. Okay." [Adela's debut: Martial & Learning. 55+12=67 / 27+16=43.] [Hubert's debut: Martial & Learning. 65+16=81 / 39+14=53.] [Gretel's debut: Martial & Learning. 40+15=55 / 42+17=59.] It's not the worst demonstration you've ever seen, you suppose. Gretel flanks and approaches until just out of the candlelight, then with more enthusiasm than accuracy Adela and Hubert begin to pelt the Skaven position with fire and lightning. There's a moment of hesitation and cowering, but the lack of casualties emboldens them and they charge out with a shrieked battlecry, and then Hubert draws his sword, Gretel summons her scythe, Adela projects a fiery sword-blade from her wand, and you nod in approval as the three of them strike down several of the rats each and send the rest fleeing. There's a moment of silence, then the three ducklings begin to cheer, and it just about breaks your heart to interrupt them with a gunshot. Then four more. Five bullets for four of them. You should practice more. "Passing grades all around, but on future exams I'll be marking down for escapees," you say. "Any guesses as to why?" Adela answers instantly. "'Thinking we don't know about them makes them feel secure enough to fight amongst themselves even more'." ...did you just get quoted back to yourself? "Well done. Extra credit. Anyone wounded? Don't just say no, check. Adrenaline is a hell of a thing." Shockingly, none are. --- Over the next few weeks, you take the freshest Journeymanlings on several outings against greenskins and Skaven, some with Johann and one with Panoramia, who disquiets all three of them with her cheerily efficient weaponization of the rapid growth of thorned plants. They're definitely unsmelted ore, but there's good metal there. But sadly your newfound calling as a teacher cannot last forever, and you make preparations to travel to the Empire. You've got some crash-learning to do back at the Grey College, but then it's to Stirland to deal with the EIC and, of course, with Roswita Van Hal. But before that, possibly in an attempt to put it off just a little longer, you call in on Maximilian, who seems personally offended by the webs he's studying. "They get weaker when I cast Law of Form on them," he says as he notices you, outraged. "That doesn't surprise me," you say after a moment of thought. "Even small webs are tough for their size." "I guess I never realized how literal the spell is. 'As strong as steel' should mean stronger. Not a precisely defined set of material properties." "Speaking of material properties..." "Oh, right." Maximilian discards the temporarily metallic webbing with a clang and turns to his notes. [Studying Spiderweb: Learning, 31+16+20(Law of Logic)+7(Library: Arthropods)=74.] "Honestly, at first I didn't see a lot in there, but then I checked your books and not all of it's the same. I spoke to the We with the chip out of their head carapace and they got me some of each. The Hunters have two, one for dangling and one for hunting. The Web-Weavers have three, dangling, building, and glue. The Egg-Layers only have one, for wrapping the eggs. Five types total. The glue hardens nearly immediately, so that's no good to us. The building web is like scaffolding, they make the permanent structures out of dangling web, so it's out. [Dangling web: Learning, 75+16+20(Law of Logic)+2(Library: Engineering)=113.] "So, the dangling web- do you know what tensile strength is?" No, but you'll look it up later. "Yes." "That makes it easier. This is your all-rounder. Pound for pound, tensile strength of steel and even harder to break. It stretches like crazy too, which makes it even less likely to break but it does mean it's not gonna replace regular ropes - if you're using a rope to transfer mechanical force, this isn't going to do it for you. But for weight holding - for pulleys, for dragging, for mountaineering - this is huge. Walk into Marienburg with a cartload of this stuff, anyone that's ever heard the word 'crane' will throw money at you." [Hunting web: Learning, 79+16+20(Law of Logic)+2(Library: Engineering)=117.] "Next up: hunting web, for wrapping up their prey. They're supposed to be paralyzed, but either they like to keep a larder or they're ready for anything that might be immune, so this stuff doesn't break, pretty much ever. Teeth, claws, blades, doesn't matter. One word: armour. Light as normal clothing, stronger than leather. Light as cloth armour, stronger than chain." [Egg web: Learning, 64+16+20(Law of Logic)+2(Library: Engineering)=102.] "Finally, egg web. Look, the dangling web, that's a game-changer for logistics. You just doubled the throughput of every crane in the Empire. That doesn't matter. The hunting web, everyone important enough to get a blade in the ribs becomes immune to a blade in the ribs. That doesn't matter. Here. Feel." He holds out a crudely-woven patch of silk, and you touch it dubiously. It doesn't stick to your finger, so you give it a closer feel. "Soft." "It's silk. It's silk but incredibly durable. It's silk but it doesn't really burn, it just sort of melts. It's silk but it's right here. The second someone manages to teach those spiders the concept of trade, the Silk Road is here. I, it's-" He waves his arms in the air, searching for words. "Barak Varr has been bankrolling this entire Expedition and it's still doing it because it makes a tenth of the silk road safe and if it stays open for maybe three years they'll have turned a profit on it because silk is that ludicrously valuable. Look at this stuff. Silk is done. Silk is like burlap now. Anyone thinking of wearing silk after this is introduced will have mud thrown at them in the street. Those spiders are shitting gold. You take it, you go to Barak Varr, which is possibly the safest goddamn road in the Old World right now, and you've won at economics." --- You can't keep calling it 'liquid'. You should come up with a name for your discovery. [ ] Write in. How will you arrive in Wurtbad? [ ] Low-key. Casual clothes, a mundane horse, concealment spells, a quiet word with the castle staff to let everyone know you're here. [ ] Too low-key. Slip in after dark and wake Roswita up in bed. [ ] By the book. Give her notice a day in advance and present yourself openly to the court as a foreign delegate. [ ] Magically. You're the bloody D채mmerlichtreiter, and you'll damn well D채mmerlichtreit right up to her castle if you please. [ ] Too magically. Announced by an invisible orchestra as you appear from thin air before her in court. [ ] Dwarfily. Gyrocopter landing just outside the castle gates. [ ] Very Dwarfily. Gyrobomber landing in the town square, with a Hammerer protection detail. [ ] Too Dwarfily. Borrow a Throng from Zhufbar. You've got friends and acquaintances in Stirland. Do you want them to get involved in these events? [ ] Invite Anton as a personal friend. [ ] Suggest Anton suggest to Roswita that he should come along as an experienced diplomat and representative of Stirland's nobility. [ ] Do not invite Anton. [ ] Invite Wilhelmina as a personal friend. [ ] Suggest Wilhelmina suggest to Roswita that she should come along as an economic attache to build trade ties between Stirland and Karak Eight Peaks. [ ] Do not invite Wilhelmina. - Inviting people as your personal friends is entirely your business, except if they suggested to Roswita they should come officially and get rebuffed - in that case, it would be a major faux pais for them to come anyway. - I'm splitting this update into two because wow it's gotten away from me, but it works out well to give the Roswita decision some more granularity. - This is still a continuation of the same turn. Dealing with follow-up and consequences from the above is for later votes.

Turn 25: Scouring Fury (Part Five)

Spoiler: Reactors Sabatoge Times three

[X] Plan Reactors Sabatoge Times three
-[X] Battlegroup Orders
--[X] Primaris: Pursue New Objective: reactor heart Alpha
--[X] Secundus: Pursue New Objective: Reactor Heart Beta
---[X] At leadership's judgment, detach combat liabilities under escort to link back to Quartus's defensive location for recuperation
--[X] Tertium: Pursue New Objective: Reactor Heart Gamma
--[X] Quartus: Pursue New Objective: Withdraw to central location to all Reactors that is suitable for evacuation, set up defenses and dig in. Establish beach-head to allow resupply from fleet at next opportunity.

Scouring Fury
+060.M42+ To +065.M42+
+Let Your Fury Scour The Xeno Forevermore+

One more shot to the temple and the ork nob fell to the ground in a heap. Cyrus racked the slide on his rifle, and huffed another breath before leaning back into cover to avoid the incoming reprisal of wild shots. Other scouts around him did the same, more than well blooded at this point. His vox bead clicked thrice. Trajan Maphar, on the other hand, simply stomped forward into the maelstrom, outright bending slugs and rockets away from him. A snarl on his lips, he wrenched with his hand and sent greenskins flying, sparking lightning traveling between their bodies. With the crash of his staff onto the ground, a tongue of flame splashed over and through them as they tried to rise.

Instead of taking another shot, Cyrus paused as he heard the vox crackle open.

“Cyrus, do you read?”

“Affirmative, Chapter Master.”

His cybernetic eye flickered as the mapped tunnels and approaches thus far expanded back outwards. The new targets revealed made him grimace, though his attention was caught by a blinking designator separate from the reactor thermal blooms.

“Sending you a new location now, pull all your forces back and secure it. It is to be our fallback point.”

“Understood. Moving out now.”

Quartus Advance
70 vs. 40

As one, over a hundred Blood Ravens rose up and began firing. Those with more skill and ability advanced, throwing explosives and tossing forward mines at the feet of onrushing charges. Others, like Trajan Maphar and the Chaplain Augustine, found themselves as focal points of the counter assault. Through psychic power and absolute rage, they bulled through mobs, opening the way for the scouts behind them. Tunnels were collapsed behind them as they moved. They were few, at least compared to how many orks surrounded them, but they pushed through all the same. Even the wounded fought on, carried by their fellows or simply ignoring what they’d sustained through bloodied will.

=======================================

Tertium Advance
91 vs. 23

The bloody giant moved, leaving only carnage in his wake. Behind him, the galvanized Blood Ravens tore apart those who remained. His spite was infinite, shrugging off explosions and wounds that would have put other battle brothers on their backs. His crozius swept back and forth, each movement leaving vaporized gore behind. He was flanked by Andrandus and Anchises, their heavy flamers and heavy metal claws tearing apart those who attacked from the sides. Behind them came the Chaplains, the wedge expanding with the 1st Company marines, and further still. A single arrow head that shot its way into the heart of greenskin territory. Before long they could hear the thumping rattles which shook the superstructure for kilometers around.

The cavern had to have been carved out over the course of years, its internals built up slowly but feverishly in the nature of greenskin ‘engineers’. It was massive, with multiple portions seeming to have no discernable purpose whatsoever than because the orks wished them to be. Pistons pounded, electricity visibly thrummed through enormous cabling which snaked in their thousands into the rest of the station. Some, at least. Others were shorted out, broken, or otherwise destroyed. Even as Hannibal watched, entire swarms of gretchin banged on all a manner of things with ridiculously primitive tools. An enormous ork mek stood above it all, his arms shoved into the centermost component’s innards with his tools twitching and clanking about alongside him. At their intrusion into his territory, he tore away from it, leaving sparks flying and mechanical components shattering.

“Oy! You gits ain’t allowed in ‘ere!”

Upon his back, the ork’s tools reconfigured themselves into a pair of shoulder-slung rapid fire cannons.

“NOW GET OUT!”

===================================

Secundus Advance
50 vs. 7

Rivals
57 vs. 87

“Does anyone have a shot?” Marcus howled over the din of the fighting.

The reactor heart lay before them, its guardians, creators, and masters were more than incensed at their intrusion. Their advance had been faultless, save for the fact that there were now orks which were currently firing at them from the rear and sides. On the other hand, they were not aligned with those at said reactor, their garishly painted banners and emblems still wet from the freshly applied paint giving symbols to their new allegiance. At their head was an ork absolutely frothing at the mouth. He bore no armor save for a few sewn in metal plates in random places. Both hands had been replaced with chain-axes that were the size of a space marine in armor. On the other side of the Blood Ravens, the Big Mek in charge was shooting a multitude of guns including one that shot squigs at him.

“DIS REACTOR IZ OURZ NOW! WE’ZE GONNA TAKE ‘EM, RUN ‘EM, AND DIS PLACE’LL BE ALL OURS!”

The mek just snarled, chewing heavily on its giant cigar, and shifted its fire to center directly on said surgically altered ork.

“Zoggoff Ghraganap! Dis is DOOM-EATER’S reactor, not yurz!”

Ork stormboyz fired upwards and over the Blood Ravens to land amongst the orks defending the reactor, blades flashing as they began to get into the fight. A tunnel tore open and let loose another group of orks bearing Ghraganap’s emblem that crashed into the mek’s mobs from behind. As for the leader himself, he merely scratched at the bloody sides of his scarred head with the hafts of his chain-axes. Then he tilted his entire body in one direction, and then the next. A deep grin split his face to reveal most of his teeth to have been replaced with jagged shards of metal.

“Oh? I don’t hear nobody in me head no more ‘cept me, Zaptoof! Ain’t nobody hearin’ nuffin!”

Marcus turned his head back and forth and sighed.

“Captain, what should we do?” Ares called out in between lascannon blasts fired by the better equipped orks.

He stood, pointing towards another pile of wreckage with less greenskins than anywhere else nearby, ignoring the absolutely hellish amounts of weapons fire being pointed in two directions whipping past his body.

“There! Blood Ravens, with me! Let the orks at one another, we will go around!”

Lateral Shift
53 vs. 23 vs. 24

“Go! Go! Go!”

The wounded were gathered up and moved with them. Those that could still hold a bolter fired them, while those who struggled otherwise helped carry equipment with them. Cassius was last through, the dreadnought firing missiles and spitting assault cannon fire at every ork that tried to follow after. The aggression of the orks was more than sufficient to fill in the gaps. Without the inadvertent bulwark created by the battlegroup, there was nothing to keep them apart. With a gleeful roar, Ghraganap stormed forward, crunching an abandoned heavy bolter beneath his foot as he went. Both axes began whirling as he reached the other orks, laughing all the while even as he was shot at by dozens of Doom-Eater loyalists.

“I’ZE DA BOSS NOW!”

=================================

Primaris Advance
24 vs. 79

“Falkor!”

“I am working as fast as I can!”

White armor was scored and pitted, and the apothecary cried out in pain as he was badly struck in the shoulder by a rocket. It strained even his superhuman physiology to not ruin the extraction procedure. A hiss announced his success as the reductor vial retracted. With a grunt he threw himself backwards and abandoned the body just before the rockets tore it apart. More exotic ork weaponry turned the area he’d just removed himself from into a smoldering heap. There was almost nothing left behind. The rest of his vials shifted amongst each other, but the gene-seed within remained more than secure. Too many were covered with the blood of his fellow space marines. He glanced to his left to find the only living member of their battlegroup still equipped in scout armor.

“Sergeant Persean, are you wounded as well?”

He had been as unmoving as the dead, but twitched at Falkor’s words.

“No,” he murmured, barely audible over the din. “But they were my squad, and now they are dead.”

Originally, he had been of the 3rd Company. Then of the 1st. Reduced, again, back down to 10th as a guardian, instructor, and leader. Yet as Sergeant Persean stared at the smoldering embers of what had once been his squad, he felt only a cold emptiness. He rolled from cover, deathly silent, and began firing his shotgun into the face of the enemy. Breath sucked in and was pumped out rapid pace. Around him, the rest of the battlegroup huddled behind cover. The reactor lay before them, but there was nothing they could do to get closer than they already were. Not with the fatalities they’d already taken. The Chapter Master struck down another ork as it tried to leap over the ridge of bodies and scrap metal, but even he was forced to hunker back down immediately afterwards.

Rally Up
65 vs. 29

Except for Sergeant Persean.

He did not speak. He did not yell. All he did was breath and fire. When he ran out of ammo, he began to batter aside the orks with the butt of his weapon. When it was deformed by the sheer damage dealt to it, he began to use his combat knife. When that was snapped apart in an ork nob’s power klaw, he overturned the ork’s own weapon and caved its head in. Grappling with the body, he nearly tore the trigger out as he twisted its body around to fire it at the enemy with the ork as a shield. His armor buckled and tore apart, but he did not cry out when an ork flamer exploded around him. Instead he threw his burning body into the masses in front of him, catching squig-leather clothes and orkish flesh alike alight.

Distracted as they were, the orks could not have prepared themselves for the rest of the battlegroup to rise up and chase after the erstwhile veteran. A rush from behind broke their morale, even if temporarily, and sent them scattering backwards. Piles of broken machinery, bodies, and debris kept some safe from the Blood Raven reprisal, but not all of them. Least of all, from Sergeant Persean. The space marine leapt after them, hands extended, grasping and tugging rusted chunks of metal, ork knives, ork guns. The orks recoiled at the silent dervish in their midst, and pushed themselves back further, and further still until they fought amongst the still sparking coils and thrumming machinery that made up the massive reactor complex.

Causing Damage
13 vs 35 vs. 61 vs. 54

A series of explosions which tore apart a junction announced the arrival of a Big Mek with a surprisingly prodigious belly. No sooner than he had arrived than did another ork show up in an eye-searing teleportation bloom, their entire upper torso seemingly replaced with crude yet powerful pneumatics and cybernetics. Both possessed a close guard of mechanized orks, their mobs flooding out behind them and immediately opening fire on one another without hesitation. A third group, this one appearing to be an ork boss with an oversized jawbone that openly bulged free of its skin to expose itself to the open air, came roaring down from a dozen hatches in the ceiling and from upper walkways. Ludicrously, a giant missile had been haphazardly strapped to its back to allow it a primitive and dangerous equivalent to a jump pack.

“Oy! Stoppem! De’ze bustin’ up me generators!” Shouted the first of the mek’s in disturbingly earnest dismay.

“We’ll more than that, ya dumb git! This ere generator is gonna feed me babies all the juice dey need to krump all of you gits in line!” Boomed the newly teleported arrival, their makeshift helm and welding mask slamming down to protect them.

“Kaboom! Crash! Kill ‘em all! JUST KILL ‘EM! AHAAHAHA!”

As one, both Big Meks turned, even while shooting kustom shootas at one another.

“SHUT UP KRAKSKULL!”

The ork boss just scowled at them both.

“It’s Megaboss Krakskull, you gits! Now get outta ‘ere Brekabrak! Dis is my generator! Gunna blow it all up, show Doom-Eater whose boss!”

A look of absolute yet inhuman horror spread itself across the mechanically inclined greenskins.

“You idiot!” They shouted in unison, even mirroring each other’s gestures. “Iffin you blow up dis place, da strain to da ‘ol lektrical systems could overload everythin!” Then both meks turned to glare at each other. “Stop copying me!”

Howling in laughter, anger, or mere infinite belligerence, all three ork mobs began to charge at one another, all the while the Blood Ravens fired in every direction as they drove their own spear point in.

=================================

Quartus Securing
99

Cyrus sat on top of a rocky outcropping, carefully checking over his rifle for damage while a bevy of scouts surrounded him. In the distance, in every direction, gunfire could be still heard, but little of it was purposefully directed towards their appropriated hideaway. Without Doom-Eater providing near omniscient tactical direction, as well as information on any and all intruders within ‘his’ domain, the orks were far less capable at sniffing out his scouts and initiates. Well, there were the squigs, but those weren’t too hard to kill if one knew what one was doing.

“Report,” he said over his shoulder, remaining somewhat more focused on his weapon after a quick look at the soot and dirt covered faces of his subordinate brothers.

They all exchanged looks until one of the scout sergeants stepped forward and fell into attention.

“Approaches are watched, secured, and are currently kept free. Tunnels too narrow for proper use have been destroyed or otherwise removed from enemy usage.”

“Enemy alert levels?”

“Maintained at previous levels prior to our arrival. Using recordings and jury rigging them to broadcast regularly through the ork’s own systems was child’s play.”

Cyrus paused and turned to quirk an eyebrow at the word choice. The sergeant shifted uncomfortably at his Captain’s gaze but did not say or do anything more. After a moment Cyrus relieved them of his expression and turned back to his rifle.

“Very well. Maintain positions and stealth. Any orks that seem to be getting to close, continue ensuring they are attracted elsewhere by our baffles.”

He glanced over at the techmarine potentials, who had been of rather good utility in all of this. The preliminary apprenticing they’d begun doing amongst the other techmarines had turned out to be quite valuable indeed. Then he was forced to wince as a great squeal came across the vox and a horribly familiar voice echoed outwards once more. Though the speaker systems had been damaged, the obsessive nature of the greenskins had ensured that it would still produce the desired effect of its master.

“GRAGGH! YOU BEAKY GITS!” Doom-Eater roared once more, simultaneously stilling every ork still alive within the ship while causing numerous corpses to twitch as their implants sparked. “YOU FINK YOU CAN MAKE DOOM-EATER SILENT!?? NEVER! NOW ALL YOU BOYZ BETTER GET BACK IN LINE AFORE I KRUMP YOU ALL INTO THE NEXT SUN WE RUN INTO OR-,”

Reactor Assaults
73 vs. 11
78 vs. 39
81 vs. 66

And then Doom-Eater, ork and vessel both, was silent once more.

All of those within the battlegroup stiffened and held their weapons in even tighter grips as the superstructure of the entire vessel shuddered. Once. Then twice. Then a third time. Only a few moments were between each achingly powerful shudder, and after each the lights flickered on and wildly. Sparks flew from the exposed wiring and cabling throughout the hallways, floors, and ceilings. Aching groans from overstressed metal became explosions that split stone and sent some scouts to the floor. In that same moment, the overcrowded vox – nearly burdened to breaking by the orks broadcasting on all bands – became eerily silent as the very systems the orks were using went silent. Inside, lights clicked on from where they were attached to weapons and armor, providing thin flickering beams of illumination in a suddenly dark battlefield.

None could see it, of course, but in the void, the great burning engines of the Doom-Eater vessel choked, sputtered, and went dark. Energy shields sparked and tore apart, certain projectors and towers that produced individual umbrellas of protective energies overloaded or otherwise simply shut down. Guns that continued to expend ammo in amounts only an ork would consider to be right despite the lack of targets snapped apart or even exploded as overstressed electrical components exploded. Even its gargantuan maw which opened and closed endlessly, having done so since it had first entered the galactic plane, came to a scraping and jarring halt. Though its velocity was as of yet unchanged, there was no longer any guiding force behind it. Even the maneuvering rockets were dry of the energy they so desperately required.

“Well then,” Cyrus murmured with the vaguest surprise in his voice.

Tactical Withdrawals
81 vs. 80
73 vs. 28
46 vs. 6

Though the hallways and chambers of Doom-Eater were darkened, soon enough they were lit once more by the lights of thousands of guns and sparks of power weapon fields. Grenades created blooms of heat and death. Vox channels came to life as the Blood Ravens took up communications with one another once more. Reports of firefights and various tactical retreats started to flow as all battlegroups pulled away from their completed objectives and let the orks fight amongst themselves. Reactor Heart Alpha was a completely smoldering ruin, the greatest amount of the work done by the orks themselves rather than anything that the Chapter Master and his personal troops had done. Reactor Heart Beta had fallen similarly, though Captain Marcus had ensured that a number of explosives that had caused a chain reaction were personally planted. Such was his course that his battlegroup tore apart those orks who still lived after the chamber’s self-immolation, ensuring that only the Emperor’s Angels of Death were left alive there for a long time to come.

In Reactor Heart Gamma, Hannibal Palrun personally threw the Big Mek in charge of maintenance and protection into the central-most components – the heart of the heart – which slew both master and machine in a single stroke that set off rippling overloads for over two kilometers around.

All that the orks could use to track one another was the sheer violence they were unleashing. Which, as was their nature, was more than enough. The Blood Ravens, however, had no such controlling compulsion. They shifted, moved, and in a manner that would likely frustrate certain other Chapters and elements of the Imperium, outright avoided fighting. More than enough fighting was offered up, as the greenskins fell upon each other with glee. An utterly unknowable amount of grudges, anger, and simple desire to fight after being kept from doing so ‘properly’ for so long had been unleashed. With the reactors dead, in two of three cases destroyed beyond repair, the chance for Doom-Eater to retake control through his older methods had been utterly denied to him.

Steadily, carefully, the Blood Ravens began to arrive. Cyrus and his scouts provided overwatch. Through scope and laser targeters to illuminate the darkness, they guided their fellow space marines in. First were the most wounded, those remaining most capable of fighting residing at the rear guard. But still they came on and through. Still dripping with the gore of the dead, the Master of Sanctity ordered a path cleared for him and the rest of his brothers. Elsewhere, the apothecaries were hustled through another tunnel from other battlegroups, hoarding the precious gene-seed. Soon enough, even the Chapter Master came, one hand around his thunder hammer and the other dragging the comatose Sergeant Persean, still smoldering.

“Here we are,” Hannibal growled, hefting two wounded battle brothers over his shoulders as he pushed his way into the secured cavern. “You will not die today, brothers. Not today.”

“Cyrus.”

“Chapter Master.”

Gabriel Angelos was a mighty warrior, it could not be said otherwise. But his armor sagged, chipped and scarred by the more exotic weaponry available to ork meks. His face had taken a bolter round, the wound already on its way to healing. The rest of the battlegroup, those still alive, showed the same and worse. Apollo would require apothecary attentions, but the same could be said for many, many more. In fact, by the end of the accounting, the Blood Ravens would discover that there was, in truth, not a single one among their number – excluding the scouts and neophytes – who was not wounded. Even the dreadnoughts were not left untouched.

“With the reactors destroyed, their shields and defense cannons cannot function,” Cyrus nodded approvingly. “We can call in the fleet now, commit to cyclonic blasts to crack this place open.”

“Indeed,” Gabriel nodded, “But first, we need to get out. Extraction is now our top priority.”

Cyrus shrugged and revealed a detonator from beneath his cloak. A single click was all that was required before a solid sixty seconds of continual explosions rang out. An entire series of walls slid away, vaporized or removed. Load-bearing sections fell inwards. Those passages that had initially led into the captured cavern where the sum total of the vast majority of Blood Ravens resided were sealed. Only one path led out, straight to a launch bay previously cleared in the past. Cyrus noted that there would be negative reports for those scouts who flinched even though they knew where they were planting their explosives.

“I don’t remember ordering you to prep such a route,” Gabriel noted idly.

“It is better to prepare an exit plan than not,” Cyrus shrugged. “In this case, our exit will, hopefully, not require our deaths.”

Sometimes, Cyrus knew, even Deathwatch Kill Teams died to ensure success.

===============================================

The universe swam in and out. Multicolored monsters and images flickered beneath fluttering eyelids. In the distance, he heard the beating heart of reality, stuttering but constant.

“It has been ten hours. All life threatening wounds have been healed as best as possible. He is stable as we can make him without prolonged hearing time. Revival commencing.”

Hadrian’s eyes snapped open as he tore free of the restraints keeping him strapped to the medical slab. He made it halfway to standing position before twin hisses announced the introduction of tranquilizers. Snarling, he struggled mightily against both of the apothecaries holding onto his arms. Ten seconds passed before the aggression filtered out of his system and he blinked, his mind chemically cleared. The smell of charnel flesh and gun smoke which had clogged his mind in suspended animation was replaced, his brain processing the scent of antiseptic and sterilized materials. The Captain of the 4th breathed hard, looking back and forth across the apothecarium of the Omnis. Nero Gracchus glared at him with his helmet removed, showing, for once, his amber eyes. They were narrowed nearly to slits.

“Captain. Are you properly cognizant?”

The tone was rather sarcastic, but Hadrian elected to take it as full sincerity.

“Yes.”

He shifted slightly, only to stop as the grips on his body refused to budge.

“You can let go of me, Chief Apothecary.”

Nero rolled his eyes and stepped back, letting the thoroughly wounded Captain to stand freely. His body still wept blood, but the vast majority of his wounds were clotted and what bones could be knitted back together had been. The Chief Apothecary very deliberately did not help as Hadrian immediately collapsed to one knee, breathing hard. He gurgled and spat out some clotted blood, one thoroughly scarred hand grasped at the slab to drag himself up to his feet. Second by second he felt the tremors in his body cease and he, in turn, glared back at Nero, who simply shrugged.

“Thank you, Nero,” Hadrian said through gritted teeth. “So…much.”

“Of course,” Nero nodded slightly. “Do you need anything else? I, personally, would recommend you return to bed rest until your wounds can heal properly.”

Hadrian began stomping away. Coincidentally he also happened to aggravate a number of his wounds by doing so, but he would be damned and before the Golden Throne itself before he would ever admit it.

“I’m heading to the command throne. Is the fleet ready to move?”

“Of course,” Nero called out after him. "Not that you are, but don't let me stop you."

Spoiler: Collected Results Of Phase 5

- Warboss Tactical Possibilities: Exterminatus Weaponry/Deep Strike Teleporters/Strike Force Penetration Through Mundane Means
- Tactical Consideration: Orks show high amount of 'advanced' weaponry and armors, and significant coordination through Doom-Eater communications.
- Tactical Consideration: 2 Reactor Hearts Permanently Destroyed/1 Reactor Heart Deactivated By Damage.
- Tactical Consideration: Ork communications completely disrupted and destroyed. Psychic predictions state that it is likely that Doom-Eater may extricate himself to reassert authority personally.
- Tactical Consideration: Doom-Eater Defenses Deactivated.
- Tactical Consideration: Blood Ravens Fleet Active, Movement/Deployment Capable
- Tactical Consideration: All Non-Quartus Blood Ravens Injured, Splitting Up Battlegroups = Suboptimal Results Highly Likely
- New Notable Character Revealed: Veteran Scout Sergeant Persean, 10th Company/1st Company/3rd Company. [Murderous Guardian/Silent Dervish]

Current Possible Tactical Targets Of Station:
- Engine Sectors Alpha/Beta/Gamma
- Anti-Orbital Defenses Include: Looted Imperial Broadside Cannons/Scattered Orkish Lance Turrets/Ork 'Heavy Gunz'/Ork 'Gunz'/Ork Torpedo Bays [Increased Accuracy And Knowledge Provided]
- Energy Shield Projector Points Located, Destruction Would Allow Bombardment If Anti-Orbital Weaponry Removed.
- ‘Maw Of Gork (Or Mork)’ Additional Characteristic Revealed: Fleet Deployment Capabilities
- Construkta Yard Gamma
- Depths Of Doom-Eater [Precise Location Of Warboss Unknown]

Battlegroup Primaris [All Injured But Functional]
Gabriel Angelos, Apollo Diomedes, Honor Guard [Captain Doukas/Chaplain Volkoss/Apothecary Falkor]
15 1st Company marines
1 Scout Sergeant
1 Apothecary [Carrying 18 Gene-Seed]
1 Chaplain
Techmarine Quarius Zergan and 3 other Techmarines, 3 Rapiers (Heavy Bolter)

Fatalities
9 Scouts of the 10th Company

Battlegroup Secundus [All Injured But Functional]
Captain: Marcus Crixus TH
Company Champion: Uriel Hamul TH
Epistolary: VACANT
Apothecary: Constantius Romallius TH [26 Gene-Seed Reclaimed]
Chaplain: Ares Actus TH
10 1st Company
30 Unassigned marines from the 10th
2 1st Company Dreadnoughts
1 Scout Sergeant and 9 Scouts from the 10th Company
2 Apothecaries
Chaplain Ravias/Chaplain
Techmarine Hestior/2 other Techmarines, 2 Rapiers (Heavy Bolter and Laser-Destroyer)
1st Company Tomb-Brothers Cassius

Fatalities:
1 Techmarine
15 10th Company Marines [Unassigned]
1st Company Tomb-Brother Brutus

Battlegroup Tertium [All Injured But Functional]
Hannibal Palrun
24 1st Company Marines
40 unassigned marines from the 10th
2 1st Company Dreadnoughts
1 Scout Sergeant and 9 Scouts from the 10th Company
2 Apothecaries [4 Gene-Seed Reclaimed]
Chaplain Antonius/2 Chaplains
Techmarine Calus/Techmarine Daedal/2 Techmarines, 2 Rapiers (Heavy Bolter and Laser-Destroyer)
1st Company Tomb-Brothers Adrandus/Anchises

Fatalities:
N/A

Battlegroup Quartus
Captain: Cyrus Octavius
Epistolary: Trajan Maphar
Apothecary: Marius Astophiles [10 Gene-Seed Reclaimed]
Chaplain: Augustine
1 Apothecary
6 Scout Sergeants
Scouts [2nd Stage]: 0
Scouts [1st Stage]: 60
Neophytes [2nd Stage]: 125
(Specialist Neophytes [2nd Stage]: 0 Apothecary/2 Chaplain/9 Techmarine)

Injured But Functional
35 Scouts [1st Stage]
45 Neophytes [2nd Stage]
1 Scout Sergeant
1 Chaplain Neophyte
3 Techmarine Neophytes

Fatalities
21 Neophytes [2nd Stage]
5 Scouts [1st Stage]

Battlefleet Blood Raven

1 Gladius Frigate Destroyed [4th Company]
Minor Damage Across All 1st Company Escort Ships
Burning Seeker Has Taken Notable Damage (Starboard/Port/Rear Weapon Arrays/Engines) [4th Company]
Spiraling Fury Has Taken Minor Internal Damage [1st Company]
1 Faith’s Horizon Gunship Thunderhawk Destroyed [10th Company]
2 Howling Hatred Gunship Thunderhawks Destroyed [10th Company]
3 Omnis Arcanum Gunship Thunderhawks Destroyed [1st Company]
Minor Damage Across Remaining 4th Company Escorts
Minor Damage Across 10th Company Escorts
1 Nova Frigate Destroyed [10th Company]
1 Gladius Frigate Destroyed [1st Company]
Legacy of Polonius Lance Array Destroyed, Will Require Repairs.
Scientia Est Potentia Has Taken Significant Damage To Hull/All Weapons Arrays/Command Deck. Multiple points in hull penetrated by boarding torpedoes and drills. Currently undergoing patching and sealing. [4th Company]

Captain: Hadrian Priscus [Cannot Commit To Personal Combat]
Company Champion: Trexus Nubius [Bears Power Axe/Power Fist Dual Combination] TH
Epistolary: Nero Achillian [Bears Psychic Hood/Raven's Aegis Talisman] [Farseer/Daemonologist]
Apothecary: Caesar
Chaplain: Ateren [Powerful Bionic Arm/Leg]

Company Strength: 77% Strength (53% Effective)

Additional Members
Chief Apothecary Nero Gracchus/Apothecary
1 Chaplain
Master of the Forge Martellus Ravias/3 Techmarines/

Veteran Sergeants:
- 5 1st Company Veterans TH
- 5 4th Company Veterans

Injured And Functional
30 4th Company Space Marines
All Tarantula Sentry Turrets

Injured And Non-Functional
20 4th Company Space Marines
Captain Hadrian Priscus [Left Arm Requires Bionic Replacement]

Dreadnought Notation
3 4th Company Space Marines Interred In Dreadnought Frames [3 Dreadnought Frames Used, 1 Remaining In Armory]
- Brother Relian
- Brother Aeneas
- Brother Polites [Newly Revived]
- Brother Turnus [Newly Revived]
- Brother Mezentius [Newly Revived]

Phase 5 Orders:
[] Blood Raven Ground Force Orders
-[] Evacuate To Launch Bay For Retrieval By Fleet
-[] Something Else (Write-In)

AND

[] Blood Raven Fleet Orders
- [] Retrieve Blood Raven Ground Forces, Then Commence Exterminatus
- [] Something Else (Write-In)

Turn 21 Results - 2480 - Part 3

Spoiler: Voting results [*] Ride to Black Fire Pass and take a Dwarven monitor down Skull River, stop at Barak Varr, and then up Blood River. Reasonably fast, comfortable, maximizes Dwarf-y showing off. [*] The EIC has potential to be an amazing source of information, and now that it can be trusted, Mathilde will shape it as such. [*] Introduce him to King Belegar as a seasoned diplomat who can round up mercenaries for him. [*] Introduce him to Prince Gotri as a factory builder seeking his advice in gunsmithing. [*] Introduce her to King Byrrnoth of Barak Varr, who would love to have a new distributor in the Empire for all the valuables from the East now that Death Pass is secure. Transportation for an Elector Countess and her escort is simple enough, but it gets trickier when you factor in a Dwarven delegate and her escort. The head of her escort speaks to the head of your escort, and a compromise was struck: the two escort gyrocopters will keep a watchful eye on the party while the Hammerers would be waiting at the Skull River. Without Dwarves, whose tireless pace could not compare to the speed attainable by swapping horses at every waystation, the four hundred miles of the first leg of the journey should take no longer than six or seven days. You refrain from commenting you could manage it comfortably in two days, and in one at a stretch. The Elector Countess is the definition of civility, exchanging no more than the required pleasantries and doing no more than giving your shadowhorse a long, uneasy look when you first summon it. An early start gets you to Tarshof before night falls, and from there a good day's ride should make Vigaun, but it seems other plans were also in motion. [Gyrocopter spot check: 28] [Greatswords spot check: 25] [Mathilde spot check: 94+10(Windsage)=104] Between Potting and Worden, what you initially take for the smell of rot in the air quickly resolves itself as a warning from your additional senses, and you call a warning as you draw your revolver and try to locate the source of the stench of necromancy. Roswita and the Greatswords immediately dismount and the greatswords form a protective phalanx around their Elector Countess, and the abandoned horses start to whinny in nervousness as their own senses start to pick up on what yours already have. This part of the Old Dwarf Road is carved into the hils of the Stirhügel. An army could be within a stone's throw and you'd never know it because of the uneven terrain breaking line of sight in every direction. "East!" you cry, and eleven heads swivel at your instruction as the source of your alarm reveals itself. A bear at first glance, but a second glance would reveal the terrible wounds that felled it, a smell would make clear the stench of rot, and to your Magesight it is thick with Shyish and Dhar, and only one of the many spells it bears would be the one that has risen it from the dead. Flanking the creature are a pack of Dire Wolves - the giant wolves of the mountains and deep forests that are so often slain and resurrected into the service of vampires and necromancers that there's a term for that. Raised again and again into service, some end up as little more than withered flesh stretched over bone, kept whole only by the magics that dominate them, but these are as fresh as the bear, fur matted with blood and eyes aglow with hunger. [Stand and Shoot: 43+21=64] You sacrifice a second to weave Ulgu into the cylinder of your weapon - these are flesh rather than spirit, but with how thick the spells are on them you'll take no chances - and then you unload the weapon as the creatures charge forward with unnatural speed. Two of the wolves are downed, but the bullet that hit the bear tore through organ and muscle rather than shattering bone, and with magic doing the heavy lifting it will take more than that. You reholster your revolver and draw your sword, the creatures too close now to spend time on a reload, and with a glance you confirm that the Greatsword escort has formed a wall between the oncoming beasts and their Elector Countess. The mismatched pack is beelining towards them and ignoring you, and your steed shares none of the fears of the panicking beasts that the Greatswords had been riding. One thought shapes Ulgu around you, and a second has your shadowsteed accelerating into a charge. [Selecting your target: Martial, 46+26+5(Tactics: Undead)=77 vs 94+30(???)=124] [Mathilde vs Wolves: Martial, 58+26=84 vs 72+15=87] With coordination that would normally be far outside the capabilities of these constructs, three of the wolves split from the pack and intercept you before you can close with the bear and with unnatural strength they leap towards you as one. The first impales itself upon your greatsword, expiring with eerie silence as the Ulgu in your blade disrupts the spells that animate and bind it, but a second rakes filthy claws along your arm, and to your shock the claws sink through your magical armour and open long, bloody gashes in your forearm. It had absorbed some of the impact, or you'd have been clawed to the bone, but you've just figured out what at least part of the other spells present are doing. The third creature went for your steed, and if whatever passes for its mind is capable of confusion, it must surely be confused now as it dangles by its jaws from the uncaring Shadowsteed's neck. [Mathilde vs Wolves Round 2: 57+26=83 vs 81+10=91] [Mathilde vs Wolves Round 3: 94+26=120 vs 59+10=69] You dimly register the increasing loud thrumming of approaching gyrocopters, but you're far too preoccupied to consciously register it as you elbow one wolf off you and intercept the lunge of the second with your blade, steel cracking teeth as your arms absorb the impact. The creatures are no real threat to you, but they are taking up time you don't have, as the others close on the defensive line of the Greatswords. Another lunge, and you meet this one with the pommel of your sword in the throat. The undead are usually immune to the normally-incapacitating throat punch, but between the creature's lunge and your own counterblow there's enough force for the crunch of crumbling vertebrae to be heard and the creature goes limp. It won't take long for the magic that controls it to reroute around the remains of the nervous system it was using, but you can use the time that's bought, and as the third wolf finally gives up on trying to savage your horse and crouches to leap, your sword slices through its back, spine, and rotting organs. Again, not necessarily a kill, and again, it doesn't matter. While you were taking care of these, the rest of the battle was unfolding. [Gyrocopter strafing run: 73 vs 4+30(???)=34] With horrifying speed, one of the gyrocopters buzzes mere yards overhead as its pilot pushes the limit of his machine, and it just manages a strafing run before the creatures impact the Greatswords. One of the wolves leaps into the air to try to intercept the shot, but this is not the early-model gyrocopters where the front cannon merely vented steam from the engines. Far from the Engineer's Guild of Zhufbar or the orthodoxy of Karaz-a-Karak, Prince Gotri had gifted his command with a variety of weapons ranging from almost acceptable to barely tested, and with a burp of released pressure, an iron ball the size of a fist was expelled with such force that the gyrocopter visibly slowed, and instead of intercepting the projectile the wolf became part of the payload. The bear was knocked sprawling by the blow and a fraction of a second later, the ball ignited and begin to spray burning pitch in every direction from holes drilled in its casing, and two more wolves diverted themselves from the charge to fling themselves atop it to smother the flames. [Greatswords vs Wolves: 5+15=20 vs 11+20=31] The charge that finally struck the Greatswords was greatly diminished, and you don't see how five undead Dire Wolves could be much threat to twice their number in Greatswords, but perhaps you've gotten blase about the myriad enemies of man. Maybe fear paralyzed them, maybe the spells empowering the creatures gave them reactions faster than they expected, maybe they were just unlucky. Whatever the reason, one man falls with the teeth of a Dire Wolf in his throat and a second begins to scream as merciless jaws tear through flesh and spill organs into the dirt. You don't have the luxury of hesitation, and even as your brain starts to weigh the danger of the bear against the unfolding disaster of the Greatswords, you're spurring yourself towards the latter. [Gyrocopter intervention? 43] [Mathilde's Charge: 24+26=50] [Greatswords vs Wolves Round 2: 24+15=39 vs 68+15=83] [Greatsword morale test: 75] [Mathilde's flanking: 83+26=109] You have a very similar problems to the gyrocopters, and though you're able to slay one of the wolves and draw the attention of the second, the remaining three continue to make a mockery of the Greatswords and each of them accounts for another of the supposed bodyguards within seconds. But though you've got some very pointed remarks to make about their swordplay, you can't deny their courage, and those that remain stand their ground long enough for you to dispatch the one that turned to face you, then cut through the remaining three in a flurry of blows. [Damage done to bear and wolves: 11] [Gyrocopter intervention: 73] Unfortunately, that is not the end of the battle. The bear emerges from the singed pile of its protectors, and shockingly so do two of those protectors, eldritch energies filling the gaps where muscle and bone have been burned away. Two of the wolves you dispatched earlier are climbing back to their feet, and though the Greatswords react by making doubly sure the downed wolves before them are out of the fight with a hail of additional blows, it doesn't solve the problem approaching. One of the gyrocopters flying overhead goes some way to doing so, as a bomb detaches from its stabilizer and explodes between two of the approaching wolves, knocking them sprawling. You grant yourself the luxury of a second to run through possible scenarios in your head, and you barely keep yourself from sighing as you dismiss your shadowsteed with a thought and land lightly on the dirt of the road below. Despite any lingering ill-feeling towards the one that dismissed you from your previous calling, to serve and protect the Electors of the Empire was one of the primary purpose of the Colleges. The remaining Greatswords part for you to join their ranks, and six blades stand against the approaching creatures. [Mathilde vs Undead: 42+21=63 vs 44+5=49] [Greatswords vs Bear: 35+15=50 vs 67+30=97] [Greatsword vs Wolf: 21+15=36 vs 91+5=96] [Greatsword morale test: 72] If you had time, you'd be insulted that whatever intelligence is guiding these creatures thought you only merited a single wolf. But though you strike the creature down in midair, it does mean you can't intervene as the undead bear slams into the Greatswords with bone-shattering force, and two of the remaining Greatswords go flying backwards with force that suggests they'll not be getting up, and the final remaining wolf accounts for a third. Again, to their credit, the two remaining Greatswords do not break, and throw themselves at the bear with wordless cries of fear and defiance. [Greatswords vs Bear Round 2 97+15=112 vs 61+30=91.] [Mathilde vs Undead: 77+21=98 vs 62+5=67.] And two swords sink deep into the bear's rotting chest, and stick fast as the bear roars in frustration. Some of the intact muscles must have still been in use, because the creature can do nothing but thrash violently as sickly energies crackle through its body, seeking a workaround. With the Greatswords distracted, the final wolf throws itself at Roswita, who in the glimpse you catch of her looks strangely peaceful as she readies her own blade to defend herself against the wolf, but before she has a chance to your sword swings up and through it, sending two halves flying through the air. [Bear: 2+30=32.] And with a crackle and a sinister glow invisible to mundane sight, the spells animating the bear misfire, and with your recent insights you're able to see exactly how. The spell of animation runs through intact muscles like a rat in a maze, trying to find a new way to achieve locomotion, and at the same time the empowering spells are filling those muscles with terrible power. The two spells meet and rebound each other, and though that would normally cause barely a moment of interference for the bear's controller, the rebound occurs in a muscle impaled upon Imperial steel. Dhar tries to crackle up a blade that is home to ambient Chamon, and while that does turn the Chamon to more Dhar and the blade into an expanding cloud of shrapnel, it does not do good things for the spells. Every muscle fries in an instant, adding to the smell of charred meat already in the air from the work of the gyrocopters, and the control spell vanishes from your sight. You're unable to see how, exactly, it would be affected, but you could guarantee that it would not be an enjoyable experience for the caster. Before you have a chance to relax, a second crackle fills the air, and you whirl around trying to spot its source. The noise resolves itself into a hiss, and then a dry, hissing laugh, coming from the still-moving mouths of each of the fallen, wolf and bear and Greatsword alike. "Almost got you that time, didn't I Rosie?" comes a man's voice, and one that bears the accent of an Altdorf noble, but through the filter of one necromantic transformation or another. "Almost gets you nothing, Alkharad," Roswita replies, clearly going for boldness but unable to keep the weariness out of her voice. "Got me eight, actually. Oops! Looks like nine!" He laughs again, and not mockingly. This is the laugh of someone genuinely entertained. You look over to the two remaining Greatswords, and see that only one has released his blade and stepped away from the now-talking form of the bear. The second is slumped forward, his body shredded by shrapnel of steel and bone that exploded out from the bear and seared by the released energies of the spell of empowerment. "That's not the score you care about, is it?" Roswita snaps. "One down, two to go." "I've told you, Grim Wood was an outpost, a colony. You did well there, I grant, but if you live long enough to cross the Templa you'll live no longer. Even the von Carsteins knew better than to try to extend their grasp to Teufelheim." "The von Carsteins are gone, and soon, you will be too," Roswita says. "You kill me, another takes my place. I kill you, your whole rotten kingdom crumbles." Many necromancers are mad enough to pontificate to their enemy, but some are cunning enough to do so as a distraction. Your blade interrupts one of the bomb-blasted wolves as it rises back to its feet. "She's good," comes the chorus of voices, including the one at the end of your sword. "New bodyguard? A Witch Hunter? A Myrmidian Priestess?" A shake of your head interrupts Roswita's reply. No need to make yourself known to whatever it is. "Anyhow, I'll be off. Plenty to do. I daresay those new Dwarf friends of yours won't fly so well with a flock or two of bats in their whirly bits." With a final rattling hiss, the last of the magics flicker out, and only Dhar and death remains. --- With nine of her ten bodyguards fallen before she's halfway out of Stirland, Roswita has no choice but to accept the offer of transport she earlier rejected. One gyrocopter shoots off to summon back the gyrocarriage, and the other buzzes around in cautious circles. "Necrarch," Roswita says suddenly, diverting your attention from the Greatsword tending to his fallen comrades. "Claims to be one of the eldest, but they all do. Fear of the von Carsteins kept all the others quiet, but when Castle Drakenhof fell and none of them appeared, it rang the dinner bell for them all. The Lahmian in Nachthafen is long gone, but Mikalsdorf and Waldenhof are openly ruled by others. Tempelhof is full of Blood Dragons who delight in testing themselves against the Black Guard of Morr, and Hunger Wood is home to at least three Strigoi and their ghoul courts, growing fat off the fallen. Not a week goes by without us burning some idiot necromancer trying to dredge corpses from Hel Fenn. And, of course, Alkharad. Based out of Teufelheim, but what he's really interested in are the forests. We chased his disciples out of Grim Wood in the west, but according to the Witch Hunter archives and the Slayer Keep's Book of Grudges, he's been lurking in the Tangled Wood for centuries, venturing out to find new creatures to experiment on." Her voice is dry, but you can hear the exhaustion in it. "Not the first time he's taken a swing at you, I take it?" "Barely a week goes by without it, ever since the Battle of the Eisig. Bats, birds, wolves, rats, deer... I've already lost more Greatswords than Da did, even including the ones that fell at the Battle of Drakenhof. Eventually he'll get sick of playing and send some terrible thing from the deep forests or the mountains or the Dark Lands." That explains the Shyish. Plenty of citizens of the Empire live under threat of attack, but few have the personal attention of the beings that rule the night. --- The gyrocarriage arrives soon after to take you to the next leg of your journey - you suggest going straight to Eight Peaks, but Roswita is determined to keep mostly to her original plan despite the intervention of Alkharad, and with the sole remaining Greatsword staying behind to see the fallen are properly interred, you're now protected 'only' by the Hammerers and the guns and crew of the river monitor. Propelled by the secrets of Dwarven artifice, which aren't all that secret if one can see the Chamon in the metal and the Aqshy in the flames and have recently experimented with kettles, you're carried down Skull River at a speed that is agonizingly slow by your standards but blisteringly fast by the standards of logistics. Perhaps out of unvoiced gratitude, perhaps from contrast with something that was actively trying to kill her, perhaps because you're the only other human around for her to talk to, she seems to have lost her desire to keep far from you. She's not exactly warm, and her conversational topics are perhaps understandably limited, but it makes a nice change from the long and lonely voyage you expected to have. When your responses show a proper understanding of the subject at hand, she excuses herself to rummage through her bags and comes back with a map optimistically labelled 'Eastern Stirland' and covered with hand-drawn notations. Roswita has obviously studied military strategy extensively, and been taught by those who know the subject, but you've got a larger well of experience to draw from and an insight into the mind of one commanding the Undead. The miles slip past as you teach her to not just react to the movements of the Undead, but to interpret them and decode the enemy's intentions, and by the time you arrive in Barak Varr you've found yourself offering to lend her some of the more relevant parts of your library. An Elector Countess of the Empire is an important guest, but a Councillor from the Karak that has so dominated recent events is possibly even more so, and by means of a string of coloured flags the river monitor has forewarned your destination. As the boat slides into dock, you are greeted by none other than King Byrrnoth, who won his crown by killing a sea dragon from the inside. His greeting to Roswita is effusive and in fluent Reikspiel, and his greeting to you is more casual but heartfelt in Khazalid. The legend of the Expedition has rippled through the Dwarven world, and you feature rather prominently in it; as one who gambled on the Expedition and won, King Byrrnoth is delighted to have you visit his Hold, even in passing. Though it hasn't been long since your last visit, Barak Varr is even livelier than you remember, and to a degree you didn't expect. You knew it had been enriched by waves of silver from Karak Eight Peaks and treasure from Karak Azul, and expected it to be energized by the prospect of safe passage through Death Pass. What you didn't account for was the effect of the sheer amount of staple goods that now flowed through Barak Varr - food, of course, still paid for by King Byrrnoth, but also luxuries from the Empire for the human and Halfling colonists, and flowing right back is wood from Ulrikadrin. Foreign ships needed wood for repairs, and the Dwarven Carpenter's Guild existed and was very touchy about being overlooked in favour of blacksmiths and masons, but more than anything else, Barak Varr hungered for charcoal to fuel the forges of their shipyards and feed the flames of their steamships. You take Roswita through on a circuit of the marketplace, translating here and there, and try not to be too visibly smug that every Dwarf you speak to knows who you are. Some in Barak Varr didn't care for the glories of the past, and some unfortunate few hadn't been enriched by the Expedition's success, but it would be very hard to find someone in both categories at once. After a very comfortable night in the royal guest rooms, your journey continues but in much greater stature. King Byrrnoth has been invited to the celebration at Eight Peaks, and has decided he will accompany his honoured guests on their voyage. You're quite sure he'd sail a dreadnought up the Blood River if he thought he could get away with it, but there exists a single extraordinarily svelte ironclad for this exact scenario, and the Bokkul becomes your home for the next leg of this journey. Roswita might be single-focus, but having prolonged access to a foreign King is an opportunity an Elector Count would have to be daft to not capitalize on, and after a few rebuffed inroads she siezes the King's attention and imagination on the subject of her war with the Zangunaz. The Vampire Coast has been a constant navigational hazard for centuries, and the Barak Varr navy has accumulated quite a list of grudges against them and their kind. They talk at length upon the subject of their shared hatred for the vampires, and by the time the Bokkul arrives at Ulrikadrin he's promised to have a trainer of the Barak Varr Marines accompany her back to Stirland and teach her proper combat. [Strategic insight: 77+21+5(Strategy: Undead)+4(Library: Undead)=107] --- Sadly, there's no Dwarven artifice to skip the last leg of the journey, and the best you can do is wield the considerable status of the party to claim the most stalwart of the available beasts of burden. The Underway tunnel is a lot more inviting with the surface evened out and lamps burning at regular intervals, and before long you're emerging into the now-familiar mountains, and smile to see the silver pikes of the Undumgi in the distance. When finally you arrive at the East Gate and part ways with Roswita, you feel that you've made your peace with the girl. She's stubborn and wrongheaded about magic, but just like her father she's got a will of steel. You just hope that she doesn't share her father's fate. Other guests swarm into the Karak, and only most of them are the many children of King Kazador. Several siblings of Prince Gotri come to represent Zhufbar, Elders from Karaks Norn, Hirn and Izor are here to represent the Young Holds, Karaz-a-Karak has sent a Loremaster to properly record the occasion, and though Karak Kadrin has sent no delegate, a swarm of newly-arrived Slayers pass along some gruff best wishes before they hurry off to investigate this mountain full of trolls they've heard so much about. Roswita technically has a peer present, as Elder Hisme Stoutheart of the Moot is here to cluck with pride over the Moot's first colony and enjoy enormous amounts of Dwarven ale. The Winter Wolves are present in force, as are the leaders that have emerged among the Undumgi and Ulrikadrin, and the presence of representatives from the Knights of Taal's Fury and the Knights of the Vengeful Sun indicate that Esbern and Seija were successful in locating them. The Emperor sent a delegate, and most of the Elector Counts have someone present to be seen and to let them know what the hell is going on down there. And though they may be far down the list of local leaders, the Baron of Blutdorf and the President of the Eastern Imperial Company are also here to pay their respects. The first introduction to make is, of course, to Wolf. Anton lowers himself on one knee to return Wolf's quizzical stare, nods gravely, and gives independent verification of Wolf's status as a Good Boy, and from that moment on Wolf remains stuck to Anton's side. The next target is trickier, and with time sparse and his time in great demand, it could be that nobody else could snatch a few minutes of the King's ear at a moment like this, but you manage it and he has a short but dense talk with Anton and names a figure that flabbergasts you, and then you're shocked again when Anton doesn't wave away all talk of a finder's fee, merely talking the King down to a percentage that will still refill the treasury of Blutdorf and then some. Your second port of call is Prince Gotri, who is knowledgeable and radical enough that the possibility exists that he'll let slip some Dwarven secrets. You begin the conversation innocently enough by telling the Prince that Anton will be rounding up mercenaries for the upcoming attack on Karagril, and will therefore need a gyrocopter that can hold a passenger, and Anton steers the conversation through what you're almost certain is natural friendly interest into the topic of firearms. Anton's spent a fair bit of time learning the subject recently, but there's clear gaps in his knowledge and Prince Gotri seems to finds this offensive. He explains a few details, and then produces some schematics to go deeper into a few of the trickier parts, and by the time you flee the room to maintain plausible deniability Prince Gotri was disassembling a handgun under Anton's fascinated gaze. [Anton vs Gotri: Diplomacy vs Intrigue, 91+12=103 vs 7+6=13] Seeking safer company, you greet Wilhelmina and show her around the place. To your surprise she turned down your offer of gyrocopter passage, but it turns out she used the trip to familiarize herself with the riverine trade branching out from Barak Varr as well as the fledgling Ulrikadrin settlement and the newly-reopened Death Pass, and when she arrived at the Karak her eyes had already taken on that worrying gleam she always got when there was money to be made. She puts aside her ambitions to approve of your rug, equivocate on your furniture (very well made, but too unadorned for her tastes), and raises an eyebrow at the sprawl that is your library, spots your trade section, and raises the other eyebrow and gleefully accepts your offer to lend her a few of the rarer texts. She climbs up to your Tower, stares in bafflement at the room of marble and wood and glass, and mentally files it under 'Wizard things' and gives no comment. The local EIC members get a terrifying surprise inspection and try not to panic under the watchful eye of 56% of the company shareholders. And having leveraged your title to claim the ear of a second King in as many days, you unleash Wilhelmina upon King Byrrnoth, and wonder if she finally met her match. [Wilhelmina vs King Byrrnoth: Stewardship, 95+19=114 vs 3+25=28] Apparently not. Wilhelmina came into this meeting with a plan to secure access to the goods coming out of the resurgent Silk Road, but apparently dropped that overboard somewhere between Barak Varr and Eight Peaks because she talks of the canal Karak Kadrin has dug, makes observations on the shame of a landlocked Karak outdoing the might Barak Varr in the realm of riverine trade, and makes a series of observations about the proximity of the Aver Reach and the crater lake of Black Water. King Byrrnoth summons his advisers, who take a moment to react to the questions they're being asked and hurry off to get maps and reference materials, and before your eyes a plan takes hold that is going to shatter everything the Empire thinks it knows about trade. Barak Varr is coming. --- One of the smaller peaks surrounding the base of Karag Lhune has been carved away to form a mighty amphitheatre, and a crowd of thousands fills it to witness Karak Eight Peaks reward its allies. After watching both of your guests take a sledgehammer to the status quo, a sword seems almost prosaic. Or maybe it just seems that way because Dwarves don't believe in doing things by halves, and though it's certainly gratifying to hear a tale told where you're the deuteragonist, it does begin to wear after the first few hours of painstaking detail. Nevertheless, with willpower you gained from forcing the very fabric of reality to bend to your will, you manage to remain conscious and appear interested until the recitation finally catches up with the current day. "The Dwarves," King Belegar intones, "have a long and noble history. Many are our glorious deeds and grand heroes, stretching back all the way to our Ancestor Gods. The history of Karak Eight Peaks can make no such claim, as for three thousand years it was lost to us. With steel and fire we have retaken two peaks, and with steel and fire we will retake six more. But in the battles that allowed us all to stand here today, we did not stand alone. The Knights of the Empire stood with us! The Halflings of the Moot stood with us! The men of the Wolf-God stood with us! The men of the Asoborn stood with us! The men of the Undumgi stood with us! And the Wizards of the Colleges of Magic stood with us! "I have been reminded a great many times of the importance of Grudges, but I fear the Karaz Ankor has forgotten their counterpart. So many die to strike out ancient wrongs in the Dammaz Kron, but how many concern themselves with what other scores remain unsettled? Where is the Dalaz Kron, to be a weight around our necks when the acts of honour and courage of our oldest allies are not repaid? Let the message go forth for all to hear: just as the Dwarves will spill a lake of blood to avenge the past, so too will we move mountains to repay it. And today, using gromril wrest from the claws of our foes, Clan Angrund and Karak Eight Peaks repays those that fought and bled and died alongside us to recover our home." Dwarves, anyone could tell you, do not make swords. Dwarves, anyone could also tell you, are stubborn as all hell. So when King Belegar Ironhammer says make swords, the Grandmaster of the Karak Azul Blacksmith's Guild learned to make a sword, and not being one to reinvent the wheel, a glance can show you where they took their lessons. The representatives of the Knights are presented swords that bear striking resemblances to the hand-and-a-half swords of Bretonnia. The Ulricans receive a blade that clearly draws inspiration from the ceremonial blade of the Reiksmarshal, from before Solland was destroyed and its Runefang became the symbol of office. The Undumgi sword that Francesco Caravello receives differs only in material and craftsmanship from those wielded by the swordsmen of the Empire. On behalf of the Halflings, Titus receives a blade modelled after the short-swords of ancient Tylos. Roswita's blade is clearly modelled after a Runefang, and her expression is troubled as she considers it. And at last, your own blade, and you hold your breath as it is drawn from its scabbard to be presented to you. It's a Greatsword. Well, of course it would be a greatsword, but it's a Greatsword greatsword, only scaled down slightly to match your build and exhibiting the sheen of gromril instead of the glint of steel, and lighter than you expected. Three runes are carved into it, and the only reason they do not blaze with radiance is they have been specifically made not to, and as you take in the amount of power it contains you need to remind yourself it was made by the eldest Runesmith of the Karaz Ankor to keep from carefully putting it down and then fleeing in the opposite direction - and, to your fading horror and rising delight, it's still absorbing more, and you watch traces of Ulgu get pulled from the surface of your skin to feed the power of the blade. "Might take a while before you can thank the artisan in person," King Belegar murmurs to you over the hearty roar of the crowd, and at your quizzical glance he gives the slightest nod in the direction of the front row, where alongside a cheering King Kazador, Thorek Ironbrow's gaze is fixed on your sword and he is literally vibrating with fury. Oh. --- [Master Rune of Kragg the Grim: each blow delivers as much force as required to cut or shatter whatever it is struck against, up to the approximate impact force of a cannonball.] [Rune of Superior Skill: any foe struck by this sword has all magical weapons, armour, items, and positive magical effects cease working for several minutes. Though an original rune, the effect is very similar to Thorek Ironbrow's prototype rune. Knowing Kragg, this is almost certainly deliberate.] [Rune of the Unknown: when held by its owner, at a thought it can disappear, and will reappear again when desired. If not currently disappeared, weapon can be summoned to the owner's hand from a distance of up to several hundred yards. Kragg thought he'd never find a use for this rune because no Dwarf would trust their weapon hidden away somewhere they couldn't see.] --- When all the celebrations come to an end, it will be time once more for the Council to convene. While your success is pretty clear based on Roswita's presence, there is the matter of the spider silk to discuss. Who will you present this matter in front of? [ ] The entire Council. They can be trusted. [ ] Prince Kazrik and Princess Edda. They will be the ones that have to monetize this information. [ ] Dreng and King Belegar. The spiders are currently his responsibility. [ ] King Belegar only. Nobody else can be trusted. What recommendation will you make? [ ] Don't change how we treat the We, just strike a deal for their excess silk. [ ] Try to move the We into a more peaceful existence. Supply them with food in exchange for silk. [ ] Try to uplift the We. Fill them with knowledge until they're able to understand what the big deal is, then have them decide how they want to act. Also, your sword needs a name. Or possibly multiple. [ ] Write in.

Turn 22 - 2480.5 - Foes Near, Foes Far

Spoiler: Voting results [*] The entire Council. They can be trusted. [*] Try to uplift the We. Fill them with knowledge until they're able to understand what the big deal is, then have them decide how they want to act. [*] Branul Lhune, "the art of cleverness in moonlight" or Moonlit Wit. [*] Bar Rikkaz, 'Way Opener', 'Door Crusher', 'Nevertheless, Hammer' The many visitors to Eight Peaks drift away in the days following the ceremony, as Anton takes a gyrocopter to hunt down mercenaries, Wilhelmina hitches a ride with an EIC carriage, and Roswita again rides with King Byrrnoth. With Alkharad's warning still fresh in her mind, she turns down your offer of a gyrocopter, and will instead travel by river and be met at Black Fire Pass by Gustav and his finest Outriders. Though she never seems entirely at ease in your presence, she doesn't go out of her way to avoid it, and when you part you wish her luck in her campaign against the Undead and mean it. Life in Eight Peaks returns to some semblance of normal, and with the Council convening once more you find yourself wishing you'd feigned an excuse to arrive late - Prince Gotri is delighted to be able to show off a completed Engineering Bay, and the elevator that lets the gyrocopters be moved from the level of their individual bays, and either politeness or Dwarf thoroughness means nobody speaks up as he shows off each new tool and implement he's gathered for the repairs of the temperamental and fiddly machines. When he finally finishes, the Council reconvenes in the Council Chamber, other reports concerning inaccessible or distant accomplishments. "It's the Lhune Depths," Dreng reports, speaking of the source of the air that combined with the fire in the elevator shaft to turn Karag Lhune into a chimney. "It must surface somewhere, because huge amounts of air were being sucked through it by the fire. By all accounts, it was never close to fully mapped before the Karak fell, and there's no telling whether it's always had an opening or three thousand years of seismic activity have opened something." "Have a grating installed at the bottom of the elevator shaft, then," King Belegar says. "We've no time to solve the mysteries of the past just now. How go the war preparations?" "Sufficient provisions for the Throng of Karak Azul and any others that may join the fight, and ammunition enough for anything short of a prolonged siege." "Good. Have your Rangers start probing Karagril. Get as much information as you can without tipping them off that we're coming. Princess Edda, what of my ships?" She shrugs. "Under normal circumstances they'd be willing, but the Barak Varr navy is crash-expanding and they've got neither ships nor shipyards to spare." You keep a neutral expression, fairly sure you're at least indirectly responsible for that. "Prince Gotri, can you build ships?" He shakes his head. "Completely different Guild, completely different paradigm." "Can you build a shipyard, then?" He considers that. "I could," he decides. "Or at least get it to within a few tools and tweaks of suitable." "Head to Ulrikadrin and get started, have their Grand Master pay me a visit at his convenience to negotiate the details. Prince Kazrik, how were things in the Hornhold?" He hesitates, torn between disclosure and discretion. "Things between the King and his heir are thawing. There is no question in the succession." "Good enough for me. Last thing the Karaz Ankor needs is a succession crisis. Go get me a shipwright. Barak Varr preferably, but failing that try Zhufbar or even Karak Kadrin. Get an experienced Journeyman if you can't get a Master. If need be we can make do with barges and gunboats. Gunnars?" "Unsalvageable. It's been filled in with the stone from the amphitheatre, and the door has been bricked up." "Once we retake Karagril, we'll build it anew. Set up temporary shrines in the Chiselwards. Grungni, Valaya, Smednir... Prince Gotri, Morgrim?" "We've got a shrine set up in the Engineering Bay." "Gunnars, check if Kragg or Thorek require a shrine to Thungni, too." He nods. "Mathilde, you had news?" You produce a square of fabric from your pocket and slide it across the table to Edda, who frowns at it and picks it up. "We've had the first of the successful caravans return, but I don't-" "It's not from Cathay. It's from here. From the We." Belegar grasps it first, his eyes locking on the square of fabric as he starts to calculate. Princess Edda slides the fabric over to him and he examines it carefully. "The Elves are said to muck about in spidersilk, but that's some damn-fool business with thousands of regular-size ones. But these..." "The individual strands are as fine as that of normal spiders, they just use more of them," you say. "They've got different types for different purposes. That silk comes from the Egg-Layer, the Web-Weavers produce a different type that would make an amazing rope, and the silk of the Hunters could be made into excellent armour. Light as cloth, strong as chain." One doesn't make a claim like that in front of a crowd of Dwarves without being able to back it up, and you produce a significantly larger sample that Maximilian's inexpert fingers managed to weave into something resembling fabric. Eyes go from Belegar's Ironhammer, to your Branulhune, to Dreng's runic hammer, to Prince Kazrik's axe bearing runes of his own creation, to Prince Gotri's delicate engineering hammer, and Princess Edda sighs, turns demurely away, and retrieves a small axe from somewhere under the numerous layers of clothing Dwarves habitually wore. She removes the leather cover from the blade and in a surprisingly savage overhand swing gives the silk her best shot, and the crack that reverberates around the room and the ping of ricocheting stone reveal that in a fight between Dwarven steel and spider-silk, the loser was the table. "I would've killed them," King Belegar says slowly. "Even after the Gorzhufokri got them talking, if anyone but you had suggested making an accord with them, I'd have had them shoo the beasts into the Underway and then doubled the guard in case they came back." "I'd've too," Dreng agrees. "But they're not forest spiders, they're not cave spiders. I've been teaching them to share information with the patrols." "So, how do..." King Belegar trails off, trying to find a way to phrase it. "It's difficult. I can definitely draw parallels to your ancestors and mine, when the Dwarves first taught those who would become the Empire to shape metal. But while it seems the We isn't quite a single entity, it's closer to that than being multiple. So... imagine a primitive human, alone but content. He spends his time hunting for food, and every time he goes to the river, he leans in and plucks out a nugget of gold. And he'll build himself a little hut with walls of gold nuggets, and when it comes time for him to move on to find new hunting grounds, he throws all the gold back in the river, knowing he'll just find more in his new home. If you've made an ally of this human because of his skill with the bow, what do you do when you find out about the gold?" There's a busy and slightly guilty silence. Dwarves in general don't appreciate metaphor, seeing it as manling foolishness that needlessly complicates issues, but this one is straightforward enough to do its purpose - get past them thinking of the We as spiders, and getting them to think of them as a person. You continue on. "We could ask that if he's finished making his hut, when he pulls new gold out of the river, could he give it to us? And he probably would. If his hut is finished, he's got no need for it. Or you could tell him that you'll supply a nice house and all the food he needs if he spent all day by the river finding gold for you. But while both of these leave him no worse off and can even benefit him, we are profiting by the naivete of our ally. And to put aside the moral concerns - and it would be very easy to say that we need to put our lives first, and the trickery could buy us weapons or mercenaries - the thing about the We is that it is curious, it is logical, it is patient, and it is learning. It is within our power to take what advantage we can until it learns just how hard we've been bilking it. But the only sustainable solution is that we teach it, at least until the point where it understands enough to make an informed deal. For now we take what cast-offs it will give us and offer it food for more, but keep a record of every inch of it until the day it is able to name its price and then pay it every copper penny that it didn't know to ask for previously." "Couldn't we," King Belegar begins, and then stops. "No. You're right. This being is our ally, and it would shame us to take advantage of it." "My impression is that if we supply reading materials it will get itself there in time, but it is encountering a great many concepts it doesn't understand. It will take time and patience." King Belegar looks to Dreng wordlessly, who frowns in thought and then shrugs. "I'll ask it for silk, and offer it food, but I wouldn't know where to begin." "Mathilde, see to the education, whatever method you think best. Dreng, if your Rangers can take captives that would be ideal, but don't risk lives. We're already importing livestock, we can import more. Princess Edda, start a ledger - record every scrap of silk and every beast we end up feeding them, and what we paid for them. Start recruiting weavers, and make it clear there's a new Clan in the offering. That should get us a Master or two. Leave Karak Azul and Barak Varr and Karaz-a-Karak until last - I want weavers that have known jute and flax and hemp and sheep-wool, not just mycelium and goat. Prince Kazrik, while you're in Barak Varr stop in at the Dyer's Guild, let the Grandmaster know that King Belegar would appreciate an audience at his convenience - no idea if the stuff will take to dye but it's worth a shot. No point letting a single unworked strand out of the Karak, it'd be throwing gold away." --- "Talked to Byrrnoth," Belegar says as the others file out. "Seemed quite taken with the Elector Countess. Mentioned she seemed to be in a spot of bother." "When Castle Drakenhof was destroyed and nobody responded, it banished all the lingering fears the other vampires had about the von Carsteins. They see Sylvania as the ideal fief." "Seems to be the story of all our foes. Knock one over, two takes their place." He scratches his beard in thought. "I'd not say no to you working your magic, literal and otherwise, in Karagril. But if you think you can make a difference in Sylvania, take a squad of Hammerers and a flight of gyrocopters. Wave the banner and all that, show off your new sword. Probably won't make a difference in time for Karagril, but there'll be plenty more battles after that and we can use all the help we can get." --- Because I forgot the purchases last turn, and because I will be travelling for the next five days, this set of voting will be in two stages. For the first 24 hours, voting is to be restricted to the tower/library/rune/enchantment purchases. This vote will close automatically instead of being announced by myself. After that, voting can begin on the actions. [ ] Tower of Dawn and Dusk - with ritual and material and expert consultation, make your Tower like a tuning fork for Ulgu. Bonus to enchantment, rituals, spell learning, spell making, and power stone creation within the tower. 250gc, 5 College favours. [ ] Tower of Oh Dear - with a series of very prominent buttons easily accessible from anywhere in the room, be able to drain all magical energies in three heartbeats. Near-complete immunity to miscasts and any other conceivable magical threat. 200gc, 3 College favours, 3 Dwarf favours. [ ] Tower of Serenity - Perfect temperature, perfect level of background noise, perfect conditions to get those bloody papers written. Or for someone else to do it for you. It even has a rune to keep your drink warm. Every turn, writing or dictating 1 paper costs no actions. 300gc, 3 College favours, 1 Dwarf favour. [ ] Tower of the Burning Shadow - to your sorrow, Burning Shadows cannot be cast on a mountain. To your delight, there's a way around that. There may not be a practical purpose to this, but deep in your soul you know you want to turn the entire shadow of Karag Nar into acid. 150gc, 4 College favours. [ ] [LIBRARY] No purchase. [ ] [LIBRARY] Write-in. [ ] [RUNE] No purchase. [ ] [RUNE] Write-in. [ ] [ENCHANTMENT] No purchase. [ ] [ENCHANTMENT] Write-in. [ ] [PURCHASE] No purchase. [ ] [PURCHASE] Write-in. --- Mandatory Actions: Pick one from each category. Journeyman Maximilian de Gaynesford, Gold Wizard [ ] Allow him to spend all his time on his metalworking studies. [ ] Have Maximilian learn a skill: specify what from who. You may pay for a trainer. [ ] Have Maximilian learn a spell: specify which. [ ] Have Maximilian study your Skaven firearms. [ ] Have Maximilian study your Eshin throwing star. [ ] Educate the We. [ ] Previous Task: Have Maximilian perform or assist with spider autopsies. [ ] Have Maximilian attempt to write a paper (choose which from 'Publish or Perish') [ ] Have Maximilian write papers on subjects you dictate. Magister Johann, Gold Wizard [ ] Allow Johann to spend all his time investigating the Skaven (Choose: Clan Moulder, Mors, Skryre or Eshin) [ ] Allow Johann to study the Ratling Gun. [ ] Have Johann study your Skaven firearms. [ ] Have Johann study your Eshin throwing star. [ ] Have Johann join you for your adventure in Karagril. [ ] Have Johann join you for your adventure in Sylvania. [ ] Have Johann learn a skill: specify what from who. You may pay for a trainer. [ ] Have Johann learn a spell: specify which. [ ] Previous Task: Have Johann perform or assist with spider autopsies. [ ] Have Johann attempt to write a paper (choose which from 'Publish or Perish') The Eastern Imperial Company Your outstanding debt: 1,000 gc Your share of EIC profits: 100 gc / turn Current Focus of the EIC: Handgun Factory in Blutdorf (Grand Opening in 18 months) [ ] Put policies in place that local news should be collected and sent to you (rumour mill). [ ] Have those supplying the Stirland Army keep you informed of events in the Sylvanian Campaign. [ ] Have the Eight Peaks branch keep a careful eye on the mood and actions of the Undumgi. [ ] Have the Eight Peaks branch keep a careful eye on the mood and actions of the non-Undumgi civilians of Karag Nar. [ ] Found an internal investigation division, to investigate possible misconduct. [ ] Found an auditors division, to make sure the ledgers are in order. [ ] Start hiring handlers who can then start hiring informers and begin to collect non-public information. [ ] Reach out to Julia to find out if she's interested in being poached or passing on information. Personal Actions: choose between five and seven. Specify the additional action or actions. On a poor unmodified die roll (<40) these will suffer from inattention or will not have as much time available as they should. On a terrible roll (<10), botching the task or suffering long term consequences will result. Current Task: [ ] Educate the We yourself. [ ] Hire an open-minded Loremaster from a Young Hold to teach the We. [does not cost an action or your money] [ ] Hire an Altdorf professor to teach the We. [does not cost an action or your money] [ ] Hire a Priest of Verena to teach the We. [does not cost an action or your money] [ ] Hire a Priest of Esmerelda to teach the We. [does not cost an action or your money] [ ] Hire a Priest of Taal or Rhya to teach the We. [does not cost an action or your money] [ ] Karagril: Carefully map as much of the mountain as you can. [ ] Karagril: Sabotage weapons, equipment, and food. [ ] Karagril: Assassinate competent leaders. [ ] Karagril: Spread terror among the greenskins. [ ] Sylvania: Teach Stirland's officers the strategies and weaknesses of the Undead. [ ] Sylvania: Give Roswita's Greatswords a crash course in everything they should already know, and then some more. [ ] Sylvania: Investigate the attempts on Roswita's life, and see if you can determine the mechanisms, spells, and controls that make it possible. [ ] Sylvania: Investigate Alkharad for yourself, and if a good opportunity arises, take it. [ ] Sylvania: Investigate the Strigoi of Hunger Wood, and see if you can add another skull to your collection. [ ] Sylvania: Investigate the Lahmians of Waldenhof and Mikalsdorf, and if you can, teach them why their kind usually remains behind the scenes. [ ] Sylvania: Investigate the Blood Knights of Tempelhof, and if you can get one on their own, see how their vaunted skills measure up. [ ] Sylvania: Investigate all the Vampires as efficiently as possible, seeking only information, not opportunities. [ ] Establish a weekly meeting for the various Journeymanlings and Ducklings that you've accumulated, so you can keep tabs on what they're up to and assist and intervene as necessary. Self-Improvement: [ ] Ask an acquaintance to train you in a skill: specify who and what. [ ] Hire a trainer to come to Eight Peaks and teach you: specify what. (costs favours for Dwarf trainers, money for human ones) [ ] Travel to the Grey College and attend lessons there. (1 College Favour per class; 100gc can be paid instead for non-magical classes) [ ] Attempt to learn a spell from College-supplied scrolls (specify which) [ ] Gain enough control of your unruly shadow to still it temporarily. [ ] Practice shooting while invisible. Karak Eight Peaks, friendly: [ ] You have set up a Shrine to Ranald. Expand it into a Temple to the Night Prowler - an underlit and disreputable pub for those who value privacy to gather. Guaranteed cloaked stranger in every corner. Costs 100gc. [ ] You have set up a Shrine to Ranald. Expand it into a Temple to the Gambler - a gambling hall with clean cards, guaranteed unloaded dice, fresh sawdust in the fighting ring, and a lottery every Festag. Costs 100gc. [ ] You have set up a Shrine to Ranald. Expand it into a Temple to the Deceiver - a pawn shop filled with strange knick-knacks, odd devices, foreign books, and a shopkeep that knows more than they should. Costs 100gc. [ ] You have set up a Shrine to Ranald. Expand it into a Temple to the Protector - a clean and respectable tavern for Undumgi to visit after they finish their patrols. Costs 100gc. [ ] Crime is inevitable, so it may as well be organized crime. Send word to Heideck and make sure that when an underworld emerges, it will be a Ranaldian one. This cannot be tracked back to you. [ ] Crime is inevitable, so it may as well be organized crime. Send word to Heideck to send individuals who will construct an underworld under your command. This will be concealed, but could be tracked back to you. Will be under your control; 2 organisations cost 1 action per turn. Karak Eight Peaks, hostile: [ ] Kvinn-Wyr is full of trolls. Investigate this for yourself. [ ] Travel underneath Kvinn-Wyr and investigate Karag Mhonar. [ ] Travel through the Underway into Karag Yar, to investigate Clan Eshin. [ ] You've mapped the territory of Clan Mors. Go down there and cause some havoc. [ ] You've mapped the territory of Clan Mors. Go down there and see what you can acquire. [ ] Clan Moulder are set up under Karagril. Investigate. [ ] Investigate underneath Karag Lhune: the Lhune Deeps and the Grand Abyss. Research: [ ] You've got Ranald's Coin around your neck. Study it to see if you can gain an insight into Divine Energy. [ ] Send to the Grey College for the appropriate scrolls to learn a specific spell: specify which. [ ] Investigate how Pall of Darkness interacts with your sharpened magical senses. [ ] Investigate how the We communicates with... itself? [ ] Investigate the Skaven firearms, including the warpstone alloy bullet and the warpstone-impregnated gunpowder. [ ] Investigate the Skaven throwing star, that somehow remains constantly sticky with venom. [ ] The Second Secret of Dhar teaches how to collapse it upon itself. Practice upon local Dhar taint, and very cautiously see if this works with Warpstone. [ ] Try to establish a relationship with the Cult of Verena, with the intent of offering them access to your rarer tomes in exchange for copies of some of their own. Aethyric Vitae (15 gallons): [ ] Investigate the exact circumstances required to induce a transformation. [ ] Investigate how living things react to exposure to the Vitae. [ ] Investigate how the Vitae reacts to Dwarven magic-dampening Runes. (2 Dwarf favours) [ ] Attempt to interest one of the currently present Runesmiths in the interaction between Runes and Vitae. (Will start at the top and work your way down) [ ] Call in favours to get a specific Runesmith to examine the interaction between Runes and Vitae with you. [ ] Investigate how the Vitae reacts with Divine Magic. [ ] Investigate how the Vitae reacts to a power stone. [ ] Investigate how the Vitae reacts to being subjected to power stone creation methods. [ ] Instead of seeking the secrets of the blood, simply see if it can be weaponized in some way. Enchantment and Spell Creation: [ ] Enchant an item with a Relatively Simple or easier spell (specify what and which) [ ] Attempt to create a spell (must have been previously said to have been plausible by me, have the post where I did so handy) Publish or Perish (if Max is writing papers you dictate, two of the below can be selected for a single action): [ ] Collate the information that the Army of Stirland collected during the Purge. [ ] Write a paper on the Waaagh energy and magic witnessed during the Expedition. [ ] Write a paper on your personal understanding of countering Waaagh Magic. [ ] Write a paper on the Black Orc Warboss' worship of Only Gork, and what you saw of the Rogue Idol ritual. [ ] Write a paper on Mathilde's Multidimensional Aethyric Projection. [ ] Write a paper on the physiology and venom of the We. [ ] Write a paper on the psychology and social structure of the We. [ ] Write a preliminary paper on Aethyric Vitae. Karag Nar Penthouse: each turn, you get ONE free choice in this category. Additional selections cost actions. [ ] Have a tower built atop Karag Nar: -100gc for 1 room, bonus to room's purpose. [ ] Have additional rooms excavated underneath your Penthouse: -50gc for 2 rooms. Setting up rooms for specific purposes will have to wait until new rooms are constructed or excavated. Only one construction or excavation can take place at a time, but you can do one of each. Building downwards will increase by 1 each time; second set of excavated rooms will be 3 rooms, third will be 4, and so on. Building upwards can be added upon; towers can be added on to or additional towers can be built. The distinction between the two is entirely cosmetic. Personal Relations: [ ] Spend time assisting with a fellow councillor's task: specify who and how. [ ] Spend time investigating a character without their knowledge: specify who. [ ] Wolf is fully grown and a Very Good Boy. Train him. (increases his intelligence, he may learn to speak Praestantia) [ ] Wolf is fully grown and very magical. Deepen your familiar bond. (may unlock a new familiar ability; risks obsession) Ranald's Coin - specify which face it will be set to [ ] The Gambler: specify an action this will apply to. A +20 bonus to up to two dice rolls resulting from a single chosen action. [ ] The Night Prowler As long as you are outside of private property and within a town or city, nobody will question your presence and nobody will be able to find you if you do not wish them to. [ ] The Deceiver: describe how this will be used. Lies you have developed beforehand will be delivered perfectly. The listener may believe you to be mistaken, but they will never believe that you are lying. Cannot be used to tell truths. [ ] The Protector When you act in a way that defends an individual or group from a danger that you did not cause, they will become aware of what you have done and will believe you acted selflessly in doing so. - Due to the coming Social Turn, you no longer get a free choice in Personal Relations. - Starting a few hours after this is posted, I will be travelling for the next five days. If there is anything unclear or missing from the above, please let me know quickly. I don't know how much time I'll have free, so even though it's quite possible I'll still keep up and answer questions and whatnot, operate under the assumption I'll be gone until six days from this post. Please keep things civil until then, and if a topic starts getting heated or weird, I'd appreciate you moving away from it, at least temporarily. - I've given the Sword the two most popular names, and I've tweaked the first into Branulhune, as the double-L in Branul Lhune feels awkward to me. - I've been asked about rifles; if you wish Mathilde to purchase one, enter it as merely 'rifle' under Purchase. There will be several options available, running from 100 to 500 gc. - There will be a chance to act in Karagril before the army marches (as an interlude or mini-turn), but what you can achieve in a day or two does not compare to what you can achieve in a month. - If one of the Vampire type-specific Sylvania options are chosen, Mathilde will only engage if she judges her odds as very good, and will avoid unfavourable fights. - Only one education option for the We need be chosen; if that option fails, you can choose another later. The We are patient. ONLY PICK ONE EDUCATION OPTION. - You can write in another education method, but take my advice: 'throw wizards at it' is not the solution here, and besides, they'll snipe your papers. - This is the first and last turn of the half-action grace period. I start rounding up instead of down next turn. - VOTING MORATORIUM: For the first 24 hours, voting is to be restricted to the tower/library/rune/enchantment/purchase options. This vote will close automatically instead of being announced by myself. After that, voting can begin on the actions.

Turn 22 Results - 2480.5 - Part 1

Spoiler: Voting results [X] [RUNE] No purchase. [*] [PURCHASE] No purchase. [*] [ENCHANTMENT] No purchase. [*] Tower of Serenity - Perfect temperature, perfect level of background noise, perfect conditions to get those bloody papers written. Or for someone else to do it for you. It even has a rune to keep your drink warm. Every turn, writing or dictating 1 paper costs no actions. 300gc, 3 College favours, 1 Dwarf favour. [*] [LIBRARY] Plan To Kill Imperial Undead - Extensive (50g) Imperial Vampires - Extensive (100g) Imperial Necromancy - Extensive (100g) Bretonnian Undead - Extensive (100g) Bretonnian Vampires - Extensive (100g) Dwarf Vampires - Extensive (100g) Bretonnian Greenskins - Extensive (100g) Bright Magic - Extensive (100g) Death Magic - Extensive (100g) Celestial Magic - Extensive (100g) [*] Plan Fuck Alkharad, Free Max Edition -[*][Max] Have Maximilian attempt to write a paper (choose which from 'Publish or Perish') --[*] Collate the information that the Army of Stirland collected during the Purge. -[*][Johann] Previous Task: Have Johann perform or assist with spider autopsies. -[*] [EIC] Have those supplying the Stirland Army keep you informed of events in the Sylvanian Campaign. -[*] Ask an acquaintance to train you in a skill: Gunnar and Greatsword -[*] Karagril: Carefully map as much of the mountain as you can. -[*] Sylvania: Investigate all the Vampires as efficiently as possible, seeking only information, not opportunities. -[*] Sylvania: Investigate the attempts on Roswita's life, and see if you can determine the mechanisms, spells, and controls that make it possible. -[*] Sylvania: Investigate Alkharad for yourself, and if a good opportunity arises, take it. -[*] [OVERWORK] Establish a weekly meeting for the various Journeymanlings and Ducklings that you've accumulated, so you can keep tabs on what they're up to and assist and intervene as necessary. -[*][Penthouse] Have a tower built atop Karag Nar: -100gc for 1 room, bonus to room's purpose. -[*][Coin] The Night Prowler -[*][FreePaper] Write a paper on Mathilde's Multidimensional Aethyric Projection. -[*] [FREE] Hire an open-minded Loremaster from a Young Hold to teach the We. The first room in your tower had been an amazing display of very complex magic. The second is comparatively humble in scope. It does not seek to remove magic, but to remove distractions, to allow for the better harnessing of your painfully limited waking hours. Perhaps one could look at this as a frivolous use of limited resources, but to you it was an investment. You were sitting on a large and growing number of potential papers and something needed to be done to fight the tide. A handful of runes scattered throughout the room absorbed magic, but without the urgency or totality of the previous room. Both the fireplace and the candles would never require refuelling or relighting, though the former achieved it through a much milder variation on Stoke the Forge and the latter via Inextinguishable Flame, and both would remain the same size and colour whether they were radiating heat to fight the chill of night or gone completely cold to keep from adding to the heat of the day. Apprentices from Prince Gotri's nascent Engineers Guild had installed a system of pipes that could cause the trickle of a fountain or the simulated patter of raindrops, and an apprentice Runesmith had applied a single very simple rune so that the water would flow obligingly without requiring any mundane source of impetus. Book cradles could be unfolded from the walls, each sporting an extremely basic Move cantrip to keep a book obligingly open without having to resort to cracking the spine. One wall could be unfolded completely to reveal a massive chalkboard and an ample supply of chalk, as you had surrendered to practicality after considering how much effort it would be to achieve the same result with your MAP or other spells - but you did have it enchanted with Cleansing Glow so it could be cleaned off in an instant. And not least of all, the desk itself, where two visible runes would keep any drink suitably warm or cool, a small rack hidden away in the wall to keep quills and ink on hand, and an ample supply of papyrus, vellum, parchment, and even the Cathayan wood-pulp 'paper' that many older wizards were sure would never catch on. You had explored the possibility of magical dictation, but had run into roadblocks early and often. There were two ways for it to work - one where the enchantment would access the mind of the user, and one that relied only on sound. The former was several disasters waiting to happen, as so far the intended users of the tower were yourself and Maximilian, which meant that at best half and more likely both of you would have a foreign magic operating on your brain, and creating Dhar inside one's brain was as terrible idea as it sounded, and even if your belt would protect you from it, it would still prevent it from working. The latter was trickier than it sounded, and you would either need to create or enslave a sentient mind for the purpose - rather drastic, morally dubious, and that's what you had Maximilian for - or you build a complete understanding of Reikspiel or Praestantia into the spell itself, which would be an utterly titanic undertaking. Infuriatingly, Dwarven runes could perform this easily - but only for Khazalid. Something to do with both the Klinkarun alphabet of Khazalid and the art of Runesmithing both descending from the Ancestor Gods, apparently. An interesting line of enquiry at a time when you're drowning in them, but no good for you unless you write a paper for Dwarven eyes only. --- King Belegar's orders to you hadn't been phrased as such, but that was a show of trust in you rather than any alteration of the relationship that existed between King and Councillor. Your official task was the education of the We, but unless you did so yourself, both the pay and influence to acquire a teacher would come from King Belegar and Karak Eight Peaks rather than yourself, so all you had to do was choose the best candidate and spend a few minutes writing a suitable letter and sealing it with the now-familiar sigil of the reborn Karak. You give the matter some thought, and then send off letters via gyrocopter relay to two Dwarves you once shared the Expedition's Council of War with - Durin Wutokri of Karak Norn, and Ulthar Alriksson of Karak Hirn, explaining broadly the task at hand and guaranteeing the safety of whoever might apply, but being clear that the task would be extremely unusual - letting it go unsaid that if a human wizard says that, to even a slightly conservative Dwarf it was sure to border on lunacy. By the time you returned there would be at least one candidate waiting, and if there were multiple, chronicling the rebirth of the Karak could employ any number of unsuitable teachers. Speaking of Ulthar Alriksson, you are given to understand that he always has been Prince Ulthar, but has only started going by that title recently. Whatever sort of royal family intrigue that the situation has sprung from, it leaves any Dwarf who you ask about the matter extremely uncomfortable and only willing to speak very circuitously about the matter. As Dwarves would never hesitate to expound on actual misdoings, you gather the matter must be extremely embarrassing, not unlike some of the more esoteric parts of the whole Dieter IV business. You put the matter from your mind and see to putting things in motion so you can leave the Karak for a few months and be mostly sure of it still being intact when you return. After some thought you've decided to perform your own scouting of Karagril rather than assisting Dreng with his. Dreng's Rangers will be focusing on gathering innumerable tiny details of the possible avenues of attack to remove as many unknowns from the rapidly-approaching invasion as possible - important work, but one that can be done by a great many Rangers who know that specific job better than you can. What only you can do is map the entirety of the Karag beyond the defenders, and to ensure the information is as current as possible you'll do so after you return from Stirland. You do, however, perform a few forays into the approaches to Karagril to make sure there's no unexpected surprises that might snare a Ranger but would be no difficulty to an incorporeal wizard, and pass on the information to Dreng for him to refine over the next few months. Your two underlings are put to work. Maximilian is given the daunting task of distilling the massive amount of information the Purge of the Haunted Hills gathered into something properly compiled, indexed, and analyzed. Johann is provided with a pile of spider corpses, several each of the Hunters and Web-Weavers and a single massive Egg-Layer. It had been nearing something similar but not quite the same as 'death by old age' that resisted all attempts to translate it, and its weight in goats had bought the corpse in what would have been an extremely fraught negotiation with any other race but was completely straightforward with the We. They did not see the corpse as one of them, they saw a worn-out and discarded component, valuable only for the nutrients that could have been recycled. --- The final matter to put to rest before Sylvania was the matter of your martial techniques. Branulhune was an amazing weapon and you itched to explore the possibilities that the Rune of the Unknown could allow for, but before you strike out into that unknown, you need to master the more conventional techniques common to all long blades. Once more you request Gunnars act as teacher and sparring partner both, and once more you try to reach the next plateau of sword-wielding ability. [Teaching: Martial, 22+??=??] [Learning: Martial, 75+20+7(Library: Greatswords)=102] You can't deny that Gunnars is extremely able with a blade, but once more proves a template to observe and learn from, rather than an active teacher. That he's evasive rather than taciturn when he doesn't want to share information is uncharacteristic for a Dwarf, but the end result is the same: you do a whole lot of talking for very little in response and learn basically nothing about the Priest of Gazul. But perhaps his lack of active instruction could be considered a benefit, because instead of rote learning of the techniques, you need to examine each as he performs them and spend the time and thought to grasp their purpose, allowing you to slot each neatly into your repertoire where they best serve instead of simply ticking them off a list. By the time you and Gunnars part ways once more, you feel you've developed a style entirely your own - part Empire Greatsword, part Order of the Guardians, and part entirely your own, which nobody weighed down by armour could replicate. The strengths of both have merged and should prove especially advantageous against enemies made predictable by bloodthirstiness or an inability to think, such as Orcs, Beastmen, and most Undead. It would also be a nightmare to face when there existed no possibility of flanking or circling, such as tunnel-fighting or holding a choke-point. You're very satisfied with the progress you've made, and can barely wait to unleash both it and your new sword on any enemy foolish enough to give you the opportunity. [Skill acquired: Advanced Greatswords] [Trait acquired: Master Swordswoman] --- Once more, gyrocopters ferry you and a squad of Hammerers to Stirland, and the populace of Fort Redemption are no less awestruck than that of Wurtbad. Roswita seems less stilted in her greeting to you, which you take as a good sign, and once the onlookers are dismissed and you tell her the reason for your presence it takes more than a moment for her to respond, and the waver in her voice as she speaks the almost-ritual phrases of a grateful Elector Count communicates more than her words do. The idea that maybe she won't die in the coming months is a new one to her, and she might need some time to come to terms with it. [Initial once-over: Intrigue, 43+19+5(Strategy: Undead)+6(Library: Vampires)=73] Roswita goes about her business as usual, albeit with a squad of Hammerers within shouting distance and your own careful eye trailing behind. For the first time you've flipped your coin to the face of the Night Prowler, and the effect is as subtle as it is potent. You're definitely still visible, as people avoid bumping into you and the friendlier folks nod a greeting as you pass, but you don't get the stares you normally do. You're a face in the crowd, just one more person in the bustle of the Fort and the surrounding sprawl of tents, shanties, and even a few proper buildings that have sprung up around Stirland's forward base for the Sylvania campaign. The effect even seems to extend to animals, or perhaps only to those that aren't just animals, as a crow with a swirl of Dhar where the Ghur of a wild animal should be fails to react to your presence until you skewer it with a shadowchisel. That goes some way to lowering the chance of Roswita's imminent demise, and answers a few questions. The crow was clearly living up until you made it otherwise, even if its long-term health would have suffered from the Dhar that controlled it. As a Vampire Alkharad would have no trouble overpowering the animals he collected, but if he could ensnare them while alive he wouldn't need to, and could kill them in a way that kept the corpse as intact as possible for the spells that would reanimate it. It also explained how he would know of Roswita's movements with enough time to prepare an ambush when she decided to visit Eight Peaks. The literature surrounding Vampires suggested they had a certain amount of influence over certain creatures, though it wasn't clear whether this was the result of an unusual application of necromancy or some inherent trait of the species. You consider telling Roswita, but decide against it for now. It would make her slightly safer if her soldiers knew to keep the Fort clear of corvids, but could also delay any imminent attacks until the passage of time forced you to move on. --- [Week 1 observations: Learning, 65+26+10(Windsage)=101] As Roswita rides out to personally settle some dispute about the recent sale of parts of the Hunter's Hills, your parallel journey upon your Shadowsteed leads you to exactly what you're looking for. You hone in on the foul smell/feel/taste of necromancy just as it begins to gather, and watch from a safe distance as what appears to be no more than a smear of foul magic floating in midair expands into the silhouette of what looks like a withered corpse dressed in the puffy trousers and waistcoat that would have been fashionable for an Altdorf noble in the Time of the Three Emperors. The ability to transform into mist is one that the less reliable books ascribed to Vampires, and you'd assumed it was a misunderstanding of the ones that wield Ulgu rather than the necromancy they were known for, but it seems there's more to it. You stalk the silhouette as it beelines through the scrub, passing unimpeded through thorned bushes and leaving a trail of wilting branches and dead leaves. Your Aethyric Armour renders you as immune to the thorns as the silhouette's incorporeality does, and you leave your Shadowsteed behind as you follow the trail into the cave that the bushes concealed, taking a moment to wrap yourself in Substance of Shadow as you leave the sunlight. And just in time too, as the first alarmed bat flies through your incorporeal form and out into the sunlight, panicked by the intruder. You do your best to ignore the stream of other bats doing the same as you push through the cave until it opens up into an open chamber, and the cause of the bats' alarm is clear as the silhouette moves with clearly unnatural speed, flitting around the chamber and jabbing fingers of Dhar into the largest specimens. "This will do," the being says, a strange echo to his voice. "Take one each. One at a time, in order of seniority. I'm watching you, Andrei." Alternately guiding and chiding, the voice walks an unseen class through the process of reanimation, and one by one the slain bats twitch jerkily upright, flapping wings experimentally. Even the largest of them only has a wingspan the length of your arm, and in total fourteen corpses are waiting for the attention of the unseen necromancers. A bat swarm was a tricky enemy, but with Roswita escorted by a score of Gustav's outriders on top of her normal escort, this can barely be considered an attempt on her life. But the lesson unfolding before you adds a new meaning to it. He wasn't just harrying Roswita, Alkharad was training his disciples. As the penultimate corpse jerks to life, the silhouette dissolves and flows into the final corpse, which jerks to life with much greater speed and grace than the others. You watch the flock take flight, flap experimentally around the cave, and then fly in formation out of it, and you have to resummon your Shadowsteed and ride with all speed to watch the attempted assassination unfold. The bats fly in formation rather than in the normal chaotic swarm, but Roswita bisects the first with a Dwarven boarding axe and the others swerve aside to avoid her blow. With the element of surprise lost, the Outriders make quick work of the others, plucking them out of the sky with deadly accuracy. --- [Week 2 observations: Learning, 97+26+10(Windsage)+10(previous crit)=143] A second attempt unfolds as Roswita rides to Siegfriedhof, and once more you're able to witness the entire process from start to finish. Though it is obligingly shrouded in shadows, Hunger Wood is not home to any wholesome wildlife, and instead a lurking pack of ghouls are slain one by one by the apparition, and once more the twisted lesson unfolds. With their twisted forms already home to Dhar, ghouls are both more receptive to necromancy but also less predictable in their responses to it. As you watch the beasts rise back to their feet and have their muscles begin to bulge with unnatural energies, you frown to yourself in thought. The bats were barely a threat, but ghouls were nasty enemies even without the benefit of necromantic empowerment, their teeth and claws practically guaranteeing infection from the slightest wound. You resolve to intervene, and watch closely until the most precarious moment and then interrupt with the slightest jolt of Ulgu, which disperses within moments of its work being done. "Doina," the voice scolds as the ghoul that was rising to its feet shudders as Dhar runs rampant through it. "I know you know better than that. What just happened?" Whatever answer the apparition gets, it doesn't satisfy it, and it reaches out and squeezes the unlife from one of the previously-raised ghouls in frustration. "Just put a rag over it until it stops bleeding! Next up, let's go." Another well-timed nudge, another spell tears itself free of its owner's control. "Ionuţ! Someone check the chart, I'm sure he's on his last chance." One of the ghouls crumples, presumably as its controller abandons it to consult said chart. "That's what I thought. Hold him down- I said hold him! If I have to come over there myself-" The rest of the reanimated ghouls crumple and the silhouette shrinks back in on itself, and as soon as it is reduced to the size of a fist, it shoots off into the sky, heading east. --- [Week 3 observations: Learning, 50+26+10(Windsage)+50(previous crits)=136] Perhaps he'd grown suspicious, perhaps he was merely fortunate, but the third manifestation of Alkharad was shrouded in the lingering energies of a recent battlefield. But knowing exactly what to look for means that even if you didn't catch it at first, by the time the stag had been reanimated and the group had moved on to the other deer, you were watching. The apparition is carefully watching each corpse as it reanimates, but a handful of deer don't merit you risking your observations, so you let the lesson unfold without any interruptions, confirming the mental notes you'd previously taken and pay closer attentions to the process of empowerment that the creatures undergo. Part of you winces at the thought of adding another paper to the to-do list, but as far as you know these capabilities are unknown to the Empire. --- You'd grown familiar enough with the sensation that it requires no actual attention on your part to notice the final manifestation of Alkharad, and the final lesson you witness adds an unexpected twist as the Vampire walks his students through the process of splitting their attention between two corpses at once. One day, that could prove a dangerous ability, but as you watch the ravens stagger about and attempt again and again to take wing, you're fairly confident that today is not that day. Alkharad eventually tires of the spectacle, instructs his students to release their hold on their second raven, and once more a necromantic flock takes wing to give the Outriders some practice. You've seen enough. Time to start investigating the other side of these events. --- You've never seen a more miserable town that wasn't being actively bombarded. Teufelheim's walls are lined with the corpses of wolves and bears and mountain lions, preserved by Dhar and ready to be animated at the slightest whim of the town's master - and their unceasing gaze is turned inward, not outward. Under a thousand glassy stares, a terrified populace do their best to scratch a living from the forests, hunters searching despondently for an animal not already slain and reanimated, woodsmen trying to decide which tree is least rotten, miners venturing out in groups in the faint hope that numbers will protect them against the terrible beasts of the mountains. The tiny strip of land between the Templa and the forests barely supplies enough food to sustain life, and from the hundred conversations you observe unnoticed, the populace are forbidden from crossing the river to access the unforested lands of the counties of Drakenhof or Waldenhof. The river flows fast and cold and deep, and the bridge is watched over by the rigid corpse of what must be a terrorgheist, a bat grown so large as to rival the size of dragons. However, not all in Teufelheim are miserable. Instead of the burghers and nobility of a more typical town, the upper class is populated by those wearing black robes that you suspect are deliberately aping those of the Colleges of Magic. It seems Alkharad takes disciples by the score, and when they're not learning the twisted art of necromancy they're lording their status over the locals and using it to claim what little wholesome food and petty luxuries trickle in from the few traders bold or stupid enough to try to find a profit in the most cursed corners of an already cursed land, and at the slightest pretext or even none at all, they take control of the nearest beast carcass and use it to wound or terrify whoever has displeased them. But not kill, which is easier said than done when attacking someone with a resurrected predator. Presumably they don't have that right. You're getting a feel for Alkharad's personality, and you barely bother to trail the necromancers to confirm that the keep in the center of town is where they're based out of. Ranald's Coin gets you to the portcullis, Doppelganger gets you through it, and the predictably lacking lighting inside it allows Substance of Shadow to remove all but the slightest chance of detection as you flit through the structure. Almost every room has preserved corpses, and it seems only the choicest specimens receive the honour of being displayed in the keep. You peruse a shockingly diverse museum of death complete with tarnished brass plaques. A chimera, a pair of rhinoxen, griffons and hippogryphs and demigryphs, a herd of pegasi... dozens of magnificent beasts reduced to trophies and weapons. And in a dusty room lined with rotting scrolls, the remains of what appears to be a long-abandoned attempt to piece a dragon skeleton together, which from the surviving notes seems to have been foiled by the bones being from three different dragons, and even cumulatively not being enough for an entire skeleton. You contemplate the massive skull, and are glad that he failed. [Infiltration: Intrigue, 51+19=70] While an incredibly useful spell, Substance of Shadow does have limitations, and one of which is that to sufficiently honed Magesight, the spell itself is visible even though the caster is not. The disciples that reside in the ground floor of the keep are far from this level, but those of the dungeons are those more favoured by Alkharad and thus given more detailed tuition. So you compound your magical concealment with more mundane methods, sneaking on silent feet through the basement of the keep, and play it safe by withdrawing if any of the necromancers seem even slightly alarmed. With painstaking care, you map every inch of one sublevel, then another, then a third. Conversation after conversation adds to your knowledge of the happenings of this dark corner of the Empire, and even though most of them are dedicated to petty infighting and backstabbing, useful information can be plucked from them like flakes of gold from alluvial soil. The picture that emerges is clear: Alkharad has been collecting disciples since the earliest successes of the Purge of the Haunted Hills. His primary intention is the projection of power, both in his harrying of Roswita and in his skirmishes with the other Vampires that have emerged of late, but in the process he's turned Teufelheim into a College of Necromancy. The correct response to this is ride hell for leather for Altdorf and have a quiet but intense word with someone who'll have a quiet but intense word with someone else who'll have a quiet but intense word with the Emperor, and from that point on it's all armies on the march and unleashing the sort of wizards that have made it their life goal to redefine scorched earth. But you've seen first-hand how much time it takes to assemble such an army, and how slow that march actually is, and in the time that takes a significant number of the necromancers would surely scatter and become the nightmares of future years. Sometimes a scalpel today is better than a hammer tomorrow. And if the odds turn against you, you could leave and then contact Altdorf. [Start slitting throats: Intrigue, 41+19=60] The pettier necromancers are the easiest targets, and the town is full of places where a body can be stashed and the air is thick with rot anyway. You whisper a silent apology to Ranald for using the Coin to this end, just in case - Ranald frowns on unnecessary violence, but on the topic of necessary violence he's much more sanguine. The Coin seems to have restrictions similar to Take No Heed, in that actions that draw attention to yourself disrupt whatever effect is causing you to be overlooked, but as soon as the corpses are stashed and your shadowchisel banished, the effect resumes as though it never left. [Moving down a level: Intrigue, 11+19=30] You're not as fast with the scattered necromancers as you'd like, and by the time you've returned to the keep the air is thick with tension and the necromancers huddle in worried groups, speculating on the various disappearances, and despite embracing necromancy they remain human so they've lit candles and stoked fires to banish their nervousness. You do your best with the situation in front of you, but the wrong door opens at the wrong time and you're not quite fast enough to prevent the cry of alarm in the instant before chisel meets throat. The chorus of dying gurgles and the yells and footsteps of rapidly approaching necromancers is the sound of failure, and with a scowl you reach out and crush the nearest candle in your fist. [Prepare for company: Learning, 18+26=44] It's not enough. A fire's roaring nearby and lanterns line the corridors, and you barely have the seconds to wrap yourself in Aethyric Armour before the first necromancer rounds the corner, eyes widening as he spots you. [Round One: Fight! Martial, 93+33=126 vs 35+10=45] Fine. With a thought Branulhune is in your hand, and the first necromancer barely has a chance to realize how doomed he is before it's shearing through ribs as easily as flesh. The ones following behind try to screech to a halt, but you're already approaching before they even manage to turn and with negligent ease Branulhune tears through each one. You had hoped that Kragg would bestow his Rune upon your sword when you made your request, but you'd imagined it as a behemoth of brute strength. You'd underestimated him. Every impact imparts exactly as much force as is required, and even if you weren't magically inured to fatigue the sword's smooth movement through bone and viscera would allow for more sustained combat than a clumsier Rune that delivered bone-juddering impacts with every swing. Like a vengeful ghost, but actually the complete opposite of a vengeful ghost, you orbit the memorized halls of the Keep, ensuring anyone that sees enough to go from alarmed to raising the alarm then swiftly passes into the next life. The cries of alarm end before long, and you find yourself once more shrouded in silence, and you're actually taken aback. Thick stone floors, you realize. Nobody above this level is alive to hear anything, and nobody below it can hear anything. You frown to yourself as you reluctantly wipe clean and resheath Branulhune, and swap your spells of battle for ones of concealment once more as you resume your grim descent. [Advanced disciples: Intrigue, 96+19=115] Sure enough, the penultimate tier of Alkharad's disciples remain engrossed in dissections, meditations, and murmured conversation. You interrupt the first two, and spend some time contemplating the third until you realize you can encompass the three of them in the arc of a single swing of Branulhune. A single level remains, one you didn't scout because you didn't fancy sharing a room with a centuries-old Vampire until you were ready to go all in, no matter what spells cloaked you. You spend some time debating on the stairs, but in the end you didn't want to put much stock in the hope that a centuries-old Necrarch Vampire with a proven track record of novel magic use would have poor Magesight, and instead you pour energy into your shadow until it lashes about eagerly, ready to taste blood once more. [Alkharad's readiness to receive guests: 38] [Mathilde vs Alkharad: Martial, 88+23=101 vs 87+28=105] You'd pictured him leading another assassination attempt on Roswita, but even if preparations were required that would only take a fraction of the Vampire's time. He's currently hunched over a lectern, muttering to himself as he peruses the book, and you make your decision in an instant. There's unlikely to be a better scenario than this. You approach to within a meter of him but between the swing and the impact he moves, and he hisses in surprise as three of his fingertips fly across the room from his attempt at parrying your blade. "You're not-" he begins, then interrupts himself. "A Grey? But..." His eyes flick down to your belt, and then to your sword. "The famous Mathilde Weber." Sustained by pure Dhar instead of blood, Necrarchs wither to a corpselike appearance. Alkharad is no exception, and the clothes of the Altdorf nobility of years past that he dresses in only highlights his inhumanity. "Alkharad," you say, only paying the scantest fraction of attention to your words as you watched for any hint of assault or spell. "I've a spot on my shelf picked out just for you." "I don't suppose you're at all tempted by the arts of necromancy?" he asks, as casually as if he was offering you a drink at a bar - but he remains poised to act and his severed fingers are skittering across the floor to rejoin the rest of him. "I've had better offers," you respond. [Mathilde vs Alkharad 2: Martial, 1+23=24 vs 56+28=84.] Speed, you think as a fraction of second extends to a lifetime as the creature ducks under your blade and extends yellowed fingernails towards your gut. Are all Vampires this fast? Or does Alkharad excel? In a grotesque mirror of your blade, his fingernails punch through Aethyric Armour and your robe and your skin and your intestines and don't meet a scrap of resistance they can't immediately overcome, and agony floods through you as his talons tear open what you can only assume is your liver. Branulhune slips from your hands, and the part of your mind not occupied by agony begins to recalculate. [Alkharad's magical spot check: Learning, 17+34=51.] "It's interesting," he says, as he pulls his hand free from your torso, examining the blood and viscera clinging to it curiously, not noticing or not caring about the mirror of your wound that has appeared in his stomach, carving through organs he needs much less than you do yours. "Alive, you'd be useful. Dead, you'd be obedient. But if I can suspend you right in the middle..." He leans close, filling your fading vision with his hideous visage. Your Magesight remains clear, and you can see Dhar leaping to his will, and a tendril of hideous magic extends from his bloodied hand and reaches towards you to try to enslave your soul right on the cusp of death... And is met with the full force of Dwarven indignance. Alkharad howls in agony as fire burns inside his skull, and with your last scrap of willpower you allow the nonsense words of a Jade Enchantress' whimsy to trigger the seed in your palm. In the strange sensation of painlessness where you know there should be pain, vines burrow through muscle and veins up your arm and into your torso, and bark grows over the gaping hole in your abdomen as your intestines are unscrambled and your liver knitted back together. By the time you pull yourself back to your feet, Alkharad is doing the same, smoke pouring from his nose and ears. "That," he pants. "Was incredibly stupid of me." "That makes two of us," you admit. "Don't suppose you'll call it a draw?" "No." "Good. I wouldn't have honoured it." [Mathilde vs Alkharad 3: Martial, 47+23=70 vs 7+28=35] He feints low, then feints high, then actually goes left. You're impressed that he bothered when you didn't have a sword in your hands, and you almost regret that a thought is all it takes to change that and sever the gore-slick hand that darted forward once more and send it flying across the room. "What the hell did you do for them?" he asks, frowning at your sword, paying no heed to the stump where his arm used to be. "Oh, you know. Settled some Grudges. Reconquered a Karak." "Which one?" "Eight Peaks." "And I thought my neighbours were bad." [Mathilde vs Alkharad 4: Learning, 83+26=109 vs 76+34=110] A moment before it's too late, you spot the stirring of Dhar within the vortex of it that a Vampire resembles to Magesight, and with an effort of will deflect the projectiles that fly from Alkharad's eyes, spinning off into the room behind you... [Mathilde vs Alkharad 5: Martial, 57+23=80 vs 11+28=39] ...and effortlessly cleave through Vampiric flesh to send the other arm flying, taking the energies of the second spell Alkharad was shaping with it. You look at him as he looks down at himself, and he sighs. [Spite against you vs spite against others: 51 vs 66] "Okay," he says. "Mihnea in Mikalsdorf doesn't actually know any magic, he just uses rings and sceptres. Ioana in Waldenhof never learned how to control bats, she just calls them before a battle and hopes it convinces the enemy not to try anything in the air. And Gabriella died back in '62, and a mortal pretended to be her for years." "Do you think I'll show you mercy for information?" He snorts. "Of course not. I just hate them. Tell everyone about Gabriella, that would really eat at them." "Why are you so casual about this?" you can't help but ask. He smiles. "I'm a Vampire. Sure, you'll keep a close eye on my remains. Will your children? Your children's children? For me, tomorrow will be a new world, full of new beasts and new magics and people that have forgotten what I can do." Branulhune cleaves through neck and spine, and does nothing to remove the smile that remains on Alkharad's withered lips. --- With anyone in the keep that could animate the local beast carcasses disposed of, you send a Marsh Light up into the sky, and within minutes the comforting sound of a wing of approaching gyrocopters fills your ears. Along with the head of Alkharad, you've also piled up your chosen loot from the tower. Unfortunately your cargo space is limited, and no doubt the second you leave, the local populace will descend upon the now-defenceless keep and strip it of valuables. You've had to burn the books you'll be leaving behind to prevent them from disappearing into the local population. The two with the most votes will be kept. [ ] Dragonbone. [ ] Gold and jewels. [ ] Proof of the 'College of Necromancy'. [ ] Detailed trade ledgers. [ ] Books on Necromancy and the Undead. [ ] Books on Vampires and Dhar. [ ] Books on Shyish and death gods. - Reminder that when I say 'you can only pick X amount because [reason]', it's not an invitation for cunning plans to actually get all of them. - The remainder of the turn will continue in the next update. - The Proof item would raise eyebrows throughout Altdorf and significantly boost your reputation among the Empire's leadership. - The Trade Ledgers would send a great many merchants to the pyres who betrayed humanity and the Empire by enriching the Undead, and their wealth and belongings would be forfeit. This will weaken the remaining town-dwelling Vampires, enrich Stirland, and leave a vacuum the EIC could step neatly into. - On the subject of anti-Vampire-reconstitution plans: the Witch Hunters have tried them all. There's a reason they keep Vlad locked up under the Grand Cathedral instead of doing something complicated and elaborate with his remains. Keeping it on your mantle and bopping it with a Dispel if it tries to regrow skin is the least bad plan, and there are entire rooms and Perpetual Apprentices dedicated to this in the Amethyst College.

Turn 26: Echoes Of Genocide (Part Three)

Spoiler: Voted Plan

[X] Plan: Step 4 Is Profit
-[X] Strategic Path For Initial Phase
--[X] Reclamation First
-[X] Strategic Path For Next Phase
--[X] Retake
---[X] Kuru, then Matsuya
----[X] 1st and 10th Fleet, Justinius Probalis, Gabriel Angelos, Apollo Diomedes, Honor Guard
---[X] Avanti, then Vatsa
----[X] 2nd and 4th Fleet, Hannibal Palrun, Nero Gracchus
--[X] Middle
---[X] All ground forces
-[X] Next Phase
--[X] Interdict
---[X] 1st, 4th and 10th Fleets, 4th Company
--[X] Continued Bombardment
---[X] 2nd Fleet
--[X] Top
--[X] During first two steps Librarius will concentrate on predicting the actions of the Suysh and where their defenses are the weakest. During 3rd step, they will concentrate on locating the enemy Queens and if their connection to the rest of the Hive is psychic and if it can be disrupted.
--[X] Vehicles and unassigned specialists to be distributed equally amongst battle groups.

Echoes of Genocide
+065.M42+ To +070.M42+
+Through The Foe's Obliteration Do We Earn Salvation+

When the Blood Ravens finally emerged from the warp, they did not advance immediately. The temperament of their Master of Fleets notwithstanding, there was reconnaissance work to be done before making any major moves. The last reports of the Deathwatch were by now far too old to rely on for surety. Auspex scans went out across the system, probes flitting forth and sending back information to be collected and analyzed. All four planets, for a start, remained as they were. Roiling industry existed across their surfaces, the result of years of Suyush habitation and construction, while above them floated the orbital defense platforms and Suyush-crafted shipyards as was expected. Elsewhere, the Sacred Crown space station slowly rotated in the void. A transport fleet of Suyush ships likely laden with war material and supplies was still berthed around it, while a squadron of Suyush cruisers floated about it as protectors. Its defenses were known to be formidable, with macro batteries and lance turrets aplenty – though it was unlikely any of its launch bays still held Imperial fighters or bombers. All of this was expected.

However.

To the surprise of all those present over the tactical table, holo-picts of the system flickering in the dim light, was a rather glaring change to the information the Blood Ravens had been given. Two changes, in fact.

An entire quadrant of the Sacred Crown’s defenses had been turned to slag, battle scars obvious even from long distance auspex scans. The cruisers present around the station themselves showed battle damage that was, just as the space station’s wounds, something all-together unexpected. Specifically, thanks to the fact that even cursory auspex scans, joined with the ability of the Librarius to peer beyond the confines of their ships, was proof enough that the wounds suffered presently were far too recent. The last Deathwatch incursion attempt had been an entire year ago, while the patchwork repairs done thus far to station and guardians was only a few weeks old. More pertinently, the battle damage was recognizable, especially to Hadrian upon the command throne, his mind linked with the cogitators of the Omnis Arcanum.

It was damage dealt by the exact same munitions that an astartes strike cruiser was capable of.

“Any further identifying characteristics possible? Debris? Signal ghosts? Anything?” Gabriel called up to Hadrian.

The Captain had nothing to give in return but grit teeth and a shaking head.

“I’m sorry, Chapter Master,” Hadrian snarled quietly. “There’s nothing.”

Only then did Gabriel turn his gaze to Justinius. Words were not needed. Blinking, on the other hand, was, as psychic light began to emanate from the Chief Librarian’s eyes that quickly advanced from luminous to blinding temporarily. The air that puffed out from his lips was as a chilling fog, while in the extreme faint distance a small crackle of lightning and thunder could be heard despite the atmospheric controls on the bridge. The serfs on the bridge did their best to cringe away from the display of psyker powers, turning away and hunching over their consoles. Words that simply could not be understood were murmured in a language that was not built on pure linguistics, all the while the Chief Librarian reached out with one hand in the vague direction of the station.

Peering Through The Veil: 22
Then he blinked with the lights illuminating his eyes fading away. The crawling sensations suffered by just about everyone else present bled away as well. Justinius sighed and pinched at the bridge of his nose, attempting to staunch the faint trickle of blood.

“I cannot pierce the veil enough to grant us answers. All I see is old dust and blood, a cloud of it blocking me.”

Frowns abounded amongst the Blood Ravens, then, but they had little time to delay. The moment their ships had entered the system, the auspex scans were showing the xeno ships and forces beginning to react to their presence. Defensive positions were being built up on the planets, stations brought to full readiness, the enemy ships coming to full wakefulness. Thankfully, it appears that the sheer time between incursions by the Imperium has lulled them into a slight sense of false security. Not nearly as much as it should be, since apparently someone was just here, but their ships are scattered throughout the system. Even their battleship is not at the Sacred Crown, apparently instead over the world of Vatsa.

“Very well,” Gabriel said calmly. “Prepare yourselves, brothers. Our first primary objective is the reclamation of the station. There, we will be able to investigate at first hand.”

================================================

Assault And Boarding
89 vs. 36

For too long, had the Suyush held this system. They’d taken it and moved on to other Imperial systems before anything could be done, and they’d resisted the piecemeal Deathwatch insertions since. But they had, in this battlezone at least, never faced so much force concentrated at them. Turning to face the foe, their strange rock-like hulls and inhuman oblong shapes made them appear as if almost squeezed asteroids than anything else. But the weapon systems were obvious, as were the engines on the back. They were certainly ugly, but with it they carried a visible menace upon the tactical screens. It was easy to see how they had repeatedly proven themselves equals to the Imperial Navy, their speed and weaponry making it possible to peel open or melt holes in the hulls so that their ravenous kind could flood the innards of any ship from escort to battleship.

But they did not face the Imperial Navy here.

They faced the Blood Ravens.

Bombardment cannons fired at the longest possible ranges, while caestus assault rams prepared themselves for boarding. The xeno answered with all of their alien fury, yet they were not prepared for the leap forwards that the strike cruisers performed. Before heat-cannons and thermal wave blasts could even be turned on, the Blood Ravens had already shot past, their own boarding parties crashing into their hulls. Apollo Diomedes battered aside a dozen of this new foul alien race in the time it took them to realize he was even there. On another ship, the new captain of the 2nd Company fired his weapon down a corridor, incinerating an entire incoming wave of Suyush defenders. While the ships tried to turn about to fire upon and launch their own boarding parties against the faster space marine ships, the battle barges turned wide and fired broadside after broadside against their foes.

Upon the Sacred Crown itself, the 10th Company landed in great numbers, their scouts disappearing into its depths. Within the hour hundreds of aliens lay dead, whether they were newborn or hearty hungerers, slaughtered in all a manner of methods. By knife to throat, mine, detonation pack, ambush with high powered shotgun blasts, and more. The Suyush, in turn, were forced to turn about, trying to reinforce their failing control of the station even as their ships began to come to a stuttering halt in the void above. Crude void shield systems met melta bombs, while heat cannon reactors were sabotaged and set to erupting. One xeno cruiser practically fell apart as its own weaponry was turned inwards and overcharged, its hull and crew melting as one misshapen mass while the Blood Ravens turned to the thunderhawks and left the dead foe behind.

Reclamation
66 vs. 41

The alien fought back, for this was their newly claimed domain, but they could not resist the advance no matter how many bodies they threw forth. More and more of the ships around the Sacred Crown died, reduced to husks from their slaughtered crews and destroyed vital systems, nothing less than perfect targets for the Blood Raven fleet. Elsewhere, across the system, the Suyush pushed their engines into whatever it was they called the redline, while the Omnis Arcanum and other ships began to pick up an alien vox transmission. It took a moment for the servitors and cogitators to solve the differences in broadcasting and receiving in time for a voice to come across the vox broadcast on a widely general band. The source, unsurprisingly, is from the Suyush vessel type classified by Imperial observers over the past few years as a ‘Scorchnest’ Battleship. Which is where, apparently, the queen is.

“-and know that you too will suffer the rage of Prexis Void-Slake! My brood shall slaughter you, and eat you all! Your blood will feed my children, your meat will be mine to take! MY! MEAT! MY! MEAT! MY! ME-”

Her voice is a disgusting squeal of insectile chitters and reptilian hisses, all of it rendered as booming thunder.

But for the Suyush upon the station itself, there was no queen to guide them perfectly other than in engendering their rage and aggression. However, there were still many hungerers present, their pheromone signature that of Queen Void-Slake, and thus they carried her authority. But as the battle went on, they found that for once there were true elites for them to battle against, and that while a particularly resilient guardsman was a worthy meal, space marines were a far hardier meal to grasp. Over five hundred Blood Ravens had invaded the Sacred Crown within a day of the chapter’s arrival in-system, their information more than sufficient enough to plant them in effective range of the station. Either the Suyush didn’t possess the capability to move the station, or the desire, or some combination of the two. Years of records were more than enough to paint a preference to claim territory and hold it to bypass the resource usage it would take to build their own.

Locking It Down
50 vs. 45

The Chapter Master would be the one to take the strategium, the very tip of the spear to slaughter the last of the hungerers present. Elsewhere across the station, larders of cooked and preserved meat would be discovered, a great many of the hunks still possessing the uniforms they’d died in. Weapon stocks were found as well. A great amount of techno-heresy had been performed, to the utter outrage of the techmarines once they began to examine the systems of the station left behind. The foul Suyush had begun forcibly integrating their technologies, turning pristine monitoring and communication systems into horrible amalgams of alien tech. Imperial reactors, turned to Suyush desires and specifications. All for them to keep the Sacred Crown working as its original purpose, only for new masters. Martellus himself was able to, even on a cursory examination, tell that they’d been coordinating mining and refining work across the rest of the system. They even still possessed the old networked connection to the orbital defense stations. The 10th Company had found the Suyush trying to sabotage the station when they knew they would lose it, to disable weapon systems, void shielding, and most importantly, the central reactor complex. With the latter’s damage or destruction, the station would be left utterly defenseless, or worse, be torn apart entirely.

But as the 10th Company began to scour every nook and cranny, they also sought information.

===============================================

Computer Evidence: 2
Scouts Evidence: 40

“Chapter Master, you’re going to want to see this,” Martellus called as he tore away the Suyush computers for scrapping, revealing the far humbler and much more natural Imperial cogitators and monitors beneath.

Gabriel glanced at him from across the strategium, nodding once, before returning to his conversation with Apollo. The formerly disgraced champion saluted and marched off to continue purging the station. Martellus listened to the command vox line, even though most of his mind was not focused on it, and felt some part of him grow warm with the knowledge that so many more of the xenos were dying. Their abuse of the holy machine angered him deeply. Especially considering the conditions that he’d found a great many of the cogitator banks. Behind him, he heard the steps of terminator armor announcing Gabriel’s arrival.

“What is it, Martellus?”

“This is the cogitator bank that held a certain amount of the data scanning records of the station. The Suyush deleted the information on a great many, but not all. This one,” Martellus thumped his fist on it, making the entire half-melted bank shake. “Contained the ones most pertinent to that one blasted area of the station.”

Gabriel frowned, the metal of his bionics making the otherwise mild expression twist into a far more menacing grimace. Or perhaps he really was grimacing. It was not always easy for Martellus to tell. Turrets, he could understand just from a glance. Most machines, from examinations. For everything else, it was a bit more difficult. But in this case, there was certainly something unhappy about it, considering that the cogitator was melted and practically slag. The Suyush computers that had been placed on top of it for purely practical reasons of needing the space.

“This one’s damage…it’s older?”

Martellus nodded rapidly.

“This was not done by our weapons, Chapter Master. But it is consistent with plasma gun damage, not with Suyush weaponry.”

“Curious indeed,” Gabriel’s frown deepened as he pondered the issue. “It was destroyed purposefully, then. To keep the identities of those fighting secret?”

Would the Inquisition send a force ahead of the Blood Ravens, and then go through the effort of removing their presence? The Tarquindil had been helpful thus far, but she was yet an Inquisitor Lord. Gabriel did not doubt for a second that she would authorize such a mission for some reason or another that she would not share even on pain of death. It was the way of their kind, and while he could respect it, there was a certain flare of irritation that she would do such a thing. Another Deathwatch force? Some other astartes Chapter contacted? Or, Gabriel wondered, if the astartes present were loyalists at all. It was known that many a chaos space marine did not care for the xeno races. It would be entirely within the capabilities of that sort of foe to wish their presence concealed, lest they be discovered by the Inquisition’s agents.

“Chapter Master,” Cyrus spoke lowly across the vox, his greetings punctuated by the crack-boom of his sniper rifle, “Do you have a moment?”

“What is it, Cyrus?”

===================================

“We’ve found something, in an abandoned area. It appears to have been…looted, before we arrived. Fuel supplies, heavy weaponry, and the like.”

Despite the years of Suyush occupation, this storage area had apparently still been worth raiding. There was no proof, really, of what had been stored here, but Cyrus knew that it had possessed some appreciable amount of war material. But more importantly were the signs of battle that had led here. Bolter scoring on the walls, yet to be repaired by the Suyush. A deep carved portion of a wall that had most certainly been dealt by some power weapon or another. There were faint bloodstains that had led them there, all of them being very, very old and also Suyush in origin. Whoever had come through here had suffered few to no casualties while dealing a great many to the Suyush in turn. Then they had taken what they wanted.

“Any evidence as to their identity? Deathwatch? Loyalist? Traitor?”

“Unfortunately…,”

Cyrus bent down and picked up a bolter shell left in a corner, a scant handful of weeks’ worth of dust on it. He rolled it about in his fingers before pocketing it and snapping his fingers to gather the rest of his scouts. There was nothing more to be done here, nothing more to be found. There yet remained a number of Suyush alive. That would have to be resolved within the next few days, otherwise the Blood Ravens would never be able to properly say that they had truly retaken the station. It was not quite the same as being on a Kill Team, or being a Kill Marine, but personally, Cyrus enjoyed having so many more brothers on-hand rather than not.

==========================

Remaining Functionality
87

Luckily, despite there being over five hundred Blood Ravens assaulting the station, there was remarkably not nearly as much damage dealt to the station’s infrastructure than estimated. Not to say there wasn’t any damage, of course. There was a significant portion of the station that had been destroyed, and evidence of whoever the other astartes were causing notable internal damages. But for the most part, the Suyush had tried to restore what damage had been dealt, and had done their best not to destroy what they required. There were even a number of weapons systems that the Suyush had not really known how to utilize themselves due to the differences in operation requirements. Of course, without maintenance for so long meant that restoring them to functionality was another thing entirely…

Techmarine Restoration
93

And yet, it was done. Martellus personally took charge of the frantic restoration efforts, pulling servitors aplenty from the ships and bringing his entire tarantula turret compliment to stock the station’s internal defenses. By the time the other Suyush ships arrived within effective combat range with the Sacred Crown, they were surprised to receive a salvo from the station’s reactivated lance batteries. Even with a fourth of its body turned to slag, the old beast had some claws left to it. Ones that its machine spirit, according to Martellus, was eager to use against the ones that had dared to turn it against its true masters for so long. Though its macro battery munitions had long been expended, and Martellus refused to do anything other than remove the grafted Suyush weapons on the hull, the lance batteries still burned hot and often.

Then the Chapter split once more, a number amongst the fleet for necessary boarding precautions. The rest, however, remained on station. Given the speed of their assault and reclamation, they had more than enough time to set up defensive positions across almost all vital areas. Neophytes grumbled at mining so many corridors, as compared to the ‘glorious’ combat that they’d been allowed to partake in it was drudgery, but none disobeyed. Gabriel Angelos, on the other hand, strode to the strategium and activated its communication systems once more, for it yet remained connected to the Suyush ships – simultaneously granting the Blood Raven fleet access to the enemy’s entire network due to the Suyush’s integration efforts.

It would have been better for the xeno if the Blood Ravens had been less skilled in taking the command centers, but under the wise predictions of the Librarius, such important assets had been preserved.

“Listen well, alien filth,” Gabriel growled across the system, staring ahead at the tactica-projector with its threat designator colorations restored to default. “I am Gabriel Angelos, Chapter Master of the Blood Ravens. I do not care what your name is, for soon enough it will be nothing more than a foot note in the chapter’s records. Your larders are, as we speak, being thrown to space. You will have no meat from us. The Sacred Crown is the Imperium’s property, now and forever. If you desire it back, if you wish to save your…meat,” he spat the word, “You will face us, here and now. Come, or don’t, and prove your cowardly nature for all in your brood to see.”

Alien Reclamation Attempt
88 vs. 5

There was silence, in response, but several of the Suyush ships only began to accelerate further. Behind, the Scorchnest twitched as it unleashed its innards, proving its nature as a massive carrier. Alien interceptors and transports ballooned around it before flying in a misshapen cloud towards the Sacred Crown. The Blood Raven fleet, on the other hand, remained back. Far back. The station was more than tough enough to weather the initial waves, and behind them the astartes vessels began to fire upon those Suyush ships approaching the station and chipping away at shield and hull alike. On the station itself, multiple boarding vectors had remained clear, simply to completely trap the passages just beyond. When the first of the xeno boarding transports arrived, some boring through the hull, others landing in the cleared out hangar bays, they found themselves torn apart by concentrated salvos from the 2nd Company and the entire tarantula array compliment of the forges.

It was, really, the first time the Blood Ravens had seen a more properly motivated Suyush rush, something which had caused entire Imperial Guard regiments to buckle. They were certainly less in number than any of said regiments, while the Suyush ranged from clawborn to hungerer elites. But they would not be found wanting. Heavy bolters and lascannons, grenades and mines, simple massed bolter fire, all these and more completely shredded a great many multitudes of the Suyush. Remarkably, however, this proved to only increase the bloodlust of the alien, their own cannibalistic natures showing themselves as a number of them died with bloody chunks of their brethren in their mouths. Others died, choking not just on their own blood but the bones of fellow Suyush stuffed in their cheeks.

In the void, the chapter fleet advanced quickly. The Omnis Arcanum split its power entirely to its engines and its fore shielding. Then, with Captain Hadrian personally helming it, the battle barge slammed its bulk into and through a Suyush cruiser while the rest of the fleet followed behind. Close range battery fire came afterwards, while boarding parties were teleported into the rest of the enemy ships. But they did not stop, their engines continuing to burn as the ships sped away, their deadly payloads delivered and their shields in need of regeneration. A smaller number of Suyush ships attempted to follow, while others began to push ever more of their kind onto the station as their ships began to come apart.

Frantic Assault
11 vs. 95

But numbers began to tell, as well as something that had been unexpected. With the Scorchnest approaching, it activated something that had, historically, not been proven to be common across similar vessels elsewhere across the sector. It possessed one of the rare Suyush teleportariums. Suddenly, there were a great many hungerers present across the Sacred Crown, some of the most elite troops the xenos possessed appearing deeper within behind the original defensive lines. Then, more worrisome, was the arrival of royal guard Suyush, hulking with scales as thick as dreadnought plate, tearing their way through the station’s forces. The Blood Ravens reacted as best as they could, but being struck from multiple directions at once still brought a great many low.

In one corridor, a scout’s scream cut off as their head was roasted red and their brain melting out of eye sockets boiled empty. In another, a newly promoted member of the 2nd Company bellowed in pain as a Suyush blade plunged into the ceramite and into their chest, while from behind another of the alien’s bit into their throat. A venerable tarantula turret fired until its ammo counter ran empty, and found itself turned to a pile of slag, its corpse stomped beneath Suyush clawed feet as they ran further in. Elsewhere, a small number of neophytes were forced to go for their combat knives as their position was overrun, only saved by the arrival of a single assault marine. While their elder was torn apart limb from limb, the neophytes were able to flee, though the sight of the sacrifice would require a strong session from a chaplain after the battle was over. All the while, Queen Void-Slake’s personal vessel approached closer and closer to the station. Cruisers were melting significant portions of the hull to allow greater concentrations of their troops through.

The Mechanicus would not be pleased.

Rally Assault + From Behind
57 vs. 15
82

They would tolerate the damages, however, so long as the station was in some way recoverable. Something the Blood Ravens sought to ensure. Before it could continue to menace a retreating tactical squad, one of the royal guard found itself battered into a wall by Apollo Diomedes, the duel that came after short-lived indeed. There was barely enough time to even recognize he had been there before the champion was elsewhere. In another section of the station, the Chief Librarian simply waved his hand and prove that the fires of his mind were hotter than the thermal weaponry of the alien. They barely even had time to scream before their very souls were consumed by the flames. In the void above, the Blood Ravens turned about at the sharpest possible angle that would not tear the hulls apart. They returned, then, to batter at the Suyush ships once more, retrieving boarders by teleportarium and sending them back out once they were resupplied.

But then came something else entirely.

At the edge of the battlezone, the warp tore open. From the immaterium came a strike cruiser with a handful of escort gladius frigates. Immediately, their engines fired them at full speed ahead, their macro weaponry firing upon the Suyush ships from behind. Even as the Blood Raven fleet crashed once more into their alien counterparts, the strike cruiser was flying past them towards the Sacred Crown. It moved too quickly to halt due to the positioning of the other ships, vox signals bouncing off of it as they refused to respond. Amongst the blood-slick corridors there was a flash of lightning and the crackling smell of tainted ozone, and reports began to flood into the reclaimed strategium of new space marines appearing within and opening fire on the Suyush.

“Unceasing Upon The Enemy!”

Gabriel paused as he heard the war cry, pausing as he lifted the head of his hammer from the still twitching corpse of one of the xeno royal guard. All around him, the rest of the honor guard kept their weapons at the ready even as the foreign astartes came around the corner. Their red and white armor was splattered with the gore of the alien, and yet they paused upon sighting the Chapter Master. For a moment, there was nothing more than a tense quiet, booms of warfare echoing in the distance. Then the red and white armored space marines hung back as their leader advanced, his power sword flickering in the dim lighting. The painted green laurels on the white of his helmet were chipped and battered.

“Greetings, brothers. I am Sergeant Turiel of the Scarlet Lions. I am glad to see fellow astartes. Has the Inquisition finally deigned to send us aid?”

Gabriel exchanged a look with Captain Laskaris before glancing back at the so-called sergeant.

“We were unaware of the Inquisition already contacting another chapter. They gave us much information, but nothing about you.”

Turiel simply snorted, holstering his bolt pistol as he did so. Behind him, the rest of the Scarlet Lions seemed to relax somewhat as well.

“That is unsurprising,” he responded dryly. “There is only one company of us granted to this assignment, much of our Chapter is currently embroiled in the fighting near Ultramar. We assaulted the station earlier, but our strike cruiser took damage as well. We had to retreat to lick our wounds for a time.”

“I…see.”

There was some truthfulness to his statement, or so Gabriel felt, but not wholly. But before he could bring his questions to the surface, one of the walls was melted to yellow sludge and a swarm of Suyush came pouring through. At their head was one of their royal guard, while those behind were of the hungerer elite. They howled and screeched at the interlopers, firing chest-mounted thermal cannons at close range while swiping about with their claws and biting with fangs that were impossible sharp. A pair of the Scarlet Lions died, while Captain Laskaris took a claw through the stomach while another member of the honor guard was sent flying backwards from a bone-shattering tail slap. But for all their fury, they faced some of the most elite of the Blood Ravens, and so within moments the battle was done.

“The Blood Ravens are as fierce as they say,” Turiel grunted as he pulled his sword out of an alien’s chest. “But we cannot wait here.”

“No, we cannot,” Gabriel agreed.

Silently, however, he was requesting that all Scarlet Lions were registered and logged by every Blood Raven battlegroup which encountered them. He had never heard of the chapter, but then there were rumored to be a thousand of them spread out across the Imperium. In truth, even he, as a Chapter Master himself, was aware of only a few hundred by name, much less by war cry or progenitor. So he watched, and listened, as nine full squads were reported across the Sacred Crown. Some were cooperating with the Blood Ravens, others simply rushing from fight to fight. One group had even teleported into the strategium where Martellus remained, only to depart soon after their identities were confirmed.

Finishing The Void Fight
72 vs. 24

In time, the enemy fleet was fully destroyed. None seemed to even consider retreat an option with a queen backing them. As for Queen Void-Slake herself, thankfully the alien teleportarium technology was not powerful enough to shift her bulk itself. The sudden introduction of a knight sized foe would have been troubling indeed, especially for the continued integrity of the station. Instead, she screamed and ranted as the Blood Ravens surrounded her ship, tearing it apart from part to part. When one ship’s void shielding broke or failed, they would pull back and be shielded by another vessel. In this revolving bombardment schedule, the Blood Raven ships avoided considerable amounts of damage. At the same time, on the Chapter Master’s orders, they closely scanned the arriving Scarlet Lion strike cruiser.

To be sure, it had battle damage consistent with Suyush weaponry. But it had a great many scars which had come from a multitude of sources as well.

In the end, the queen in command of the system’s void-based forces died screaming. The engines had been disabled early on, and so there was no chance for her to even evacuate.

==================================

The meeting would come a few hours later, as the wounded and dead were tallied. This time, the leader of the Scarlet Lions present came by thunderhawk, presenting himself to the Blood Ravens as the rest of his company gathered itself in one of the larger launch bays.

“Chapter Master Angelos, I am Master Akermian of the Scarlet Lion’s 2nd Company. I bid you greetings in the name of our chapter, and give thanks that you’ve arrived.”

That, more than anything, finally slotted the chapter’s progenitor in Gabriel’s mind. There was but one legion and its successors who built their command structure as such. A successor of the Dark Angels. Not so rare as those of the White Scars, but then no legion had been so prolific in its successors than the Ultramarines. As for Akermian himself, his armor possessed silvery gilding amongst the red and white, to the point that his winged helm was silver in coloration compared to the gold some might have expected. His entire body, as well as that of his command squad, possessed a rather significant amount of cloth about them, ensuring that even while wearing their power armor they were robed and hooded. All save for Akermian, whose hood was down. At his side was a deactivated power sword, on the other a plasma pistol.

“I greet you Master Akermian. We were unaware of the Ordo Xenos approaching another chapter for this, but will not turn away allies against such a foe.”

Akermian just gave a hollow laugh in response.

“Of course they wouldn’t say anything. Why would they? No, we’ve been trying for hit and runs for a while now, across the sector. We’ve only just recently begun targeting this system in particular, as it was decided that we could concentrate our efforts here rather than spread out across the sector.”

“I see.”

The Scarlet Lion just shook his head.

“The Inquisition has to have known we were operating in the sector for the past year, I do not know why they would not contact you. But as it is, we have a common cause, beating back the damned alien.”

Refinement And Continuation
Initial Phase Concluded! Either vote to continue on as previous planned, or modify plan already in place! Please view the spoiler tabs for tactical considerations!

[] Continue With Current Phase Plan

Spoiler: Current Planned Phase Plan!

--[] Retake
---[] Kuru, then Matsuya
----[] 1st and 10th Fleet, Justinius Probalis, Gabriel Angelos, Apollo Diomedes, Honor Guard
---[] Avanti, then Vatsa
----[] 2nd and 4th Fleet, Hannibal Palrun, Nero Gracchus
--[] Middle
---[] All ground forces

OR

[] Alter Upcoming Phase Plan As Follows (Write-In)

Phase 1 Completes!

Spoiler: Total Casualties/Fatalities

10 of 2nd Company Wounded
4 Scouts [1st Stage] Killed [8 Gene-Seed Recovered]
15 4th Company Marines Wounded
5 4th Company Marines Dead [10 Gene-Seed Recovered]
1 Tarantula Sentry Turret (Twin-Linked Heavy Bolters)

Spoiler: Phase Objectives + Tactical Considerations

Space station Sacred Crown recovered. 1/4 of station is heavily damaged, inoperable! Lance batteries online! Communication network returned to Imperial control!
Tactical Consideration! Orbital Stations Networked Sacred Crown! Can be shut down, allowing greater chance for boarding procedure success!
Tactical Consideration! 3 of 4 Orbital Stations Over Planet Vatsa Functional! One Destroyed! Auspex Records State From Space Marine Vessel Combat! Chrono-Records Indicate From Same General Period As Sacred Crown Damage!
Tactical Consideration! Scarlet Lions Assaulting Planet Vatsa Next Phase! Committing Entire Company To Planetary Assault!

Spoiler: New Imperials In Sector

Scarlet Lion’s 2nd Company, led by Master Akermian [Appears To Be At Full Strength] [Dark Angels Successors] [Warcry: Unceasing Upon The Enemy!]
1 Strike Cruiser, 4 Gladius-class Escorts [Minor Damage To All Ships]

Turn 26: Echoes Of Genocide (Part Four)

Spoiler: Altered Phase Plan

[X] Alter Upcoming Phase Plan As Follows (Write-In)
-[X] Strategic Path For Next Phase
--[X] Retake
---[X] Kuru, then Matsuya
----[X] 1st and 2nd Fleet, Justinius Probalis, Gabriel Angelos, Apollo Diomedes, Honor Guard
---[X] Vatsa, then Avanti
----[X] 10th and 4th Fleet, Hannibal Palrun, Nero Gracchus
--[X] Middle
---[X] All ground forces

GM NOTE: Apologies for lateness. But better now than never, I suppose?

Echoes of Genocide
+065.M42+ To +070.M42+
+Through The Foe's Obliteration Do We Earn Salvation+

Going by the auspex scans, surface activity across all of the alien-held worlds in the system was up more than a thousand percent. Factory production, assembling defensive positions, and so on. From the retaken Sacred Crown, the Blood Ravens watched, planned, and within the day, readied themselves to deploy once more. Their fleet divided in two, while the sons of the Lion drove out without hesitation. To the younger Blood Ravens it was somewhat confusing as to why they would drive out alone, but their veteran brothers granted them wisdom. For those who had fought in the single concentrated mass since being promoted from scout, it was one thing for the histories to tell of a single company, alone, ranging out into the harsh void. It was another to watch it happen.

“We will remain here,” Martellus grunted as he employed pure physical strength to wrench more alien technology off and away from the Imperial cogitator banks. “Restoring what capabilities and weaponry the station possesses will be a worthwhile endeavor. In the meantime, we can also access the other defensive stations. We will be transmitting information to your ships as you go. Good luck Chapter Master.”

“May the Unknown Primarch watch over you, Martellus,” Gabriel said gravely before marching away.

As the highest in Chapter command left the Master of the Forge behind, Hannibal reared up and smashed apart another piece of xeno technology of unknown purpose with his crozius. Martellus did not even flinch, his mind and efforts wholly consumed with the likely lengthy repairs required for Sacred Crown to return to true form.

==========================================

Above the planets Kuru and Matsuya hung their once prominent defensive stations. Installed by the Imperium centuries ago, the remnants of their capture damage were still visible to the scans of the Blood Raven fleet. It was easy to see where the xenos had boarded, melting their way through and then later patching up the holes they’d burnt into the hulls. By now, it was very likely that the former crew members on the stations were all consumed. But that did not give the Blood Ravens pause. The echoes of the horror and pain on them were audible to the Chief Librarian’s ears from halfway across the system. This only stoked the fires of rage in the astartes as they began their own boarding procedures.

Repair Efforts
43

The time it took for their ships to reach Kuru and Matsuya was enough for Martellus to reconnect the network of the Sacred Crown with its lost attendants. Then, with one signal, the power systems around the defensive stations flickered once, then twice, then a third time. With each pulse, the teleportariums of the Angels of Death activated. Suysh found themselves suddenly surrounded, vital system control centers were flooded with enemies, and docking bays were blasted through. Weapon systems attempted to target darting Blood Raven ships, but it was too late. Just as in the past they had not been quite capable of defending themselves alone, they could not defend their new masters from the Blood Ravens. The astartes vessels were too fast, and too heavily armored and shielded, ensuring that no damage could be truly taken before they escaped.

Station Assaults
48 vs. 19/35 vs. 63
73 vs. 28/15 vs. 40
66 vs. 36/63 vs. 30
70 vs. 16/40 vs. 80

On the stations around Kuru, the shields held more strongly than anticipated, forcing the Blood Ravens to resort to more physical measures. This did not dissuade them, however. For all that the Chapter Master and his Honor Guard were enough to take a station alone, elsewhere Captain Marcus of the 1st Company could do similar measures. It was the newly reborn 2nd Company that struggled the most, though this was to be expected given their newness. In the end, of course, an assault ram carried Captain Sicarius to the forefront where he took to the fighting with vicious fury. The scent of blood in the air carried the xenos to great heights of martial defense, but in the end, they could not resist forever. Ugly stations that they were, and lonely positions as well, it seemed that Kuru and Matsuya’s station occupants possessed few of the elite amongst their number. Worse, the lack of Queen communion kept them from overriding their normal biological instincts when dozens of space marines came storming through the corridors.

In the end, after two weeks of fierce fighting, it was done, and the stations were retaken over both worlds. The wounded would require healing, but the scope of the campaign would let such a thing be done soon enough. A trio of marines of the 2nd, unfortunately, fell while stopping the suicidal Suysh from detonating the reactor of their station. A noble series of deaths, to be sure, and ones that brought victory. For without their sacrifice, the station would have been lost, and the forty other marines of the 2nd Company present with it. Elsewhere, a teleporarium mishap had resulted in a squad being thrust out of position, vulnerable to being surrounded due to the heavy weaponry of the alien. Though the squad came out victorious, it was not without grave cost.

-6 2nd Company Marines (12 Gene-Seed Recovered)

Below, the xenos seemed to boil over the surface with even greater ferocity, continually preparing for the invasion that had come to dislodge them.

=========================================

Elsewhere, the planets of Vatsa, then Avanti were the target. Vatsa was a curious matter, for the records on Sacred Crown revolving around the loss of a defense station were gone. But the fact remained, of the four, three remained. A massive gap in the overall defensive grid that the planet once possessed. Only debris remained of the station, and even that was curiously difficult to de-mystify. Somewhat frustrating, the sons of the Lion barreled past and through this opened hole, landing multiple thunderhawks onto the planet below. They seemed entirely unconcerned with retaking the stations at all. It fell to the 10th and 4th Company to retake the three remaining. At the least, due to the orbital differences of all four planets, there was enough time for Martellus to work on restoring the Crown’s connection to the stations after learning from his previous work.

Reconnecting
52

Unfortunately, the Suysh had desecrated much of the Omnissiah’s works. Though he was able to begin cycling the station shields and weaponry, it was only as effective as it had been before, no more, no less. It would be largely up to the marines present to manage anything of true worth.

Station Assaults
80 vs. 55/73 vs. 35
17 vs. 30/81 vs. 62
84 vs. 83/55 vs. 55
88 vs. 36

There was a growing number of Blood Ravens who had taken to wary awe of the Master of Sanctity. The largest of the Blood Ravens living without dreadnought internment, Hannibal Palrun’s deeds were quickly growing in fame. This was no different. A formation, unofficially known as simply the Fist of Purity, had come into being rather unexpectedly. All unattached Chaplains followed behind their great master as he bellowed and battered his way through the enemy. Their black armors and white skull helms were soon painted with the alien gore of Suysh, a chorus of hateful litanies screamed throughout the station that soon enough fell to them. Elsewhere, the 10th Company fought their way against a tide of alien foes, preferring to lead the enemy into ambushes and crossfires than to leapt their way into the fray without suitable protection. In this, Captain Octavius found them wise. Uncommonly, Nero Gracchus deployed himself, his white armor darkened by the blood of the enemy as he administered his skills as a healer to the wounded on the battlefield.

Over Avanti, after a week of fighting over the stations of Vatsa, the 4th Company drove forward first. the fighting was shockingly short, the relentless Hadrian demanding no respite whatsoever. Within but a single day the walls and floors were painted with the blood of the enemy, and the station once more broadcasted loyal hymns. If there was damage left behind on the station for the techmarines and adepts of the Imperium to restore, then that was the price of victory. At the end of that single violent day, the foe was dead and Hadrian was already preparing his forces for heading down to the planets below. The 10th Company similarly required time to resupply and ready themselves.

But with the victory over Vatsa coming as thoroughly as it did, there was time. Time for the Blood Ravens to observe their…allies.

On the planet below the Scarlet Lions had struck multiple xeno complexes with seemingly no pattern at all. To be sure, they killed the enemy, but they did not seem to be pursuing any individual objective other than said killing. Occasionally, they would unleash bombing runs from their thunderhawks to put pause to xeno charges and reinforcement columns. Sometimes, they would strike an infantry column before fading back into the desert wastes of the planet, other times they would fight protracted battles to penetrate and destroy hardened Suysh positions. But then there was little more time for speculation, for the Blood Ravens themselves were dropping to the four planets themselves. A middling approach had been decided upon, for without sufficient data an assault on a Queen would be suicide even if one could be found so quickly.

Instead, the Angels of Death assaulted those factories and arms depots where the enemy vehicular strength was stored, forcing them to try and protect what they could against the speed of the enemy.

Kuru Landings 72 vs. 29
Matsuya Landings 100 vs. 1
Vatsa Landings 36 vs. 80
Avanti Landings 33 vs. 45

On the planet of Kuru, the former town and factorum complex of Amber Mills was lost to total conflagration. Techpriests ignited fuel lines and reactors alike to create a chained series of destruction. There was nothing to preserve there, no human lives to save, nothing that the Mechanicus would care to preserve. All had been melted down for perverse alien machinery, a wholly alien complex sprouting from the abused corpse of the Imperium’s own industry. Unlike with the Sacred Crown, there had been no need to preserve elements of Imperial technology to ensure control, for the whole of the planet belonged to the perfidious alien. As it was, Amber Mills was only the first of many enemy vehicle complexes to be targeted. An armored column here, a factory which produced aircraft there, an entire shipping yard where many tanks had been preparing to be shipped onto distant battlefields. The 1st Company dominated Kuru’s airfields as well, utilizing orbital bombardment with matchless efficiency.

But their destruction paled before the anger of Captain Sicarius.

In his first grand deployment, his brothers – newly promoted they may have been – had failed. Not in securing their objectives, but in matching their brethren. To compare newly promoted Blood Ravens to the veterans of the 1st was a fool’s errand, but even so, there was a burning need to prove himself. For had not the new captain of the 2nd been passed over for leadership of the 1st for a younger, unproven, less experienced marine? Though few would know it, Sicarius would confess in confidence to Hannibal that he did not know if he would be able to make up the difference, for Captain Marcus had more than proven himself. It was one thing to be a well-regarded sergeant. Entirely another to command an entire company, especially in the trying times the Blood Ravens found themselves in. The highest of Chaplains in the chapter had told him thus – the Emperor had provided a proving ground in this campaign, but it would be up to him to actually prove himself.

Hannibal could not have known how his words would inflame the 2nd Company’s captain, nor the brothers of the 2nd Company.

All seventy members of the 2nd Company fell from the skies above Matsuya as a single massive drop. No thunderhawks, only drop pods, and yet they targeted one of the largest and most well defended factory complexes on the planet’s surface. It had been built up as one of the original beachheads that the Suysh had created upon taking the planet for themselves. An entire army of Suysh was present there, infantry ranging from their most base trooper to the most elite of their Hungerers. Fang tanks and scream claw VTOL craft were present in large number, several of which were manned. Captain Sicarius did not care. He announced the arrival of his company with a concentrated orbital bombardment, and landed amongst the ashes at the very center. From there, the 2nd Company roared out into the night, firing plasma weaponry in such number that what had been midnight became day for twice in a row.

But they did not stop there. Within the day, the entire complex had been set aflame, and the 2nd Company had moved on, leaving the thunderhawks to bomb the site repeatedly and prevent the return of the Suysh. Then they struck another complex. Then another. Then a third. In the time it took the 1st Company to capture a comparable victory as the 2nd had committed in their initial deployment, the 2nd had repeated their performance thrice more. Individually, the Suysh infantry could not often stand up to the Blood Ravens, and they did not give them many chances to test this. In time, they began sending out larger and larger parties of Bloodscales and Hungerers, for far too many Clawborn had died to the hands of the 2nd Company. Eventually, matters progressed to the point that the sheer destruction required the attendance of one of the fearsome Royal Guard, sent to try and defeat the threat by the whims of the one of the planet’s Queens. It was further accompanied by a number of their stealth troops and void screamers alike, all to try and kill the doughty marine.

Captain Sicarius vaporized the Royal Guard from the knees up, nearly overloading his plasma cannon in the process. Meanwhile, the stalkers were shot apart and the void screamers torn asunder by blade and grenade. Apothecaries descended eagerly and worked alongside those psykers available to the company for many a week. Within a month, they had discerned the precise pheromone-psychic trail, chemical and warp intertwined as a command thread. A path has been found, a path to a Queen, on the planet. It is now known where one resides, having so foolishly tried to kill one of your own. By providing their own psykers, their stalkers, and the Royal Guard, consumption and analysis of the resulting memories, coupled with the expertise of the apothecaries and librarians, there was information aplenty to analyze. Now? You know where one is. A massive swathe of territory could be broken up into anarchy.

However, the records of the Deathwatch caution against basic assassination, and her presence within a major mine prevents you from orbital bombardment. Cyrus, from a planet half a solar system away, advises placement of teleportarium beacons, to boost and improve the signal, to ensure that those who commit to the killing can be retrieved. A harder fight, to be certain, being forced to pause repeatedly and install the beacons, leaving behind more and more to prevent the repeaters from being lost. Whosoever would be the last of the parties required to delve to the deepest point and slay the Queen would have to be prepared for the absolute possibility of death, even should they succeed.

But then, you are space marines. Such a fate is not unexpected.

Things did not go as well on Vatsa or Avanti, however. The Scarlet Lions did not bother communicating with the 10th Company or the 4th Company, busy with whatever it was that they were doing. The Suysh, riled up as they were by the attacks of the foreign chapter, repeatedly ended up running counter to attempts by the Blood Ravens to pursue their own objectives. More than once, a base that was assumed to be less defended suddenly was due to an alien redeployment due to a Scarlet Lion assault. An armored column was redirected and ran into the Blood Ravens before an ambush could be properly set due to an assault elsewhere by the Scarlet Lions upon a Suysh base to the north of the canyon. Injuries began to mount, and as they did, assault efforts were forced to slow in turn due to lack of action-capable personnel. Progress continued to slow, further and further, though few could fault Captain Octavius for slowing the 10th Company down slightly rather than risk the valuable neophytes after a Suysh warband managed to surround a number of neophytes and literally eat them. Experience was one thing, carelessly throwing them into the fray was another entirely. On the other hand, the aggression of Hadrian had finally found a match, clashing in dozens of battles against the Suysh, struggling to strike down depots without taking too many casualties. For all that ceramite was proving itself a remarkable defense against the heat-based weaponry of the alien, they still possessed more primitive yet still frustratingly effective chemical-based explosives.

The Veteran’s Eye
82

But then…

=====================================================

It was a cavern, located just a handful of minutes away from a currently smoking ruin which had once been a Suyush artillery compound. It had not been one thing. It had been a hundred. Small bits of data collected within a mind centuries old, its own twisting pathways divergent from many of his kind. Cyrus had been unconventional amongst the Blood Ravens even before he joined the Deathwatch, and that had not reversed itself in the time since he had left them. But the patterns were undeniable, to one such as him, in this one instance. He was not prideful enough to think that he could not be fooled, he had seen his betters fall into such a trap before, and so he remained entirely open to the possibility that he could be wrong. But he did not think he was, in this case. For many, the patterns of the Scarlet Lions were without rhyme or reason. Their targets were from a wide selection, none seemingly granted more precedence than the other. But not to Cyrus. Not to him.

They were driving the Suysh towards the Blood Ravens, and had cost him neophytes. He would not forget that. Nothing so obvious, certainly not, but he had realized that they had managed, very carefully, to repeatedly deploy themselves such that the aliens were being used as a wall between the two distinct chapters. No evidence existed that could prove it, none besides his word. So he had ranged out alone, leaving the rest of the Company to rest and regroup after the latest failed offensives. He had stalked past and through the xeno lines, and into the burning wastelands left behind by the Scarlet Lions. And he had discerned their target, finally, tracking every data point and extrapolating. He also knew he had but moments before they arrived to the cavern itself, despite the fact that there was almost nothing at all to differentiate this hillock from those that surrounded it.

Save for the battle damage. Plasma scars on the rocks, heavily eroded by the wind patterns in the area. Krak explosive traces in the soil that his bionic eye could see where the naked eyeball could not. The winds blew so harshly in this area that what evidence there was would no longer be there within another few years. But he was here now, and so delved deep. Here, a bolter round had cracked stone. Here, the wash of a heavy flamer had scorched the rock black, the soot almost completely gone by now. Further he descended in silence…until he found it.

Or him, rather.

It was a grave site, hastily made, but with purpose and some scraps of dignity.

A power sword, its housing and internal components irreparably turned to slag by the Suysh heat weaponry, stabbed down into the earth. A single black and green pauldron piece, heavily scarred and shattered into three, had been placed against the sword. There was no body, obviously, but the inside of this portion of the cavern’s walls, a rare area protected from the punishing environment outside, held all the signs he needed. A great battle had taken place here. Blood still stained the rock, both astartes and alien alike. There was no heraldry at all, neither on the blade nor on the pauldron. But that was all the time he had, the servo skull he had left outside informing him as to the screaming arrival of three separate thunderhawks.

It was time to see if the works of Martellus were truly enough. He had less than sixty seconds before they would arrive, not enough time to leave, but enough time to hide himself.

Soon, the Scarlet Lions arrived. They were led by the one who had called himself Akermian, so-called Master of the 2nd Company of their chapter. There was little patience in his approach, stomping forward through what scant signs that could possibly have been left by Cyrus’ passage without care. He was accompanied by a full ten terminators, but it was another who pushed past them all and halted the procession with a single silent gesture. The golden rosarius which dangled from his neck gleamed in the darkness of the cave, save for three black pearls that were interspersed throughout the chain. The crozius he carried identified him, somewhat, but there was nothing of the bombastic fury typical that Cyrus would normally have expected. He knelt, retrieving a massive tome bound in leather, its ancient pages yellowed and fragile. Then, he began to read, flitting from one page to the next. Not even Cyrus could hear what words he might have muttered, the angle he’d chosen when he hid not allowing him to read either.

A servo skull rose up as well, its loadout entirely non-standard, and began to scan the sword and shattered pauldron. There was a long moment, where Cyrus did not even breathe at all. Then another. Then another still.

“Well?” Akermian finally rasped out. “Was it-,”

“No,” the chaplain said as he stood, an audible note of frustration and disgust in his voice. “It was not. This was another. That makes ten against ten. They opposed each other, and sought to use the aliens as their weapons as well.”

Akermian just growled.

“Then we are wasting time here. We know where we must go. The longer we spend on this benighted world, in this pathetic system, the longer the hunt will take,” he snapped out, turning around to begin marching back out of the cave. “Set the explosives like at the other sites. Leave no trace behind.”

Twenty of the thirty Scarlet Lions present swiftly left, Akermian and his chaplain with them, leaving a single squad behind. Slowly, they began to place a number of melta charges about the cavern. However, one paused as he prepared to place one more pack of explosives by the sword and pauldron itself. His hesitation was noted by the others, who had finished their own tasks. So focused was the rest of the squad on their paused brother that Cyrus had extricated himself from his previous position and was halfway up the cavern when he paused to hear them speak.

“What troubles you, brother? Place the last of them and let us be gone from this place,” he heard one mutter.

“We do not know who they were, only that they fought what we all fight, but we ensure that their memory is forgotten. I do not know what to think about that,” came a quiet but steady voice.

“You may speak with the chaplain after we are done here. Complete your duty, and move out. I took a chance on promoting you to my squad. Do not forget that, Celerian.”

“…understood.”

There was a final click and beep, but by then, Cyrus was away. He was even further when the hill and its secrets were removed from the surface of the world forever, and further still to rejoin his company.

===========================================

Gabriel roared as he brought his hammer down, shattering the body of the hungerer in a trio of strokes that a lesser man could not have managed. The hammer rose up and fell down in a blur, shattering armor and scale alike, obliterating the bone and meat that made up its body. All around them the Suysh were charging, desperate to protect the last of their tanks and fueling supplies. It was all for naught, however, as the timed explosives placed within ensured that despite thousands charging to attack the hill that the Blood Ravens had claimed for themselves, the depot began to be torn apart from the inside. Despite the 10th Company being on another planet entirely, it was not as if the marines present had forgotten their lessons so quickly. The foe resembled an angry ocean of beige scales and rock-like armor, the strange yet unique fizz-whine-thrum of their thermal cannons filling the air. Missiles and plasma cannon shot answered back, dreadnoughts scouring the field with their assault cannons. Whole piles of shell casings rattled about underfoot, sometimes being pressed deep into the earth by an unerring boot of ceramite.

A crackle of the vox had Gabriel turning slightly, his terminator plate simply absorbing and diffusing away the thermal cannon shot which splashed against him. He angled himself simply, yet that was enough to stymie a great amount of the foe’s potential weapon power. Around him, the rest of the Honor Guard filed in, while Apollo himself outright charged into the enemy. Such was the strength and speed with which the champion did his duty that the very cracked and dry earth split and erupted in small spikes beneath his feet. A literal trench was driven not just into the ground but the foe who had dared to stand upon it.

“Chapter Master, this is Martellus?”

“Speak, Martellus. You have news?”

“Aye, sir. The Scarlet Lions have left the system.”

That, more than anything, put Gabriel to pause. Even the roaring of aliens completely surrounding his position while the battle barge overhead triangulated the correct coordinates to teleport them out could not distract him from those words.

“Explain, Martellus.”

“They withdrew all of their forces, claimed that they had found enough information to locate the home system of the Suysh Hives, and departed immediately.”

Gabriel leaned back to avoid the swipe of a massive thermal blade, the white hot material sizzling with enough excess heat to char flesh within a foot of its body. In the same motion he spun Godsplitter about one-handed and cracked it into the claw clutching the blade, shoulder-checking the alien in the same motion. Scales cracked as the weight of his armor and the strength behind it pulverized a good chunk of the hungerer’s body. Stomping down, he prevented it from reeling back too far and simply reached forward with one hand to wrap about its throat. Rather than strangle it, he squeezed beyond such a point that it instead simply tore the alien’s head from its shoulders. There was a crackle of tainted ozone in the air, and he glanced up at the stars to where the Omnis was surely waiting.

Then there was the transition, and for a terrible eternal instant he and all his nearby brothers were flung up through the warp and into the teleportarium of the Omnis. He did not even need to pause as he prepared for a new teleportation towards a new target. The techmarines were working tirelessly to ensure the success of such a tactic, but Gabriel knew simply by a cursory listen to their chatter that he would have to ride along the thunderhawks instead for a time, for the warp could only broker such manipulations for a certain period of time before its writhing made the risks of teleporting outweigh the possible benefits.

Then there was a thrumming of the ship as its bombardment cannons fired. Far below, the Suysh army which had sought his head were obliterated, plums of dust and blood rising high into the air as the aliens were vaporized.

“What should we do, Chapter Master?”

Gabriel grit his teeth and shook his head.

“We can do nothing about it, for now. We have our own duty. If they wish to abandon their so easily, so be it.”

“I also have a message from Cyrus, Gabriel. He has some worrying news.”

Gabriel slowly began to grind his teeth as the message was relayed to him. It only grew worse when he heard that there were the beginnings of fluctuations within the warp. The Suysh had gotten signals out, and their ships would be oncoming. Thankfully they had planned for this, and a significant portion of the fleet present had already prepared themselves for such an eventuality. When the aliens arrived, the Blood Ravens would be ready for them, their ships leaving orbit to perform interdiction duty. The news that a Queen had already been located was welcome, and so salved his bitterness ever so slightly. If one could be tracked down and killed, so too could others. The Librarius assured him that such would be the result if one was slain, if only so they could track the emanations that came from its death, as well as the following transfer of the hive's membership being switched to another Queen's control. That, more than anything, would be the key. Once that was done, the Queens would begin to fall, one way or another.

Refinement And Continuation
Phase 2 Concluded! Either vote to continue on as previous planned, or modify plan already in place! Please view the spoiler tabs for tactical considerations!

[] Continue With Current Phase Plan

Spoiler: Current Planned Phase Plan!

--[X] Interdict
---[X] 1st, 4th and 10th Fleets, 4th Company
--[X] Continued Bombardment
---[X] 2nd Fleet
--[X] Top
--[X] During first two steps Librarius will concentrate on predicting the actions of the Suysh and where their defenses are the weakest. During 3rd step, they will concentrate on locating the enemy Queens and if their connection to the rest of the Hive is psychic and if it can be disrupted.
--[X] Vehicles and unassigned specialists to be distributed equally amongst battle groups.

OR

[] Alter Upcoming Phase Plan As Follows (Write-In)

Phase 2 Completes!

Spoiler: Total Casualties/Fatalities

10 of 2nd Company Wounded
4 Scouts [1st Stage] Killed [8 Gene-Seed Recovered]
15 4th Company Marines Wounded
5 4th Company Marines Dead [10 Gene-Seed Recovered]
1 Tarantula Sentry Turret (Twin-Linked Heavy Bolters)
-6 2nd Company Marines (12 Gene-Seed Recovered)
-12 10th Company Neophytes

Spoiler: Phase Objectives + Tactical Considerations

Tactical Consideration! Orbital Stations All Successfully Reclaimed!
Tactical Consideration! 3 of 4 Orbital Stations Over Planet Vatsa Functional! One Destroyed! Auspex Records State From Space Marine Vessel Combat! Chrono-Records Indicate From Same General Period As Sacred Crown Damage!
Tactical Consideration! Scarlet Lions Have Departed System! Cyrus is personally certain that they deliberately ensured the Suysh ran into certain Blood Raven efforts, but has no real proof. After all, they were still killing aliens, and the aliens simply reacted. The Scarlet Lions were tracking one party, and found two. Apparently their 'quarry' was in combat with another group entirely, resulting in multiple locations across Vatsa being sites of evidence, all removed by concerted Scarlet Lion efforts. Identities of either of the two parties is unknown.

Turn 26: Echoes Of Genocide (Part Five)

Spoiler: Voted Plan

--[X] Interdict
---[X] 1st, 4th and 10th Fleets, 4th Company
--[X] Continued Bombardment
---[X] 2nd Fleet
--[X] Top
--[X] During first two steps Librarius will concentrate on predicting the actions of the Suysh and where their defenses are the weakest. During 3rd step, they will concentrate on locating the enemy Queens and if their connection to the rest of the Hive is psychic and if it can be disrupted.
--[X] Vehicles and unassigned specialists to be distributed equally amongst battle groups.

GM Note: This one got a bit away from me, but at least it's here! Moratorium for 3 Hours.

Echoes of Genocide
+065.M42+ To +070.M42+
+Through The Foe's Obliteration Do We Earn Salvation+

The warp crackled and tore as the Suysh ships emerged, their rocky and asymmetrical exteriors trailing eldritch energies that quickly dissipated as the laws of physics reasserted themselves. The Sacred Crown’s advanced auspex sensors, restored to the Imperium’s nominal control, painted them the moment they did so. There was a screech of fury from the queen residing within the hulking Scorchnest, its attendant cruisers and escort ships riled up by their progenitor’s anger at the sight of the still floating remains of the Suysh fleet which had once patrolled the solar system. Hadrian spared a handful of seconds towards a bridge servitor’s warning lights of an incoming transmission. The tracked source was, predictably, the enemy battleship.

“BLOOD-ROT UPON YOU, THIEVES, MURDERERS, TAINTED MEAT! SISTER VOID-SLAKE’S DEATH-OATH SHALL BE FULFILLED! YOU WILL BE OUR MEAT! SO SWEARS LEXTAL STARFEASTER! MEAT! MEAT! MEA-,”

A twitch of attention from his place in the command throne and the vox channel closed. Hadrian simply raised an eyebrow as he glanced both at the tactical screen at the foot of the command throne and arcane systems of the throne itself. Through the venerable sensors and cameras of the Omnis, he saw the xeno fleet burning its engines to get into combat range. Around his ship, however, came the rest of the Blood Ravens fleet. They readied themselves, engine-hearts burning fiercely, and he felt a tight grin come across his face as the bombardment cannons began to ready themselves as well. If the Suysh wished to frame and build their vessels as if they were earthen, as if they were planetoid? They would be cracked apart like them too.

“Attention all ships,” Hadrian’s fingers tightened over the throne’s edges as he leaned forward. “Fire at will!”

Once more, the void between the planets and star of the system were lit up by weapons fire.

“Come and die, xenos. This is the Emperor’s space. You are not welcome,” he hissed beneath his breath.

================================================

Not every ship under Blood Raven control proceeded to the fight brewing on the edge of the system. The 2nd Company fleet, newly assembled as it was, remained over the worlds and continued to batter them down with unceasing bombardment fire. This was what they were, quite literally, made for. Two strike cruisers they might have been, but for many a world throughout the warring galaxy one was enough. But perhaps just as important were their teleportariums, systems which sizzled and popped with unnatural airs and electricity as the techmarines and lesser Blood Raven psykers maintained their continued function. Of the four worlds to be reclaimed, it was Matsuya where a Queen had been properly located. Found thanks to the works of Captain Sicarius, and so it was he who earned the honor of leading the charge while the rest of the Chapter continued to fight on the other planets to keep them from organizing properly – though elements of every company were sent, of course, for given the records of the Deathwatch, they would need the help.

Bluevein Mountain was the place, its hollowed out innards large enough to provide a safe home for the Queen that now inhabited it. Its mines were now resources for the alien, rather than humanity, and this could be allowed no longer. It had, in its time under the reptilian grip of the Suysh, become quite the bastion for the foe. Guard towers, sensor arrays, artillery, even patrolling aircraft were present. Here, there would be a number of the elites that could not have been found in the columns and bases elsewhere. But Captain Sicarius did not care. How could he? He had a target, and he had his brothers beside him. A number of the 10th Company had even left their own assigned planet, momentarily at least, granting him aid in the form of Captain Cyrus who willingly subordinated himself for a time.

Bluevein Mountain Skirmishes
Infantry - 12 vs. 1
Vehicles - 32 vs. 12

First came the distractions. Assaults along the edges, utilized thoroughly by the vehicles that would be far less effective in the tighter quarters of the mines. There were rapidly redeploying assault marines on jump packs appearing from the skies before departing back behind entrenched tactical marine lines. Wedges of predator tanks and razorbacks drove up, fired, and reversed away as the Suysh attempted to retaliate properly. From every direction around the mountain came the probes, the scorched and burnt remains of former defensive structures long-destroyed by the efforts of the 2nd Company aiding such things. Assault bikes came screaming over the wasteland, while above the thunderhawks rained fiery death when they were not fighting it out with Suysh aircraft.

Such a thing could not continue forever, of course.

Bluevein Mountain Insertions
86 vs. 16

But when the moment was right, the Librarius sensing the moment that the defenses parted in a handful of specific locations, the 2nd Company struck. The targets were a trio of entrances into the mines, their defenders momentarily reassigned, all before more reinforcements could arrive or bubble up from the depths. The whole of the 2nd Company tore through the Suysh with blistering long range weapons fire keeping them pinned in place for assault marines to leap down and slaughter those who hunkered down behind rock and steel. Captain Sicarius personally led the charge, firing his plasma cannon as he went, each blast of superheated death lighting the way as they fought their way into the tunnels. At the same time, the 1st Company, led by Gabriel, fought ever fiercer on the outside, their terminator-clad bodies presenting just as much if not more of a threat, forcing the Suysh to split their attentions even further. Such was the death they granted to so many xenos that a higher number of hungerers and royal guard emerged from the tunnels to strike under open air than remained within the mountain.

Pushing Within Bluevein
48 vs. 37
31 vs. 35
92 vs. 95

Flamers of both xeno and Imperial design soon illuminated the caves, transforming a darkness that the Suysh could navigate without issue into a scorching light-filled hellscape. The Suysh knew why the enemy had come. Of course they did. This was the home of one of their Queens, and so the foe had come to kill her. They, rather predictably, began to swarm in defense of their precious hive. The most elite troops the alien possessed were sent forth, hulking monstrosities of hardened scales and inhuman musculature wielding weapons that even some marines would struggle to hold as easily. Dreadnought fought dreadnought-sized aliens, stomping tombs beginning to glow yellow under the sheer heat, granting the half-dead marine within horrifying sensation as their shriveled husks began to almost boil within the fluids that surrounded them. Chaplain Ravias, absent from the Fist of Faith that fought elsewhere in the system, bellowed vile curses and incandescent hatred towards the alien as he rallied those who stumbled from their wounds.

Unification
12 vs. 25
93 vs. 15
40 vs. 5

Insertion had relied on a multi-pronged assault, rather than simply hoping that a single push could get the Blood Ravens inside. But after that had been achieved, they needed to try and regroup within. This proved to be harder than expected for one group, a number of 2nd Company marines taking wounds as the Suysh tore and bit at their ceramite. In one case, a marine had his armor stripped entirely from one of his arms, the meat within then subsequently turned to melted flesh and bone, a waxy mockery of a true appendage that required immediate amputation. Elsewhere, Captain Sicarius and Captain Octavius alternatively shot a hole through the enemy or somehow managed to simply slip past. The cavern they found themselves in was one large enough to bear the scars of the Queens passing, a massive chamber which had once simultaneously been an ore processing plant and barracks for slave labor who would have never seen the light of day in their entire lives.

“Captain,” Sicarius nodded briefly before twisting about and firing his weapon once more, unleashing a sphere of blinding light that soon erupted as it struck a royal guard in the chest.

“Captain,” Cyrus grunted back as he fired again and again with his rifle, pausing for a moment to trigger a series of planted detonation packs which reduced a Suysh charge into nothing more than bloody chunks.

Truly, it was unsettling how the Suysh were happy enough to gobble the giblets that remained of their brethren. A vast number of bloodscales had maws that were drenched in the ichor of their own kind, simply racing forward on all four limbs to get to the fight. A method of travel that easily allowed them to duck their head momentarily and scarf up as much meat as they could along the way. Others, those wounded, were similarly cannibalized by their fellows. The moment a Suysh was too crippled to fight, but not yet dead, those around them would reach over and tear out gobs of meat and bone for devouring, their weapons and gear seamlessly redistributed amongst the rest of their ‘squads’. More than one bloodscale now sported extra rifles and incendiary grenades than they had begun with.

“Are we ready to descend?”

Cyrus simply nodded. The beacons were not too large, not like the bulky constructs that Boreale had demanded for his fighting, a chain rather than an island unto themselves. Sicarius fired again, bellowing for ammo to be brought up to him and then leapt down from the higher pile of rocks and ruined ore machinery he’d found himself atop. He paused only to slap the blood-covered pauldron of his chaplain before advancing. But that was signal enough. Ravias lifted his crozius high, its power fields still sparking and lashing out after being slammed into a charging hungerer’s chest and out through the back. The advanced systems within the chaplain’s armor came to life, his vox-cast booming out on every Blood Raven channel.

“Brothers! Into the darkness we go! Into the foul alien hive we descend! We bring the Emperor’s light! We bring his fury! For we are, all of us,” he paused to smash the legs from beneath another hungerer and twisted his weapon about to obliterate its skull without stopping his movement, “Blood Ravens! We are the Angels of Death! MAY NONE FIND US WANTING!”

A resounding cheer went up, and the Blood Ravens responded.

“MAY NONE FIND US WANTING!”

Descent 1
30 vs. 81

As a concentrated mass, the Blood Ravens struck deep, descending through passages caked with alien filth and architecture. It would be decades of work on the part of the Imperium to truly excise every remnant of their presence from this place. Hovels where noble human miners had once worked for twenty hours a day were now home to whole swarms of Suysh who curled about each other to share body heat when they were not on deployment. Machines that had once been blessed weekly by the Mechanicus now groaned under the weight of their alien modifications, forced into battle by raging Suysh who did all they could to force the invaders back. Yet, such was the capabilities of high quality ceramite that rather than melting innards, than boiling away armor, the Blood Ravens were simply left glowing under the immense heat more than anything else. For the Suysh, it was as if dozens of beings made of pure light were fighting against them.

To be sure, however, many a weapon of the Blood Ravens were rendered inoperable either from damage or from the danger of continued use. Even the highest quality of plasma weaponry was delicate in terms of heat distribution at the best of times, and so even the Captain of the 2nd had to resort to putting away his relic weaponry and took up the venerable bolter once more to continue the fight. Where ceramite provided, flesh happened to fail. The Suysh began to charge in greater and greater number, overwhelming squads and tearing ceramite apart under their own mediocre power weaponry. More than one marine felt his skin begin to blacken and flake away where the ceramite could no longer provide protection. Barrels began to deform, thermal sensors becoming less than useless at the same time.

Descent 2
43 vs. 50

Minutes stretched into hours. Hours stretched into days. Momentum for both sides began to slow as they ground against one another. The mountain became a charnel pit within the depths. It did not matter how many times an alien died, for the Suyush devoured all – bone, skin, meat, it made no differences. The ground could not become carpeted with bodies, for there were almost no bodies present. The Blood Ravens found themselves forced into ever tighter quarters, collapsing tunnels that would require much work to clear whenever the Imperium came upon them to restore the mines properly. Tertiary concerns, for ones such as space marines, but each was an outlying failure, at least in the mind of Captain Sicarius. Rather than a great plunging spear of death, they had been blunted again and again. Each time the Blood Ravens tried to redirect, to follow a new portion of the mine network, they found their efforts stymied. Blood was shed, apothecaries desperately worked to keep wounded marines alive. More than one who had found themselves wounded into suspended animation was revived not back in a proper apothecarium but upon the battlefield itself, their wounds patched just enough to return them to being able to at least fire a bolter or carry supplies.

“We must push through!” A sergeant cried before he was buried in bodies.

It took precious moments for the squad around him to slay every one of the creatures piling atop him, retrieving a bloodied but still living sergeant from beneath. Roaring, he revved his gore-clogged chainsword as he rose and threw it into the throat of a charging Suysh. Thankfully its momentum carried the soon-to-be corpse right back to him so he could grasp it around the hilt and tear it away. A vigorous shaking for a few seconds to clear the teeth was all he had time for before another mass of bodies hit him, heat-blasters and thermal cannons causing his exposed wounds to bubble and smoke. It seemed to do little but annoy the veteran of the 1st Company rather severely.

“This isn’t working!” A newly promoted marine cried, “Push them ba - argh!”

A stalker had gotten close, its stealth capabilities letting it dance around the press of bodies and cut out his throat. Though it scabbed over quickly, the marine nonetheless was momentarily dropped to his knees as his body worked overtime to keep the wound from being a fatal one.

====================================================

Gabriel slammed his hammer into the side of the Suysh tank, the eruption of the fields unleashed rocking it badly and blowing a hole into its hull. Within half a second of the first strike, a terminator had approached and plugged the new hole with their heavy flamer, triggering it to roast the Suysh inside. For all that they had far higher heat tolerance than normal humans, even they could not withstand the raw flames so easily. Screams came from within the tank, and even as a hatch opened an assault marine leapt atop the tank and slammed it back down with nothing more than their boot and the strength behind it. Before he could continue, the maelstrom of battle all around them still raging, the vox crackled.

“Chapter Master! This is Martellus. We’ve just received a long-range astropathic message from the Inquisitor!”

Perplexed, Gabriel frowned as he surveyed the battlefield, rattling off orders even as he contemplated what Martellus was saying to him.

“Here? Now? The campaign is not over yet. What were the contents of the message?”

A loud clanging could be heard over the vox instead of an immediate answer as Martellus presumably tried to perform percussive maintenance on something or other.

“It took a moment for the Librarius to decode the message,” he eventually said, “But it could be summarized as her being glad to inform us that she has found some allies for us, which should be arriving soon.”

Gabriel ground his teeth as he remembered the revelation that Cyrus had brought him.

“Well, we were going to have words about her choice in tools – there will be recompense for what her ‘aid’ have brought us,” he growled out. “For they have arrived and already left, having done little to aid us at all! This only means our ‘discussion’ will be sooner.”

“Chapter Master, that’s just it,” Martellus sounded surprised as he continued to read the message in print form, “I fear we have been deceived.”

That was enough to give Gabriel pause while the rest of the Honor Guard fought around him.

“Explain, Martellus.”

=====================================================

Naval Combat
47 vs. 45
51 vs. 54
84 vs. 90
33 vs. 12

From the warp, they emerged, clad in contempt and pride. Thick, blocky vessels bearing proud emblems of the Imperium. They arrived at the rear of the battle where Suysh ships and Blood Raven vessels fought in close range. The Omnis slammed its armored prow through a cruiser, shattering it into a trio of flame-spewing pieces. Elsewhere, a pack of escorts fired with everything they had as another Suysh cruiser fired enough ballistic weaponry to make an ork take note right back. Damage was sustained, of course it was, but thus far Hadrian had kept from outright losing any ship, a prospect growing more and more difficult as the battle went on. Unlike Void-Slake, this new Queen was not slovenly and weak from lack of conflict, and was eager to board and land torpedoes through every void shield she could batter down. But then came a new fleet, a quartet of strike cruisers with over a dozen attendant nova escorts.

Thunderhawks flew freely, joined by a number of stormravens, who bore familiar colors.

Graviton surges began to fluctuate throughout the entire system soon after. Minor earthquakes could be felt on all four planets, while their orbital stations came dangerously close to being broken out of orbit. The reason for this became clear as a large battle barge came barreling out of the warp directly over Matsuya, firing out its first drop pods before the tear into the warp could even finish closing. From the vox came a system-wide broadcast that sparked even in the helmets of those within Bluevein, a bombastic bellow of near deafening proportions – even to a space marine’s ears.

“What ho, foul xenos! Thou hast erred greatly in thine perfidious manner, for these planets be the Emperor’s worlds and none others! You face no longer but one chapter of his Angels of Death, but two!”

The emblem of the Scarlet Lions was emblazoned across the vessel, its designation finding its way into the cogitators seconds later. The Scion of Honor bent in places, here and there, as the graviton surges sought to tear the ship apart for daring to appear as it had, but for a wonder the superstructure held. From his place in the Sacred Crown with its advanced sensory technologies linked with those of the orbital stations, the Master of the Forge winced as he saw the stress fractures and flickering to the void shielding which would no doubt require long hours of repair. Yet he couldn’t help but be impressed as the venerable battle barge refused to allow its defiance of conventional warp travel wisdom – and the laws of physics – to deter it.

“Know this well, creatures of the darkness! The Scarlet Lions have come! I, Bartorius, have come! 3rd Company, deploy!”

Within the next five minutes, a hundred space marines had landed upon the planet.

==============================================

Gabriel’s expression could be described, if anyone could see it within his helm, as one of blatant disbelief.

“Martellus, are they actual Scarlet Lions?”

“I…,”

“Confirm if they are or not, Martellus!” Gabriel snarled before striding back into battle to clear his mind.

“One moment, Chapter Master,” Martellus said breathlessly, hands almost dancing over consoles. “It…appears they are telling the truth. Every identifier, every code-sequence, call and response…they are Scarlet Lions.”

“If that is the case,” Gabriel tore another hungerer’s head off, letting a trio of scrabbling bloodscales fail to do more than scratch the paint on his armor. A solid swipe of his fist slew one, then the next, while the third was shot off of him by one of the Honor Guard, “Who, by the Unknown Primarch, were the others?”

“I don’t know!” Martellus shouted back. “I’m sorry, Chapter Master, but their codes were just as up-to-date!”

================================================

“BLOOD RAVENS!” Sicarius did not wince as the sound came blasting through his vox, “Blood Ravens, do you read?!”

“This is Captain Sicarius, who is this,” he replied with calm that he most certainly did not feel.

“Worry not, fellow sons of the Emperor!” Was the almost cheerful voice’s response. “We, the Scarlet Lions, have come to work towards the destruction of these aliens alongside you! The Inquisitor briefed us. Your location, and the teleportarium repeater beacons you’ve placed along your path, tells mine mind that you hath located one of their despicable Queens!”

All around Sicarius, the 2nd Company fought a desperate battle, launching grenades in a constant staccato towards tunnel entrances that many a Suysh continued to charge through. Elsewhere, a wall collapsed as a number of monstrous royal guard came through it, screeching in their click-hiss tongue. Behind them, floating above them, psychic energies sparking around their body, was one of the horrific psykers of the Suysh. With a gesture, a number of marines screamed and fell to the ground, hands clutching at their skulls as blood began to be pulled violently from their upper orifices.

“We are currently attempting to slay one, yes!” He answered as he fired towards the psyker. “Someone kill that creature, now!”

“Trajan,” Cyrus growled. “Go!”

The epistolary leapt to the fore, his staff bathed in pure psychic light.

“Face me!” The marine roared.

“We would aid you, then, save your denial of such an action! Tell us, Blood Raven, thine desire!”

Sicarius glanced about him. At where marines were being dragged back by their fellows, their wounds requiring patching if only to keep them from dying outright. Towards a tomb-brother, his enormous mechanical tomb collapsed to the side as its reactor was simultaneously kept from erupting while continuing uninterrupted function. To do otherwise, to fail, would be to ensure that the systems keeping the marine within alive failed as well. Pride briefly flared in chest at the 2nd Company, his Company, requiring aid. But he felt the eye of Cyrus on him, the tales of Apollo Diomedes and Boreale echoing in his mind the whole while.

“Aid us if you can! Techmarines, transmit teleportarium permissions!”

“Haha! Verily, then! Glorious battle awaits us, and we shall be as brothers in shedding blood!”

The air was filled with crackling lightning and tainted ozone before lights of unknown origin spread throughout the cavern flared. A resounding cacophony of thunderous miniature explosions heralded the arrival of new marines. At their head was a marine with a white helm with crimson wings along the sides. He appeared to have teleported with his power sword held high in one hand, a bolt pistol in the other. He looked, by armor design and weapon choice, close enough to what Cyrus had seen before. This was not a good thing, by the cynic’s reckoning.

“Scarlet Lions! With me, mine brethren! UNCEASING!”

With that, he rocketed upwards on a jump pack before redirecting and landing right back down into the enemy. All around him, over a hundred more marines bearing the heraldry of the Scarlet Lions joined him.

“UNCEASING!”

Lions And Ravens
42 vs. 26
42 vs. 19

Sicarius was not far behind, charging forward into the stumbling foe with almost reckless abandon. He may have accepted the aid, for now, of these interlopers. But that did not mean for a single second that he would let them do all the work. All that he had required was for something to break the deadlock. The Scarlet Lions had provided such, and he would ensure that his own brothers could take advantage of it. He noted all he could as marines of both chapters charged. An absolute abundance of power weaponry and bolt pistols lent credence to a far more close-range specialty amongst these Scarlet Lions compared to those who had been present before, though they had a number of marines laden with heavy weaponry at the same time.

“Forward, Blood Ravens! Forward! In the name of the Unknown Primarch, let none find us wanting!”

====================================================

Void Resolution
32 vs. 25

The last of the Suysh reinforcement ships hung in the void, shattered to the last. Such was their frustratingly sturdy construction that the Mechanicus would likely be able to obtain many a sample from the debris field that had been created. Hadrian grit his teeth at the damage reports for some of the ships, but overall they were all perfectly stable and ready for battle once more if required. He would, of course, prefer that every vessel under his command came out pristine from every conflict, but that was a passing fancy, an impossibility that he spared but a handful of seconds to dream of. As it was, with Martellus doing some patchwork at the Sacred Crown, the techmarines and servitors already present on the ships, and a few weeks, they could leave the system any time. But with interdiction work complete, he could at least return to bombardment efforts.

“Captain,” a servitor buzzed from somewhere on the bridge. “We are receiving a communication from one of the Scarlet Lion vessels – identified as the Purity’s Blade.”

“Put them through,” he muttered, attention splitting itself to take care of a dozen tasks besides the conversation.

“Salutations, fellow sons of the Emperor!”

Hadrian blinked, his mind momentarily derailed by both the words and archaic gothic.

“Greetings…?” Hadrian let his question continue into the silence.

“Ah! A folly of mine own enthusiasm,” the speaker said with tight and disturbingly genuine recrimination in their voice. “I doth have the honor to be Captain Kallek, of the 2nd Company of the Scarlet Lions!”

Hadrian’s attention slowly began to turn more and more weight to the conversation. For he knew, as did all of the captaincy and others amongst the leadership, that such a thing was required to be patently false lest another to have deceived them. Almost unbidden, twitches of his thoughts and wishes were translated by the command throne into silent and secure communications with the rest of his ships. Steadily, the Blood Raven fleet extracted itself from the debris field and formed up, making sure to keep the Scarlet Lion vessels in front of them at all times.

“Captain? Not master?” He said instead of the immediate accusations that came to mind.

“Ah? Hah, no,” Kallek said with a slowly fading boisterousness, “In the manner of the Lion’s sons, eh? No. Well, perhaps,” he replied slowly, contemplation obvious through the static-filled vox. “It is still up for debate.”

“What do you mean?”

Hadrian steadily began to blink out a call to alert and arms amongst his company once more, standing down his original schedule of having them return to quarters. This might yet, he knew, come to a new fight.

“Ah, it is but to our shame that the Scarlet Lions know not our Primarch,” Kallek sighed loudly with a painful grief. “Tis an old wound, verily, suffered sometime in the 34th Millenium that our homeworld was destroyed by the vagaries of Chaos, demanding that we be bound ‘pon the stars, whilst simultaneously destroying much of our records and histories of the past.”

Hadrian just stared at the tactical screen displaying the Scarlet Lions fleet that slowly floated past in the void.

“And none others remembered?”

It was not the question he wanted to ask, but it was the one that came out first. Now all of him was intensely focused upon the speaker. He felt the old ache, the painful urge, the blazing fire that had consumed so many Blood Ravens in the past. Over the possibility, the question, the absolute certainty that the information was out there, and that they simply had to find it. One way or another, the Blood Ravens would know their origin, and here, then, was yet another chapter who knew not had been their progenitor?

“In part, in parcel,” Kallek admitted, “References to our name, our heroes and champions, in the records to other chapters, but none as to that question’s answer so specifically.”

It was not another denial, another Inquisitor denying information, and yet Hadrian felt the wound to his heart as if it had been.

“We, too, know not our Primarch,” he said through suddenly dry lips. “We…have searched for so long…”

“Ah. Then I can do naught but wish thine efforts luck, rather more than us Scarlet Lions. By the order of Chapter Master Platon in the 35th Millennium, we ended ours.”

That, more than anything, brought Hadrian up short. His mind simply could not grasp, in those first few seconds, the words that had just been spoken.

“Excuse me?”

“He reason’d that it didst not matter,” Kallek said, his previous cheer slowly returning to him, “We art still yet loyal sons of the Emperor. We still serve His Imperium. We couldst and shall not doth nothing more than honor Him in that.”

There were a number of blinking lights in the back of his mind, insistent requests for confirmation on whether or not to attack or prepare defenses, whether to reassign techmarines and servitors from hull repair to weapon readying. He both saw them and saw them not.

“But you do not know!” He almost hissed, his voice becoming something quite unlike his normal voice.

“Aye, thy words be truth,” Kallek somehow managed to communicate a shrug with those words. “But the writings of Platon are required writings for all initiates to memorize.”

Then he coughed slightly, clearing his throat.

“‘And know this, mine brothers, there doth not exist a shame greater than to fail thine Emperor, to besmirch His legacy. We must, therefore and henceforth, never do so. Our father be without name, and yet we know the Emperor, and thus, who we wilt honor. Thine blood, thine gene-seed, be His legacy, before any others. Know this for sooth, and know that no other detail of origin matters. We are the Emperor’s chosen, his Angels of Death. We are his Scarlet Lions,’” Kallek finished his reciting with reverence.

“But-,”

“But aye, enough of such things!”

The engines on the Scarlet Lion ships flared as they began heading towards the planets.

“We hath come to assist in thine retrieval of these worlds in His name, not merely pontificate! Let us engage in glorious battle together!”

Hadrian twitched before ordering his ships to turn about and do the same as their peers.

“And you know you are not of the Lion’s sons?”

“A most intriguing subject, forsooth, one mind brethren have debated for generations, but alas, the sons of the Lion say they know us not,” Kallek managed to verbally shrug once more. “In truth, our name cometh from the now extinct Lemnian scarlet lions, whose mighty frames once stalked the red grasses of our homeworld Lemnos. Before Chaos came, that is.”

=================================================

Descending
99 vs. 5
46 vs. 23
35 vs. 77
90 vs. 1

For a week and a half, the Blood Ravens had been stymied in their efforts within the Bluevein Mines. No longer. With the Scarlet Lions supporting them, they plunged into the deeps with absolute purpose and unshakeable fury. For all that the Suysh defenses grew ever more desperate, more and more bodies being thrown in the way, they could not be stopped. Three space marine captains, two of Blood Raven origin and the third from the strange Scarlet Lions, led their combined forces deep within, one mile, then another beneath the surface of the world. Every variety of the alien was represented in those deeps, all serving the will of their Queen. Clawborn in their tens of thousands, whose vast numbers could not be put to proper work due to the tightness of the tunnels the space marines traveled through, the caverns that the blew apart. Bloodscales, veterans, who found all their experience shredding apart Imperial Guard doing nothing to prepare them for the fury of dozens of power sword-wielding Scarlet Lions. Crimson crashed into scarlet, and one hue soon overwhelmed the other.

One level after another they went down, any mine elevators an absolute impossibility to make use of due to the surety of sabotage and open vulnerability to enemy attacks. Instead, they trudged their way through filth-ridden tunnels, transforming alien barracks into slaughterhouses, abattoirs in revenge for the many humans killed here by xeno hands. They took the paths that had been carved into the rock and dirt first, before the elevators could be built, through older mine shafts that had been closed off due to having been exhausted. Here, they found hungerers, the ogryn-sized brutes roaring out of the shadows. Heat-blade struck power-sword, primitive and divergent technology managing to hold up to the ancient blades that the Scarlet Lions wielded. For a time, at least, before the Blood Ravens shot the hungerers apart as they were forced into such blade-locks. Also came stalkers, assassins of xeno origin who leapt from the ceiling, from the corner, from behind despite the impossibility of managing to gone unseen, and struck at every single vulnerable spot they could before dying. Wounds were taken, of course, but none truly fatal or crippling. No, the greater portion of these came from the cabals of void screamers, the alien psykers achieving in number what none could do individually. More than one Scarlet Lion was immolated by soul-searing flames, a pair of 2nd Company marines similarly lost to bolts of piercing ice that managed to turn their blood solid within their bodies – only to shatter them moments later.

In time, they reached the hollowed out deeper portions, places where given time clouds might even have formed within the enormous caverns. Here, entire cities and factorums had been built, now inhabited by nothing even resembling a human. Here, drilling and refining machinery that were as large as homes trundled back and forth. Here, at the absolute lowest point, after a full month of fighting downwards, did the space marines come upon the Queen. The rumors did not disappoint, nor did the Deathwatch records. In the far distance, over a large stretch of plains which positively boiled with an ocean of Suysh bodies, was a bloated and fattened lizard creature, all fat and bulbous compared to the harsh angles and metals of an Imperial Knight, yet equal in general size. She sat at the direct center of the cavern, surrounded on all sides by an ocean of white eggs all around her. Even as they watched, several more piles of such things came spewing out of a series of holes along the lower back of the skin, slick with a disgusting mucous and slime that kept them form shattering as they felt to the ground below.

“Ah! There lies the beast, sloth and malice pon her brow!” The Scarlet Lion’s commander cried out, swinging his power sword slowly through the air as he stalked back and forth.

He was, as it turned out, the same one who had introduced the Scarlet Lions into the system at all. Force Commander Bartorius, also known as the Captain of the 4nd Company, was utterly indefatigable, or so it seemed. He was near matchless with the blade, as Cyrus had seen, and seemed like he was either promoted from being a chaplain or had suffered a gross disservice in terms of specialist selection. In that he talked loudly and often, focused just as much on buoying the spirits of his fellow marines as he was in fighting. In the past month, not only Cyrus but every marine of the 2nd Company had heard a great many tales of the Scarlet Lions. An apparent philosopher in their Chapter Master Platon, who had died fighting in one of the Black Crusades. Of the ‘Naiser Crusade’, one that Cyrus had never heard of but had dealt with over a hundred worlds brought back into the Imperium’s light. The hunting down and slaying of the Chaos warband who had been responsible for destroying the world of Lemnos, the homeworld of the Scarlet Lions, thousands and thousands of years ago.

“She’s completely surrounded,” Cyrus grunted, “We would be charging to our death trying to get through all of that.”

“You speak truly, Cyrus. However, there may be another way,” Sicarius motioned them over.

All around them, their combined forces were fighting, for the Suysh had become very aware of their presence. Even now, surges were beginning to arrive at a momentarily recaptured mining factorum which was serving as their forward operating base. The aliens greatly outnumbered them, and in this cavern there were none of the spaces that the space marines could normally use to remove numbers as an effective disadvantage. Heavy bolters, lascannons, missile launchers, and heavy flamers were being used in heavy abundance, just enough to keep the enemy back for now. It would not last. Something needed to be done, and soon.

“Speak, noble Raven,” Bartorius said without looking at Sicarius. “Let us not mince breath!”

“We go up and over, drop down, and slay her, all while carrying teleportarium beacons with us.”

Cyrus merely raised an eyebrow.

“We brought climbing equipment with us, did we not?” Sicarius said hotly to the unasked question.

“In case of cave collapses, mine-shaft lateral and vertical movement requirements, and the like,” Cyrus said grudgingly. “But we don’t have enough for everyone here, not nearly.”

“We don’t need to,” the taller marine shook his head. “All we need to do is get over here, and slay her, then teleport out.”

“You’ll need quite the distraction to keep them from noticing marines clambering up the cavern walls and ceilings.”

“Then, I would’st pontificate that our course be clear, then,” Bartorius mag-locked his blade to his hip just so he could put his fists upon them instead. “You, sir, hold thyself as one truly skilled with the shadows. Whilst you and yond brethren clamber in darkness, let us present a light to demand their attentions!”

Cyrus just looked at Sicarius.

“He’s not wrong, Cyrus. It was what I was planning to suggest anyhow.”

“You don’t want to go yourself?”

“I would not risk the campaign simply for slaying but one Queen,” Sicarius bit back in a guttural growl, one of his fists clenching at his side. “There are more, besides.”

Cyrus simply looked at him before nodding curtly.

“Very well then. Pull back to a more defensible position. We’ll gather up the explosives we’ll need before heading out.”

Distraction
75 vs. 55

The factorum was abandoned, a new location found. This was a raised hill, one where an entire administratum complex was located. Once, it had been a place for hundreds of adepts and their mountains of papers and data slates to be organized. Once, the information that flowed in and out of that place could have staggered an un-augmented mind. But now, all of the aid servitors were gone, the cogitators ripped out or destroyed, the walls barren of Imperial tapestries and artwork. Even the statues of the Emperor and his most loyal sons and greatest saints were gone, long ago having been melted down into ammo to be fired into Imperial lines. But while the Blood Ravens might not have been sons of Dorn, they could still admirably fortify their location. The Scarlet Lions even volunteered to keep the enemy away to allow them more time. All the while, a large number of the 10th Company relied on every bit of their stealth training to clamber upwards at a steady pace. They carried amongst them simply tremendous amounts of explosives, abandoning all but a combat knife and teleportarium repeaters on their persons, such was the demand for speed and stealth.

Climbing
43 vs. 30

Below, the battle grew ever fiercer. Suysh began to swarm along and up the slopes that had been prepared by the space marines. The entire complement of mines that the Blood Ravens had brought with them were. Towers at the almost keep-like structure became heavy weapon hard points, firing down at every foe they could sight. The walls were manned by over a hundred marines, throwing grenades and firing bolters without a moment of pause. Occasionally, the assault marines would use their steadily depleting jump pack fuel to leap up, over, and then down into the enemy to shatter charge attempts and ruin alien momentum. The Scarlet Lions leapt back and forth, every attempt to take the walls faltering before their blistering assaults. Unfortunately, unlike the marines themselves, the walls were not made of ceramite. Thermal cannon blasts, not just from royal guard but from advancing fang tanks as well, began to melt holes in the walls that required the Scarlet Lions to descend below to both beat back insertions and reduce their strength upon the walls. There was little point in trying to plug such gaps wholly, they had not the material nor time to do so, and anything that was shoved into place would be melted soon after more likely than not. All that mattered was that the techmarines were able to construct the largest possible teleportarium repeater beacon at the very center of the complex.

Cyrus saw none of this, for he and a number of his most experienced scouts had been clambering vertically and then horizontally for hours. They did not pause. They did not have time to.

Battling Defense
12 vs. 49

A space marine next to Sicarius had just enough time to roar in pain before his head detonated. Another alien psyker howled with laughter as they floated back and forth at insane angles and speeds. Elsewhere, a number of fang tanks fired as one and blew apart one of the sections of the wall, sending both Blood Ravens and Scarlet Lions to the ground far below in terrible crashes. Some were wounded, some were not, but all were soon surrounded as Suysh clambered through the hole blown in the wall. Some were torn at by a dozen different heat-blades and razor sharp claws, others had close-range ballistic weaponry crack and chip holes into their armor, many were reduced to outright fighting on their backs against the enemy despite the wounds that began to grow in number and scope. It was then that Scarlet Lions began to carve their fellows free, bolt pistols booming and power weapons flaring with power. Sicarius watched this, firing his plasma cannon all the while, before once more activating the vox. But the signal was weak and flickering this far beneath the earth, and repeaters and boosters for the teleportarium did not do the same for the vox. Still, he tried. He had to.

“Chapter Master, do you read? Gabriel, this is Macharius Sicarius! If you can read me, we require aid at the furthest point! We’ve located the Queen, but we are being overrun!”

Vox Call
64

For a moment, there was nothing but static, making Sicarius grit his teeth.

“We are on the way, brother-captain! Hold until we can reinforce you!”

The Captain of the 2nd Company released his breath explosively as he unconsciously nodded.

“Very well, Chapter Master. We will hold!”

To punctuate his statement, he turned and fired the plasma cannon once more as another hole was opened up in the walls. The shot went directly into a screaming hungerer’s maw, the resulting superheated explosion taking out a number of its nearby fellows as well. To his immense anger and frustration, the aliens were beginning to turn the old mining machines of the mountain against them. Enormous drills and digging machines were beginning to chug their way up the paths, the Suysh seamlessly parting around them to let them forward. Growling, Sicarius made his way up the walls once more and began barking orders to focus on them. The fang tanks blowing holes in, he could handle, as well as the infantry, but a single one of those machines could collapse an entire quadrant of the complex walls.

Holding
13 vs. 71

“Agh! Damn the Mechanicus for their doughty construction and palmy machines!” Shouted Bartorius as another series of missile strikes utterly failed to do more than to scratch the paint off of one of the ever closer mining machines. “Were these damnable things personally blessed by the Omnissiah?!”

It seemed so, at least, as a ridiculous amount of ammo had been expended – wasted, really – trying to destroy or at least halt the machines in their progress. But for little more than soot marks and scored paint. Sicarius had stopped bothering minutes ago, instead focusing on destroying targets that he knew would truly suffer. Dialing up the cannon to its maximal mode, every miniature sun that he unleashed upon the aliens below struck down a tank. Often included in such vaporized carnage were several Suysh at the same time. But it could not last, and he knew it. As did Bartorius, though he showed it little other than his increasingly elaborate curses upon the enemy.

“We must pull back to the inner portions of the complex, these walls will be lost soon!”

Bartorius did not answer immediately, instead firing his bolt pistol into the crowds below until it clicked empty. He cursed beneath his breath before mag-locking it to his armor and nodding at Sicarius.

“Verily, forsooth we must ready ourselves for the press that shall no doubt come! Back, brothers! Back! To yon inner defenses we must away!”

Tactical Withdrawal
63 vs. 81

It was the best that could be done, with the walls literally crumbling all around them. When the first of the digging machines burst their way through entirely, allowing the tide of aliens within, the Blood Ravens and Scarlet Lions had only completed a certain portion of the retreat. Certain groups were overtaken, and though many hacked their way free, they did so carrying the bodies of their wounded who were already beginning to curl into sus-an states. Others were not so lucky, and found themselves torn apart in screaming pieces before furious apothecaries could push their way through to rescue the precious gene-seed, in turn taking their own grievous injuries in the pursuit of their course. Still, they pulled, and pushed, leaving bouquets of grenades behind them as they went, others who had managed to reach the inner sections of the complex already turning about to fire over the heads of withdrawing marines.

Then Sicarius, who had managed to clamber to one of the higher towers left stable, and grimaced further. Even if every dreadnought in the chapter had been present, from every company, they would have been outnumbered five to one by the oncoming royal guards. The largest possible variations of their kind, second only to the Queen who squawked and screeched at them from over two miles away. They thundered up the hill, battering aside any Suysh who got in their way with merciless violence. Those whose bodies were broken by this provided little more than meaty chunks for their fellows to feast upon as the greater mass surged forwards.

Reinforcements
41 vs. 28

It started slowly and with an odd delay, one that – aside from Trajan Maphar who fell to one knee as he felt the warp twist about – only the techmarines could track through their readouts. Hidden here and there, the repeater beacons briefly flared, and within the mountain, within the inner and last portion of the complex not overrun, there was the scent of tainted ozone and the faintest of ethereal howling which nonetheless filled the ears of everyone present. Human or otherwise. Then with a blinding series of flashes, the entire 1st Company of the Blood Ravens and the 3rd Company of the Scarlet Lions came into being. Thankfully, the beacon placement and strength was enough that they did not lose anyone within the mountain or the warp, but the techmarines seemed rather agitated as they went over the latest of the beacons with whirring mechadendrites.

They did not arrive all at once, obviously, but nonetheless did so quickly enough that it almost did not matter. The terminator-clad Blood Ravens did not even pause, already spinning up their lascannons and assault cannons as they pushed to the fore. The Scarlet Lions, for their part, delivered devastator squad after devastator squad onto the battlefield. One of them, his winged helm a close mirror to the one that Bartorius possessed, leapt upwards and joined is fellow with the aid of a jump pack. Unlike the sword that Bartorius held, this one held no ranged weapon at all, both arms instead bearing lightning claws.

“Bartorius! How fares you, Force Commander?”

The Scarlet Lion turned and splayed his arms wide, a fierce bubble of laughter makings its way out of his throat.

“Hah! Kleonoi! I doth find this a most testing battle, but then, how could it not be!”

They exchanged wrist-claps that clanked their blood-soaked ceramite together.

“My heart swells with the sight of my brothers in the 3rd Company, Kleonoi, though mine own 4th are my most preferred, of course. With haste, though, for we must fight these vile things away here and now!”

“Of course!”

Then both were leaping into the fray, leaving Sicarius to exchange a look with his Chapter Master. Gabriel simply looked down at him, eyebrow raised, otherwise expressionless.

“Are they all like that?” Sicarius finally asked.

“In the limited time I have spent fighting alongside Captain Kleonoi, I regret to inform you that it seems to be so,” Gabriel told him in a tired voice that soon faded when he saw the alien hordes approaching them. “But there will be time for questions on such things later, and we will be speaking as to the character of Akermian,” he growled, marching forward with his hammer rising with him. “For now, we fight! Come, Blood Ravens! With me!”

=======================================

Cyrus had done a lot of things in his centuries of life, but this would rank amongst the more dangerous, he thought. Around him, the rest of the scouts watched as he slowly packed more and more explosives together. Some of them were holding themselves to the rock with nothing more than fingers and their boots. Others had worked hard to chisel in holes for certain portions of their body to be held. Due to the height of the cavern, the enormous mountain hollowed out over generations of human lives, they were wholly covered in shadow. It was not as if the Administratum or Mechanicus would have seen the point in expending the resources to light it all up. Nor was it such a cavern that it could possess its own major weather patterns – save for occasionally winds. Nonetheless, with their camo cloaks shrouding them all they looked nothing more than like bats, with Cyrus commanding the appearance more than any other with his legs hooked to the ceiling and the rest of him pointing directly down.

“Captain…,” one of the scouts said, breaking the silence of the past few hours. “Are you sure about this?”

Cyrus looked over to them, his hands continuing the assembly work.

“The Queen needs to be killed, does she not, scout?”

“But, you’ll be marked…,”

“If that is so, then we will use that to our advantage if at all possible. If not, we will adapt. It is the way of things.”

There was a final foreboding click, and they all looked at the enormous package he held with both arms.

“Tell me, initiate,” he grunted before letting it hang in the open air with only one arm still clutching at it.

The weight of it was straining, even for him, yet still he held on.

“Have you ever hear the tales of Kronus, and the Thur'Abis Plateau?”

==================================================================

Withstanding
82 vs. 66

“What?!” Bartorius roared in outrage before slicing apart another bloodscale, twisting about to kick a clawborn up into the air where it was shot apart by other Scarlet Lions. “Falsehood and mockery! The valorous Kallek hath held the mantle of Captain of the 2nd Company for over a century, and thither hath never been one such named as ‘Akermian’ pon our ranks of leadership!”

Gabriel had seen little point to waiting in making his concerns known, and better now, where the Scarlet Lions were already engaged in combat, than later when they might be in a situation to lie with greater ease. As it was, the Force Commander of the Scarlet Lions was not taking the news particularly well.

“And yet they were here! Using your heraldry, and your battle cry!”

Bartorius snarled and backhanded another clawborn and stomped across the battlefield over to Gabriel, firing his bolt pistol almost absentmindedly at charging xenos as he went. Once it clicked empty he grabbed the larger marine by the armor and turned him slightly to better face him.

“I would see the truth of this, Blood Raven, lest I demand satisfaction for the besmirching of our good name!” He choked out in a voice full of rage that nearly shook the Lion apart.

“Should we all survive this fight, have no doubt about that, Bartorius,” Gabriel growled, shoving the Scarlet Lion away. “There are Blood Ravens dead by the actions of those bearing your banner. We shall both have retribution, one way or another before this campaign is done.”

Both were forced to duck, if only momentarily, as a flight of Suysh VTOLs came screaming overhead on an attack run. Weaponry both ballistic and thermal blanketed the field even as return fire came spitting back up. One of the Suysh craft was hit in just the right portion of its engine to send it careening downward into a mass of xenos. Most, however, survived the return salvo and rocketed away to resupply. They glared at one another across the blood and rubble-strewn grounds before both turned away to their respective commands. Neither was willing to risk giving an inch to the alien, even if they did not particularly care for one another.

====================================================

Winds Of Death
71

The winds of the cavern blew one way, then the other. The continual explosions, the general heat levels that would grant the touch of heat stroke to mortal men without specialized equipment, and further holes bored into the earth were the creators of this. But there was a pattern to them, one that had been painstakingly observed during the travel. One that his mind had calculated in a long-running process since the moment he had begun ascent. One that, even now, he quadruple-checked before nodding. Tensing, he curled his body inwards and then out, beginning to swing himself back and forth. In. Out. In. Out. Then, at the exact right moment, he let go. Death fell with nothing more than a quiet beep to announce itself. A blast of wind, the result of a hundred tanks firing, of thermal drafts blooming from cannons booming, and it whipped directly opposite the direction he’d thrown it. This, of course, was planned. For after continuing to fall, it twisted about in the air as it was tugged in another direction entirely by the drafts coming from the northern tunnels of the mine, who had consistently released such with absolute precision within a miniscule second difference from each instance to the next. There was no such divergence here either, at least none worth noting.

Cyrus watched and waited, barely bothering to breathe, his face an absolute study in concentration.

Eventually, the package achieved terminal velocity.

Down it went, its descent only somewhat arrested here and there as it was shifted horizontally by the winds, but never was its progress truly stymied. One minute passed. Then another. The distance was considerable, after all. But he knew explosives better than anyone in the rest of the entire chapter, save perhaps Martellus who by dint of his position knew secrets of Mars that not even Cyrus was personally privy to. There was nothing more than a quiet beep to mark its passage through the darkness of the cavern, even when it passed from darkness into fell light borne of xeno-inspired industry and life. The attendant army that encircled the Queen were enough noise pollution on their own, thousands of feet stomping, tanks rumbling, hiss-clicks of their foul speech filling the air. None of which was as loud as the disgusting wheezes of the Queen herself, or the regular bursts of mucous and slime from her laying orifices which were continually producing new egg clusters. Around her were entire clusters of alien psykers, the warp screamers bathed in psychic fires or wreathed in discolored lightning.

It was an army capable of matching one of the Imperium’s, in many a circumstance. A full Imperial Crusade, perhaps, could crush and destroy their race. But stretched as the Imperium was in all directions, one simply could not be marshaled for such an effort. Not when Armageddon teetered on the brink of destruction, when all of the realm of Ultramar was embroiled in conflict with Hive Fleet Leviathan, when so many battlefields and crusades had already been called across the galaxy. But such a thing was, perhaps, not needed.

Or at least, that was what Cyrus thought when the combined explosives of the entire 2nd Company of the Blood Ravens and many of the 4th Company of the Scarlet Lions, along with scavenged Suysh munitions impacted the top of the Suysh Queen’s head and exploded. Plasma and melta and vortex combined into a concurrent explosion of epic proportions, and in a resounding series of shockwaves which made many of the closest aliens around the Queen being thrown to their feet. Despite the grim captain’s words, it was of course not nearly the same level of detonation achieved by the immensely powerful plasma bomb that had once been used on the planet of Kronus. For all that it nearly shook all of the scouts off of the roof that they clung to with desperate strength.

But it was close enough.

Once the light had faded, the Queen from the waist up was gone, leaving only charred and smoking ruin behind.

“Return, return now!” Cyrus shouted suddenly, and the teleportarium beacons began to flicker and vibrate heavily as the warp was once more torn open.

The techmarines clustered around the largest assembled repeater shouted the same as no one in the entire cavern could possibly have missed the explosion. High in orbit, the ships responded to the signal that appeared on their consoles. Within seconds, they began to activate. For a wonder, the Suysh had ceased their attacks entirely, as it turned out, allowing a great many of the wounded to be pulled to their feet so that a teleportarium could pull groups out. From the largest of the royal guard, to the clawborn who were just beginning to push their way out of their wet shells, every xeno visible had paused in their movement. This hesitance lasted but a moment, but for Trajan Maphar, it was an eternity. It was worse, as it turned out, due to his lack of injury putting him towards the end of the priority list on evacuation protocol.

The 10th Company epistolary could only scream as his eyes and began to gush blood, his entire body locking up from the titanic forces being unleashed just on the other side of the veil of reality.

For he saw, in truth, the form of a Suysh Queen.

What had been a bloated pathetic thing in flesh was a horror of magnificence in the warp. The leviathan-sized soul of the Suysh Queen, already being torn asunder by predators and harvester creatures who desired any and all possible sustenance. Its body twisted and writhed under the attentions of those that would soon end it, but he saw, truly, what it was. Laced psycho-reactive pheromones spread throughout its existence, coating and lasting far beyond pure organic possibilities. Spread by every royal guard, themselves possessors of symbiotic growths grown alongside and within them by the very nature of their targeted growth. He watched, and heard, as the Suysh Queen’s presence thinned and focused itself, bending the tides of the immaterium with a strength that not even the Chief Librarian could possibly have possessed for a single instant.

There were no words, only intent.

Vengeance and hatred, all targeted, impossibly, by one of the first teleported out of the cavern.

Despite never seeing Cyrus Octavius, never knowing he was there, for that brief instant after physical death before the soul was disassembled, the Queen knew him.

And then so did her hive.

The sheer effort of such a thing burnt the massive soul of the Queen away entirely, leaving not even embers left behind while simultaneously scorching the many daemons who had come to try and feast. With its completion, the Suysh left within the mines screamed so loudly as to burst a space marine’s ear drums within his helmet. Their very flesh split open as something inside of their bodies activated, musculature engorging, fangs and claws lengthening, their very bodies being altered by the death scream, their Queen’s final command. Then they turned as one and began to charge, weapons aside from their own blades left behind. Tanks gunned their engines and started running over those who could not get out of the way. VTOLs accelerated at top speed to initiate suicide crashes.

Only then, as one of the last, was Trajan returned from within Bluevein Mountain to arrive gasping and choking on his own blood on the floor of the Howling Hatred’s teleportarium.

==========================================================

Force Commander Bartorius slammed his fist onto the side of the table, but said nothing as he listened to the audio logs provided by the Blood Ravens. He had been joined, as it turned out, by the other two captains of his chapter. Three companies of the Scarlet Lions had come, and none of them were particularly pleased. Captain Kallek, of their 2nd, and Captain Agamat of their 3rd, were just as deathly quiet as Bartorius, though Gabriel could tell that they were only just barely holding their fury in. The trio of foreign marines devoured every bit of sensory data that could be provided to them by the apparent imposters. Who had borne their colors, their banners, their words, their symbols. Who had even possessed their codes, somehow, something that Bartorius had been first to dispute before the truth of the matter had struck him silent.

Finally, the last data entry came out.

“This is Master Akermian. Seeing as you have these planets well in hand, the Scarlet Lions shall pursue the home of the Suysh directly. We have scoured their foul alien cogitators and located it.”

“Wait, Master Akermian,” Martellus spoke quickly on the recording, “If you have those coordinates, then share them so we may-,”

“You will surely find them in time should you search enough yourself, Blood Raven. I would insult you by simply taking such a thing from you. Emperor guide you.”

Bartorius breathed deeply, his entire body almost heaving with each inhalation and exhalation.

“I knoweth such blackguards not,” he finally said.

Slowly, carefully, he reached up to pull his helmet off with both hands, letting it fall carelessly onto the table as he bowed his head. His bald head was weathered, the skin a dusky brown with dozens of white scars here and there from long centuries of battle. He sighed before looking up with dark amber eyes to lock eyes with Gabriel who – along with all of the Blood Raven captains – stood across the table with arms folded. Then he looked to his left and jerked his chin at Kallek who approached and picked up one of the data slates and began to scour its contents.

“Thou art the most learned in the records and history of the chapter within our force, brother-captain,” Bartorius spoke in a whisper. “Tell me forsooth.”

Kallek did not even require a minute before slamming the data slate down onto the table with enough force to crack it.

“It be of our codes, Force Commander,” the other Scarlet Lion said morosely. “It is that of the 8th, not of the 2nd, but yon Blood Ravens could knoweth not such a thing.”

All three of the Lions appeared to wince at the news.

“The…8th Company?” Gabriel asked calmly, his fury now granted a direction that was not aimed at the ones before him.

“The noble 8th Company were lost half a century ago in the fires of Armageddon,” Bartorius rasped. “With all hands, by the guns of the monstrous greenskins. Their code structure hath never been scoured from the logs because there was no one to use them anymore.”

Agamat, who had spoken rarely since arriving on the Omnis Arcanum, stepped forward while placing a hand on his force commander’s shoulder in a remarkably comforting gesture.

“Then someone doth be besmirching the 8ths legacy, their names, and dances macabre with their emblems and symbols,” he growled. “And such must be stopped.”

“…aye, aye,” Bartorius muttered, straightening as he did so. “Forsooth! The Lions of Lemnos shall not have such desecration stand!”

He whirled upon his fellows and pointed back out the hallway.

“Brothers! Assemble your companies and prepare for deployment!”

He whirled back to Gabriel.

“We will fight alongside you, Chapter Master of the Blood Ravens, and once the Jahal System is reclaimed once more, we shall hunt these villains down! We will show them the meaning of unceasing upon the enemy!”

Then he stomped, no, ran back towards his ships without another word. The Blood Ravens were left to speak amongst themselves. The chance of further deception, given everything in the galaxy? High. The chance that it was truth? Frustratingly high as well. But they could not simply lock the Scarlet Lions down and attempt to interrogate them. There still remained a number of Suysh Queens on each of the four planets, though the slaying of one had proven even more beneficial than initially thought. The splitting of the leaderless hive had given evidence as to the location of two more upon Matsuya, the psychic impressions gained by Trajan shared with the rest of the Librarius had assisted in the locating of others on the other planets of the system. A well-trusted weapon of the Blood Ravens, knowledge, had finally been honed enough by death and violence to be properly turned upon the Suysh.

All that was required now was for it to be directed.

Refinement And Continuation
Phase 3 Concluded! With all the knowledge gained thus far, and the aid of the Scarlet Lions, choose how the remainder of the Jahal System Cleansing will go. This means that the phase will continue until all objectives are completed barring major shake-ups such as an Ork WAAAGH!! entering the system, Gabriel or any of the Captains dying, etc. Choose carefully. Due to the extent of the phase's time-frame, it is assumed all wounded marines are healed and return to service, and that damaged ships return to Sacred Crown for repair. They will still be in this post's casualties notation, simply for tracking purposes, but can be assumed healed/repaired as best as possible by the beginning of the final phase. Information gained on killing requirements, psychic aid, etc. will be factored into the planning of the characters now that they have that information. Moratorium for 3 Hours.

4th Phase Pathing
Void Placement
[] Bombardment: Write-In Which Fleets Go To Which Planet For Orbital Aid Purposes (Teleportation, Bombardment, Drop Pods, Etc.)
[] Interdiction: Write-In Which Fleets/Ships Remain On Interdiction Duty

Company Placement
1st and 2nd Fleet, Justinius Probalis, Gabriel Angelos, Apollo Diomedes, Honor Guard, Spread Across Currently Concentrated On Matsuya with minor elements on Kuru
10th and 4th Fleet, Hannibal Palrun, Nero Gracchus Currently Concentrated On Vatsa with minor elements on Avanti, with Captain Octavius having elected to go to Matsuya to assist with Queen slaying, returning to Vatsa for start of next phase.
[] Keep Positions As They Are
[] Change Company Deployments For The Planets (I.E. Shifting 1st Company to Vatsa or 10th Company to Kuru) (Write-In Changes)

Planetary Ground Target Priority List [i.e. Top, Middle, Bottom for Kuru/Middle, Bottom, Top for Matsuya/Etc.]
[] Kuru (Write-In Ground Priority List)
[] Matsuya (Write-In Ground Priority List)
[] Avanti (Write-In Ground Priority List)
[] Vatsa (Write-In Ground Priority List)

Phase 3 Completes!

Spoiler: Total Casualties/Fatalities

All 4th and 1st Company Ships Damaged In Some Measure Or Another! Requires Repairs For General Combat Effectiveness!
38 of 2nd Company Wounded
8 of 1st Company Wounded
12 10th Company Scouts [1st Stage] Wounded
4 Scouts [1st Stage] Killed [8 Gene-Seed Recovered]
15 4th Company Marines Wounded
5 4th Company Marines Dead [10 Gene-Seed Recovered]
1 Tarantula Sentry Turret Destroyed (Twin-Linked Heavy Bolters)
-16 2nd Company Marines (32 Gene-Seed Recovered)
-12 10th Company Neophytes

Spoiler: Phase Objectives + Tactical Considerations

Tactical Consideration! 'True' Scarlet Lions Have Arrived In System, True Support Sent By Inquisitor Lord Tarquindil! 2nd, 3rd, and 4th Company of Scarlet Lions, bringing 1 Battle Barge + 4 Strike Cruisers + 12 Nova Frigates in the void and 300 marines plus specialists on the ground. Led under command of Force Commander Bartorius, also Captain of the 4th Company. True Identity of 'False' Scarlet Lions Unknown!
Tactical Consideration! Suysh Death-Scream Vengeance Effect Identified As Psychic/Organic Effect! Librarius Believes May Be Possible To Deflect/Alter/Defend Against If Entire Librarius Focused Upon Said Task During A Queen Killing!
Tactical Consideration! One Queen Dead! Matysuya In Major Disarray! Cyrus Currently Death-Marked!
Tactical Consideration! 1 Queen Located On Kuru, Vatsa, Avanti! 2 New Queens Located On Matsuya Due To Queens Exerting Control To Claim Now Queen-Less Hive For Their Own Forces!
Tactical Consideration! Scarlet Lions have elected to push entire ground force onto planet Vatsa to search for signs of the 'other' Scarlet Lions! Battle Bare is on orbital duty, their strike cruisers and escorts on inderdiction duty!

Turn 26: Echoes Of Genocide (Part Six)

Spoiler: Vote Plan

[X] Plan no idea what I'm doing
-[X] Interdict
--[X] 2nd, 4th and 10th Fleets
-[X] Continued Bombardment
--[X] 1st Fleet
-[X] Change Company Deployments For The Planets
--[X] 4th and 10th Company to Matsuya
-[X] Matsuya
--[X] top
---[X] All ground forces
----[X] If possible, use Cyrus's Death-Mark to pull forces away from the Queens
----[X] Use the Librarius to avoid further Death-Marks

GM NOTE: I'm sincerely sorry for the delays. Life has been...life.

Echoes of Genocide
+065.M42+ To +070.M42+
+Through The Foe's Obliteration Do We Earn Salvation+

The first of many had fallen, and yet it had been a grievous task nonetheless. But as ever, the more knowledge of the foe the Blood Ravens possessed, the better they could plan their assaults. Considering the effort and materials used up in the slaying of but one Queen of the xeno race, it was decided by Gabriel Angelos that they would concentrate their forces upon the plant of Matsuya. While this would allow the aliens to reinforce the worlds that were left without space marine presence, at the very least the Scarlet Lions would ensure that the world of Vatsa would feel the full force of their wrath and indignation. In an odd mirror, they would be scouring the planet for evidence of the false lions, just as said imposters had sought to do the same for their own quarry. Hundreds of marines redeployed thusly, injuries and wounds healed en route to their new deployments. Many ships, of both chapters, shifted position as well back out into the void such that they could interdict against the surely incoming alien fleet which would be arriving soon.

“Fight well, Lion,” Gabriel declared to the foreign Force Commander. “We shall meet again, soon.”

“Verily, Chapter Master Angelos. We shall be but a planet away!” Bartorius replied back in his odd Gothic before striding away to a waiting thunderhawk.

The assembled leadership of both companies shared similar sentiments amongst themselves before separating properly. The Blood Ravens strode as one towards their own transports. A new target had been decided upon shortly before. Though they knew not the Suysh Queen’s name, they knew where she was thanks to the efforts of scouts and tactical analysis. A deeply dug canyon manufactorum complex which both refined mined materials from across the planet and produced small arms and light vehicles at the same time. The angle of it made bombing runs difficult, what with it being built into the very sides of the canyon, and orbital bombardment was not a prominent option due to the importance of the complex itself for the industrial capacity of the planet.

“The 4th Company and the rest of 10th Company will be arriving soon, Chapter Master,” Sicarius informed Gabriel as they stomped up the ramp into the waiting thunderhawks.

Gabriel simply nodded and glanced over to where the Chief Librarian himself stood amongst the rest of his assembled Librarius.

“Justinian!” He called out, causing the large marine to turn about, psychic light flickering out of his eyes even when he closed them. “Are they ready?”

“As ready as they can be,” Justinian grunted, clapping a hand over the somewhat recovered Trajan Maphar’s shoulder. “We have examined the memories of young Trajan, but it will remain to be seen if we can challenge such a released psychic presence until we are actually faced with it.”

“I suppose that is the best that can be done, for now,” Gabriel muttered before jerking his head towards the transports. “But enough of this. We must begin the assault. The 4th and remainder of the 10th will join us when they can.”

============================================

The Slategrass Canyon Complex was an odd beast, but not one without openings to it. Exhaust piping and cooling stacks which sprouted up out of the ground like squat metal bulbs. Launch and loading bays from where ceaseless transports arrived and departed both in the age of the Imperium’s rule and now under the alien’s dominance. Such transport streams slowed, and then ceased, however, with the encroachment of the Blood Ravens. Weapons-fire, and interceptions by the Thunderhawks, began to choke their ability to reinforce and supply themselves. This had the natural result of causing the Suysh to begin concentrating what forces they possessed and begin building up defensive positions. They, just as the Hive which had been concentrated in the mountain, knew most likely what it was the enemy intended. The psychic shockwave of a Queen’s death had most certainly alerted the other Queen’s upon the planet as to the death of one of their peers. Further evidence of this was the splitting apart of the remaining alien forces around Bluevein and across the planet in two different directions. Subterfuge would no longer serve the alien in concealing their presence, and they knew it.

Death-Mark Abuse: 54 vs. 29

However, what could not be discounted was the sheer power of their alien instincts. The moment Cyrus Octavius, Master of Recruits and Captain of the 10th Company, entered within some unknown range of distance, a great many of the Slategrass Canyon’s occupants abandoned their posts. For all that a new Queen had asserted dominance over a great many of them, many evacuating to the complex under Blood Raven and Scarlet Lion fire, they were inextricably soul-locked upon avenging the death of the one who had birthed them. Prepared defensive positions, chokepoints, cross-fire set-ups, and more were left emptied as the aliens screamed for the blood and meat of the one who had performed the greatest of crimes known to the Suysh. In turn, Cyrus turned about whilst in a land speeder, forcing the aliens to chase after him. The approaching Blood Raven lines purposefully split apart themselves, allowing a massive gap between them to allow the aliens – insane as they were with chemical fury and psychic commands – to pass by without aggression. There were greater targets awaiting them in any case.

Initial Assault Paths
Infiltration: 93 vs. 49
Open Attacks: 4 vs. 56
Deep Striking: 82 vs. 39

Though they were bereft of their Captain’s leadership, Cyrus had prepared the 10th Company well. Veteran scout sergeants led them into disappearing into the complex’s chimneys, cooling stacks, and exhaust releases. The heat and smog within them would have blinded and choked those without the specialized organs and equipment the space marines possessed. Once within, information began to flow from the scouts reports. Enemy numbers and positions, armories, and the like. They even began initial assassination efforts, as well as laying down explosives to block out alien pushes from certain portions of the complex. On the outside, things did not progress nearly as well.

With all the fury that could be mustered, the Blood Ravens began to descend the canyon walls, or advanced from either end of the canyon’s reaches. But despite the abandoning of a great many defenses by those most recently inducted into the Slategrass hive, there remained plenty more to take up those same positions once more. The Blood Ravens pushed, and the alien pushed back, heat cannons and slug weaponry firing in enormous arcs to grind down any who tried to intrude. A full three dozen pushes were enacted by the Angels of Death, only to find that they were repulsed every time, garnering only injuries ranging from light to grievous for their efforts. Captain Sicarius, chosen to lead this assault, refused to waver for even a moment, however. He was unbowed despite the setbacks, and through the flames, proved his mettle well enough at ensuring that his brothers did not falter. Besides which, he knew that it was unlikely in the first place that they would be able to simply smash their way through the enemy defenses.

But then, he did not need to.

Especially when the 1st Company teleported past the enemy lines, aided by the presence of laid down beacons and repeaters by the 10th Company. The Honor Guard followed the Chapter Master himself as they flashed into existence in the deeper portions of the canyon complex, storm bolters and assault cannons beginning firing before the Suysh could even begin to register their presence. Gun emplacements were smashed from behind, reinforcement mobs of aliens shredded to pieces and slaughtered in great number. Heavy flamers and power weaponry lit up the darkness in brief glorious flashes of purging flame and shearing destruction. Xeno commanders found themselves attacked within their bunkers and bastions with abandon. Here, linked up with the infiltrators of the 10th Company, they ensured that enemy communication relays also fell dark, alarms silenced before they could activate, ensuring the carnage could continue at length. It would take half an hour for the aliens to manage to propagate the fact that they had been attacked from behind, and thus the fire levied upon Captain Sicarius’ detachment was lessened quite rapidly.

At which point he ordered a full charge as the Suysh turned around inside their tunnels and pillboxes upon the onrushing terminator-clad 1st Company whilst the 10th Company fired from the shadows.

Defense Destruction: 77 vs. 88

Trapped as they were, with absolutely nowhere to go, the Suysh fought with fatalistic abandon. Marines fell, some rising, some remaining still as they were locked into suspended animation by their own biology. And yet there were those who would never rise again. A marine of the 2nd Company who was left as nothing more than a torso and some of a neck, the rest of his body devoured by his killers before they too were shot apart. A marine of the 4th, newly arrived from orbit, had fallen as his helmet was forcibly torn from his shoulders by a pair of hungerers, his skull turned to slag. There, too, came casualties amongst the 10th Company, those not yet as masterful as their seniors in matters of stealth. Overall, however, the action was successful enough.

The Blood Ravens had entered the complex, the aliens not doughty enough to repulse them. Only one half of the complex required insertion in the first place, the other side of the canyon not entertaining the presence of a Queen. Nevertheless, the most injured of the Blood Ravens, who could not be carelessly thrown against the heavy defenses awaiting the Chapter, were instead granted another duty. To take up their own new defensive positions, absconding with or outright replacing the emplacements of the xenos. Rapiers and predators, incapable of journeying through the tightest quarters, were instead placed here. Sicarius took to this new duty with a grim implacableness, swearing an oath that not one alien would pass by his cordon while the rest of the Blood Ravens delved within.

===========================================

Gabriel examined the corpse of one of the larger Suysh subspecies, its dreadnought-sized frame releasing a nearly unholy stench from its ruptured innards. This one had not even died to a blow from without, rather it was it attempting to consume a fallen marine that had killed it. A bandolier of krak grenades had split its bolter-resistant carapace from within in a massive explosion. The marine in question, one Brother Tybolt, still yet lived. The marine of the 4th Company was angrier about the fact that, while he had managed to escape the creature’s jaws, his grenades had not, than anything else. It seemed that the demeanor of the 4th’s Captain was beginning to be imitated by his company.

All around him, the rest of the Blood Ravens were rallying up. The 10th Company, with Cyrus at their head, had already disappeared into the interior, doing their duty. It was now time for them to do the same. The concentrated psychic might of the Chapter was present, their safety paramount more than anything else to hopefully counteract the repercussions of the mission being undertaken. Also nearby was a fully assembled so-called ‘Fist of Faith’ formation, the black armor and skull masks of thirteen different chaplains making them stand out almost as much as the blue armored librarians amongst the Blood Ravens. At their head was the Master of Sanctity himself, Hannibal Palrun, of whom Gabriel knew it was whispered had gained the moniker of the Crimson Goliath. As for himself? Gabriel carefully bent his head from side to side, feeling the ever more seamless transition between bionic and flesh in terms of sensation, the troubles of the past failing to mark him here and now.

Then he spied Apollo Diomedes, standing nearby yet apart from all of his brethren. It had been a divergent choice, he knew. There was no position known as ‘Chapter Master’s Bodyguard’ anywhere within the Codex. Yet he had watched, and he had listened, both to Apollo himself and from Hannibal who had served as the confessionary chaplain for Apollo for decades now. For a wonder, they had arrested the worrying descent that the champion had been spiraling into. Yet, in that same vein, they had not seen much improvement either. Hannibal had pointed out that Apollo still, even now, desired something…else. Penance, perhaps. Redemption, really. Something he could not achieve in a position as lofty as he currently stood within, counted as a close companion to the Chapter Master still despite the change in just who that Chapter Master was.

Starting over as a mere battle brother, to make his way once more, had been brought up by some, Gabriel knew. As had being sent over to the Chaplaincy instead, perhaps to use his lessons to aid in their vital work. The Deathwatch was another suggestion, this one brought up by Apollo himself in his private confessionals with Hannibal. A privacy only broached due to Apollo only somewhat subtly implying that the Master of Sanctity could and should bring it up to Gabriel. There were few places a marine could go that would so surely test them and punish in equal measure to the extent that Apollo so clearly still desired. As a member of a kill-team, or perhaps even more extreme, a lone kill-marine, Apollo would be pushed in ways that the chapter could not yet. Save perhaps for leaving on a suicidal one-man mission into the Eye of Terror or to the planet of Armageddon.

===========================================

Slategrass Complex Invasion 46 vs. 90

The initial invasion of the complex depths did not go well. This was undeniable. It was not simply the sheer numbers that the Suysh rallied to defend themselves, but the variety as well. An absolute deluge of hungerers, their ogryn-esque yet alien physique allowing them to burst through walls. Royal guard erupted from the floors and ceilings within which the Blood Ravens marched, while stalker forms slunk out of vents to drop explosives and unleash unique alien poisons. Multiple void screamers were sighted, and yet at least here the presence of the combined Librarius allowed for a definitive series of defeats in the favor of the space marines. More than one void screamer found their very souls snuffed out by the burning light unleashed by Justinius personally, while other mere lexicanum worked in tandem to provide a numbers advantage against individual alien psykers. The aliens knew the environment well, and unlike Bluevein had highly altered the environment of the complex to suit their unique biology and methodology. Entire sections of the complex were utterly changed compared to the blueprints provided of the area, forcing improvisation whilst under immense pressure.

Marines fought, and marines died.

Grinding Forward: 61 vs. 96

Even the terminators of the 1st Company began to slow, the sheer weight of fire upon them, both chemically propelled and heat-based taking their toll on even their venerable armors. The front ranks of space marines began to glow white hot, beginning to cook slightly in their armors. One unfortunate marine suffered seal breaches due to a stalker’s weaponry and began to have his armor’s innards fuse to both black carapace and skin alike through the heat unleashed upon him. Elsewhere, blood-crazed clawborn were shoved forward by uncaring hungerers and bloodclaws to launch suicide assaults. Enough volume of xenos explosives strapped to their bodies were enough to send even ceramite-clad space marines flying backwards, trapping many under rubble as well. The war in the shadows did not progress well either, a successful insertion allowing too many neophytes to build up unearned confidence, only to find themselves cut down in the darkness by Suysh stalkers or discovered by void screamers.

Rally Push: 99 vs. 45

“ENOUGH OF THIS!” Hannibal Palrun roared, rising up from behind cover, his black armor already chipped and pitted heavily. “IN THE NAME OF THE EMPEROR CHARGE!”

He lifted his crozius in one hand, bellowing, and leapt forward. None others could join him in this suicidal feat, none save the rest of the chaplaincy. Thirteen in all, they charged, each screaming out a personalized litany of fury and hatred towards the alien. The largest walking space marine in the chapter led the charge all the way into the Suysh defenses, uncaring of the wounds inflicted on him. With one titanic smash of Thunder Blood into a heavy flamer emplacement, he was bathed in light and flame as the weapon’s fuel cells erupted. But he did not pause, did not cease, instead continuing on whilst quite literally emblazoned. The high copper content in that particular promethium mixture set the flames with a particular green tint, and yet through the blaze strode the rest of the Fist of Faith, fully formed.

“WE LIVE AND DIE AS BROTHERS! NOW, WITH ME, BREAK THEIR LINES!”

A royal guard approached, its rumbling steps as heavy as Tomb-Captain Thule’s own revered frame, yet under the sheer might of Hannibal it was lifted up and thrown amidst a crush of chaplains who beat upon it into gravity-blasted meat with their weapons. An entire platoon’s worth of hungerers attempted to stymie the punishing charge and found themselves counter-charged instead. No wound seemed capable of causing the chaplains to slow, each blow levied upon them either in melee or by ranged weaponry only seemed to incense them further. Always, always at their head, was Hannibal, who alternatively screamed in fury or laughed in derision at the dozens of attempts made to kill him in as many seconds. The further the Fist of Faith progressed into the Suysh lines, the more those lines fractured and compacted, allowing the rest of the Chapter to rise up and attack without pause.

Gabriel personally led the Honor Guard in a stomping advance in the same vein as the chaplains in a slightly different location, their success introducing another heavy fracture in the enemy defenses. Between him and Apollo Diomedes, the foe found themselves toppled again and again. Within an hour, the fight was done, the remaining Suysh either slain or retreating. Hannibal was found atop a mound of corpses, his bronze skin charred black as his armor where portions of the ceramite had been destroyed. His chest heaved, the red gleam of his helmet’s lenses seeming to burn with a righteous light. But he stood regardless, his wounds clotting and healing already, the rest of the chaplaincy assembled about him at various heights upon the mound. They too had all suffered wounds ranging from light to grievous, but they troubled them not.

The apothecaries would see to them as they marched.

“Forward, brothers, we must advance!” Gabriel called out, striding into the choking heat and darkness as he did so.

Without pause, the Blood Ravens followed.

==========================================

Captain Hadrian seemed motionless as he sat upon the command throne, but in truth his mind was afire with information and communications passing across the chapter fleet. While some of the ships had been seconded for orbital bombardment work, he knew his duty here was just as important. Thankfully he had received reinforcements in the form of the supposedly true Scarlet Lions. Even better was the communication brought by Martellus, who had finally brought the repair systems of the Sacred Crown back online. It was not the same as true major shipyard, but with the aid of the tech marines the work would be more than enough given proper time. After the planets were taken back fully, it was likely that it would only take a few months for the Blood Raven fleet to be repaired enough to advance towards the enemy home system.

If they ever found the coordinates that was. Speaking of which…

“Martellus,” Hadrian grunted, “Any progress on discerning the coordinates of the Suysh home system?”

The response took a moment, but eventually it came with a crackle of static and a hissing sigh on the part of the Master of the Forge.

“We are still working on it. The more Suysh ships you destroy and tow back to the station, the more of their filthy alien machines we can examine. We have a few fragments, here and there, and are narrowing it down, but more is needed.”

There was a sudden cacophony of warning klaxons which caused several of the bridge crew to jump slightly in their seats. Hadrian cut off the communication with Martellus without hesitation and ordered his ships to ready up. It was well he did so, for no sooner than had the Blood Ravens and Scarlet Lion fleet begun orienting themselves towards the gravimetric disturbances than did another fleet of Suysh ships slip out of the warp and into reality once more. This time, there was no noticeable royalty-bearing vessel amongst them, but that was fine enough with Hadrian. They somewhat even outnumbered the enemy, that fact among others making Hadrian posit that it was in fact a scouting fleet, sent to investigate the loss of communications and the lack of response from one of their precious Queens.

He was more than happy to inform the Suysh exactly as to what had happened with the aid of his bombardment cannons.

“Captain Hadrian! Huzzah! It seems that we once more may partake of joined battle betwixt our fleets against yon alien filth! Let us engage in glorious battle as brothers!”

He could do without Captain Kallek’s comments, he would admit privately, though at least he brought ships with them.

=======================================

Complex Descending
Infiltrators: 38 vs. 18
Main Force: 78 vs. 43
Rear Guard: 93 vs. 79

“For the glory of the Imperium!” Gabriel boomed as he shouldered aside another dying Suysh while smashing aside a charging hungerer with his thunder hammer.

Deeper and deeper into the complex did the Blood Ravens descend. Over the course of a week there was a maelstrom of violence unleashed upon the alien which had dared to take the complex for their own. A storm that the aliens had never thought to face, never had been made to face before. These were not the scant PDF who had faltered in the beginning days of the alien invasion. Nor were these the desperate guerillas who had remained afterwards, only to be hunted down in the years afterward. These were the Emperor’s Angels of Death. These were the Blood Ravens. And though some of them may have fallen getting into the complex, they refused to relent. The apothecaries performed admirably, ensuring many a wound was healed or patched, whilst working in tandem with the techmarines to provide field maintenance on dozens of venerable suits of power armor to ensure continued combat was even possible.

Under Gabriel’s leadership, they marshaled a punishing pace indeed, even for space marines. At any given moment, bolters were firing, lascannons were sending spears of light down tunnels, and missile fire was transforming the insides of passageways into smoking piles of meat chunks and shattered alien metals. The dreadnoughts were of particular use, some remaining back at the cordon line in Hellfire variants while others were equipped as pure Assault Dreadnought patterns. At their head was Tomb-Captain Thule, whose leadership and fury against the enemies of the Imperium were welcome indeed. He was just as likely to help pick up a faltering marine with impossibly delicate usage of his appendages as he was to use the bulk of his frame to shatter walls and Suysh bodies in equal measure.

The pressure levied against the Blood Ravens did not lessen, no, but in fact increased. But such was to be expected, considering the mission at hand, yet still the Blood Ravens refused to slow. Behind them, too, the other half of the Hive boiled up out of the various entrances and exits of the canyon and immediately threw themselves against the side which the Blood Ravens had claimed for their own. Captain Sicarius threw back just as many attacks upon his position as the Suysh threw against Gabriel Angelos and his brothers. Heavy bolters and plasma cannons fired again and again, shell casings falling in enormous piles around various space marines.

“None shall pass, alien scum!” Sicarius roared as he fired his plasma cannon again and again.

=====================================

Interdiction
Blood Ravens: 62
Scarlet Lions: 73
Suysh Scout Fleet: 43

“Send out the techmarines and servitors to scavenge the wrecks,” Hadrian ordered, eyes straining against the dozen tactical screens he’d pulled up around him.

The fleet had not taken too much damage, more scars and scrapes than anything else. But every bit of damage was something to be repaired later. Thankfully, with the permissions of the Chapter Master, he would order some of the ships back to the Sacred Crown for such. Without it, he knew that it was just as likely that even if they possessed the coordinates to properly locate the enemy homeworld they would not be able to persecute the war properly. The longer it took them to conquer the planets present, the longer it would take for them to repair their ships? The more time the enemy had to prepare. Time he did not wish them to have. But for now, he would remain present, just in case the enemy had more ships to immediately throw at them. Though he could not help but wince slightly internally as the cross-ship vox crackled once more.

“A most glorious battle forthwith, Blood Raven!” Kallek boomed in his ears. “Victory hath been made here pon this stellar battlefield!”

“…indeed,” Hadrian sighed. “What is the status of your ships?”

“Mine own ships art hale and hearty, forsooth!”

“…I see.”

The Imperium was vast. The galaxy vaster still. Yet Hadrian could not help but violently desire to know just who was responsible for providing the planetary lexicon for lost Lemnos. Or perhaps at the very least to know how it had changed in the past ten thousand years since the Great Crusade to become…that. And then somewhere bombardment cannons would factor in, he just couldn’t figure out where or when. In any case, the battle had been won, not after hours and days of fighting in the darkness but in a wild accelerated rush at close range. A fight the Suysh normally excelled in, but then, they simply had not faced space marines before. And while Hadrian’s company were now fighting a planetary battle, the Scarlet Lions had seen fit to donate twenty-five of each of their companies present to fight within the void.

====================================================

Delving Deep
51 vs. 35
80 vs. 73
100 vs. 77

A level, and then another. Vast amounts of the complex had been constructed with a mixture of rockcrete and plascrete where greater durability was required. This, in turn, had been supplemented with alien alloys of foreign production to shore up perceived weaknesses within the mind of the alien. The deeper one went, the more changes were obvious, entire hallways and caverns carved out for the singular purpose of allowing the Queen greater access. This was, at least, the surmised opinion of the Librarius after vigorous debate. Considering the average size of a Suysh Queen, it was necessary for them to secret themselves deep within the earth more often than not. It was then the Hive’s responsibility to cover up the trenches and holes dug by their presence. Unfortunately for the aliens, the psykers of the Blood Ravens were capable of discerning the echoes left behind by such a presence, whether experienced or freshly promoted. For all that their physical forms were disgusting sacks of slimy and undulating scales and fat, their psychic presences were – once properly studied – actually discernable against the background of their multitudinous broods. If one strained. And worked together with the rest of the Librarius.

A dozen tales of brilliance and heroism were born within the darkness of the complex where alien geometries and design philosophy first melded with and then completely overtook stalwart Imperial construction. Apollo Diomedes grappled with two hungerers at the same time, slaying them both even as terminators of the 1st Company struggled to reach him through a mob of bodies. Davian Thule may have been placed within a dreadnought, but he thundered down the passages belting out hymnals of hate from his broadcast systems at the highest speed he could push his sarcophagus. The Chapter Master struck down void screamer after void screamer with his hammer, while elsewhere the Fist of Faith stormed through line after line. The skull-helmed preachers shattered every defensive emplacement that the enemy tried to put up to stop them, only ever pausing just long enough for the apothecaries to plug the holes in their flesh and the techmarines to patch the holes in their armor. Said techmarines also used their collected knowledge, knowledge that grew after every battle, to sabotage enemy equipment from afar. At least, enough for the scouts to rise up and blow them to pieces. There were holding actions, pincer movements, tunneling explosions, ambushes, charges and counter-charges, and more. The enemy grew ever more frenzied, but the Blood Ravens would not relent. They could not be stopped, not even slowed. They were outnumbered, vastly so, but that had ever been the case in this conflict.

The Royal Guard were summoned, the mightiest warriors that the Suysh could bring to bear, and these too fell. Torn asunder by the claws of Davian Thule. Beaten down by the hammers of Chapter Master Angelos and Apollo Diomedes. Vaporized entirely by the combined psychic might of the Librarius. Shot apart, blown up, ambushed, buried, and in some cases simply overrun. Hundreds of space marines fought through the tunnels with all the might that the Emperor could grant them and all the incalculable fury for the alien that they could muster. Even the neophytes, those not even granted the blessings of the gene-seed, fought alongside those they would soon become with admirable skill. Something not missed by the scout sergeants and Captain Octavius himself.

For days, then weeks, they dove deep beneath the earth. Regular resupply missions were carried out by the aid of the thunderhawks bringing in more war material, a steady strain of servitors and neophytes hefting enormous pallets of ammunition and teleporter beacons into already cleared passages. All to ensure that the momentum was kept at the blistering pace that had been achieved. Until, finally, they reached the deepest hollow left within the complex. A place where the Suysh Queen had carved out for itself, after squeezing its disgusting amorphous bulk through the complex, a place wholly given over to the xeno mind and preference just beyond the noble Imperial architecture. A place that could not have been dug to due to the instability such efforts might have caused to the complex itself, nor bombarded from orbit if one intended to restore the facility. That would have taken months, perhaps longer, for an Imperial Guard regiment to batter their way into.

But it did not face the Imperial Guard.

Extermination Efforts
45 vs. 33
29 vs. 10
59 vs. 50

When it was revealed, the pict-captures later placed into the Librarius records would show a horribly bloated thing. It was of a slightly redder complexion than the Queen previously killed, but its disgusting flab and constant birthing of mucous covered eggs slopping out of its overly porous skin was familiar enough. It screeched continuously, an endless screaming drone which caused the air to reverberate continuously. Practically reclining within its mountains of eggs, it writhed back and forth as more were produced. The Librarius were able to warn of a psychic pulse which began to emanate from it, hundreds of eggs splitting open and releasing all manner of Suysh at various stages of gestation simultaneously. This newly birthed horde staggered out and towards the Blood Ravens at steadily increasing pace alongside the rest of their hive who had already been present.

The battle lines had been drawn, but the Blood Ravens knew they need not approach any further than they already had. For they had brought all the ordinance they needed with them. Even as the Suysh charged into prepared heavy bolter and lascannon positions, the whirlwinds of the Blood Ravens began to unleash their devastating payloads. Every time the Suysh threatened to actually breach the lines, assault marines rose high into the cavern’s air before descending to earth with bone-shattering force. The Queen screamed in pain as the initial incendiary payload of six artillery platforms slammed into her enormous and thus easily targetable frame, and screamed further still as krak missiles followed shortly after to break through her fatty and now burning exterior. This caused the Suysh to fight even harder. Heat cannons and rapid fire slug throwing weaponry set the Blood Ravens and the ground around them to glowing even as craters began being blown into them.

Here and there, the sheer volume alone coupled with far more accuracy than, say, orks would be capable of ensured that even the power armor of the space marines would take damage. More than one marine was sent flying backwards as a missile struck the ground near them, or their body head on. Most were gathered up by the apothecaries, while a few doughty marines instead chose to get right back up and into the fight then and there. In one nearly dire case, a veteran of the 1st Company, Sergeant Flavius, shifted his terminator-clad body into one such missile, blocking bodily what would have otherwise wiped out a squad of neophytes who had managed to get too close to the front. All the while, the whirlwinds continued to fire. They alternated between the three missile types, starting with the traditional explosive warheads, to the incendiaries, to the krak missiles, and back again.

With each salvo, the Librarius flared their own psychic abilities to counter-act those of the enemy. And it was needed. For the true threat of a Queen aware of her foes was not to be discounted. Localized psychic lightning storms began to form, only to barely be snuffed out by the Librarians. Void screamers, the enemy psykers, would erupt in skin-flaying and armor breaking explosions of pure psychically charge sound. Gigantic spears of heat would stab from nowhere, capable of sending a space marine flying and killing a neophyte after a handful of seconds of exposure. All of these and more, the Librarius fought, the whole assembled might of the chapter locked into a ritual circle of their own design, each channeling together with the Chief Librarian at their head.

In the end, who struck the final blow could not be told for certain. The whirlwind crews had grown ever more synchronized as the fighting had gone on, after all.

===========================================

Justininus was aware of the alien’s vile soul leaving its putrid flesh behind the very second it happened. With a single hard clenched fist, the physical realm departed, leaving the mind-melting cornucopia of impossibility and half-reality to be revealed in its place. Around him was a massive corona of psychic energies, much of it not even his own, as fellow librarians worked to support him. He saw the true form of the Suysh Queen’s soul, abhorrent in the extreme, just as it saw him. Here, it had ballooned in malformed shape compared to its now dead body, but the stains of its death were still there. Huge portions of its projected form were missing, signs of the violent explosions that had caused its death. He heard it begin to speak, but he cared not for the contents, for the vengeance it promised to levy upon him. Instead, he raised his arms to his sides, palms facing towards it and fingers clenching.

He knew what was coming next.

The Librarius as a group more felt, than saw, the Queen’s attentions shift towards the whirlwind crews. They could not see the threat facing them, though they were aware of the consequences of being the deliverers of death in this instance. To those with the capability of seeing, it was a horrific thing to behold. Even as her form, her very being, was disintegrating from the stresses being placed upon it, she flooded towards the whirlwind crews. Her wailing shrieks burnt dozens of daemons and lesser creatures of the warp from existence even while the rage behind it birthed as many more. Then, for just an instant, Justinius shifted his being, interposing himself before what was becoming less the a fallen being and more the fury of a dying star.

Phantom heat came, pouring outwards, a final order to be given.

Only to slam into vast black wings, so dark as to swallow all light before them. A stark, dour thing, standing in total contrast to the self-combusting blaze which assailed it. All around them, the warp screamed as it ever did, but here, now, in this one instance, there was the resounding and solidified concept of protection. Of cessation. The origins of the protective work were storied indeed, and one never to be revealed to those not of the Librarius due to certain portions of its foundational sources. But in any case, it held, the image of protective black wings held strong, a beating core of blindingly bright red crystal at the center with Justinius himself at its core. The Queen raged, and beat upon the shield held up before it, and yet…it held.

Physically, none could see the Librarius anymore once the ritual had begun. Marines nearby were forced to turn their heads away as the light grew ever brighter, purest white light flickering with motes of absolute black. A pair of Lexicanum collapsed, blood trickling from their eyes and ears, while elsewhere a codicier’s ritual chanting transformed into one long ragged scream that seemed to possess no end. The apothecaries could do nothing but watch, and trust that the bodies of the Librarians would hold out long enough to receive aid. All the while, Justinius stood, motionless, without even sweat on his brow to show the struggle he was undertaking in withstanding the Queen’s final act. His eyes had become as of solid light, now.

Again, and again, the Queen slammed her bulk against his shield, desperate now to reach her killers. More and more of the soul was used up in each strike, from its own stresses and from the parasites which were beginning to feast upon a rapidly decaying soul. Soon, near mindless now, it turned and instead focused upon the Chapter Master himself even as he stood at the battle line locked in combat. Here, then, was the master of all those who had fought against her hive, had ordered her death. Yet as such blazed towards him, the shield shifted and blocked her once again. Again, the Queen’s flickering soul turned, to Apollo Diomedes, who was responsible for saving the life of the Chapter Master after his near death on Cyrene. And again, this time with its strength spent further and further, it was blocked.

Eventually…despair rose up even past the previously incandescent fury, and the alien found that it could not batter its way through the defense conjured. It could not go around it, nor divert it.

In the end, as it flailed ever weaker, Justinius Probalis watched with restrained calm as it dissipated entirely.

In reality, the psychic duel lasted but moments. The Queen died, and the psychic and biological reaction that was so feared on a dozen planets throughout the rest of the sector simply did not come to pass. There was no overdrive of adrenal production, no absolute fearlessness, no charging swarms with skins splitting from rapidly mutated musculature which could pick up space marines and tear them apart with their bare hands. There was, starkly, nothing.

And then there was terror.

For the Suysh, this had never been done. A Queen would fall, and a target would be set. The hive would be reabsorbed later on by another. Even in the days of civil conflict between the hives, where the Queens fought each other, such a thing had never been done. It was incomprehensible. Rather than the fury of their slain mother invigorating them, there was emptiness. Emptiness, and no guidance at all. The Royal Guard, their souls so linked to the Queen, faltered as that connection was left in ruin. Then, they too, fell, torn apart as the whirlwinds turned their payloads upon the confused and milling swarm. Without guidance, the hive broke apart and tried to flee, turning their backs and heading back towards the still warm corpse of their Queen. The Blood Ravens did not halt their attacks, and instead began marching forward from the line.

Chainswords cut through spines rather than rib cages, bolter shells slammed into knees and boots fell upon the backs of heads, and the Blood Ravens refused to stop. The aliens turned and ran, and ran, climbing up the eggs which they had just been birthed from, only to be cut down where they stood. The whirlwinds switched to incendiary payloads exclusively, setting aflame vast portions of the hive. Heavy flamers unleashed their own gouts. Fearfully, falling onto their most base instincts, the aliens began to eat, to feast upon the dead, dying, and living alike. The battle had come to an end, but the extermination would take an hour more.

================================================

From neophyte to Chapter Master, the Blood Ravens emerged from within the manufactorum complex drenched head to toe in alien gore and viscera. Slategrass Canyon Complex had been cleansed to satisfaction, and though much of the hive remained, they remained without any leadership above squad-level leadership. Piles of enemy dead lay in the deeps between the two canyon walls, prevented utterly from piercing into the half which had housed their Queen. They were utterly unaware of their Queen’s death, and could do little but screech ineffectually as the thunderhawks flew down while high in orbit the teleportariums began to go to work. Within the next sixty minutes, all the aliens had left were their dead and dying. Panic shortly ensued amongst the surviving members of the Slategrass Hive when the remains of their Queen were discovered. Uncaring for their rapidly propagating mental deterioration save for the possible tactical usages, the Chapter scoured their armor clean, rearmed, resupplied, and healed what injuries could be healed.

There were yet Queens remaining to be slain on Matsuya. The Death-Mark on Captain Cyrus was still functional, and retained some tactical worth still. But things were different than before. Now, the enemy had been faced in battle, again and again. The full measure of their alien arsenal had been weathered, the information collated and analyzed by the Librarius and strategic cogitators. There were dead Queens, dead Royal Guard, portions of flesh and structure taken for inspection. The biological gift known as the Omophagea of the space marines had been put to use, partaking of brain structure of various Suysh variants, up to and including the Queen of the Slategrass Complex herself. And, for a time, the space marines of the Blood Ravens did not descend to the planet below again. Even as the Scarlet Lions ran rampant across another world, they waited. They studied all they had learned, won through blood and sweat and death. They collected reports granted from a dozen worlds and hundreds of battlefields from the Imperial Guard, requests for information granted long ago only answered and delivered months later due to the chaos of so many different points within the sector.

Then, and only then, did the Blood Ravens descend to Matsuya once more.

As The Seeker of Truth Did, So Shall We
70 vs. 40

And in this, they followed the glorious example of the Great Father, Azariah Vidya, when he fought within the Gothic Sector in M37. And while Qulus Trine was no longer the responsibility of a non-existent 8th Company, a responsibility stripped by the Civil War and the repercussions afterward, that too was a victory to be held close to their hearts. To honor those two victories amongst so many others, the Blood Ravens fought alongside their Librarians once more. Though the Chapter was depleted of its previous and far more potent psychic might of the past, there was still power that remained within their ranks. Analyzing the presences of the Queens, having tasted their foul alien sorceries firsthand, coupled with all the other information at their disposal, the Blood Ravens descended at various locations across the planet, one after the other.

71+15=86 vs 75

The Obsidian Desert Mining Pit, where another Queen had been discovered previously, was the first target. Flecks of obsidian which coated the dusty floors of the corridors were crushed into ever finer powder. Assaults on Blood Raven strike teams were blunted due to said teams suddenly withdrawing, in turn dragging their foes into ambushes and crossfires. Plunging deep strike teams tore into the rears of advancing Suysh columns as they tried to stopper the tide of space marines before disappearing once more. It was a hard fight, undeniably, but one still won regardless as the Blood Ravens grew more adept at simply outfighting and outthinking the Suysh forces. Reinforcements were delayed, elite teams blown apart by mines and hidden explosives, Royal Guard targeted by the Fist of Faith or the Chapter Master before they could do little more than roar in fury. In the end, the final blow was struck by the Chief Librarian, who elected to further test matters by slaying the Queen outright by setting an avatar of purest psychic flame upon her in the shape of a screaming raven. Thus, he was already the main target of the Death-Mark, yet to the shock of the Queen and her Hive, stood strong with the Librarius behind him.

62+15=77 vs. 43

Then came Vehicular Manufactorum A7b, sequestered in the Tang-Yung Valley, was where a third Suysh Queen was determined to be located. Here, the Fist of Faith carved out a new legend for themselves. Bellowing litanies of hate and fury, they challenged the entire Suysh Hive present to face them as they charged at the open entrance to the complex where many an alien tank had come rolling out of for many a year. Then they made good on their oaths and charged forward despite the numbers which answered their demand. Behind them came the total armored might of the Chapter, from rapier to land raider, but the Fist of Faith was the only infantry present at that battle. For unbeknownst to the alien, scouts of the 10th Company infiltrated behind enemy lines and placed teleporter beacons down in areas designated by the Librarians. Areas clear only for a scant few minutes at a time, yet precisely when there were no Suysh to stop them, much less know they were there. Carefully, steadily, without pause, they did this until the Queen had removed much of her strength to fight off those at the entrance to the manufactorum. Only then did the Blood Ravens strike all across the manufactorum simultaneously, further isolating the Queen as her remaining forces shifted to respond, allowing scouts to infiltrate deeper amidst the ensuing chaos. At the furthest depths that the Queen had hidden within, teleporting was inadvisable due to the margins of error meaning that a marine might be lost through translating back to reality while within the rock. Instead, the 1st Company, terminator-clad, skulked with the predictive aid of the Librarians.

Then, once they reached the chamber with the Queen, once the administrative nexus of the manufactorum, they fell upon the alien with heavy flamer, assault cannon, and lascannon aplenty. Chapter Master Angelos slew the beast personally, approaching through her legions of eggs and battering his way into her innards with the aid of Godsplitter. Even the forced release of said eggs could not stop the 1st Company, the greatest heroes and veterans of the chapter doing what more than one Imperial Guard regiment had been slaughtered doing without taking any fatalities at all.

100 vs. 76
93 vs. 4

By then, the two remaining Queens on Matsuya had actually begun meshing their forces together, tunneling beneath the earth in order to try and group up. Their tactics at hiding themselves within human installations was failing them, for the Blood Ravens were able enough to both bring their strength to bear without the danger of irreparable damage to precious technologies. They abandoned the underground refineries they had both disappeared into, tunneling deeper into the world. Orbital bombardment to reach them would possibly crack the earth too far, forcing – they hoped – their foes to try and come after them in ways that would be untenable. Continually birthed defenders and truly fortified areas, they struggled to summon the hives of their fellow and now slain Queens, only to find that without the unique bio-psychic reaction normally resulting from a Queen’s death that they could not. A vague, yet notable bond remained, one that kept the remaining hives from being easily assimilated.

Even so, the hopes of the alien were not to be. By the time they had begun their digging and evacuation efforts to a hidden fallback area, it was too late. The Blood Ravens had already found them, and in fact had been planting teleporter beacons and explosives for some time. It was only through the psychic predictions and intensive studies of alien psychology performed by the Librarius, coupled with individualized analysis of the subtle differences in behavior of various Suysh Hives, that they could have predicted thus at all. The explosives set back evacuation proceedings long enough for the rest of the Blood Ravens to arrive. For strike teams to break through hastily assembled new defenses, to cut into the back of already retreating forces, and, eventually, to perform the grim duty set before them. Who were these two last Queens on the planet? Allies? Friends? Brood-sisters? They showed a level of companionship that the others had not displayed whatsoever, the only similar incident being when the void-borne Queen had arrived swearing vengeance, soon to die as well.

And yet, it did not matter in the end.

Their bodies and their hives were burnt, bombed, and destroyed. Their very souls burnt into non-existence.

As was only right, in the name of the Imperium and the Emperor.

=======================================================

Gabriel gave a muted sigh of relief as his skin felt the touch of recycled air for the first time in a considerable period of time, watching idly as various portions of his terminator armor were lifted away. Serfs and servitors immediately saw to cleansing and purification rites, while two techmarines began enacting repairs on what portions of the plate required it. The sheer level of alien gore which had coated it would require considerable effort to scrape away indeed. He did end up raising an eyebrow at the sight where a particularly powerful void screamer had struck with a concentrated bolt of crystalized warp-flame. The impact site would have been particularly grievous were it not for the strength of the armor itself, certainly enough to have broken through and slain a marine wearing standard power armor.

A few moments later found him dressed in a large robe glowering over the tactical display within a war room in the Omnis Arcanum.

“The Suysh still rule the planet, but they are utterly without leadership,” he muttered, “And without a new Queen to re-establish control, there is little reason to think that they will somehow rally. Martellus, what can planetary scans tell us?”

The Master of the Forge deftly manipulated a few of the knobs and switches on the table, changing the holo-projection to a green geographically accurate sphere. Then, with another press of an activation rune, enormous swathes of red began coating the planet in varying levels of density.

“Over two thirds of the planet is still infested with the aliens, but without their Queens as commanders they’re falling into more and more feral instincts,” Martellus spoke clinically as he continued to adjust the projector’s contents.

A flick of a finger and the planet was reduced while several rotating screens appeared displaying recon footage sent by various scout teams. In one Suysh were tearing into one another, some dropping their weapons entirely so that they could better shovel the cooked meat of their foes into their mouths. In another, a Royal Guard of one fallen Queen slammed into another Royal Guard from a different Suysh Hive. Though they displayed far more tactical capability than their lesser brethren, there was still a distinct animalistic bent to their combat, as well as the utter absence of their foul alien language save for guttural single sentences that Martellus did not even bother translating.

“They still retain control and access to various vehicle production facilities, for now,” Cyrus spoke up, biological eye narrowed. “But without Queens to direct them, they’re beginning to send them against each other. It’s starting slow now, largely border skirmishes between different Hive territories. But given time the fighting will likely only grow in scope.”

Martellus nodded at the Master of Recruits.

“Cyrus is right. There is the potential of, should their fighting grow too intense, that they will begin causing damage to the vital production manufactorums, among other locations. The Mechanicus would not be particularly pleased if that was the case.”

Gabriel pursed his lips.

“What of their VTOL and anti-orbital capabilities, currently?”

“Hold a moment, Chapter Master,” Martellus rapidly flicked his fingers through the piles of data-slates he had carried into the war room with him. “Hmm. It seems like the former are being sent against one another or are going unused entirely, with major defensive shielding going silent.”

All three of them looked up at the same time. Martellus had his face obscured by his helm, and Cyrus did not do much other than the faintest ghost of a quirk of his lips, but Gabriel would not restrain his smile. A hand went up to his ear as he activated the command band of the vox.

“Brother-Captain Hadrian?”

“Aye, Chapter Master?”

“Begin purification spread orbital bombardment. Do not harm the strategic targets given to us.”

Hadrian’s immediate response was a loud bloodthirsty laugh.

“I see! Understood Chapter Master! All crews, prepare for purification spread bombardment!”

Any space marine ship’s crew would know the differing levels of orbital bombardment, but it was rare that purification spread was used. It was, after all, just barely removed from Exterminatus. The majority of the time it was meant for pin-point destruction of enemy assets and bases. Or, more depressingly, to ensure that bodies and equipment were not desecrated in the case of the Kaurava campaign. In the end, the various roads would require reconstruction, as would the settlement buildings that the miners and manufactorum workers. But those could be quickly and cheaply reproduced. What mattered was that the Suysh could not readily reproduce their near endless numbers, not on Matsuya. Not anymore. As had been proven by Cyrus during the fighting, bereft of any other orders, the psychic remnants of the Death-Mark would be the greatest sign of ‘authority’ left to the Suysh. They would follow Cyrus, into the jaws of death if required.

Within moments, the Omnis Arcanum began to shudder ever so slightly, the only sign to those within its depths that it was unleashing its bombardment upon the planet below.

“What of the Scarlet Lions? How fares their fighting?”

Martellus mumbled a quiet prayer to the machine spirits as he switched the planetary display from Matsuya to Vatsa. There, the red cloaking the planet was interspersed with small emblems of the Scarlet Lion heraldry. Some of them were holding position, others were showing estimates on their rather rapid movements across the planet surface. Occasionally, a muted beam of yellow would fire down from their battle barge to represent their own ongoing orbital bombardment efforts. Though, to Gabriel’s eye, it was undeniable that little progress seemed to have been made. In comparison to the Blood Ravens, at least.

“Well, they certainly did not arrive with their entire chapter’s Librarius to aid them, Chapter Master,” Martellus spoke as he zoomed the image in slightly to focus on certain areas of the planet. “But their ferocity is unquestionable. They have, at the moment, killed two Queens on the planet, of an unknown number.”

“I see,” Gabriel rubbed at his chin, “I imagine a not inconsiderable amount of their attentions are not on the Suysh at all, however.”

“I would have to agree with you,” Martellus nodded, pointing out with the aid of the haptic interface to touch faded Blood Raven symbols now covered by Scarlet Lion ones. “They have utterly scoured the areas that Cyrus noted down for them and then some. Of course, we can’t expect them to have found too much just yet, and they don’t seem inclined to share just now.”

“Hmmph.”

“In somewhat better news, Chief Librarian Justinian reports that they’re getting closer to discerning just where and how we should get to the Suysh home systems, coinciding with my own techmarines scanning the wreckage from the Suysh ships and the data left on the cogitators in the Crown.”

There would be that, at least. Hopefully, they would possess that information sooner rather than later, even if they could not quite yet justify leaving before completing their duty. There was little else to discuss after that, save for minor maintenance reports. Martellus would soon leave for the space station once more, while Gabriel himself would be practicing in the chapel before it was time to deploy again. Perhaps an hour or so of rest before persecuting the rest of the campaign on one of the remaining three worlds of the system with Queens on them. The only thing that Gabriel could find worrisome in the immediate moment was the fact that no other fleet had arrived. Whether that was because the Suysh were building up their numbers, redirecting ships, or something else, he could not know. Not until it happened. But the nature of the universe was such that he refused to think that the aliens would not be coming through the void once more, and soon.

Refinement And Continuation
Phase 4 Concluded! With all the knowledge gained thus far, and the aid of the Scarlet Lions, choose how the remainder of the Jahal System Cleansing will go. This means that the phase will continue until all objectives are completed barring major shake-ups such as an Ork WAAAGH!! entering the system, Gabriel or any of the Captains dying, etc. Choose carefully. Due to the extent of the phase's time-frame, it is assumed all wounded marines are healed and return to service, and that damaged ships return to Sacred Crown for repair. They will still be in this post's casualties notation, simply for tracking purposes, but can be assumed healed/repaired as best as possible by the beginning of the next phase. Information gained on killing requirements, psychic aid, etc. will be factored into the planning of the characters now that they have that information. With all Queens on Matsuya slain, and the information thus gained, it should now be possible to target the remaining planets, whether that is to aid the Scarlet Lions on Vatsa or target the other remaining two! Sacred Crown has regained its ship repair and maintenance capabilities! Moratorium for 3 Hours.

Phase Pathing
Void Placement
[] Bombardment: Write-In Which Fleets Go To Which Planet For Orbital Aid Purposes (Teleportation, Bombardment, Drop Pods, Etc.)
[] Interdiction: Write-In Which Fleets/Ships Remain On Interdiction Duty

Force Placement
1st Fleet, And All Ground Elements Of Chapter On Matsuya
2nd, 4th and 10th Fleets On Interdiction Duty
[] Keep Positions As They Are
[] Change Company Deployments For The Planets (I.E. Shifting 1st Company to Vatsa or 10th Company to Kuru) (Write-In Changes)

Planetary Ground Target Priority List [i.e. Top, Middle, Bottom for Kuru/Middle, Bottom, Top for Matsuya/Etc.]
[] Kuru (Write-In Ground Priority List)
[] Avanti (Write-In Ground Priority List)
[] Vatsa (Write-In Ground Priority List)

Progression List
[] Write-In Planetary Progression List [Kuru, then Avanti, then Vatsa/Vatsa, then Kuru, then Avanti, etc.]

Phase Completes!

Spoiler: Total Casualties/Fatalities

4 Scouts [1st Stage] Killed [8 Gene-Seed Recovered]
5 4th Company Marines Dead [10 Gene-Seed Recovered]
1 Tarantula Sentry Turret Destroyed (Twin-Linked Heavy Bolters)
16 2nd Company Marines Killed (32 Gene-Seed Recovered)
1 1st Company Marine Killed (2 Gene-Seed Recovered)
25 10th Company Neophytes [2nd Stage] Killed

Spoiler: Phase Objectives + Tactical Considerations

Tactical Consideration! 'True' Scarlet Lions Have Arrived In System, True Support Sent By Inquisitor Lord Tarquindil! 2nd, 3rd, and 4th Company of Scarlet Lions, bringing 1 Battle Barge + 4 Strike Cruisers + 12 Nova Frigates in the void and 300 marines plus specialists on the ground. Led under command of Force Commander Bartorius, also Captain of the 4th Company. True Identity of 'False' Scarlet Lions Unknown!
Tactical Consideration! Suysh Death-Scream Vengeance Effect Identified As Psychic/Organic Effect! Librarius Has Shown Repeated Success In Diverting/Blocking Effect So Long As Entire Librarius Tasked To Doing So!
Tactical Consideration! Tactical Objectives For Campaign (Queen Slaying) On Matsuya Completed! Cyrus Currently Death-Marked!
Tactical Consideration! 1 Queen Located On Kuru, Avanti! 3 More Queens Located On Vatsa After Slaying Of 2 From Scarlet Lions!
Tactical Consideration! Scarlet Lions have elected to push entire ground force onto planet Vatsa to search for signs of the 'other' Scarlet Lions! Battle Bagre is on orbital duty, their strike cruisers and escorts on interdiction duty!
Tactical Consideration! No Second Retaliatory Suysh Fleet Has Arrived Yet, But It Is Expected Soon!